I'm actually super pleased to see finally for the first time I think that I have ever seen this happen—
dear cybersecurity industry if any of you folks like work in AppSec or InfoSec like—this is,
we are helping out civic services and volunteer groups and activist groups with our expertise far too little far too late.
Right. But basically, there's like the COVID-19 cybersecurity response now,
that folks that people are doing, who are in the industry, who are sitting there setting up the equivalent of like, you know, a Slack channel
for, you know, cross company collaboration, but now they're offering that pro bono to
critical infrastructure services like hospitals and health care providers and this sort of stuff,
smaller groups that are doing for example, home deliveries that are trying to set up websites and this kind of stuff.
That's great to see. Too little too fucking late! But you know, it's something.
And I'm glad to see that because that's really great.
We need more of that kind of pro bono work that is not governmental in nature,
that is just actual mutual aid, like for real people helping people, because they're neighbors, right?
Like, I like to say that just because you know, you have running water doesn't mean you want to be a plumber,
and you shouldn't have to be a plumber.
But someone in your community should fucking be a plumber,
because you're going to be better off when your pipes break.
Someone in your community should fucking be a system administrator, should fucking be, you know, doing some kind of infosec
and those people should then help those folks who don't want to do that full time.
And so it's good to see that happen.
So primarily, we're seeing ransomware attacks, primarily, we're seeing obviously continuation with phishing.
Those are sort of tied together obviously,
because a lot of, y'know, over 90% of the footholds in corporate networks
are going to be phishing related in some, some way, one way or another.
We do, for what it's worth, have an entire phishing workshop that is about Web based
social engineering attacks. So we show how phishing works.