So, there's this discussion, right, in hopefully episode one about
putting Colby's IP in the dat file, right?
So, a "dat file" is just hacker speak for a file with an extension of .dat.
I make a text file, right? So let's say this is some text.
And I put this into, you know, a file with a dot txt extension, right?
If I use the file command on that file, you'll see that it says to me that I had ASCII text, right?
So it tells me that I have a text file.
A dat file is simply a file with a—I'll move that to a dot dat extension, right? So we're taking text,
and we're changing it out with dot dat.
And the idea here is that technically a dat file, that's all it is. It's just a file with a dot dat extension.
But if I put some, for example, some binary data in it, so let's do for example,
openssl, some random bytes and put that into openssl rand,
let's say 10 bytes of random data. And if we xxd that, xxd file with a .dat.
So, here's some random bytes that I generated. This is no longer text.
It's just, you know, ones and zeros, basically. And here we can see the hex dump of it.
So now we have a dat file, which is just a data file, right short for data.
And that's all that jargon is.
We don't know exactly what rootkit Darlene was like,
Darlene was writing there, and we don't know exactly what the architecture of their sort of scheme
against the Evil Corp really was.
One possible guess, right, is to assume that if you are the FBI, trying to sort of figure out who did what,
then one of the things are going to do, is you're going to grab some evidence from the machines that you are investigating.
So for example, if we go to awesome incident response, wiki infosec, incident, awesome incident response.
So here is a repo on GitHub with a ton of tools for evidence collection,
Margarita Shotgun, it's a pretty popular one down here.
And so evidence collection in the context of DFIR (digital forensics and incident response) is
the collection of digital artifacts from potentially compromised or just sort of like machines that you have on the network that you're trying to investigate
and figuring out what it is that they were doing at the time that matters to you.
It's basically the digital equivalent of detective sleuthing right.
And so putting an IP in a dat file we are to left to assume means that there's some file somewhere
that their programming, you know, their rootkit, their hack against Evil Corp was tracing the locations of connecting computers.
And if you find an IP and again, an IP is going to be something like for example, right?
Right. So here's some example IPs, these are all sort of my
local network IP, you can see that you probably also have like a 192.168.10, or 192.168.1 or 192.168.200 or something like that
network wherever you are.
And so these are IP addresses, as we may already know,
and putting an IP in a dat file probably means something along the lines of
faking some evidence that would then be collected from tools like these
by a digital forensics and incident response group
that would then point to quote "Colby's terminal," by which they mean the computer that Colby uses in his office.