Right. So this is known as cryptographic mixnet.
M-I-X-N-E-T, and the idea here is that because we have a blind node in the middle there,
then if we can trust some, which is to say, enough of a percentage of the network,
then you are reducing the amount of metadata and information that can be gathered by your adversary
such as the NSA. Not saying it's perfect and there's definitely been traffic correlation,
you know, issues and, but those are not vulnerabilities of the Tor system.
The Tor system as it exists today,
in sort of like a design, right is as robust as it was in the 90's when it was developed in the Naval Research Lab at the Naval Research Laboratory NRL
the US NRL or something like that.
And that's because the design is a mixnet.
Just like for example, if you familiar with Bitcoin tumblers
where you basically do Bitcoin money laundering, right?
Cleaning money from Bitcoin. That's the same principle.
You send a bunch of data in, so it's hard to figure out where that data comes out.
That is, we look at, for example, a cryptographic mix net on Wikipedia.
This is what you want to read, if you want to know more about that.
And what's—mix network. Yeah.
And what's really cool about this, this sort of paradigm is that as long, again, as long as you can trust some nodes,
then you have a very, very high probability of making it at best or, you know,
at worst, extremely hard for your adversary to find stuff out about you.
We know, the NSA has trouble with Tor. We've seen that in the Snowden slides since 2013.
Tor itself, the cryptographic protocols are not broken.
There are sometimes bugs in Tor Browser, which is primarily a Firefox issue, right?
If we go to for example, Tor browser and go to about Tor Browser, you'll see it's based on Mozilla Firefox,
which is one reason why we tell you constantly keep your software up to date.
You'll see a little green icon here if your Tor browser is out of date. And the minute you see that you want to update.
In fact, you may even want to go to "About Tor Browser" before you do anything else because the first thing that—when you open Tor Browser—because what it does is it updates.
Here Tor browser is up to date, right it checks for an update.
So, most things when you hear Tor has been hacked, it's actually Firefox browser has a vulnerability in it,
which is almost always solvable for most people. Just by doing this.
About -> Tor Browser, and you're up to date.