When you have a password like for example, you know,
let's just say this is my password, it's not right,
if I was to log in system, then I would need a username and password to login you see this on the Facebook website
and so on.
There's a couple things that happen when you give a remote site your access credentials,
like when you launched you know, GoBrunch, you know, you signed in to GoBrunch to come here,
you know, you made an email address, you made a password you put you put those in,
Hopefully, what GoBrunch is doing—I don't know, I'm not privy to this sort of stuff—
what GoBrunch is doing is hashing it, which is to say that it's taking this content, right password,
right. So there's my, there's my password echoed.
And it's taking that password and putting it through something like a hash function.
Now, hopefully it's using something like bcrypt. I'm going to just demo this with shasum.
And I'll use SHA-1 because it's super fast. And
when I do that, you can see that I get this other piece of text. Right.
So this is the SHA one hash, sometimes called a digest or message digest of the text of the data password.
If I put in something very similar, but not exactly the same, like for example, with a zero,
I'll get a completely different result. And see how these seeds are completely different.
A small change in the input will produce a massive change in the output.
And that's really important because it means that you can't sort of deduce that this is password,
or that this is password with a zero unless you do this process yourself.
So if I, for example, do this a bunch of times, right and I save this output a bunch of times. So let's go ahead and do this and we'll save this to for example.
Yeah, right. So I will put this output and I'll say, you know, these are
hashes, right?
And then we do this, again, oops, I want this to be word, right. And then I do this, again for maybe password one,
and then maybe for password two, and you get the idea, right?
If you look at these files, you know, here are all the hashes that I now have have computed.
Instead of a dash here, it would be the actual text that you put in.
So it's a mapping between the hash and the input that that hash produced.
So hopefully GoBrunch and every other service that you use passwords with, does something like this.
The process is a little bit more involved cryptographically. We can talk a little bit about password based key derivation functions, PBKDFs,
which sort of extend passwords and generate keys based on input and then produce hashes.
Anyway, the point is, conceptually at some point, there's going to be a piece of data stored a secret that's stored on the server you are trying to log into,
and they're going to match that with the input you gave it to see whether or not the password you entered is actually the password that they remember.
But they're going to hopefully keep your password in this form this hashed form rather than just keeping the plaintext.
So one super easy way to find out is if you've ever used the like remind me my password feature
and they have—you ever get like a—you know, sign up for a site or something like you know,
dinky forum or something, make your account, log out and then instead of logging back in
log in using, like, the account recovery feature,
and if they send you back your plain text password, then you know they are not hashing.