This is sort of where the like, it's good to know how the tool works so that you can use it.
So you understand what it's doing.
But it is also just as important for you to know how to use the tool, right?
It's not important that—you need to both know how to use it safely and what it is doing.
How it works.
Only knowing one of them right doesn't cover you.
Knowing how it works might have you be very knowledgeable about sort of the technical side,
but not knowing how to use it safely means that your OPSEC, your operational security,
could be compromised.
And what I mean by that is simply the things you do your operations,
right, could be compromised simply by stuff you do that the technology is not designed or not equipped to protect you against.
So if I go to facebook.com and I log in here,
right let's say I'm you know, Shayla and I suddenly, nah, let's say I'm Sam Elliot cuz Shayla doesn't use,
nah, let's use Shayla,  'cause let's make her awesome.
shayla@mac.com right, can I type in my password here?
If I were to log in? This is not obviously a real Facebook account. But if it was,
you know, what would be happening here? Why would this potentially compromise
my Tor connection to at least Facebook?
Yes, Facebook does have an onion site. In fact, let's go there facebookcorewwwi.onion.
Well, so Razi says whoever owns the end node gets your creds.
It's not so much about the end node in this case, right?
Because, theoretically, especially with the Facebook, onion service, right,
and also the HTTPS connection that we're making to,
to Facebook right, the end node here. Well, I guess now we're on the onion site. Let's go back.
The exit node right is not going to know our creds because we are still HTTPS encrypted, right?
We have that little lock icon we can see that it's, the actual certificate
by Facebook so if I actually inspect the certificate super closely,
you can see that the SHA 256 fingerprint here is going to match Facebook's.
But in any event, the point is that if it's encrypted, then the exit node isn't going to know your creds,
the site you're going to log into, it's going to know your creds, right.
And the point here is that Facebook has like fucking bugs everywhere, right?
Like, I mean, what sites do you go to that doesn't have a Facebook like icon.
And so if you're now browsing around to different sites, Tor browser will try to do some things to protect you in that scenario, it's called circuit isolation.
But you know, because Facebook is sort of has one of these that really
wide reaching you know, there weren't there you can basically think of them as like the Internet Five Eyes, right?
The Five Eyes are like those nation states that have come together, the United States, England, I think Australia,
there's a couple of others but the point is like Facebook is basically like a five eye,
right like Microsoft, Facebook, Google, the FAANG, you know,
Facebook, Apple, Amazon, Netflix and Google thing. Yeah.
Those companies have like web bugs basically fucking everywhere on every fucking website.
And so if you go to a bunch of different sites, after logging into Facebook on Tor Browser, then it is possible
through traffic correlation for Facebook to potentially start to get some profile of you, right.
And so it's not bad to log into Facebook, feel free to do that over Tor Browser.
But it's not necessarily something you want to then immediately start doing like stuff that you would maybe not want to search like, you know,
you know, I'm not gonna do that right now, but
in the same tab, or in the same session.
And so in between those two things, you want to click this button, the New Identity button,
and that'll sort of wipe your Tor browser history in a certain way, give you a new circuit etc.
And that's what this is for.
So this is for unlinking your previous activity to your future activity.