<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2020-07-02T12:15:26-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">Student Profile Series: Satisfaction Brought it Back</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/06/14/student-profile-series-satisfaction-brought-it-back.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Student Profile Series: Satisfaction Brought it Back" /><published>2020-06-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/06/14/student-profile-series-satisfaction-brought-it-back</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/06/14/student-profile-series-satisfaction-brought-it-back.html">&lt;p&gt;For years now, Tech Learning Collective has been training students in technical skills that they’ve used for personal projects, career advancement, and activist organizing efforts. As society’s collective reliance on digital skills has skyrocketed, especially with more people forced to adopt distance-everything routines like “e-learning,” working from home, and online socializing, so too have &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/04/02/mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour-highlights.html&quot;&gt;we at Tech Learning Collective adapted&lt;/a&gt; how we teach. The most notable change is that we now teach solely online via Internet video conference, since all of our traditional classroom spaces have been forced to close either temporarily or, sadly, permanently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new online-only format means we’ve been able to reach many more students, which is itself a good opportunity to re-examine our processes and rethink some of how we do what we do. To that end, we invited some recently recurring students (those &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/05/19/as-tech-learning-collective-grows-quality-is-signature-of-classes-and-workshops.html#unwavering-comittment-to-our-mission&quot;&gt;students who have attended more than one workshop&lt;/a&gt; within the last five months) to speak with us about their backgrounds and experiences studying with Tech Learning Collective. Our goal was to collect qualitative data regarding the effectiveness of our Web site and other communications channels, understand why certain referral mechanisms are successful (or not), and generally improve our operational and educational process at every stage of a student’s learning path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reviewing the recordings, we felt that some of the interviews not only provided insight for us about who our newer students are and why they’re showing up again and again, but that the conversations could also be a valuable way for other current or prospective students to learn more about Tech Learning Collective itself, our history, our motivations, and &lt;a href=&quot;/about/#our-difference&quot;&gt;what makes us different&lt;/a&gt; from other educational resources available elsewhere. And so, with their permission, we’re choosing to publish some of those interviews in a sort of podcast-like blog series we’re calling the Tech Learning Collective Student Profile Series. We hope you enjoy listening to (or reading the transcript of) these conversations as much as we did!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this first installment, we talk about nurturing the bloom of students’ curiosity, how to overcome the challenge of finding a way in as a beginner, and what some good things to keep in mind might be when you’re feeling overwhelmed, lost, or out of your depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;controls&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/tech-learning-collective.student-profile-series.profile-1.mp3&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0 auto; width: 100%;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/tech-learning-collective.student-profile-series.profile-1.mp3&quot;&gt;Download the audio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;TLC interviewer:
First of all, before we get too far into this, I just want to know, can I record you?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Sure.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Okay, great. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student: Yeah, if there’s anything that I’m like off record, I’ll just state it beforehand, but I can’t anticipate anything like that happening. Or I don’t anticipate anything like that happening.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Totally, totally. Yeah, this shouldn’t be too personal or anything like that.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
[Laughs.]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
How are you by the way? Are you okay? You just came out from the protests against the George Floyd murder.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Mm hmm. Yeah, yeah, I’m fine. It’s just pretty hot outside. It’s pretty beautiful. Actually, there’s a lot of folks there. There’s some folks handing out like hand sanitizer and water. And making sure everybody’s okay. Which is beautiful. There is a lot more police presence there. I mean, I knew there was going to be but there’s a bit more police presence than I expected right when I was leaving. And the helicopters just came out just a little bit ago. So I still have two friends that are marching. I like just turned off at the street from my house.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Right.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
And like people were honking their horns which is just gorgeous. It was great.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Nice!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
And bus drivers giving everybody thumbs up. Yeah. So yeah, but I’m going to check in on my friends on a little bit to see to see how it ended up progressing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Good. Good to hear. From what I understand you are very recent student. You haven’t been coming for a very long time. So yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Totally, totally.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Can you tell me that story?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Let’s see where I can start. Yeah. Okay, so I saw a posting on Jeff Stark’s email listserv Nonsense for the Mr. Robot Happy Hour. And I was like, “Oh, that looks cool. Sure.” You know, it was like, watch the first episode. I was like, great. And then I got hooked on the TV show and watched all four seasons before the happy hour, which was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Oh, that’s a lot of TV!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, it was a lot of TV. I mean, you know, got some time on my hands right now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
I guess there isn’t a better time for it than right now, that’s true.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Oh my god. It was like, kind of surreal though. Um, let’s see and then when I was in the happy hour, I was totally in over my head. Folks were asking questions that I didn’t even understand the question, much less the answer. And it was just this moment of like, what? And then some pieces I could get. And I was like, yeah! But it just kind of left me with this feeling of like, huh, what’s going on? And I actually ended up getting out of the call at about like an hour in and I know that y’all ended up going for probably about three hours with that happy hour, I believe?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah, we thought we were gonna actually end at after one hour. And what happened was that it was just so much fun. And people kept having so many good questions, and we kept having so many good conversations with folks. And you know, with the happy hour, as I’m sure you recognized, it was very much sort of all over the place. It wasn’t a curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Oh, totally, free-form.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Exactly.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, yeah. And I had looked at the website a little bit in advance for the curriculum on the Anarcho-Tech website. And on TLC’s website and honestly I was a little like, what am I getting into? What is this thing going to be? What’s it going to look like? Like—&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Were you nervous? Were you—was it was an apprehension, what was that?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
No, it wasn’t that I was nervous. But like, I, like, when I was looking at the Anarcho-Tech website on the GitHub. I was, it was a little in some ways like, where do I start on this? It was almost like a ball of yarn where I’m like, well, where’s the beginning or the first layer? What? So it was more like that. And then when I was in it, I was definitely like, oh, I’m over my head. Like, is this because I don’t know these things? Or is it? Oh, and I actually have a somewhat odd question for you.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Oh?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Um, I realized I have no idea what your name even is.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah, that—&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
And I don’t know if that’s intentional or not, but…?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Out of the sort of anarchist principle of collective action, we do not assign names to what we do in the group.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Got it. Okay.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
And so that’s why. So it is very intentional thing. That’s why, you know, you’re always going to see me as a TLC instructor and so on and so forth, partly because of the nature of TLC as primarily a school designed to train politically motivated activists in computer network operations that are, of course, extremely potent.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Totally, totally. I had a sneaking suspicion that was it. But then I was like, at first, I was also a little, like, hesitant because I was like, I don’t know who’s behind this and who’s teaching me these things?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Fair!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Or do they know some of these other people I know, and I actually haven’t started checking out like, checking out TLC. Um, in terms of like, vetting through people I also know. It’s a little like, huh, why haven’t I yet? But I feel like I’m getting a lot of the classes. And I feel like your analysis of different things you’ve said, I’m like, Yeah, right on. Okay. Cool.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah, well, okay. So, let’s talk about that a little bit because obviously, you know, one of the unique things about our work here is that we are in this environment that is incredibly hyper-masculinized and incredibly militarized, and also sort of incredibly geared towards the levers of capitalism, right? It is almost a cliche these days, when you hear people say, “Well, I want to get a good job,” and what they kind of mean is either something in tech or something and like, you know, sort of a white collar field where they’re doing something with technology and data science. This sort of stuff, right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
And so it’s been very interesting to try to form for lack of a better way to say it, a marketing position that simultaneously does not feed into the things that we are against politically, but also creates enough of a visible ruckus for the people to notice that we’re here and that we’re actually pretty competent, and that the things that you’ll be learning are the things that you’ll be learning in any other sort of environment where you’re learning these things, with the added benefit of doing so in the ways that we do we—and we can talk a little bit more about that later, the hands on aspect, so the fact that there’s the Socratic method, the fact that there’s, you know, an extreme militant focus on Free Software and sort of immediacy of the benefits of using those technologies, and so on—has been really challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And one of the one of the debates that we’ve been having is, you know, do we go the sort of like, you know, potentially more confrontational route of being more vocal about the ways in which we are trying to make this sort of more not mainstream, but more sort of recognizable by people who are very active political organizers and activists and infrastructural, you know, to supply them with infrastructural capacities, or do we temper that a little bit and sort of speak to the, for lack of a better word, the desperation that the American public is feeling right now about joblessness and economic strife. And of course, obviously, the never ending, you know, attempted slavery of the citizens that is in this country. So, so, or literal slavery is in the past 400 years. So yeah, so that’s been sort the debate. And I’m kind of wondering, that’s a big lead up to this question of, you know, you were saying, who are these people? I don’t know. So like, you know, when you when you found the posting on Nonsense, and then you said you found Anarcho-Tech and you saw the relationship, or at least some relationship between the two groups. It wasn’t off putting you say, but it was a little bit mysterious. So how did that play into your decision to like, then, you know what, I’m gonna see what this is about.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Um, let’s see. So I did the Mr. Robot Happy Hour. And then I poked around on the website a little bit more. Ended up signing up for that free overview of the website, because I was like, maybe I don’t know how to like, kind of like grapple in or like, where to start or that beginning of that frayed edge can let me in you know? Which I found that to be incredibly helpful. There’s some information that I felt that I didn’t pick up on on the website, based off of that call, which was super, super helpful, even though then I went back and looked and was like, Oh, the Web site said all that stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah. That’s okay. That happens as well.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, and I was not, I was absolutely not turned off by seeing that affiliation between TLC and the other organization that all of a sudden I’m blanking on because my dog is barking.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Anarcho-Tech, probably.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
In some ways that like made it more interesting for me because I was like, oh, because I figured the politics would be pretty on point. And the like the idea of like, I mean, I use a computer all the time, you know, but I know that my level of knowledge—like I know a bunch of tech stuff like…. I don’t know, somehow like seeing like the affiliation with the anarchist was like, oh, I bet the security culture is pretty top notch and so like learning cybersecurity from some folks that are into security culture seems like they’d probably be legit. My last professional job was [REDACTED] and the cyber security team there was, is amazing and is more intensive than any other nonprofit I’ve ever worked for. I mean, obviously. But they took, like, security culture to the next level in a way where I was like, oh, whoa, how do I, oh, am I putting myself at risk for this? Or like, what do I not know about? Like, the little pop ups that say accept my cookies? And I’m like, I don’t want to how do I say no? Where is the buttons? Just close the window! You know?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Right.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Um, which was one of the things where I kind of wanted to be like, is there like, just an entry level class that y’all offer on like what to do about the cookies?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
You know, ironically, I think there is! There is the “Digital Defenses for the People” workshop, which is a little bit more of like, a sort of a conversation than it is workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Oh, Practical Digital Security, I see it! Got it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
You know, it’s interesting, now I actually have so many questions because the way that you sort of approach this is really, really, really great. Um, so one of the things, you know, we’re not trying to train just anyone in the public, right? That’s why we say if you’re looking for a job, we’re probably not the place for you, like, there are plenty of places you can go get a job certificate, or like an introductory class on this or that. And while we do obviously think that our both material and training is, not to be arrogant about it, but far better than what we’ve seen elsewhere. And I’ll let others be the judge of that of course. The goal is really not to train people who are sort of passively interested, but rather to train people who have a commitment to the sorts of political change that we’d like to see and have an understanding that that will require an infrastructure that doesn’t currently exist and needs to be built, not in the form of new tools, but in the form of an educational sort of milieu that provides the knowledge necessary to gain the skills needed to use the tools that are already available.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And that has been an incredibly challenging thing to get across, because and this is sort of where the question comes in, because people who identify themselves as sort of privacy centric or interested in digital security as, you know, as advocates, as opposed to people for whom, you know, primarily they’re interested more on an individual basis, which is, again, not wrong, we welcome them as well. But that’s not really the goal. The real goal is like, you know, to train the people for whom this is going to be part and parcel of a larger motivation, that they’ve been some of the most difficult to get into classes. And so even though we’re parts of groups like the Electronic Frontier Alliance, you know, I don’t a single EFA member has come to our groups. It’s very hard to get EFF members to come to come to workshops free or not. And so, you know, it’s heartening to hear actually, that you come from [REDACTED] you have a background in [REDACTED] organizing, I imagine, because that’s more clearly more or less, you know, that. I wouldn’t say better, but I want to say it’s like, it’s more where we’re trying to reach.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, it’s more in line. Yeah, yeah. So I feel like I do have somewhat of like a theoretical framework, but mostly for TLC, it’s like, purely been curiosity driven. It’s like, I go to one class, and I’m like, Oh, that was cool. Save a bunch of tabs, like, look into some stuff like, Oh, I wanted to do that. And during the process of the class, you usually like reference another class and I’m like, Oh, I should sign up for that one, too.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah, I mean, that’s the nature of the media, I think is that it’s, A) it’s very easy to sort of interlink things. So one lab goes right up quickly to another, but also I think the actual subject matter is itself extremely intertwined. So you can’t really be good at, like, you know, good in the sense of like, you know, they say you need 10,000 hours to master a skill, right? Well, if you’re, you’re flying, you know, you’re flying an airplane, you need 10,000, you know, hours in front of you in the cockpit, and you’re more or less doing, you know, one balancing act, right? Which is keeping the plane in the air. And with computers, it’s not true at all. Because you are, you absolutely have to do all the things all at once, at the same time. Right, right, in order to be good with the computer, because what the computer is, is really just an extension of the way that it allows you to think and process information and then re-express that information through, you know, other means whether that’s setting up servers or putting you know, lines of code into a project or something and that’s really not something that you can do if you only focus on hyperfocus on one skill area. So it’s a very different game.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
It’s totally different. And I do have to say to the other thing for me, that’s really helpful in the way that the classes are framed. It’s not just like, this is how you do it, like click this button, type this and do this. It’s a lot more of like the underpinning of why and how it works, which I think like takes it to the next level, especially for me, where I’m like, oh, I’ve got this and this, and I can kind of connect it to what I learned about this. And then I think, like, it allows me to critically think about processes and systems before being told about it. Does that make sense?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Totally. Yeah, actually. And that kind of leads me to that other question that I was wondering about a little earlier. So you have some tech background. But you know, at the same time, you also say that you came to the Mr. Robot thing and some some stuff was like totally over your head. And I think that’s a pretty common experience actually, where people sort of have some exposure to one thing or another. Maybe they’ve even worked in the field. But you know, one thing that we’ve seen over and over again, I’m not sure if this is because again, the approach that we take in the class that you just highlighted, or because of the material being, you know, sort of—what we like to say is that our 101 classes are 201 or 301 classes elsewhere. And that’s not to say that we think that they shouldn’t be 101, like you couldn’t do them. It’s just that when we have 101 level classes, we’re already using the most so-called advanced technologies and tools that you’re going to see in the, you know, in the much more advanced classes. And that’s because there’s no real distinction between the tools you use, you just have to know how to use the tool. It’s like saying, here’s a you know, giving someone a power tool, when you’re teaching them cabinetry making is not wrong. Right, they’re gonna need to know how to use a sander so you don’t not give sanders to beginners, right? They’re gonna use the same tool, you just have to actually train them with that, and we don’t see that happening in other classes. So that’s one of the things that we do. But so like this, this common experience of having sort of maybe initial sense of being overwhelmed and then even though you have some background, how do you, how did you reconcile that with curiosity, you know what, what drove, what made the curiosity win?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, like where did I, like how did I bridge that gap. Because it was overwhelming and I was a little intimidated where I’m like, oh, maybe I’m out of my depth. Maybe this is not the path I should be looking at, even though I’m, I’m curious, maybe I should just like look at some other stuff. And I think I signed up for your email listserv. And I ended up getting the email about the free overview about the website. And I was like, why not? Let me just like, maybe there’s something I’m missing. Maybe there’s like an entry point that’s easier for me. Or maybe they’ll explain to me like, which one is the 101 or where it’s ease, like, Where’s the ideal path in some ways of like a student or learning. So I think that like just jumping from that, like “what?” to a pretty accessible overview of the website, which at first I was like, maybe I shouldn’t even like to take this thing because are they just gonna show me what’s on the website?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Was that not what happened?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
That is what’s happened and there was more than just that, you know, like, I felt like there was a different type of framing. And now I’m trying to think. It was more personalized. So, any questions that any of the other students had were answered.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Well, it was real time. That’s a big difference.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
It was real time. Yeah, it was totally real time. And it wasn’t just like an intro to the website, but it was an intro to all of TLC is what it felt like, right? Yeah, kind of gave like an overall arc of like, what the program can do, or like what the organization can do.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Is that how it happened and then I was like, oh, I’ll just sign up for one class. We’ll see. Because honestly, I am currently unemployed and just got an extended unemployment 13 weeks from the government. So I all of a sudden had a little bit of a pocket of money. And I was like, Oh, I can take one of the classes. I mean, and especially with the tiered model that you have for queer-identified and femme identified folks. I was like, Oh, I can afford to like risk $28 and see if I learn anything. Um, and I felt like I got enough value out of that first class. And that’s when I was like, oh, I’ll sign up for the next thing. And then that’s when the curiosity kind of snowballed. Does that make sense?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah, it does. Thank you. Very helpful, too. So do you then feel like well, first of all, which was that first class?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
I think the first one I took was the Tor workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
The Tor workshop? Okay.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
No, no, I took the BitTorrent. Um, I think Tor browsing is the next one I’m taking. I think?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
I think it’s coming up. So possibly. The BitTorrent workshop also is that, you know, that’s a there’s a funny story behind that one, but I’ll get to that later on. Just that it was never intended to sort of be like, it’s never, it’s not in our curriculum anywhere. But then lockdown happened. And we realized, you know what, actually, this is something people are asking about all the time. We might as well just do one.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Totally.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
But yeah, so what was your? So that was the first one you took. You’ve now taken, um….&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
I’ve either I thought I’ve taken like two or three and I’ve got like five, like four or five lined up maybe? Looking at them, I think, yeah, I can’t remember. Let’s see I’ve taken BitTorrent. Um, the virtual machines? I feel like those are the only two I’ve taken so far outside of the Mr. Robot happy hour and the intro. That can’t be right. Can it? I feel like I’ve taken another one.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
You were in numerous classes that I remember teaching over the last month and a half. So, maybe were you in the exploiting web applications workshop? Was that one of them?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Oh, yes. I was in that one. I was in that one.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
So that’s a good example, right, of a workshop that’s like nowhere near intended for beginners. How did you feel in it?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Oh, that one was great. Yeah, I really liked the, the gamification of the fruit stand isn’t that the name of the website?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Juice shop.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Juice shop. That’s right. That’s right. Yeah, that made it like, a lot easier. I don’t know. Like, I just really liked it. I think that the second thing you got to the, um, the exploits using the database language, what is that?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
SQL?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, SQL. That was when my brain like exploded.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
But you didn’t feel like, left behind, like it wasn’t, because you know, that that’s an example of a class that’s really, you know, for us, it’s considered, you know, a sort of a 201 level class. So for most people, you don’t even really get to that until you’re talking about, you know, you’ve taken a networking, you know, curriculum, much less a single course.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, well, I mean, I feel like, I kind of expect to go into a class like that, like, almost like, it’s like immersion. Like, when you’re learning a new language, where I feel like I’m going to go into the class, I’m not going to get, I’m not going to understand everything, and that’s okay. That’s not the point.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Exactly. That’s true.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
The point is for me to get value out of it, and figure out like how I can, like connect some dots, right? Um, so like, that’s the big thing for me. And then I like, I save all the tabs in Pocket that I opened up during the class and I tag them all with TLC, and then I go back and look at things and, you know, like, sure, there’s a certain amount of self guided learning that can happen as well. So it’s kind of the nice and interesting to feel like I can get my hooks, my claws in, or like my teeth into something. Like there’s more there.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
What was your favorite class?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
What’s my favorite class so far? I don’t know. Um, I thought oh, I do have to say I thought that the CMD online modules, especially the mystic one was adorable!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Awesome! That’s the “Enchantment at the Command Line” you’re talking about?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, yeah, yeah, that one was adorable. Um, I think that one might be my favorite so far, which that one felt definitely 101 for me because I was expecting more of a like, how do I learn which commands that I need to know most? Um, because like I understand the concept of the terminal. And there’s some, one of the other modules was super helpful too. In terms of a little bit of like theoretical framework of using terminal that I hadn’t really like, put into place.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
And these are the free ones that are just on the website, the Foundations courses. Yes?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, yeah, exactly, exactly. Yeah. Um, but I’m still feeling a little like, I’m like, Oh, I still don’t think my terminal skills are that strong. How do I get them stronger? I did find, what’s this one website that’s got some like, wait, let me tell you which one it is. That’s got like some terminal practice. Let’s see. That I now have some time set aside to do. Let’s see, let’s see. Well, there’s Hack the Box EU but that’s not the one for this.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah, there’s quite a number. We used to recommend Code Academy before they started charging for their beginner courses. There’s another one called Taming the Terminal that I know about. That is really good.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Oh I think that might be it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah. Okay. Yeah, Taming the Terminal is fantastic. And it’s a, it’s an article and podcast series. So we recommend that and have been recommending that for a long time. And you know, it’s interesting because we didn’t have any of the original, you know, beginning foundation courses on our website, because we simply linked out to Taming the Terminal. But it didn’t, you know, it, maybe that same thing happened where you’re like, you know, am I gonna go to this thing, and people are just gonna tell me how to read the website. I know how to read a website, but actually it was really helpful. You know, I mean, like, maybe that’s where the same thing happen. People don’t always you know, there’s a lot to read and if that’s not the style in which people are used to learning or if that’s not as you know, their learning style doesn’t sort of meld well with having to read a lot, then it’s really nice to be able to just sort of do something right then in there by loading a container in your browser, like the Foundations courses allow you to do or coming to a workshop and seeing in real time, something like this. So yeah, that makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Do you feel like they prepared you well enough for the courses, that when you were going through the foundation series? Were they, you know, were they enough to give you a sense of when I open a terminal in a class, you’re not lost?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, I can follow along in a terminal. Like, it’s like one of those things like a language, right, like I can, I can read it and hear it and understand it, but I can’t write it just yet. Right. And so it did feel like there was a, let me try. I’ll think on this a little bit more. It did seem like there is maybe like, one, one more module that I would have loved to take before some of the classes, but maybe it’s actually part of the the modules that I haven’t taken yet that are on the website.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Hmm. There are also some more being planned to be put out there. So if we have another 15 or so that is not quite yet ready for being published, but will eventually be published. So it’s possible that it’s just not complete, so maybe you’re not missing anything. It’s really just not there right now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Not there, yeah. Okay.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Okay, what about your expectations before you came? Like, have you taken classes akin to this or sort of adjacent to this sort of topic before? Is this a completely new experience? You talked about the cyber security team at [REDACTED], were they giving you any kind of corporate training that was sort of reminiscent or at least sort of in the same ballpark as this?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Let’s see. At [REDACTED] I did get some security training, but it was specific to the project that I was working on. So it was very grounded in next steps, if you will, it wasn’t very conceptual at all. It was like should we put superglue in this USB port? Should we…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Right, tool and tactic focused.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, yeah, it was very tactic focus of like, how do we wipe the phones? How do we check for malware? How do we do this? We had some like as needed kind of training. Some of it I kinda already knew like, in some cases, I would just look things up online and be like, hey, Reddit, what’s up? Let me find out this. And did end up finding some pretty fun workarounds in order to get what I wanted done. And then once I like, knew how to do that, then I played around with a little bit to be like, what else can I make it do? So like, there’s a couple things like that, where it’s like, self guided in some ways, then, definitely having some expertise of like, I am sure that you’ve picked up on the fact that I am definitely a person that doesn’t shy away from asking questions.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah, that’s great. That makes, for what it’s worth, right? The, in the classes, when they are in real time: that makes the class! You know, that’s what makes the class good! If no one’s asking questions, it’s just a lecture.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
And it’s boring. Well, not that boring. It’s just like how does that apply to this other thing I was thinking about. One thing that I’m really into the classes with other students is that sometimes other people in the class ask questions that I don’t even know to ask. Yes. And that’s the thing that I’m like whoa, wait, what do you mean? What? What’s Vagrant? What do you mean, wait, I got to Google this while you’re still talking. Oh shit, I missed what you just said because I was googling this other thing I’ve never heard of or, [laughs].&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
There is a, for what it’s worth, there is a Vagrant, not specific class but a Vagrant, there is a workshop in which Vagrant is a central piece specifically and that’s called Automate all the Things.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, I feel like I’m not ready for Automate all the Things because I can’t do the things that I want to be automated yet. So I’m like holding off on that for a second.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah that makes sense, that’s fine. But when you get there, it’s you know part of it. And also, of course, the labs themselves. The actual practice labs, you can download and run on your own, is there, they’re all automated with Vagrant.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Oh, cool. Oh, that’s nice. Nice. Yeah, I haven’t gotten to the level to run any of the labs yet. So that’s one of my things I, yeah. And you asked if I’d taken any other classes in this format. Um, I’ve taken some on-demand learning in other areas. I really find that live teachers work better for me than, like, pre-recorded videos. And honestly, just to get me in front of the computer and do it in most cases, it just like, creates that sense of like time boundedness.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah, I’ve had a very hard time learning from, uh, recorded classes as well, when I was, you know, I, I was unfortunate in that I did not actually have a live teacher at all. But the result of that was, was that it just had to, that it took me a lot longer to get to the point where I’m seeing TLC students now get to. And that makes sense. You know, the live instruction, there’s something about humans. Human mimicry, I think is a huge part of human learning. And you don’t get that if you are mimicking the recording, because what you’re missing is, as you said that you’re getting very sort of tools and tactics focus, but if you don’t find yourself in a situation where that exact tactic or that exact tool is available to you, you’re sort of out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, totally. I did shoot over an email to a few of my friends that I thought might be interested in TLC. Um, and I found and I mentioned to them in the email, no matter what the time is that set up for the class I always add an extra hour on and expect the class to go for an additional hour.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
[Laughs.] Yeah, that, I admit. So that is not every class happens that way. But I am—&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Oh, so far, it’s been consistently every class!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Okay, well, what I want to say is every class that I teach tends to do that because I have this, I just, I remember, you know, the sort of after the official close of things being always the best time for me. Yeah, I’m one of those people who’s like, always wanted to hang out later. Like, let’s go to a cafe at the coffee shop afterwards and hang out and talking. That’s, that’s when the real good stuff, so for me that’s just like, I just like don’t care about the end time. I’m just like, let’s just keep going, you know, and yeah, but I don’t—that is not a universal policy.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Oh, that’s funny. That’s but yeah, like the first time I was like a little antsy. And then I was like, what’s going on, but I want to stick around because it’s still good. And it’s so interesting. And then then every time after that, I’m like, I’m just expecting that. And then I’m like, Oh, yeah, that’s great if it ends earlier than that, whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah. Yeah, that’s…that’s my style. But so on that note, like, the thing that I’m curious about given your particular, again, you have some a little bit of corporate training experience, I think a lot of people have this corporate training experience had have this sort of scenario where they feel like they are getting a—like they’re looking through a pinhole, I think is how a lot of people might feel about it. I know that when I talk to some folks, and they talk about even being in the cybersecurity field, but trained at a job, you get this very, very narrow view of what is useful for the job, and what is useful for that specific role of that specific company.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So for example, I’ve heard from digital security trainers who have told me that they don’t feel like they really understand how to answer questions because they can only answer questions about, like, the one tool they’re trained to answer questions on. Right. And, and to me, that speaks to a failure from an education standpoint, because they’re not being trained, trained in security principles. They’re being trained in security practices. But the practices flow from the principles. You can’t actually generalize a tactic if you don’t understand why that tactic is effective in the environment you’re in. And so they find themselves sort of, not gonna say names, of course, but like, there’s some people who’ve been in some very prestigious roles in some of these national online privacy and security training organizations that have told us at TLC, told me personally, actually, that, you know, they feel like they sort of, that they’re in an environment where because they’re trainers rather than developers or, you know, the actual IT team or the actual security team at that place, that they’re not getting training in the ways that the cybersecurity team is at the IT team is, you know, and that’s really striking to me when when you’re when you’re talking about sort of national organizations whose supposed job is to train others right.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;How, I don’t understand how those trainers aren’t prioritized in those organizations. I think that tends to do a disservice to groups who were paying much more than they would pay in a workshop at TLC as an example, to have a private corporate training on these things. And so that leads me to my question, which is, when you compare your experiences, either in that environment or when you just sort of your actual experiences at TLC with the expectations that you had before you arrived at classes, how do you feel about them? Do they meet? Do they just is it just a completely different worlds like apples and oranges, obviously, the goals of  different training groups are different. And I think even you know, TLC makes a very big point about saying that you know, you’re not going to get the same kind of training with us as you would with you know, General Assembly or Flatiron School and so on, because we clearly have very different end goals. But, for your goals. Do you know, given whatever it is that you want it to do, whether it be just curiosity or you know your own purposes. Did you find that? Or have you been finding that the the workshops that you’ve been attending maps to expectations you have? Has it been completely different? What was the outcome of that?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Well, I feel like I don’t go into TLC with many expectations is first of what’s going on. I feel like if I went to any of the General Assembly classes, I would have much higher expectations or different expectations, partially because of the price tag. And yeah, I mean, really. And partially because it seems more…how do I say this? Like when I’m thinking about like, the information that TLC is providing, as opposed to General Assembly or like, say like, trainers within certain companies It feels like those are focused on like, this is what you need either for a job or the capitalist system, or for the end goal of the organization itself. And it’s not as focused on like, what do you want to learn? What’s helpful? Here’s all the information in some ways. I feel like there’s something else I was gonna say about that. But I just lost my train of thought.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Um, well, so the price point is an interesting piece of it too, because that has been, you know, so this is maybe not history you’re aware of. But for three years, TLC was entirely free. There was no classes that cost anything. There were no workshops we were doing sort of workshops on, we were a little smaller, in that we didn’t have an online presence. And so it was a little bit harder for certain people to find us. Of course, if you weren’t in New York City, that meant you couldn’t come to a workshop because they were in person, but they were all free. And then we decided in 2019 to stop doing that. And the reason weirdly, was because we got more attendance when we charge people.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Oh, because then people are more invested in showing up.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Not only that—yeah, go ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Similar to free events versus like paid events, in some cases like.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Right, yeah. But also, we found that, and I want to be careful here because I don’t want to put down the folks who are doing free digital security events, because I think that that’s great that they’re doing that, but we’re not doing what they are doing. It’s very clear to someone who has come to a workshop that what we are doing is on a level far beyond, both technically and in terms of ambition, what you’ll probably see at a library where you’re going to like, here’s how to like, you know, wipe the browser history in your phone or your tablet. Like it’s, which is why I don’t want to put them down because we’re not you know…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
I mean, people have to enter in at different places like we don’t all start at the same place. And that’s fine.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah, the challenge though, because when we were doing free events was that people thought it was the same.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Ohhhhh.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
So what happened was, we were unable to, sort of, because TLC didn’t even start in the same way that these other sort of sort of advocacy, grassroots community group things started, you know, we have a very different history as well. But what happened was because it didn’t appear to be different from the outside, if you didn’t know any better, and you didn’t have any experience already, then you looked at, you know, the 10 or 20 different, you know, groups in New York doing, you know, some kind of digital privacy, whether it be sort of a downtown meetup or whether it be, you know, a different EFA, Electronic Frontier Alliance member, or just sort of like, you know, the, you know, the city’s own, you know, here’s how to do “see something, say something” on the Internet kind of thing, right? Like, you couldn’t really tell the difference. Because nothing, none of it cost money. You could go to, you know, NYPL and go to a privacy workshop and you’d think it was the same thing as you hop into a TLC class where, you know, even though our descriptions are things like, you know, launch your own phishing attack, like, you know, the MTA is not gonna not gonna host that, you know what I mean?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
But you don’t know what that means. And so it’s hard to—&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Totally, and in some ways, when I looked at some of the workshop descriptions, some of them I was a little like, what? I don’t even know what that means, like, what would I learn what is happening here?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Right, right.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
But I do have to say one of the things that I tried to sign up for some boot camp or like, there’s some sort of like, hacking 101 through Full Stack Academy, I think, that I was gonna take and it was just boring.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
How was it so boring?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
I don’t know. Because this is exciting stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah. And so like something about like, the way that the TLC is approached either in terms of like, what can you use this for? What can this go? It’s just, it’s more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah, cool. Hm. I know that a lot of people come to TLC from, well, I’ll give this example of someone who actually came to that, a phishing workshop. And they were a cybersecurity engineer at a law firm. And they left in what I can only describe as awe that they didn’t learn what they learned at the workshop at the job. And so I’m kind of wondering from that, because this is also a thing that we consistently see happening, where people come in with an expectation of what they might learn that is far very different from what actually happens. And I kind of want to tease out whether that’s because of the material or because of the approach or because of a combination of it. I think a lot of people are, y’know, because we have these two conflicting things happening. On the one hand people come to a webinar and expect to sort of get their hands on a keyboard and sort of go through a sort of series of steps on their own, because they’ve seen that happen, right? That’s how a lot of teaching happens—&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Well I think it’s about teaching pedagogy, right? Well, I’m hearing two different things. I think it’s a little bit about teaching pedagogy as well as marketing and communications of what the workshops and events currently say on the Web site. It feels like someone who is an expert in cybersecurity wrote the workshop synopses, which is perfect and great, but for someone who is an outsider it’s sometimes, like I don’t really know what’s gonna happen. And then after I take the class I go back and read it and I’m like, yeah, that’s exactly what happened.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
[Laughs.]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
[Laughs.] Again, it’s like that thing of like, a beginner mindset of just even for marketing. And yeah, in some ways, for me personally, like paired with my curiosity, I’m like I don’t really know what’s going to happen and, gah, I’m gonna learn something! It’s helpful for me, but there’s definitely a few of the classes, oh I signed up for the shell class, the Writing with Blue Fire, where I read it and I was like I’m definitely going to be in over my head. Like, I probably shouldn’t have signed up for that class, based off of the synopsis, but I’m not sure.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Hm, have you had that experience with other workshops, where you were like, I shouldn’t do this, but then you did and it was okay, or it was exactly what you thought and it was too much, or…?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Mmmm. Let’s see. Well, I didn’t sign up for the Automate all the Things because I was like, that’s going to be over my head, um. I wanted to sign up for the crypto, the Bare Bones Crypto, but I was like, I don’t think I can do that one. I think it’s more like I haven’t taken some classes because I’m assuming it’s over my head based off of the write up or the synopsis. I know that some of the classes have that matrix that say beginner versus not.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah. The persona training matrix.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Some of them, which I think is a little bit of why I wanted to take that how to understand the Web site, where I was like, what’s beginner, what’s 101, what’s 507, like, where? Where do I get there?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah, that’s kind of another challenge, is that we don’t really have a curriculum that differentiates between what people would call beginner or advanced because we start with the things that people don’t show you until they’ve already bluntly brainwashed you to believing that a certain way of things has to be the way to go about it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Totally.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
That makes it difficult to…because, part of it is that, y’know, it’s not that there’s no progression. There’s obviously a progression, but the frustration from the teaching team, for us is that it’s, there’s a prescribed way to go about teaching this from the perspective of interest in jobs and the sort of cooperation with capitalism that does not serve the goals of an individual or a non-cooperative, capitalistically noncooperative organization such as an advocacy group whose entire purpose is to upend that system. And what we found is that part of the, and I’m speaking from personal experience here, I happen to be one of the more I’ll say experienced from the professional side of things folks in the group just because I, y’know, I’m unemployed now but I’ve had an almost 15 year career in tech and I hated it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
[Laughs.] Aw.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
I did, I absolutely hated it. I learned a lot, but I hated it. And I certainly didn’t learn comfortably. That was, uh, that was a very painful…. One of the reasons I’m involved in TLC is because I personally don’t think that you should have to struggle in anguish to learn stuff. That doesn’t make sense. As a learning methodology, that seems stupid. Learning should be easy because it’s something humans do very naturally, it’s something we were made to do, in a way, and it’s something that we can do if we’re given any kind of sensible guidance that isn’t designed to restrict us. And that’s exactly the opposite of my experience in the tech industry, and that’s what I keep hearing over and over and over again where they’re like, I’m looking through this pinhole and I don’t really understand why that group is doing that over there, or how this technology relates to what we’re doing over here, because I’m never told and I’m never shown, and I’m never given an opportunity to try it out. But anyway, sorry, that was a little bit of a vent.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
[Laughs.]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
But my point is that as a result, when you come to a beginning networking class for TLC, y’know, you’re shown Wireshark. But that’s a tool that security analysts use day in and day out. That is a military tool. You’re shown that as one of the first things we open in a networking class is already at the level of the stuff that you will see at a SOC, at a Security Operations Center, on every screen from every analyst that’s there. And there’s no middle ground. Because there doesn’t have to be because it’s the same tool. You can do that stuff in, you could teach that stuff with the complex tools, in the same way that I wouldn’t expect someone to go to a graphic design class and never be shown Photoshop until they’re into their fourth year. That’s absurd.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
But that’s exactly what happens with security and of course it’s because in Photoshop you don’t have the capability of actually, immediately, for example carving out files from an exfiltration. I mean, it’s a very militarized capability. Right? It’s a weaponized thing. So there’s a culture around the teaching of it that is itself very, very skewed. And so it’s difficult—at the same time of trying to say that, well we don’t want to say then that Wireshark is an advanced tool, because that doesn’t make any sense, actually. At the same time we don’t want to give the impression that if you have never had any background in this that you’re supposed to understand the plethora of menus and buttons and stuff. Like, that’s not the goal either. But you seem to have this understanding intuitively, where you come in and say I’m not going to understanding everything but I’m not supposed to. And I think some people do think that they have to come in and leave having that, and finding that balance has been really tricky.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Well I think that’s it, um, mmm, like the wrong assumption to go into any class and be an expert after an hour. Like it’s kind of like, so it’s like, or also like if you think about it as an analogy of a muscle, if I’m learning to use a new muscle or I’m learning a new, like, I don’t know, dance move, I’m not going to be perfect at it, at the choreography after only like a 15 minute lesson because I’ve never even learned how to do any of the, I’ve never tap danced before or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
But at the end of those 15 minutes, right, like, hopefully if you have a good teacher, you should I hope, feel like, y’know, maybe I could do this or I feel like I’m sort of getting it or I see the outlines, or I understand where we’re going.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Has that felt true to you?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, that’s totally felt true to me and I think to follow that analogy of like choreography and like a 15 minute lesson or whatever also after 15 minutes you kind of have a general idea of what the steps are even if you can’t memorize and remember them all, and that you’re enjoying it. Like I think that enjoyment is, like, key to keep going.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Right. And so have the workshops that you’ve been in at least met that bar? I mean, enough to at least continue to pay to come.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Totally! Totally. Yeah. And I do have to say that like, your following, what you call it, going down a rabbit hole of, like, a rant about something political, I’m like, what! [Laughs.] Yeah, that’s been, uh, enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
[Laughs.] Well I’m glad that that’s—I’ve been loosening my tongue a little bit, I gotta say, just because it’s hard not to in this climate, but um, I’m glad that that has been fun as opposed to, again, confrontational or off-putting. It’s definitely—&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
No, no, no. In some ways, those give a hint of what you can use this information for, right? Like, when you’re talking about, um, when you’re like, “Y’know, do whatever you want, but practice with the legal stuff.” That, like, it’s real, and then just like the hints at, like, oh maybe you want to look at see what happened with DNC, that would be, y’know, um, hints at things that make it, like, very real, but not in that prescriptive way of like, if you do this then you can learn to do this robot face. Y’know, like, it’s, yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Yeah, that makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, totally.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Well, hey, we’re at an hour and I want to keep my promise of not keeping you for longer than an hour no matter what so, um, thank you so much for taking the time to speak with me about this and for answering my questions.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah, yeah, yeah!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Sweet, thank you again, this was super fun. I really appreciate your time.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Totally, same, same, same. Thanks so much.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Interviewer:
Take care.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Student:
Yeah. Bye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">The recent spike in enrollment rates at Tech Learning Collective courses and workshops gave us a great opportunity to look closely at how we do what we do so that we can continue offering our best-in-class technical training via free, by-donation, and low-cost events supporting radical organizers and revolutionary communities. By interviewing newer repeat students, we've been able to improve our Web site, workshop descriptions, and even come up with new events. But these interviews also offer current or prospective students an illuminating look at Tech Learning Collective itself, our history, our motivations, and what makes us different from other tech schools or other digital education initiatives. Published with our students' permission, the Tech Learning Collective Student Profile Series is a set of audio recordings curated from these interviews that we'll release over time, beginning today.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.tech-learning-collective-student-profile-series.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.tech-learning-collective-student-profile-series.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Protecting protester privacy, beyond the listicles.</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/06/03/protecting-protester-privacy-beyond-the-listicles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Protecting protester privacy, beyond the listicles." /><published>2020-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/06/03/protecting-protester-privacy-beyond-the-listicles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/06/03/protecting-protester-privacy-beyond-the-listicles.html">&lt;p&gt;We at Tech Learning Collective stand with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blacklivesmatter.com/&quot;&gt;Movement for Black Lives&lt;/a&gt;. We stand with all those who are calling for immediate financial divestment from police departments nationwide and the reallocation of police department budgets towards investments in community housing, education, public health, and other social services. We applaud the small number of police officers so far who have laid down their batons and guns instead of using them on peaceful protesters and we insist that, next, they lay down their badges as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of centuries, all the various governmental bodies of the United States have routinely, repeatedly, and clearly shown their callous disregard for Black life. They have eagerly used many different weapons to kill, marginalize, and terrorize people of color, particularly Black people. A homicidal cop’s knee pressed on George Floyd’s neck in Minneapolis is simply one recent example of this barbaric and genocidal history. The badge-wearing murderers who invaded the Louisville home and took the life of Breonna Taylor is another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This racist behavior, and all of the oppressions that enable, support, or excuse it, must end &lt;em&gt;today&lt;/em&gt;, because Black lives matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As people all over the country and the world are moved to dismantle white supremacy where we live and work, some are compelled to march in the streets. Others speak up and out online. Regardless of how you choose to help put an end to the injustices you’re seeing and experiencing, our goal at Tech Learning Collective is to empower you to safely take the actions you feel are appropriate by ensuring you have the knowledge and skills needed to fully harness the awesomely potent power of the digital devices you already use every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That computer you’re using to read this very message is arguably among your most powerful assets because it can be both your pen and your sword at the same time—if you know how to use it well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be hearing about tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal Private Messenger&lt;/a&gt; that can help keep your text messages private and out of the hands of the surveillance State. Maybe you’re once again reading warnings to “use a VPN” scrolling down your Twitter feed. We’ve certainly noticed a new wave of listicles full of advice for how to stay safe while you protest showing up on popular online media outlets (yet again). What we’re not seeing, though, is the same thing that was missing the last time headlines like these exploded onto the front pages of mainstream newspapers: what do we do &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; we read the listicle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We built Tech Learning Collective for a scenario very much like this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of Tech Learning Collective were brought together even before the 2016 US presidential election by a shared overarching goal of training communities in how to liberate themselves from corporate and government overseers, especially as it relates to owning and operating their own information and communications infrastructures. We view this form of education and training as a necessary prerequisite for sustained and meaningful revolutionary action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, back on May 26&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, we scheduled &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-03-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state&quot;&gt;our next “Signal and Surveillance: How to Exercise Digital Civil Liberties in a Surveillance State” online workshop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop is a deep dive into effective Signal use, covering much more than simply how to install it. In the workshop, we explain what Safety Numbers are and why they are so important, how to do trusted third-party Safety Number verifications, minimize on-device data retention through disappearing messages and conversation trimming, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This communications safety tool is absolutely vital for the general public to use &lt;em&gt;and understand&lt;/em&gt;, especially now. Just today, the Drug Enforcement Administration, a federal law enforcement agency supposedly limited by statute to drug-related crimes, was shown to have requested and been granted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/jasonleopold/george-floyd-police-brutality-protests-government&quot;&gt;sweeping authority to conduct covert surveillance on anti-racist protesters&lt;/a&gt;. This shows us, yet again, that &lt;a href=&quot;https://truthout.org/articles/the-surveillance-of-blackness-from-the-slave-trade-to-the-police/&quot;&gt;government surveillance is disproportionately aimed at Black people ever since the days of Lantern Laws&lt;/a&gt; in the 1700’s, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.democracynow.org/topics/cointelpro&quot;&gt;through the Civil Rights era with COINTELPRO&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/03/19/black-lives-matter-fbi-surveillance/&quot;&gt;continuing today by tracking BLM organizers after the Ferguson uprising&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To further support protesters in this moment and fight back against the swell of neofascist activity on the part of government agencies, we are adding another, even lower price tier for attendance to our next “Signal and Surveillance” webinar workshop. The new $10 tier (a $13 total out-of-pocket cost) is a 50% reduction from the previously lowest, already “reduced” price tier. We continue to explore ways to increase access to world-class cybersecurity education and this latest price reduction is intended for BLM organizers and activists, protesters, and supporters of calls for police and prison abolition. Tickets for the workshop at this tier are available only through the following link:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techlearningcollective.com/r/workshop-2020-07-03&quot;&gt;https://techlearningcollective.com/r/workshop-2020-07-03&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our normal webinar price tiers ($25 tier for queer-identified and femme people, $35 tier for general admission, and $70 tier for those who can afford to help fund the digital security and online privacy advocacy communities with their financial resources) are still available via the Web site and we encourage you to choose the tier that is most appropriate for you. But in this pivotal moment, we hope more people will accept our invitation to attend this workshop at the lower price tier because we believe more widespread digital security training will be vital to the success of social justice movements whose opponents control much of the commercial Internet and racist government institutions. Please also extend this offer to a friend participating in the protests against police brutality, especially if you yourself cannot attend our webinar workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we are of course continuing to host other workshops that are relevant for protecting your privacy and helping you improve your online safety all through the month of June and into July, as we have been doing all year long. Our &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/06/workshop-2020-06-14-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything&quot;&gt;workshop on anonymous Web browsing and publishing using the Tor Browser, for example, will be held on June 14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and, &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/06/workshop-2020-06-07-gone-phishing-how-to-recognize-fake-websites-and-other-online-scams&quot;&gt;on June 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, we are re-running our combination attack/defense workshop on recognizing phishing scams&lt;/a&gt; that are often used to hijack social media accounts and steal passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To succeed in ending racism and abolishing the abusive institutions enshrined in the American system of government and so-called “criminal justice,” we’re going to need a sustained, strategic, multi-racial coalition committed to many different kinds of work. People with white privilege must be willing to listen to, understand, and take direction from Black, brown, and indigenous people. This coalition will need to use a diversity of tactics and will need to welcome constructive participation in many different ways from many different people so that we &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; remain united &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20200509023739/http://circuitous.org/scraps/combahee.html&quot;&gt;in coalition with other progressive organizations and movements&lt;/a&gt;. Tech Learning Collective believes we can do this most effectively by taking our cues from the formative radical groups who came before us such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Combahee_River_Collective&quot;&gt;Combahee River Collective&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no question that a big part of all of these efforts will take place online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We refuse to sit back and rely on the very same corporations and government institutions who have consistently failed to act ethically or in good faith for centuries to provide us with the communications channels, organizing platforms, education, and privacy-protecting tools we need to navigate the challenges ahead of us. Also today, reports revealed the CEO of the popular video conferencing tool &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/3/21279355/zoom-end-encryption-calls-fbi-police-free-users&quot;&gt;Zoom stated their intent to deny its free tier users protection through encryption for the explicit purpose of handing over user calls to the FBI&lt;/a&gt; so that they can continue to monitor and undermine protest organizers like &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2019/10/29/fbi-surveillance-black-activists/&quot;&gt;they have been doing shamelessly for decades&lt;/a&gt;. “Free users — for sure we don’t want to give [them] that, because we also want to work together with the FBI, with local law enforcement, in case some people use Zoom for a bad purpose,” Zoom’s CEO said on an investor call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time for community-owned, self-hosted, autonomous digital infrastructures and the knowledge to operate them ourselves is now. To get there, we need more people who recognize the ethics they embed into the code they write and the political relevance of the skills they’re learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let that be you. Please join us for our upcoming workshops, or help those who are looking for radical technical training find us by sharing this offer with those you believe would benefit from it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">We at Tech Learning Collective stand with the Movement for Black Lives. We stand with all those who are calling for immediate financial divestment from police departments nationwide and the reallocation of police department budgets towards investments in community housing, education, public health, and other social services. We applaud the small number of police officers so far who have laid down their batons and guns instead of using them on peaceful protesters and we insist that, next, they lay down their badges as well.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.black-lives-matter.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.black-lives-matter.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective awarded in EFA 2019 Activity Challenge, then interviewed by EFF</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/06/01/tech-learning-collective-awarded-in-efa-2019-activity-challenge-interviewed-by-eff.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tech Learning Collective awarded in EFA 2019 Activity Challenge, then interviewed by EFF" /><published>2020-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/06/01/tech-learning-collective-awarded-in-efa-2019-activity-challenge-interviewed-by-eff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/06/01/tech-learning-collective-awarded-in-efa-2019-activity-challenge-interviewed-by-eff.html">&lt;p&gt;Back in April 2020, Tech Learning Collective was informed that we were one of three Electronic Frontier Alliance member groups to win the Electronic Frontier Foundation’s 2019 “Activity Challenge.” We were unaware of the challenge because we had &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/08/13/joining-the-electronic-frontier-alliance.html&quot;&gt;submitted our application for EFA membership very late into the year, on August 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, so this award came as a pleasant surprise. It meant that Tech Learning Collective had produced enough events—twelve, by EFA organizer’s count—in a mere four months to earn our place as the group with the second highest number of events recognized by the EFA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our fellow New Yorkers, the CyPurr Collective, who have been EFA members for numerous years, narrowly beat us out by one EFA-recognized event. Their total was 13 events, spread across the full twelve months. We would like to take the opportunity to congratulate the CyPurr Collective on their 2019 Activity Challenge victory! We’re very proud to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/electronic-frontier-alliance/allies#region-eastern&quot;&gt;represent our hometown of New York City in the top two slots for this challenge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even more recently, as part of a follow up to the EFA 2019 Activity Challenge, Tech Learning Collective was excited to be interviewed by EFF EFA organizers for a feature profile that is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/06/tech-learning-collective-grassroots-technology-school-case-study&quot;&gt;now published on the EFF Deeplinks blog&lt;/a&gt; in an abridged version edited for length. The profile is part of their blog series highlighting grassroots groups educating communities about digital safety and online privacy. The series has already featured CyPurr Collective and CryptoParty Ann Arbor, who were both in attendance at &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/11/01/press-release-hackers-next-door-2019.html&quot;&gt;our recent Hackers Next Door 2019 conference&lt;/a&gt; at the end of last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full interview was conducted over email in early May 2020 but was shortened for publication on the EFF Deeplinks blog, so we have reprinted it in full here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;do-you-have-any-requests-for-your-introductory-section&quot;&gt;Do you have any requests for your introductory section?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Here is the current boilerplate text about Tech Learning Collective that we ask other groups to use when writing about us. Feel free to trim this down if needed:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school for radical organizers headquartered in New York City that provides a security-first IT infrastructure curriculum to otherwise underserved communities and organizations advancing social justice causes. We train politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Founded and operated exclusively by radical queer and femme technologists, we offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies).&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Our students are primarily people of marginalized groups and other individuals who are politically engaged. Unlike coding bootcamps that focus on moving the highest number of students through rote memorization exercises for the goal of job placement, Tech Learning Collective teachers facilitate foundational skill building through Socratic discussion and kinetic, experience-based training.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;what-inspired-you-all-to-start-the-tech-learning-collective-how-has-the-group-changed-over-time&quot;&gt;What inspired you all to start the Tech Learning Collective? How has the group changed over time?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In 2016, a group of anarchist and autonomist radicals met in Brooklyn, NY to seek out methods of mutual self-education around technology. Many of us did not have backgrounds in computer technology. What we did have was background in justice movement organizing at one point or another, whether at the WTO protests before the turn of the century, supporting whistleblowers such as Chelsea Manning, participating in Occupy Wall Street, or in various other campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This first version of Tech Learning Collective met regularly for about a year as a semi-private mutual-education project. It succeeded in sewing the seeds of what would later become several additional justice-oriented technology groups. None of the members were formally trained technologists. None of us have ever held computer science degrees. Many of the traditional techniques of and environments offering technology education felt alienating to us.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, everyone involved recognized the transformative and astonishingly powerful capacities that modern digital technologies could have in the hands of people whose focus is ethics and justice rather than profit—exactly the opposite ethos as that enacted by Silicon Valley, despite their claims to “make the world a better place.” So, after a (surprisingly short!) period of mutual self-education, we began offering free workshops and classes on computer technologies specifically for Left-leaning politically engaged individuals and groups. Our goal was to advocate for more effective use of these technologies in our movement organizing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We quickly learned that courses needed to cater to people with skill levels ranging from self-identified “beginners” to very experienced technologists, and that our efforts needed to be self-sustaining. Partly, this was because many of our comrades had sworn off technical self-sufficiency as a legitimate avenue for liberation in a misguided but understandable reaction to the poisonous prevalence of machismo, knowledge grandstanding, and blatant sociopathy they saw exhibited by the overwhelming majority of “techies.” It was obvious that our trainers needed to exemplify a totally new culture to show them that cyber power, not just computer literacy, was a capability worth investing their time in for the sake of The Movement™.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Following the 2016 US Presidential election, Tech Learning Collective members dispersed into a number of urgent community projects, but the need to offer high quality technology education to groups and individuals engaged in radical, grassroots, and non-profit work remained. Then in early 2019, and now engaged in numerous different new groups, several of us worked to loosely codify a curriculum development and student mentoring process that we had experienced ourselves be dramatically more effective at “upskilling” interested students than those provided by code bootcamps, digital vocational training, and other employment-centric initiatives. This lived experience of contrasting the different pedagogies convinced us to form what is now Tech Learning Collective’s free, by-donation, and low-cost educational efforts in our existing formats.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today, Tech Learning Collective continues offering exceptional Information Technology (IT) educational opportunities at a much lower cost than traditional computer courses (free, in some cases!) and provides supplementary funding for the existent activist projects that grew out of the first version of Tech Learning Collective meetings in the mid 2010’s. In keeping with our original mission, Tech Learning Collective is especially in service to people who might identify themselves as being “outsiders” to the mainstream “tech world.” That is, we are primarily invested in those folks who have either never been tech workers or who have otherwise felt at odds with the general culture of technocapitalism, its tech bros, and its monocultural intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s singular overarching goal is to provide its students with the knowledge and abilities to liberate their communities from corporate and government overseers, especially as it relates to owning and operating their own information and communications infrastructures, which we view as a necessary prerequisite for meaningful revolutionary actions. Using these skills, our students assist in the organization of activist work like abortion access and reproductive rights, anti-surveillance organizing, and other efforts that help build collective power beyond mere (“voter”) representation.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;One thing that hasn’t changed over the years is that, at Tech Learning Collective, students learn how to extend and enhance the existing capabilities of their projects and communities using free, open, and increasingly ubiquitous digital technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;who-is-your-target-audience&quot;&gt;Who is your target audience?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Anyone who is serious about gaining the skills, knowledge, and power they need to materially improve the lives of their community, neighbors, and friends and who also shares our pro-social values is welcome at our workshops and events. This means we take political stances including anti-capitalism, feminism, queer rights, trans liberation, anti-racism, animal liberation, environmental justice, and other social justice causes extremely seriously. Tech Learning Collective instructors make a point to embed these values in all of our workshops (“it’s a machine-in-the-middle, not necessarily man-in-the-middle”), and all of our workshop materials use examples relevant to political organizing scenarios as the basis for practice labs and other exercises (“if ‘you are part of the Rebel Alliance and a traitor,’ how will you communicate safely such that the Empire does not catch you?”).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Another way to say this is that we are uninterested in teaching people who have a lot of access to other, more mainstream technology education. If you often enjoy your downtown IT or tech Meetup group, you probably won’t find Tech Learning Collective classes comfortable. Although thankfully rare, we have occasionally had to ban some people (mostly men) for taking up too much space in classrooms, or people who seem more interested in learning just enough basic tech to begin a startup regardless of their self-identification. We are not shy about doing this because we are a grassroots political group first and a technology school second, not the other way around like basically all other professional-level tech training options out there right now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;There are dozens upon dozens of places you can go to learn how to memorize the answers to interview questions, get a tech certification, or pigeonhole yourself into a career path. Folks interested in that kind of activity just don’t last very long as Tech Learning Collective apprentices or students because we’re not putting down what they want to pick up.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-some-steps-you-take-to-ensure-your-work-is-accessible-to-people-without-a-background-in-tech&quot;&gt;What are some steps you take to ensure your work is accessible to people without a background in tech?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Making our workshops and other events accessible to people without a background in tech is actually really easy for us because both our materials and our methodology actually begins at the beginning. We know that’s something a lot of people say they’re doing but, to be blunt, we simply don’t see it happening a lot outside of Tech Learning Collective classes and workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We know what it’s like to wade into the world of digital security as a novice because we’ve all done it at one point or another. Some of us did it as recently as a year or so ago. We felt confounded or overwhelmed by the vast amount of information suddenly thrown at us. Worse, much of this information purported to be “for beginners,” making us feel even worse about our apparent inability to understand it. ‘Are we just stupid?’, we often asked ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;No. The reality is that these self-proclaimed “beginner” resources are either wildly self-referential, full of assumptions of prior knowledge, or just simply bad explanations that are incoherent at best. Often, the security resources you’ll find when you do an Internet search are all three of these things.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You are not stupid. Digital security is genuinely hard. Look, most people just don’t teach cybersecurity well, if they even bother to focus on teaching in the first place. We insist that you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; understand this stuff. It’s just that, most of the time, you’re being shown a scattershot, piecemeal presentation coming through a human filter who, often, isn’t deeply familiar with the material in the first place. Given that, is it any wonder this stuff seems damn near impossible to learn?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The real reason it often feels like you’re having a hard time understanding what the teachers at a cybersecurity class are trying to show you is that they don’t know how to explain what they’re doing. In fact, most of the time, they don’t even &lt;em&gt;show&lt;/em&gt; you anything at all, preferring instead to discuss how something &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; work in some hypothetical scenario  rather than showing you, right then and there on their computer screen, how it &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; works in real life today. Very often, these classes and events offer nothing more than slideshows containing oversimplified diagrams after a rundown asserting that the teacher holds some credentials, even though none of those credentials are “Masters of Education.” Too often, they never even actually show the technology being discussed, which we think is just absurd.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In contrast, Tech Learning Collective classes are dramatically more interactive, which makes them far more digestible and approachable for actual beginners as well as experienced technologists both. Our methodology focuses almost exclusively on providing guided, kinetic, experience-based training in fully-fledged, real-life scenarios using physical hardware, cloud environments, or both. There are never slideshows, which means it feels less like a business meeting and more like watching an episode of Mr. Robot with the director’s commentary on.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Best of all, our pedagogy is intentionally Socratic, which means our teachers repeatedly engage students with questions and challenges in real-time. We do this because we know you can watch a slideshow, read the manual, or run through the practice lab on your own time. It’s very obvious that the best use of our time together is to do what humans do best; converse, question, and mimic one another. This means everyone always gets a lot out of class time precisely because it avoids the all-too-common situation where one person runs into an error and everyone else has to wait for the troubleshooting to end before the class can resume.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We regularly receive feedback from students who have little to no background as technologists expressing surprise that they learned as much as they did as quickly as they did. But don’t take our word for it: have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://techlearningcollective.com/testimonials/&quot;&gt;our Testimonials page&lt;/a&gt; to see for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;last-winter-you-hosted-the-hackers-next-door-conference-in-nyc-could-you-tell-us-about-how-you-approached-such-an-ambitious-and-collaborative-project-were-there-any-surprises-along-the-way&quot;&gt;Last Winter you hosted the Hackers Next Door conference in NYC, could you tell us about how you approached such an ambitious and collaborative project? Were there any surprises along the way?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com&quot;&gt;Hackers Next Door&lt;/a&gt; was an incredible event, with over 25 speakers and two full days of workshops and talks. Unfortunately, we dramatically underestimated its popularity and as a result quickly ran out of capacity at our 100 person venue. In fact, we had to enlist several friends to act as bouncers as we realized that we would have to more strictly enforce our no-walk-in policy simply out of respect for our hosts and safety concerns at the space. So, until recently, Hackers Next Door was the largest event we ever facilitated. (We recently held an online event called Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour that more than doubled Hackers Next Door’s registration numbers.)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Although it did take a lot of coordination between teams (and, really, our core team went above and beyond the call of duty, personally hauling equipment like loudspeakers on the NYC Subway late into the night), we didn’t do anything particularly special to make the event happen. The biggest hurdle was simply coordinating with speakers, ensuring that all the confirmed speakers were given a time slot that they liked, and making sure that any special requests were taken care of.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Most of the coordination tasks were extremely well-regimented. Communication happened in a bulk and automated fashion. This just means we wrote email templates as the needs arose, and then sent out notices to the speaker or ticket holder lists via mail merge so everyone had the correct information about their specific session or ticket details. This is the kind of thing spreadsheets and computers have been doing since the 60’s and 70’s.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, we think a lot of other groups could (should?) be making events like Hackers Next Door happen a lot more frequently, even with small organizing teams like ours. This message, that small groups of well-organized and skilled individuals can punch way above their weight, was what we hoped to have folks take away from their experience. The event itself was simply proof that it could be done in very little time, with very little money, and with few pre-existing resources.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;the-tlc-is-incredibly-active-with-an-impressive-15-events-planned-for-may-and-even-more-in-june-how-does-your-group-share-this-workload-and-avoid-burnout-among-collective-members&quot;&gt;The TLC is incredibly active, with an impressive 15 events planned for May (and even more in June). How does your group share this workload and avoid burnout among collective members?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;There are three primary techniques we use to do this. These will be familiar to anyone who has ever worked in an office or held a position in management. They are: automation, separation of concerns, and partnerships. After all, just because we are anti-capitalist does not mean we ignore the obviously effective tools and techniques we have at our disposal for realizing our goals.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The first pillar, automation, is really what we are all about. It’s what almost all of our classes teach in one form or another. In a Tech Learning Collective class, you will often hear the phrase, “If you ever do one thing on a computer twice, you’ve made a mistake the second time.” This is a reminder that computers were built for automation. That’s what they’re for. So, almost every component of Tech Learning Collective’s day-to-day operations are automated. This includes updating the Web site, publishing new events to the calendar, sending out Webinar access details to registered guests, adding (or removing) members from our various teams, syndicating (cross-posting) events to partner sites, and more. The only time a human needs to be involved is when another human wants to talk to us. Otherwise, the emails you’re getting from us were written many months ago and are being generated by scripts and templates.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Secondly, separation of concerns: this is both a management and a security technique. In InfoSec, we call this the compartmentalization principle. You might be familiar with it as “need to know,” and it states that only the people who need to be concerned with a certain thing should have to spend any brainpower on it in the first place, or indeed have any access to it at all. This means that when one of our teachers wants to host a workshop, they don’t need to involve anyone else in the collective. They are autonomous, free to act however they wish within the limits of their role. This makes it possible for our collective members to dip in and out whenever they need to, thus avoiding burnout while increasing quality. If one of us has to step away for a while, the collective can still function smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This kind of separation of concerns probably wouldn’t be possible without the automation we’ve put in place to automate the minutia of daily operations. Without that, we would need to at least double if not triple or quadruple the number of people who could devote many hours to managing the logistics of making sure events happen. But that’s boring, tedious, repetitive work, and that’s what computers are for.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Finally, partnerships allow us to do things we could not do on our own. This also helps distribute the overarching workload, like creating practice labs or writing educational materials for new workshops. We work extremely closely with a number of other groups, which is possible because of our unique history in which our core collective members straddle several other activist and educational collectives. For example, one of our curriculum partners is Anarcho-Tech NYC, a collective of self-proclaimed anarchist hackers who provide digital security services for anti-fascist groups in New York City, with whom we collaborate on the bulk of our cybersecurity curriculum. This makes it feasible for us to take advantage of their work, while simultaneously supporting their efforts. It also means our teachers and, more importantly, our students have access to a much wider range of alumni opportunities than they would otherwise have had if we didn’t actively seek out and explore new partnership opportunities like these.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;at-the-time-of-writing-we-are-in-the-middle-of-the-covid-19-health-crisis-many-groups-are-struggling-with-shelter-in-place-but-fortunately-tlc-seems-to-have-adapted-very-well-what-are-some-strategies-you-are-employing-to-continue-your-work&quot;&gt;At the time of writing, we are in the middle of the COVID-19 health crisis. Many groups are struggling with shelter-in-place, but fortunately TLC seems to have adapted very well. What are some strategies you are employing to continue your work?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is almost an unfair question, because the nature of what we do at Tech Learning Collective lends itself well to the current crises.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The biggest change that the COVID-19 pandemic has forced us to adapt to is the shuttering of our usual venues for in-person workshops. Fortunately, we were already ramping up our online and distance learning options even before the pandemic. So we simply put that into high gear. The easily automatable nature of handling logistics for online events also made it possible to do many more of them, which is one reason you’re seeing so much more activity from us these days. The other reason, quite bluntly, is that a lot more people are finally willing to give online events a chance, making it far more worth our time to put them on.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But also, there is widespread agreement within our collective that many effective strategies for organizing, or for continuing with daily work tasks, have actually &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; changed because of the pandemic. Yes, there is huge value in physical events and other in-person efforts, and obviously there is a whole class of labor that simply cannot be done entirely online. After all, this is exactly why “essential workers” are called essential; you may be able to order groceries over the Internet, but you can’t eat them off your laptop screen. That being said, it’s clear to us that the organizing strategies of the 90’s and the mass protest movements of the Occupy Wall Street era have proven largely ineffective against the neoliberal plague sickening society today, and that most white-collar “jobs” are, to paraphrase David Graeber, anthropologist and author of the 2018 book “Bullshit Jobs,” little more than a means of greasing the wheels of capitalist machinery which serves no ethical purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Even before COVID-19 became the nightmare scenario that it has, we knew that effective political organizing required safe and secure telecommunication capabilities. The NSA, FBI, and CIA were spying on Americans long before 9/11 (COINTELPRO anyone?), much less before Zoom meetings became the de-facto “new normal.” And so, just as the Trump election in 2016 finally woke many people up to the things that privacy advocates have been saying for decades (“it’s not about whether you have something to hide, or whether you trust this government, it’s about whether you trust the &lt;em&gt;next&lt;/em&gt; administration”), we are seeing many people who have been under shelter-in-place orders finally wake up to other aspects of this reality that has already been with us for far too long.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In certain ways, for many in our collective, this “new normal” is actually a rather dated 90’s-era cyberpunk dystopia that we’ve been experiencing for many, many years. In that sense, we’re happy that you don’t have to enter this reality alone and defenseless. We kinda built Tech Learning Collective for exactly this scenario. We want to help you thrive here.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;finally-what-does-the-future-look-like-for-tlc&quot;&gt;Finally, what does the future look like for TLC?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We’re not sure! When we started TLC, we never thought it would end up becoming an online, international, radical political hacker school. In just the last two months since we’ve been forced to become a wholly virtual organization, we’ve held classes with students from Japan, Italy, New Zealand, London, Mexico, and beyond, as well as many parts of the United States of course. Many of them are now repeat participants working their way through our entire curriculum, which is the best compliment we could have asked for. We hope they’ll stick around to join our growing alumni community after that. We’re also (slowly) expanding our “staff” outside of New York City, which isn’t something we thought would happen for many years, if at all.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So we’re excited about the possibilities of the future, even as we recognize the horrific state of the present situation. We would like to make new partnerships. We would like to hold more social events. For example, we loved the several Shift-CTRL Space “queer hacker parties” that we got to make some cool tech for and some in our crew are trying to figure out what the best way to replicate or even enhance that experience entirely online would be.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But right now, we’re primarily focused on moving the rest of our in-person curriculum online and creating new online workshops. Many of the workshops unveiled this month or planned for next month are new, like our workshops on writing shell scripts, exploiting Web applications, auditing firewalls and other network perimeter defenses, and an exciting “spellwork” workshop to learn about the “spirits” that live on in the magical place inside every computer called the Command Line. So in the near future, expect to see more workshops like these, as well as more of our self-paced “&lt;a href=&quot;https://techlearningcollective.com/foundations/&quot;&gt;Foundations&lt;/a&gt;” learning modules that you can try out anytime for free right in your Web browser from our Web site.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;After that? Well, some say another world is possible. We’re hackers. Hacking is about showing people what’s possible, especially if they insist it could never happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">In four months&amp;rsquo; time during 2019, Tech Learning Collective produced twelve (12!) free or by-donation digital privacy training events for community groups and grassroots activists recognized by Electronic Frontier Alliance organizers. Only our fellow New Yorkers, the CyPurr Collective, held more events (13 events spread across the full 12 months), narrowly edging us out of first place. Later, we were interviewed by EFF organizers for a featured profile now published in an abridged form on the EFF Deeplinks blog. This post contains the complete unabridged interview.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/tlc-efa.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/tlc-efa.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hacker Trivia Night benefit weekend wraps with reminder for need of revolutionary education in revolutionary times</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/31/hacker-trivia-night-benefit-weekend-wraps-with-reminder-for-need-of-revolutionary-education-in-revolutionary-times.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hacker Trivia Night benefit weekend wraps with reminder for need of revolutionary education in revolutionary times" /><published>2020-05-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/31/hacker-trivia-night-benefit-weekend-wraps-with-reminder-for-need-of-revolutionary-education-in-revolutionary-times</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/31/hacker-trivia-night-benefit-weekend-wraps-with-reminder-for-need-of-revolutionary-education-in-revolutionary-times.html">&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective, with its educational mission, has roots dating back before the current American neo-fascist government was voted into power by a minority of American citizens. Before we came together to create Tech Learning Collective, our members have been at Occupy Wall Street encampments, running &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;digital security workshops&lt;/a&gt; about anti-surveillance tools like TextSecure, which you may recognize today as &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal Private Messenger&lt;/a&gt;. Others in our collective have been steering committee members for internationally-connected social centers, supported street medic operations in numerous American cities, and more. What makes us a collective is that all of us are convinced that the next chapter of the global movement for justice will end tragically if the movement as a whole does not dramatically and immediately invest in digital infrastructure education with a competency and urgency like never before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re doing our part as best we can by responding to rapidly shifting priorities with one eye on our short-term goals of the present moment, and the other firmly trained on our long-term goals. What are those goals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the short term: Nurture our existing students through workshops and other &lt;a href=&quot;/events/calendar/&quot;&gt;educational opportunities&lt;/a&gt; such as &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/05/event-2020-05-29-hacker-trivia-night-restaurant-and-bar-night&quot;&gt;the recent Hacker Trivia Night&lt;/a&gt; so that they become capable of administering enterprise-grade, world-class, state-of-the-art Information Technology systems in support of the existing projects they are already involved in or to support the residents of the neighborhoods they currently live in.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the medium term: Deploy and operate collectively-owned resilient critical telecom and other digital infrastructure supported by former students. Spread digital competencies in an “each one teach one” and “pay it forward” approach in which trainers train other trainers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the long term: smash the State, destroy capitalism, abolish globalized oppression inflicted by government, corporate, institutional, and interpersonal violence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/2020-05-hacker-trivia-night-liberate_United-States.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Hacker Trivia Night challenge: &amp;ldquo;You get a disappearing Signal message from your friend informing you of a new &amp;lsquo;alt-right&amp;rsquo; group whose website claims it is active in your neighborhood. Your friend wants to know the legal identities of the site operators. What is the first tool you run?&amp;rdquo;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given our approach, it’s no surprise we believe that one of the most effective ways to get there from here is to train politically motivated people who already share our ethics and commitment to anti-racism, feminism, police and prison abolition, ecological justice, and other critical issues in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and, yes, defensive and offensive cyber-warfare techniques. (Importantly, we have little to no faith in the political commitments of most existing and often quite liberal “Tech for Social Good” movements, although we would be fools not to accept their material contributions and financial donations.) We know this is a tall order, because these skills take time to develop, and also because organized, politicized efforts to teach these skills came slower and later than they should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fact is, technologies that governments all over the globe deem to be cyberweapons have already been firing at civilians for decades. The only reason resistance was not louder sooner is because, unlike lead or rubber bullets, electronic bullets don’t bruise bodies. At least, not directly. Indirectly, however, they are a critical enabler of mass social control, making it possible for the rich to keep justice away from the poor, from women, from queer and trans people, and particularly from Black and brown people in this country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, as we’ve seen time and time again, ballot boxes on their own don’t result in justice. Politicians simply ratify unjust laws written by lobbyists and police unions. More distressingly, adding laws of our own to the existing political system &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t result in justice, either. Authorities simply ignore the laws, hide their actions to avoid prosecution, or blatantly rewrite them. Not even the lofty concept of democracy, which is the fundamentally and fatally flawed idea of majority rule, does not result in justice. Things are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; going to fundamentally change for the better under a regime of “one person one vote” anymore than it would under the current “one dollar one vote” system the USA has today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/2020-05-hacker-trivia-night-liberate_Australia.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Hacker Trivia Night challenge: &amp;ldquo;Between the dates of January 1, 2015 and May 29, 2020 how many people are known to have been killed by police officers across the United States?&amp;rdquo;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an undeniable challenge, and we think there are many different good approaches we can take to addressing it. That’s why our goal is not to implement or even advocate for a specific approach, but rather to empower you to take actions you feel are appropriate backed, supported, and enabled by the awesomely potent power of the digital devices you already use every day. That computer you’re using to read this very post is arguably your most powerful asset because it—and it uniquely—can be both your pen and your sword at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend, as protests against yet another murderer with a badge were held around the country and around the world, we went forward with our Hacker Trivia Night event in the hopes that participants new to cybersecurity would get a taste of what competent digital dexterity might feel like for them. We never feel able to pin this feeling down with words, so we were happy to see that one of our fellow Electronic Frontier Alliance member groups, DEFCON 201, recorded themselves participating in the event and provided a fantastic and fun introduction to Tech Learning Collective, along with a brief orientation to Hacker Trivia Night, for their own membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than try to recreate the experience in words, we present the first (minimally edited) ten minutes or so of their recording:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/DC201 introduces TLC and Hacker Trivia Night.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/DC201 introduces TLC and Hacker Trivia Night.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as with each prior crisis, we’re seeing renewed interest in digital safety and security as more people recognize both how much more powerful control over digital infrastructure can make their campaigns as well as how central digital security culture is to the success of movement organizing. We’re honored to have been spoken of so highly by our fellow EFA member group, and we look forward to continuing to facilitate educational opportunities on cybersecurity and other IT infrastructure topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must recognize that the American State is a country whose Revolutionary War was premised on the protection of profits for its rich through the Trans-Atlantic Slave Trade. A country that was originally colonized through intentional, barbaric, continental-wide genocide. These are histories it continually seeks to downplay or whitewash, when justice demands exactly the opposite. Since its founding, the American government has made clear time and time again, over more than four centuries of indiscriminate, unaccountable, monstrous oppression, that they will cede &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; (even while they promise everything) without a demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Americans who have sat comfortably in the pot of slowly heating water that the capitalist class prepared for them are now seeing physical weapons once reserved for foreign wars sweep down residential streets. We once again find our firm but peaceful demands for peace, justice, and concrete rather than merely rhetorical equality for Black and brown people met with what would be criminally physical assaults had they not been perpetrated by gangs of badge-wearing executors of white supremacist genocide and terror called the police, an institution invented specifically to combat equality. Some who supported increased funding for either foreign wars or domestic police departments are shocked—shocked!—at the level of physical harm these government-funded legally-protected murderers and abusers in uniform are willing to dole out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all knew they had the weapons. Now we see—yet again—that they’re willing and, in some cases, even eager to use them. We have to become equally ready and able to competently use all the tools available to us: legal, physical, moral, and, once we acquire it, cyber power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s continue training together so that we can bring all our diverse powers to bear against this inhumane and unjust system. All power to the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;44,203 forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/2020-05-hacker-trivia-night-liberate_Egypt.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Hacker Trivia Night challenge: &amp;ldquo;When converted into hexadecimal, the decimal number 44,203 reveals a profound truth. How is the hexadecimal number written?&amp;rdquo;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">The global movement for justice will end tragically if we do not dramatically and immediately invest in digital infrastructure education with a competency and urgency like never before, so we wrapped up our Hacker Trivia Night benefit weekend to support local businesses hit hard by the COVID-19 pandemic with a call to action to ramp up the level of ambition that we have for ourselves in our fight for justice.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/2020-05-hacker-trivia-night-gameboard.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/2020-05-hacker-trivia-night-gameboard.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">As Tech Learning Collective grows, quality is signature of classes and workshops</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/19/as-tech-learning-collective-grows-quality-is-signature-of-classes-and-workshops.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="As Tech Learning Collective grows, quality is signature of classes and workshops" /><published>2020-05-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/19/as-tech-learning-collective-grows-quality-is-signature-of-classes-and-workshops</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/19/as-tech-learning-collective-grows-quality-is-signature-of-classes-and-workshops.html">&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective was &lt;a href=&quot;/about/#our-history&quot;&gt;founded&lt;/a&gt; in an effort to radically increase the cybersecurity effectiveness and other digital capabilities of politically-motivated individuals and groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s incredibly important not to lose sight of larger goals, especially in times of distress. For us at Tech Learning Collective, that means taking stock of how we’re continuing to fulfil our original mission while taking care of ourselves and our communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has always been our intention to find sustainable ways of scaling our educational efforts to more students—increasing &lt;em&gt;quantity&lt;/em&gt;—but we will never feel good about compromising the &lt;em&gt;quality&lt;/em&gt; of a student’s education to achieve that goal. This is particularly relevant for our subject matter, in which quantity &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be delegated to electronic devices and the entire point of education is to make a single, well-trained individual more capable than a hundred untrained operators. &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/07/22/want-to-get-good-with-computers-dont-start-with-code.html&quot;&gt;This stubbornness set us apart from every other code bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; or employment-centric tech education initiative available to potential students since we started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, amid the almost constant bad news coming at us all, we thought we’d take a moment to share some of what’s been going well for us at Tech Learning Collective, and for some of our students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;phenomenal-month-over-month-growth-in-every-area&quot;&gt;Phenomenal month-over-month growth in every area&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective has seen phenomenal month-over-month spikes in student sign-ups, scheduled events, and even workshop offerings ever since March. This has of course coincided with dramatically accelerated online event planning activities. Since we were well-prepared for stay-at-home orders and the sudden surge in demand for Internet video conferencing and remote learning opportunities, we were able to immediately offer many more workshops at much more flexible times during the week, and so we have reached many more students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/post.featured.tech-learning-collective-calendar-2020-05.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a screenshot of our monthly &lt;a href=&quot;/events/calendar/&quot;&gt;calendar&lt;/a&gt; showing our packed schedule from late April through early June. As you can see, we are running (online) workshops or other donation-based events almost every other day now. Our events now vastly outnumber &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; schools who were ranked in Course Report’s “Best Coding Bootcamps 2019–2020” report. Partly, of course, this is because Tech Learning Collective is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a code bootcamp, which means that we provide workshops on topics that include but do not end with or even focus on coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way this new growth can be seen is by simple Web analytics. Although we have never installed any Web bugs or trackers on our Web sites (that means there is no Google Analytics, social media buttons, or any other tracker on any of our pages), our server request logs have shown a sustained upward trajectory of Web traffic for many months running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/post.chart.2020-05-19.cloudflare-web-analytics.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a screenshot of the latest 30-day snapshot covering the period from mid-April 2020 through today (May 19, 2020). In May 2020, we hit 10,000 unique visitors (as measured by Cloudflare) for the month, and while some of this is due to spikes from much larger groups sharing news of our events, the trend is clear and stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet another facet of this growth is to look at where our students are coming from. In 2019, our student population was entirely in New York City because we had no online offerings. While NYC residents are still the majority of our student population, in the last month and a half alone we have welcomed new students from over seven countries including Greece, Spain, Germany, the United Kingdom, Mexico, Japan, and New Zealand, as well as more than ten States ranging from coast to coast within the United States, not including New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To both drive and support this, our small teaching team has been hard at work producing new workshops at breakneck speed. In the past two months alone, we have introduced more than a dozen new &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;online-ready workshops&lt;/a&gt;, as well as additional one-off events that have become several recurring series, such as our &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/04/02/mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour-highlights.html&quot;&gt;wildly popular “Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour” events&lt;/a&gt;. (Our &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/06/event-2020-06-27-mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour&quot;&gt;next Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour will be on June 27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and will also be donation-based.) For a tiny team our size, we feel that this is an astonishing accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things have been so good for Tech Learning Collective as an organization, despite some personal hardships endured by our team members including unemployment and reduced pay or hours at work, that we are slowly beginning to transition apprentices into teaching positions almost a year ahead of schedule. Since everyone at Tech Learning Collective is paid for their time, we were able to support our own collective members through this difficult period in a way that allows us to keep teaching classes. To be blunt, judging by how many other community groups have faced existential crises recently, we are not sure if Tech Learning Collective would have survived without the commitment of our educational team, the skill of our operations team, and the continued participation of our students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And speaking of our students….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;student-retention-and-participation-continues-to-soar&quot;&gt;Student retention and participation continues to soar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that makes Tech Learning Collective so different than code bootcamps, programmer retreats, or certification courses is the unparalleled interactivity and uniqueness of each event, workshop, or course. Thanks to our Socratic pedagogy, there is simply no way other training options can match the quality of a student’s educational experience at a Tech Learning Collective webinar workshop with one of our teachers. As a result, we’ve seen student retention and participation across all skill levels continue to soar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, since January 2020, the average Tech Learning Collective student purchased tickets to 2.58 workshops. But that’s the average, and it turns out that our student retention “bell curve” looks nothing like a bell at all. Here’s a chart showing the mathematical normal distribution of workshop ticket purchases by purchaser since January 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/post.chart.2020-05-19.normal-distribution-of-purchased-tickets.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you’ll notice is that there is a hump between the 2.5 and 4.0 mark. This is because &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; students we’ve had since the start of the calendar year purchased a total of about two and a half tickets. Then there’s a steep drop-off, with very few students buying between between 4 and 6 tickets. But look at that spike over on the right. This shows that a remarkable number of students who attend one workshop return again and again, &lt;em&gt;more than six times in just over four months&lt;/em&gt; to participate in additional workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, since January, while most of our students have attended “only” two and a half paid events, there is a new cadre of students who have so far returned for five, six, and in one comitted student’s case, &lt;em&gt;thirteen&lt;/em&gt; separate webinar workshops. We know of no other tech education experience that is this “sticky,” to use a marketer’s phrase. Moreover, since this data only charts paid events, Tech Learning Collective’s actual retention numbers are even better than depicted here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think the reason Tech Learning Collective workshops are so worth returning to is really pretty simple: we are not focused on marketing! Instead, we make sure that &lt;a href=&quot;/about/#master-more-skills-more-quickly&quot;&gt;students leave class having internalized concepts and principles that will serve them for far longer and in more contexts than they would otherwise acquire&lt;/a&gt;. At code bootcamps, most students are doing little more than memorizing the syntax of some programming language, but at Tech Learning Collective, students are learning how to think critically about every challenge they face in the digital age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our teachers actually teach, instead of simply pointing students towards references that we know they can find on their own using an Internet search engine. The result is an educational experience far more valuable, at far lower cost (both in terms of time and money), than can be achieved elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Tech Learning Collective’s sky-high student retention rate is just one data point in support of this claim. Rather than taking our word for it, here is what a few of our most recent students had to say about the classes they took this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is the best school, hands down, to learn about how to work with your computer. They offer regular workshops and longer courses, and have amazing, self-directed foundation courses about doing more with the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;—Zach, May 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Before taking the “&lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Exploring-Cyberspace-Network-Sniffing-and-Scanning&quot;&gt;Exploring Cyberspace: Network Sniffing and Scanning&lt;/a&gt;” class, I had some passing experience with one or two of the tools the instructor introduced. I would have considered myself a beginner. The instructor managed to take us into deep waters by illustrating small steps, making sure we understood the fundamental terminology, and asking us lots of questions. The scope of the class was thoughtfully limited—enough to make sure we could swim but also realize there is much more to learn. Quite an accomplishment in under two hours!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;—David Schmudde, May 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I found Tech Learning Collective’s “&lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Our-Streets,-Our-Maps-Introduction-to-OpenStreetMap&quot;&gt;Our Streets, Our Maps&lt;/a&gt;” was a highly informative and stimulating workshop. The instructor did an excellent job illustrating the great versatility of OpenStreetMap and demonstrating the wide range of queries it can satisfy. As someone who’d never before used OpenStreetMap, this workshop captured my imagination and has inspired me to plumb the depths of this valuable resource!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;—August West, May 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read about a dozen more reviews published with permission on &lt;a href=&quot;/testimonials/&quot;&gt;our Testimonials page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unwavering-comittment-to-our-mission&quot;&gt;Unwavering comittment to our mission&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet another area that we find encouraging is the demographic breakdown of our student population. As a security-first technology school, we are operating in an extraordinarily militarized and male-dominated environment. However, at our workshops, including and especially our cybersecurity trainings such as our “&lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/World-Wide-Wars-Introduction-to-Exploiting-Web-Applications&quot;&gt;World Wide Wars: Introduction to Exploiting Web Applications&lt;/a&gt;” workshop, Tech Learning Collective consistently sees more women and femmes in attendance than men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An exact demographic breakdown is impossible for us to provide because we don’t ask students to reveal their gender identity, race, or other demographic information as a condition of attendance to our public workshops. Also, our webinars are held online where students may never reveal any additional information about themselves beyond the words they type or nickname they use in class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, in order to keep ourselves accountable to our mission of serving primarily underrepresented communities, we sometimes conduct internal reviews of our progress and make some generic assumptions during the process of analyzing the data we do have. This includes classifying attendees along a coarse gender spectrum with three points (“femme,” “masc,” and “neutral”, in which we also include an implicit “unknown” gender category). The coding is keyed to a student’s preferred name in class, legal first name when their preferred name is missing or unclear, or email address when no other information was available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be sure, this system is not perfect. For example, it offers no direct insight into how many trans people have attended Tech Learning Collective workshops, and we happen to know for a fact that there are trans people among our recurring students. While we obviously take issue with such imperfect schemes when they are used as justifications to make it hard or impossible for an individual to access social, economic, or political resources, we feel that our use of this schema as a rough guide used to ensure that we remain true to our own core educational mission is both ethical and warranted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on our analysis from data collected over the last five months, we can very happily say that we are succeeding like never before. Across all paid events since January 2020, exactly half (50%, or 1-to-1) of students presented in a manner that would be consistent with the mainstream’s understanding of women or feminine as compared with men or masculine (or gender-neutral).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/post.chart.2020-05-19.Estimated Binary Gender Breakdown by Total Students.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when limited to returning students (those participants who have purchased tickets to two or more events), this ratio changes to a dramatic 2-to-1. This means, among recurring students, women and femmes are exactly twice as likely to be present than men or masculine students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/post.chart.2020-05-19.Estimated Binary Gender Breakdown by Recurring Students.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We consider this a huge success because it bucks the trend that, to date, every single other mixed-gender educational environment has had immense trouble shaking. We primarily credit our amazing teaching team, who are themselves majority femme, with making this possible. They have gone to great lengths to ensure that each class is punctuated by what one student called “femme-friendly communications.” Additionally, our sliding scale or tiered pricing structure (borrowed from our experience in the queer party scene) in which straight, cis, white, and other societally privileged demographics are asked to pay more to offset the systemic oppressions prevalent in society and the tech sector especially, is clearly proving a useful technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This data confirms our belief that it is not only possible, but economically sustainable to actually prioritize women and femmes even in what are traditionally viewed as intensely combative and needlessly hyper-masculinized fields such as cyber offense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the above is incredibly encouraging, we are a long way from our goal of a world in which political organizers and movement builders have the digital dexterity (the knowledge and skill, not just the tools) they need to radically reshape the world into a more just and peaceful place. At the end of the day, it will be up to our students, not us, to actually hack back against injustices and inequality using what they learn in our classes and workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for now, Tech Learning Collective remains comitted to completing our transition to a wholly virtual organization. We are continuing to work on bringing our more intensive courses online, and we are adding more online options to the rest of our curriculum very quickly. This month, our &lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/&quot;&gt;Foundations series&lt;/a&gt; of free, self-paced online learning modules has expanded yet again, and this will continue for the forseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re incredibly grateful to everyone who has been supporting us, from our dedicated long-time collective members to our newest partners. As we continue to build out our cybersecurity-focused social justice movement technology education materials, we hope you’ll continue to help us spread the word amongst your friends and comrades about our webinars, workshops, and special events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of your issue, effective advocacy requires competency and skill. Tech Learning Collective is committed to making sure you and your group have the skills you need to work effectively and safely in the digital age.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Tech Learning Collective was founded in an effort to radically increase the cybersecurity effectiveness and other digital capabilities of politically-motivated individuals and groups. It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly important not to lose sight of larger goals, especially in times of distress. For us at Tech Learning Collective, that means taking stock of how we're continuing to fulfil our original mission while taking care of ourselves and our communities.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.tech-learning-collective-calendar-2020-05.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.tech-learning-collective-calendar-2020-05.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Queer All the (Electronic) Things! Our Love for the Command Line</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/09/queer-all-the-electronic-things-our-love-for-the-command-line.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Queer All the (Electronic) Things! Our Love for the Command Line" /><published>2020-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/09/queer-all-the-electronic-things-our-love-for-the-command-line</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/09/queer-all-the-electronic-things-our-love-for-the-command-line.html">&lt;p&gt;June is Pride Month, and there’s certainly a lot for us to be proud about. As an entirely queer-run technology school, June is a very personal time for us. We usually take this time of year to reflect on the previous year, to celebrate how far we’ve come, and look forward to making the next year the best yet. This year, of course, things are very different. They are much harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we talk about our upcoming workshops, please permit us the luxury of getting a few things off our chests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the coronavirus pandemic, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nyc-pride.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/Press+Release+04.20.2020.pdf&quot;&gt;NYC Pride has cancelled all in-person events&lt;/a&gt;. Like everyone else, many in our LGBTQIA+ family have lost their jobs, often their only economic lifeline. But as queer and trans folks, we’re also feeling the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newsweek.com/trans-transgender-coronavirus-pandemic-covid-19-youth-students-trevor-project-1493527&quot;&gt;aftershocks from the COVID-19 crisis in ways that straight or cis people don’t even have to think about&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For centuries, LGBT and queer folks have had and continue to need to fight simply to be safe, much less welcomed, into many parts of mainstream society. Everything from walking down the street to showing up for work has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.papermag.com/nomi-ruiz-trans-women-2645743817.html&quot;&gt;tinged with danger&lt;/a&gt; long before mere human contact was itself a “risky” behavior. Even today, trans, non-binary, and gender non-conforming people still &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2016/08/in-michigan-its-totally-legal-to-fire-trans-people-for-their-gender-identity/496559/&quot;&gt;don’t have basic employment protections&lt;/a&gt; under United States law, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/think/opinion/trump-s-fight-make-transgender-discrimination-legal-may-make-sex-ncna1044026&quot;&gt;threatens &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; because &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; it does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is no surprise that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/voices/2019/06/24/pride-month-black-transgender-women-stonewall-marsha-p-johnson/1478200001/&quot;&gt;trans women were rioting against police brutality even before Stonewall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, then came Stonewall and the fight for inclusion into and acceptance—Borg-like assimilation—by a society that still, fifty-one years later, still doesn’t seem to care about whether its essential workers live or die. Forget queerness. When push comes to shove, even if you’re straight, cis, male, and white, your elected leaders would still rather sacrifice you on the altar of the holy United States Dollar to protect their precious “economy.” Get out there, essential worker, and risk your life to defend your “livelihood.” The contradiction in terms could not be more obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was “acceptance” and “inclusion” into &lt;em&gt;this mess&lt;/em&gt; really worth all the effort? What if, instead of fighting for inclusion to and acceptance by a callous system, we had spent the last fifty-one years fighting to break out of this coercive and controlling environment altogether? What if, instead of unquestioningly believing that “this is just how the world works,” we had been able to ground ourselves to the fullest extent of our queerness, confident in our rejection of the sickness of straightness from day one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would we still be job hunting? Would jobs still be the only feasible way most of us could get healthcare? Would so many of us, irrespective of gayness or straightness, be so disappointed in our government’s collective failure to do anything as simple as show some empathy for the almost &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coronatracker.com/country/united-states/&quot;&gt;100,000 preventable deaths&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href=&quot;https://trumpdeathclock.com/&quot;&gt;climbing&lt;/a&gt;) their inaction has surely caused?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine for a moment, just for one moment, what we could have accomplished by now if we had collectively spent the last fifty-one years since Stonewall fighting not for inclusion into this Hell of a society that still doesn’t care if we live or die, but freedom from the obviously wrong and damaging limitations of the supposedly inevitable false choices on which that system is based. That would have been queer power at its finest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Queer power comes from the edges. It begins as the subtle glint of color in an otherwise black-and-white world. It is the unexplained knot in our bellies that we all feel when we take the time to listen to our bodies and notice that something…something &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; is there, just under the surface, waiting for us to call it up. That it &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be there, somewhere, because otherwise none of us would be here in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does any of this have to do with the command line? To us, the command line is the queerest part of our machines. No where in a computer is its natural, innate power exemplified with as much grace or elegance as the command line. It is radically different from the “Desktop” most people experience as the totality of their computing environment. That, in and of itself, is one reason we are so enamored with our terminals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The command line lies beneath the visual surface of your computer, hidden but always present, like sacred wells held in the bases of our heretical cathedrals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To us, the command line is our route to freedom from the coercive paradigm imposed by the &lt;em&gt;industrial business machines&lt;/em&gt; of this society like, say, IBM, Inc. It is a place that is not anywhere specific and also everywhere simultaneously. It can not be accurately described as this or that because it is a third thing altogether. It is made up of pure language, and because of this it can morph into anything you imagine, and many things you cannot—yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern tech culture will describe the command line as an obscure productivity tool; something you learn only to impress other tech folk (a meaningless activity) or to become a “power user” (a meaningless phrase). Conventional tech wisdom will tell you that the command line is an intimidating, obscure, imposing place—impossible to learn and dangerous to use. This is only an attempt to hide its true nature: the command line is a place made entirely of our first occult technology, the word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love our terminals in a way not unlike the way we love our chosen families. We were presented with Windows and walls and folders and stacks of paperwork. It took us a long time to find the terminals buried underneath layer upon layer of lies, misdirections, and obstacles, and longer still to learn how to be comfortable sitting with them. They used strange words we didn’t know. Other people thought we were weird for going there. Sometimes they were even scared of us because of it. But we were nonetheless called back there time and again and, ultimately, being there proved the single most freeing experience we have ever had, reaching far beyond the confines of metal and electrical cable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, experiences like these, they stick with us. And it’ll stick with you, too. These kinds of experiences make you want to change things because, suddenly, you realize how small you had to make yourself to fit in with your previous ideas of what life could be. Admittedly, that’s not something everyone wants to do; some are simply understandably nervous, while others (like “the 1%”) recognize the genuinely existential threat to their way of “life” that such change implies. For many people, jobs and grocery stores are probably familiar. Work for a boss and you will be &lt;em&gt;allowed&lt;/em&gt;, benevolently, to survive. A world with community gardens and hydroponics are probably harder for them to imagine than one with paychecks and exploited, immigrant farm workers. Paperwork and government benefits are predictable, if maddening, byzantine, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gothamist.com/news/coronavirus-unemployment-benefits-in-ny-is-still-a-kafkaesque-mess&quot;&gt;frequently unavailable&lt;/a&gt;, and often unjust. Chosen families who support one another are not utopic, but they are at least based on human connection rather than ICE-cold number crunching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can only get to the command line by asking for it explicitly; it will not make itself known to us on its own. We can only get there from here by demanding, with the necessary force to back it up, that all the existing prisons both literal and figurative be torn down. It will not happen by visiting a ballot box once every four years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with that said, this June, we invite you to join us for these command line workshops that are unlike any other you have probably ever imagined. We know things are all fucked up right now, and we know how intimidating this can all be. But in certain ways, for many in our collective, this “new normal” so many people are suddenly experiencing is actually a rather dated 90’s-era cyberpunk dystopia that we’ve been experiencing for many, many years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that sense, we’re happy that you don’t have to enter this reality alone and defenseless. We kinda built Tech Learning Collective for exactly this scenario. We want to help you thrive here. We want to welcome you to the magical, heretical, transformative, queer world of humanity’s contemporary witchcraft. We want to welcome you to the Command Line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/06/workshop-2020-06-01-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics&quot;&gt;June 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;, at 4:30 PM, &lt;em&gt;Computer Language Foundations: Command Line Basics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You have read about people who can talk to machines. Maybe you imagined secret chambers, hidden away behind locked doors, with dark rooms basking in blue from electric fires. Some of these people seemed friendly, others scary, but all of them were powerful. How did they learn to communicate with their computers? This is your chance to learn the foundations of all computer languages, the command line, and actually begin to talk to a machine yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/06/workshop-2020-06-03-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners&quot;&gt;June 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt;, at 3:30 PM, &lt;em&gt;Writing with Blue Fire: Shell Scripting for Beginners&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Learn how to inscribe your thoughts, dreams, and desires into your computer and take your command line skills to the next level by learning how to write simple programs called shell scripts. In a way, invoking commands one at a time is like writing a program interactively, whereas writing a script inscribes that knowledge into a more permanent form. By learning how to turn commands into simple scripted programs, you can unlock the almost magical potential of your computer and more easily share that potential with others to whom you distribute your scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/06/workshop-2020-06-05-the-map-is-the-territory-a-magical-introduction-to-the-command-line&quot;&gt;June 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, at 9:00 PM, &lt;em&gt;The Map is the Territory: A Magical Introduction to the Command Line&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Get an introduction to interacting with your computer through the terminal, and a hint towards all the beautiful radical power possible there. We will learn some basics by doing spellwork, and by the end you will have literally gathered magical fragments from the ether and cast a spell from a modest digital altar.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome…to the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">At the start of Pride Month in June, Tech Learning Collective is celebrating in the way queer hackers do best. We're dedicating the first week of June as Command Line Interface (CLI) Week and hosting workshops all about breaking free from the hegemonic, oppressive, coercive, and limiting environment of the &quot;Desktop&quot; and its employment-centric office job metaphor for computing. Join us for any of these command line workshops throughout the week to help us bring down bullshit jobs and paperwork-fetishizing bureaucracies and uplift the inherent freedom and power in linguistic creativity and our ability to queer all the (electronic) things!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.rainbow-lolcat-terminal.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.rainbow-lolcat-terminal.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour Highlights</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/04/02/mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour-highlights.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mr. Robot's Hacker Happy Hour Highlights" /><published>2020-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/04/02/mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour-highlights</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/04/02/mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour-highlights.html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, we at Tech Learning Collective, an apprenticeship-based technology school for radical organizers headquartered in New York City that provides a security-first IT infrastructure curriculum to otherwise underserved communities and organizations advancing social justice causes, hosted &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/03/event-2020-03-30-mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour&quot;&gt;our first-ever virtual “Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour” online social hangout&lt;/a&gt;. More than 200 people registered, and more than 110 actually showed up, making it the single largest event we have ever hosted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being scheduled to run for only one hour, everyone who came was so engaged (and engaging!) that we continued talking tech, hacking, and discussed elements of the show &lt;cite&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/cite&gt; for more than two and a half hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, most of us had nowhere to go! Gathering places are closed, or suddenly dangerous in a whole new way. This country’s so-called “leaders” chose to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/senator-dumped-up-to-1-7-million-of-stock-after-reassuring-public-about-coronavirus-preparedness&quot;&gt;dump stocks and lie about the country’s pandemic readiness&lt;/a&gt; rather than fund health services, despite receiving daily briefings about the impending crisis. So, we came together last week to say: &lt;em&gt;fuck society!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is it about society that disappoints us so much?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, we don’t know. Is it that we collectively thought Steve Jobs was a great man, even when we knew he made billions off the backs of children? Or maybe it’s that it feels like all our heroes are counterfeit. The world itself is just one big hoax, spamming each other with our running commentary of bullshit masquerading as insight, our social media faking as intimacy. Or is it that we &lt;em&gt;voted&lt;/em&gt; for this? Not with our rigged elections, but with our things, our property, our money. We’re not saying anything new. We all know why we do this, not because &lt;cite&gt;Hunger Games&lt;/cite&gt; books makes us happy but because we wanna be sedated, because it’s painful not to pretend, because we’re cowards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuck society. It’s a world built on fantasy. A kingdom of bullshit! Governments have no respect for their own laws. Society was compromised before we even got here. Election ballots are their exploits. Belief in their good intentions is our zero day vuln. Synthetic emotions in the form of pills. Psychological warfare in the form of advertising. Mind-altering chemicals in the form of…food! Brainwashing seminars in the form of media. Controlled isolated bubbles in the form of social networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To break this cycle of abuse, at Tech Learning Collective, students learn how to extend and enhance the existing capabilities of their projects and communities using free, open, and increasingly ubiquitous digital technologies. And despite the seriousness of the current situation, our ambitious goals, and the overwhelming forces of evil arrayed against those who try to bend the arc of the universe towards justice, we try to have fun while we’re learning how to break free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week’s “Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour” was one tiny success among the mayhem. Below, we’ve shared excerpts of some of our favorite moments from the event. Watch the videos or read the closed captions to see what you may have missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#introduction-and-what-the-virus-said-poem&quot;&gt;Introduction and “What the Virus Said” poem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#mixnets-and-tor&quot;&gt;Mixnets and Tor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#password-hashes-explained&quot;&gt;Password hashes explained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#dfir-ip-addresses-and-framing-terry-colby&quot;&gt;DFIR, IP addresses, and framing Terry Colby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#unlinking-your-data-trail-with-tors-new-identity-button&quot;&gt;Unlinking your data trail with Tor’s “New Identity” Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#covid-19-cybersecurity-industry-response&quot;&gt;COVID-19 cybersecurity industry response&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction-and-what-the-virus-said-poem&quot;&gt;Introduction and “What the Virus Said” poem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Mr. Robot's Hacker Happy Hour Introduction and 'What the Virus Said' Poem.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;track label=&quot;Closed Captions (English)&quot; kind=&quot;captions&quot; srclang=&quot;en&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Mr. Robot's Hacker Happy Hour Introduction and 'What the Virus Said' Poem.vtt&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Mr. Robot's Hacker Happy Hour Introduction and 'What the Virus Said' Poem.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event opened with a brief introduction to Tech Learning Collective, a rundown of some links to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/awesome-social-distancing/tree/master/README.md#readme&quot;&gt;resources elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;, shout-outs to our sister organizations, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lundi.am/What-the-virus-said&quot;&gt;a poem acknowledging the current tragedy unfolding before us&lt;/a&gt; all across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mixnets-and-tor&quot;&gt;Mixnets and Tor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Mixnets and Tor.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;track label=&quot;Closed Captions (English)&quot; kind=&quot;captions&quot; srclang=&quot;en&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Mixnets and Tor.vtt&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Mixnets and Tor.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tor makes its appearance on &lt;cite&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/cite&gt; in the very first scene, even before the opening credits. So perhaps that’s why, for the first thirty minutes of our Hacker Happy Hour, most people asked questions about Tor. In this clip, we discuss one of the foundational operating principles of the Tor network: the fact that it is a cryptographic mixnet. We also touch on why it’s so important to keep your Tor Browser software (and, really, all your software) up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective regularly runs &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Tor-What-is-it-Good-For-(Absolutely-Everything!)&quot;&gt;our in-depth Tor workshop&lt;/a&gt;, which covers this and many more aspects of Tor use, configuration, and administration at various times. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;/events/&quot;&gt;our events calendar&lt;/a&gt; to learn when the next Tor workshop you can sign up for is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;password-hashes-explained&quot;&gt;Password hashes explained&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Password Hashes Explained.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;track label=&quot;Closed Captions (English)&quot; kind=&quot;captions&quot; srclang=&quot;en&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Password Hashes Explained.vtt&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Password Hashes Explained.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every hacker needs to crack a hash at one point or another (although the ecologically conscious hacker simply backdoors login pages), and Elliot is no exception. In this clip, we discuss what password hashes are. We go into far more depth on the topic during &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Password-Superpowers-How-to-Crack-Hashes-and-Stump-Hackers&quot;&gt;our Password Superpowers workshop&lt;/a&gt;, where we show you how to automate the process described in the video using Elliot’s favorite hash cracking program, John the Ripper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dfir-ip-addresses-and-framing-terry-colby&quot;&gt;DFIR, IP addresses, and framing Terry Colby&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/DFIR, IP Addresses, and Framing Terry Colby.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;track label=&quot;Closed Captions (English)&quot; kind=&quot;captions&quot; srclang=&quot;en&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/DFIR, IP Addresses, and Framing Terry Colby.vtt&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/workshops/DFIR, IP Addresses, and Framing Terry Colby.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a cybersecurity engineer by day, Elliot plays hacker defense, which means his job sometimes requires him to perform digital forensics and incident response (DFIR) tasks in order to collect evidence about what hackers did to which systems and when. In this clip, we (partly) answer the question, “How did Elliot frame Terry Colby?” In the process we discuss some DFIR tools, and demystify a bit of hacker jargon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unlinking-your-data-trail-with-tors-new-identity-button&quot;&gt;Unlinking your data trail with Tor’s “New Identity” Button&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Unlinking Your Data Trail with Tor's 'New Identity' Button.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;track label=&quot;Closed Captions (English)&quot; kind=&quot;captions&quot; srclang=&quot;en&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Unlinking Your Data Trail with Tor's 'New Identity' Button.vtt&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Unlinking Your Data Trail with Tor's 'New Identity' Button.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hacker or not, everyone has the right to check out books from the library without governments (the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Five_Eyes&quot;&gt;Five Eyes&lt;/a&gt;”), spouses, or parents learning which books we checked out. This is called privacy. On the Internet, Tor Browser provides one of the most robust tools for maintaining privacy as we browse the World Wide Web, our modern Library of Alexandria. In this clip, we discuss an oft-overlooked feature of Tor Browser, the “New Identity” button, why you want to use it more often than you probably are, and why it’s effective at helping you reduce your “digital paper trail.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;covid-19-cybersecurity-industry-response&quot;&gt;COVID-19 cybersecurity industry response&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/COVID-19 Cybersecurity Industry Response.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;track label=&quot;Closed Captions (English)&quot; kind=&quot;captions&quot; srclang=&quot;en&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/COVID-19 Cybersecurity Industry Response.vtt&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/workshops/COVID-19 Cybersecurity Industry Response.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pandemics are not new, but the Internet is! There has never been a global pandemic at a time when so much of day-to-day life is conducted through a Web browser. That makes it critical for people to understand how these technologies work, or they risk letting those who do constrain and control their capabilities for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This clip wasn’t really about Mr. Robot, but we couldn’t help pointing out that phishing campaigns immediately took advantage of people’s fear about the coronavirus pandemic. Some ransomware groups are still targeting hospitals and healthcare departments. While it’s great to see some industry responding in a “social good” way, we feel that this is far too little, far too late. The time to help your neighbor is not during an emergency, it is &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the emergency, something very few (if any) cybersecurity firms showed much interest in doing the way they are now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope that ending on this note will remind us all of the vital role digital infrastructure now plays in our everyday lives. Tech Learning Collective’s mission has always been to empower those who are sidelined by Big Tech in ways &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/07/22/want-to-get-good-with-computers-dont-start-with-code.html&quot;&gt;traditional bootcamps don’t and can’t&lt;/a&gt; by providing both world-class technical education coupled with a pedagogical approach that brings immediate benefit to you and your loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much to those of you who were able to join us last week for our first online “Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour.” If we do this again, we’ll focus on Season 1, Episode 2. Who knows? Maybe by the time we finish watching the show together, we will have remade society into a place where “leaders” can’t &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yahoo.com/lifestyle/stimulus-package-hurts-abortion-providers-150002213.html&quot;&gt;take financial advantage of the deaths of thousands of people&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t that be something worth hacking on?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">More than two hundred people registered for our free, first-ever virtual &amp;ldquo;Mr. Robot&amp;rsquo;s Hacker Happy Hour&amp;rdquo; digital security and online privacy crash course at the end of March. Although it was scheduled to run for one hour, we had so much fun that the event lasted almost a full three hours! In this post, we recap some of our favorite moments and share video highlights from the event. Read on for a peek at what you may have missed.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour-elliot.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour-elliot.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcoming students, alumni, and the public to our community chat channels</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/26/welcoming-students-alumni-and-the-public-to-our-community-chat-channels.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcoming students, alumni, and the public to our community chat channels" /><published>2020-03-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/26/welcoming-students-alumni-and-the-public-to-our-community-chat-channels</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/26/welcoming-students-alumni-and-the-public-to-our-community-chat-channels.html">&lt;p&gt;Today, Tech Learning Collective is pleased to invite you to our new community chat channels. These free, online, in-browser chat rooms make it easy to stay in touch with fellow and former students as well as other community members before, during, and after your course or &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;workshop&lt;/a&gt; experiences. We’re starting small, with only one open-to-the-public chat room, but we’ll be adding more as needed. All public channels will be free forever and will offer another way to get ad-hoc tech help from our talented team of technical experts, or just socialize with our welcoming, politically engaged student and alumni community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our public community chat room, accessible by clicking the “Open Chat” tab at the bottom of every page on our Web site, is a semi-moderated chat channel where everyone is welcome to stop by and spend a while. Discussions range from the technical to the humorous to the completely off-topic. &lt;strong&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective spaces, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior will result in immediate removal from this space.&lt;/strong&gt; Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, as we complete the transition to a fully remote educational format so that we can continue to provide best-in-class, affordable, security-first IT training to politically motivated individuals and groups even under &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic.html&quot;&gt;the extraordinary circumstances of the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/a&gt;, we are introducing per-course private chat channels to current and former students. If you are currently enrolled in a Tech Learning Collective course, you should already have an email waiting for you with instructions for how you can access your course’s private chat room. (New students will get a similar message near the start of their own course.) We intend for this new offering to augment our already highly social and Socratic pedagogy by providing opportunities for gatherings like virtual “office hours” for students to interact with one another as well as their instructor(s) in between classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also recognize that many already under-resourced organizations are facing immense pressure to “go virtual” and collaborate with colleagues and constituents completely online. This is why we feel that our decision to begin facilitating live chat and to offer these resources for free to interested members of the public is the next logical step in &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic.html&quot;&gt;our committment to do what we can to support our community&lt;/a&gt; during this extended period of social distancing and other hardships. Although we don’t have the resources necessary for making this a round-the-clock operation, our small teaching team will be taking turns moderating the public channel and doing their best to answer whatever technical questions you have on a volunteer basis (within reasonable limits, of course). If you’d like to support us in this, please consider &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;making a donation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you’ll stop by and say hello to us, and one another, soon! See you at an &lt;a href=&quot;/events/upcoming/&quot;&gt;upcoming webinar&lt;/a&gt; or, now, in the community chat!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Tech Learning Collective is pleased to invite you to our new community chat channels. Current and former students also now have access to private chat channels for staying in touch with their classmates even after their course ends. The semi-moderated public rooms are part of our continuing effort to integrate distance learning opportunities for the general public during the global response to the COVID-19 healthcare emergency.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.chat-rooms-chat-bubbles.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.chat-rooms-chat-bubbles.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">One way we’re doing what we can to support our community during the coronavirus pandemic</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One way we're doing what we can to support our community during the coronavirus pandemic" /><published>2020-03-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic.html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, we at Tech Learning Collective were busy &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/02/28/introducing-live-instruction-webinars-and-free-online-practice-labs.html&quot; title=&quot;Read our webinar introduction announcement.&quot;&gt;adapting&lt;/a&gt; our in-person donation-based and low-cost computer training classes designed for people who are underrepresented in the tech sector to an online training format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; spurred to do this because of coronavirus (we started this process before anyone had heard of the pandemic), but we’re writing now to remind you about it in light of these recent events. Unfortunately, many of our peer groups who do similar work teaching underprivileged people about computer technology have cancelled their events, closed continuing education classrooms, or postponed their educational meetings. Due to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20200315184949/https://www.nypl.org/about/coronavirus&quot;&gt;closure of NY Public Libraries&lt;/a&gt;, for instance, numerous community groups no longer have meeting spaces available to them. It is sad to see so many noble efforts curtailed this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While they have been doing their best to transition to an online learning model, Tech Learning Collective was fortunate in that we began this transition quite a while ago and so we were unexpectedly prepared for the ramifications of “social distancing” without even intending to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that for over two months now, Tech Learning Collective has more than quadrupled the number of total events we run, and we’re continuing to increase our online student capacity every week. We’ve also lowered prices across the board, making it even easier for people who otherwise would not have a chance to get started learning about computer technology or online digital safety to do so affordably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We figured that as New York City and other municipalities begin to further enforce closures of public spaces, and as bars, restaurants, cafes, and other community centers are voluntarily closing to help &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2020/world/corona-simulator/&quot;&gt;flatten the epidemic peak&lt;/a&gt; of COVID-19 and assist our healthcare system in supporting all the people who may need urgent medical care, many people may be experiencing changing social dynamics as they spend more time at home and away from friends, peers, or colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, a climate of fear is ripe for abuse, and that’s exactly what we’ve seen happen. Earlier this week, malware authors have started taking advantage of the panic by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibtimes.com/russians-hack-johns-hopkins-coronavirus-map-steal-user-information-2939424&quot;&gt;working coronavirus information into phishing campaigns&lt;/a&gt; designed to steal personal information and compromise computer accounts. This makes it even more important for individuals to keep their guard up when clicking on links in social media, email, and other remote communications, something that isn’t always easy to remember in times of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of this, we have chosen to &lt;em&gt;further&lt;/em&gt; increase the rate of our online events and, for the foreseeable future, our teaching staff has volunteered to facilitate repeats of workshops across different times of the day and on weekends in order to provide more activities (and, admittedly, some distraction) for anyone who feels up for it. In particular, we are partnering with more groups to host our “&lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Gone-Phishing-How-to-Recognize-Fake-Websites-and-Other-Online-Scams&quot;&gt;Gone Phishing&lt;/a&gt;” awareness training and are preparing additional learning modules that we plan to host for free as part of our open-access Foundations courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Foundations courses, which we are accelerating our work on, is our series of completely free, self-paced, in-browser digital security exercises. You can go through them without ever leaving your Web browser. A couple of these modules are already published on our Web site, and we hope to add more in the coming weeks. You can find them, day or night, on &lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/&quot;&gt;our Web site’s “Foundations” page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please consider joining us for any of &lt;a href=&quot;/events/upcoming/&quot;&gt;these events&lt;/a&gt;, and telling anyone in your social network who feels restless, is having trouble due to cabin fever, or otherwise wants to take the opportunity to spend a couple of hours taking a break from reading the news about our remote workshop options. We’re also happy to extend further discounts on a case-by-case basis. If you have any questions, &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; via email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;/events/&quot;&gt;a full schedule of our online events, including event details, see our Web site’s “Events” page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, of course, if you have any additional ideas for how we can work together to help make the next couple of months easier, please don’t hesitate to reach out about that as well. Take care, give care.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Earlier this year, we at Tech Learning Collective were busy adapting our in-person donation-based and low-cost computer training classes designed for people who are underrepresented in the tech sector to an online training format.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.laptop-table-for-bed.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.laptop-table-for-bed.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing live instruction webinars and free online practice labs</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/02/28/introducing-live-instruction-webinars-and-free-online-practice-labs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing live instruction webinars and free online practice labs" /><published>2020-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/02/28/introducing-live-instruction-webinars-and-free-online-practice-labs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/02/28/introducing-live-instruction-webinars-and-free-online-practice-labs.html">&lt;p&gt;At the end of last year, we invited the Tech Learning Collective community to our year-end conference, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/&quot;&gt;Hackers Next
Door&lt;/a&gt;. It was an &lt;em&gt;incredible&lt;/em&gt; event, with over 100 participants and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/2019/speakers/&quot;&gt;more than 25 speakers&lt;/a&gt; who inspired and challenged us to find new and more effective ways to build power in our communities. After a much needed break to recuperate but also to celebrate, our team is back with an expanded lineup of workshops and events, and more opportunities than ever before for you to take your skills to the next level, with remote/virtual/online-only webinars on topics like &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Collaboration-Across-Universes-Basics-of-Version-Control-with-Git&quot;&gt;collaboration with Git&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Taming-Daemons-System-Administration-and-Operation-Basics&quot;&gt;system administration basics&lt;/a&gt;, and more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-webinar-remote-workshops&quot;&gt;New Webinar (Remote) Workshops&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One unexpected but wonderful thing about the Hackers Next Door conference was how many people came to New York just for our event!  Attendees arrived from places such as Michigan and Colorado and as far away as California. And although the conference still focused on the local issues facing New Yorkers, with speakers from advocacy groups such as the Atlantic Plaza Towers Tenants Association who are fighting the installation of racist facial recognition software in their apartment complex, these otherwise “remote” attendees brought value and perspective all their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, we regularly heard from folks that they would love more opportunities to participate in Tech Learning Collective events, if only they could find the time or, y’know, lived in New York City in the first place! Well, we’ve been working hard to harvest two carrots with one fist (and stop throwing stones at birds). That’s why you’re invited to our upcoming workshop webinars!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective workshop webinars are 100% online events. There are no physical classrooms and so there’s nowhere you need to go, and no need to find clean clothes! Although, y’know, maybe wear clean clothes regardless. Anyway! All you need is access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of Google Chrome or Mozilla Firefox along with a fast Internet connection. In other words, if you can Netflix ’n’ chill, you have all the equipment you need to level up your h4x0r skill by attending a Tech Learning Collective webinar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like all our in-person events, our webinars are facilitated by our team of technical experts and expert teachers. This means that when you sign up, you’ll be joining a video conference with a human instructor, not a bot or a dated recording. You’ll be able to interact with the instructor via voice and video as well as with other students to tackle challenges, solve problems, and learn together. The bi-directional, real-time screen sharing options makes it easy to follow along as the instructor demonstrates how to do things like &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Clearing-Away-the-Clouds-How-Computer-Networks,-Servers,-and-the-Internet-Work&quot;&gt;sniff packets&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/The-Web-as-a-Language-What-No-One-Ever-Told-You-About-HTML-That-You-Didn't-Know-to-Ask&quot;&gt;create Web sites&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/The-Imitation-Game-Introduction-to-Administering-Virtual-Machine-Systems&quot;&gt;manage virtual machines&lt;/a&gt;, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just as with our in-person events, we’ve retained our tiered pricing structure to help ensure queer-identified, femme, PoC, and other people who have traditionally been overlooked in the tech sector have access, too. What’s more, since our own overhead is lower for webinars than they are for physical venues, we’ve decided to pass these savings on to you by dropping the price of tickets for our “remote” events by almost 30% across each price tier. There’s never been a better or less expensive way to learn the foundations of computer technology as solidly as this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;/events/&quot;&gt;our events page&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/events/upcoming/#export-event-calendar&quot;&gt;subscribe to our calendar&lt;/a&gt; to see what workshops we have coming up and to sign up for access. For more information, consult our &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;Workshops and Webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-self-paced-beginners-courses&quot;&gt;Free, Self-paced Beginner’s Courses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of learning the foundations of computer technology, we’ve also been hard at work preparing our first ever self-paced course that we’re calling the &lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s Foundations&lt;/a&gt; series. This is a series of introductory learning modules that you can use to jump-start your learing before you ever join us at one of our events, because they are all offered via our Web site. This means the Foundations courses are available anytime, day or night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s more, since we’ve designed our Foundations series to be entirely self-paced, we’re offering the whole course completely free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our Foundations series is free and always available, you can take as long as you need to work through it. Start with our &lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/#foundations-command-line-basics&quot;&gt;Foundations: Command Line Basics&lt;/a&gt; course, which introduces you to a computer terminal, one of the most important foundations of the rest of our curriculum. We’re launching with a limited selection of free materials, but are planning to expand the free courses with more labs over time, so check back regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-practice-labs-of-advanced-scenarios&quot;&gt;Free Practice Labs of Advanced Scenarios&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’ve decided to reuse the same infrastructure we deployed for our self-paced courses to put together some more bite-sized learning modules of additional, more advanced scenarios such as &lt;a href=&quot;/sample/scaling-ssh-authentication-with-certificates.html&quot;&gt;Scaling SSH Authentication with Certificates&lt;/a&gt;. If you’ve been on the fence about whether or not you should come to one of our instructor-led workshop trainings or have questions about the kind of material we teach in our intensive courses, you can try your hand at these sample scenarios to get a taste for the rest of our curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, nothing can compare to learning directly from a teacher whom you can actually see and ask questions of in real time. That’s why we’re looking forward to continuing to partner with groups around New York City to expand our in-person training, and invite you or your organization to &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; about booking a private group training for your volunteers or colleagues. In the mean time, though, we hope that these self-paced learning modules will whet your appetite until your next (or first) class with us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Tech Learning Collective is excited to offer free, self-paced beginner courses along with new webinar workshops that make it easier than ever before to level up your h4x0r skillz. If you can Netflix &amp;lsquo;n&amp;rsquo; chill, you have all the equipment you need to participate in a webinar and tackle technical problems with our team of technical experts and expert teachers. Learn more about our free online &amp;ldquo;Foundations&amp;rdquo; curriculum series and our new webinar events in this post.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured-image.webinars.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured-image.webinars.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>