<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2020-06-03T18:38:52-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective awarded in EFA 2019 Activity Challenge, then interviewed by EFF</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/06/01/tech-learning-collective-awarded-in-efa-2019-activity-challenge-interviewed-by-eff.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tech Learning Collective awarded in EFA 2019 Activity Challenge, then interviewed by EFF" /><published>2020-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/06/01/tech-learning-collective-awarded-in-efa-2019-activity-challenge-interviewed-by-eff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/06/01/tech-learning-collective-awarded-in-efa-2019-activity-challenge-interviewed-by-eff.html">&lt;p&gt;Back in April 2020, Tech Learning Collective was informed that we were one of three Electronic Frontier Alliance member groups to win the Electronic Frontier Foundation’s 2019 “Activity Challenge.” We were unaware of the challenge because we had &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/08/13/joining-the-electronic-frontier-alliance.html&quot;&gt;submitted our application for EFA membership very late into the year, on August 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, so this award came as a pleasant surprise. It meant that Tech Learning Collective had produced enough events—twelve, by EFA organizer’s count—in a mere four months to earn our place as the group with the second highest number of events recognized by the EFA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our fellow New Yorkers, the CyPurr Collective, who have been EFA members for numerous years, narrowly beat us out by one EFA-recognized event. Their total was 13 events, spread across the full twelve months. We would like to take the opportunity to congratulate the CyPurr Collective on their 2019 Activity Challenge victory! We’re very proud to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/electronic-frontier-alliance/allies#region-eastern&quot;&gt;represent our hometown of New York City in the top two slots for this challenge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even more recently, as part of a follow up to the EFA 2019 Activity Challenge, Tech Learning Collective was excited to be interviewed by EFF EFA organizers for a feature profile that is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/06/tech-learning-collective-grassroots-technology-school-case-study&quot;&gt;now published on the EFF Deeplinks blog&lt;/a&gt; in an abridged version edited for length. The profile is part of their blog series highlighting grassroots groups educating communities about digital safety and online privacy. The series has already featured CyPurr Collective and CryptoParty Ann Arbor, who were both in attendance at &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/11/01/press-release-hackers-next-door-2019.html&quot;&gt;our recent Hackers Next Door 2019 conference&lt;/a&gt; at the end of last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full interview was conducted over email in early May 2020 but was shortened for publication on the EFF Deeplinks blog, so we have reprinted it in full here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;do-you-have-any-requests-for-your-introductory-section&quot;&gt;Do you have any requests for your introductory section?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Here is the current boilerplate text about Tech Learning Collective that we ask other groups to use when writing about us. Feel free to trim this down if needed:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school for radical organizers headquartered in New York City that provides a security-first IT infrastructure curriculum to otherwise underserved communities and organizations advancing social justice causes. We train politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Founded and operated exclusively by radical queer and femme technologists, we offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies).&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Our students are primarily people of marginalized groups and other individuals who are politically engaged. Unlike coding bootcamps that focus on moving the highest number of students through rote memorization exercises for the goal of job placement, Tech Learning Collective teachers facilitate foundational skill building through Socratic discussion and kinetic, experience-based training.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;what-inspired-you-all-to-start-the-tech-learning-collective-how-has-the-group-changed-over-time&quot;&gt;What inspired you all to start the Tech Learning Collective? How has the group changed over time?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In 2016, a group of anarchist and autonomist radicals met in Brooklyn, NY to seek out methods of mutual self-education around technology. Many of us did not have backgrounds in computer technology. What we did have was background in justice movement organizing at one point or another, whether at the WTO protests before the turn of the century, supporting whistleblowers such as Chelsea Manning, participating in Occupy Wall Street, or in various other campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This first version of Tech Learning Collective met regularly for about a year as a semi-private mutual-education project. It succeeded in sewing the seeds of what would later become several additional justice-oriented technology groups. None of the members were formally trained technologists. None of us have ever held computer science degrees. Many of the traditional techniques of and environments offering technology education felt alienating to us.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, everyone involved recognized the transformative and astonishingly powerful capacities that modern digital technologies could have in the hands of people whose focus is ethics and justice rather than profit—exactly the opposite ethos as that enacted by Silicon Valley, despite their claims to “make the world a better place.” So, after a (surprisingly short!) period of mutual self-education, we began offering free workshops and classes on computer technologies specifically for Left-leaning politically engaged individuals and groups. Our goal was to advocate for more effective use of these technologies in our movement organizing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We quickly learned that courses needed to cater to people with skill levels ranging from self-identified “beginners” to very experienced technologists, and that our efforts needed to be self-sustaining. Partly, this was because many of our comrades had sworn off technical self-sufficiency as a legitimate avenue for liberation in a misguided but understandable reaction to the poisonous prevalence of machismo, knowledge grandstanding, and blatant sociopathy they saw exhibited by the overwhelming majority of “techies.” It was obvious that our trainers needed to exemplify a totally new culture to show them that cyber power, not just computer literacy, was a capability worth investing their time in for the sake of The Movement™.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Following the 2016 US Presidential election, Tech Learning Collective members dispersed into a number of urgent community projects, but the need to offer high quality technology education to groups and individuals engaged in radical, grassroots, and non-profit work remained. Then in early 2019, and now engaged in numerous different new groups, several of us worked to loosely codify a curriculum development and student mentoring process that we had experienced ourselves be dramatically more effective at “upskilling” interested students than those provided by code bootcamps, digital vocational training, and other employment-centric initiatives. This lived experience of contrasting the different pedagogies convinced us to form what is now Tech Learning Collective’s free, by-donation, and low-cost educational efforts in our existing formats.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today, Tech Learning Collective continues offering exceptional Information Technology (IT) educational opportunities at a much lower cost than traditional computer courses (free, in some cases!) and provides supplementary funding for the existent activist projects that grew out of the first version of Tech Learning Collective meetings in the mid 2010’s. In keeping with our original mission, Tech Learning Collective is especially in service to people who might identify themselves as being “outsiders” to the mainstream “tech world.” That is, we are primarily invested in those folks who have either never been tech workers or who have otherwise felt at odds with the general culture of technocapitalism, its tech bros, and its monocultural intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s singular overarching goal is to provide its students with the knowledge and abilities to liberate their communities from corporate and government overseers, especially as it relates to owning and operating their own information and communications infrastructures, which we view as a necessary prerequisite for meaningful revolutionary actions. Using these skills, our students assist in the organization of activist work like abortion access and reproductive rights, anti-surveillance organizing, and other efforts that help build collective power beyond mere (“voter”) representation.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;One thing that hasn’t changed over the years is that, at Tech Learning Collective, students learn how to extend and enhance the existing capabilities of their projects and communities using free, open, and increasingly ubiquitous digital technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;who-is-your-target-audience&quot;&gt;Who is your target audience?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Anyone who is serious about gaining the skills, knowledge, and power they need to materially improve the lives of their community, neighbors, and friends and who also shares our pro-social values is welcome at our workshops and events. This means we take political stances including anti-capitalism, feminism, queer rights, trans liberation, anti-racism, animal liberation, environmental justice, and other social justice causes extremely seriously. Tech Learning Collective instructors make a point to embed these values in all of our workshops (“it’s a machine-in-the-middle, not necessarily man-in-the-middle”), and all of our workshop materials use examples relevant to political organizing scenarios as the basis for practice labs and other exercises (“if ‘you are part of the Rebel Alliance and a traitor,’ how will you communicate safely such that the Empire does not catch you?”).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Another way to say this is that we are uninterested in teaching people who have a lot of access to other, more mainstream technology education. If you often enjoy your downtown IT or tech Meetup group, you probably won’t find Tech Learning Collective classes comfortable. Although thankfully rare, we have occasionally had to ban some people (mostly men) for taking up too much space in classrooms, or people who seem more interested in learning just enough basic tech to begin a startup regardless of their self-identification. We are not shy about doing this because we are a grassroots political group first and a technology school second, not the other way around like basically all other professional-level tech training options out there right now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;There are dozens upon dozens of places you can go to learn how to memorize the answers to interview questions, get a tech certification, or pigeonhole yourself into a career path. Folks interested in that kind of activity just don’t last very long as Tech Learning Collective apprentices or students because we’re not putting down what they want to pick up.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-some-steps-you-take-to-ensure-your-work-is-accessible-to-people-without-a-background-in-tech&quot;&gt;What are some steps you take to ensure your work is accessible to people without a background in tech?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Making our workshops and other events accessible to people without a background in tech is actually really easy for us because both our materials and our methodology actually begins at the beginning. We know that’s something a lot of people say they’re doing but, to be blunt, we simply don’t see it happening a lot outside of Tech Learning Collective classes and workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We know what it’s like to wade into the world of digital security as a novice because we’ve all done it at one point or another. Some of us did it as recently as a year or so ago. We felt confounded or overwhelmed by the vast amount of information suddenly thrown at us. Worse, much of this information purported to be “for beginners,” making us feel even worse about our apparent inability to understand it. ‘Are we just stupid?’, we often asked ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;No. The reality is that these self-proclaimed “beginner” resources are either wildly self-referential, full of assumptions of prior knowledge, or just simply bad explanations that are incoherent at best. Often, the security resources you’ll find when you do an Internet search are all three of these things.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You are not stupid. Digital security is genuinely hard. Look, most people just don’t teach cybersecurity well, if they even bother to focus on teaching in the first place. We insist that you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; understand this stuff. It’s just that, most of the time, you’re being shown a scattershot, piecemeal presentation coming through a human filter who, often, isn’t deeply familiar with the material in the first place. Given that, is it any wonder this stuff seems damn near impossible to learn?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The real reason it often feels like you’re having a hard time understanding what the teachers at a cybersecurity class are trying to show you is that they don’t know how to explain what they’re doing. In fact, most of the time, they don’t even &lt;em&gt;show&lt;/em&gt; you anything at all, preferring instead to discuss how something &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; work in some hypothetical scenario  rather than showing you, right then and there on their computer screen, how it &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; works in real life today. Very often, these classes and events offer nothing more than slideshows containing oversimplified diagrams after a rundown asserting that the teacher holds some credentials, even though none of those credentials are “Masters of Education.” Too often, they never even actually show the technology being discussed, which we think is just absurd.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In contrast, Tech Learning Collective classes are dramatically more interactive, which makes them far more digestible and approachable for actual beginners as well as experienced technologists both. Our methodology focuses almost exclusively on providing guided, kinetic, experience-based training in fully-fledged, real-life scenarios using physical hardware, cloud environments, or both. There are never slideshows, which means it feels less like a business meeting and more like watching an episode of Mr. Robot with the director’s commentary on.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Best of all, our pedagogy is intentionally Socratic, which means our teachers repeatedly engage students with questions and challenges in real-time. We do this because we know you can watch a slideshow, read the manual, or run through the practice lab on your own time. It’s very obvious that the best use of our time together is to do what humans do best; converse, question, and mimic one another. This means everyone always gets a lot out of class time precisely because it avoids the all-too-common situation where one person runs into an error and everyone else has to wait for the troubleshooting to end before the class can resume.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We regularly receive feedback from students who have little to no background as technologists expressing surprise that they learned as much as they did as quickly as they did. But don’t take our word for it: have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://techlearningcollective.com/testimonials/&quot;&gt;our Testimonials page&lt;/a&gt; to see for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;last-winter-you-hosted-the-hackers-next-door-conference-in-nyc-could-you-tell-us-about-how-you-approached-such-an-ambitious-and-collaborative-project-were-there-any-surprises-along-the-way&quot;&gt;Last Winter you hosted the Hackers Next Door conference in NYC, could you tell us about how you approached such an ambitious and collaborative project? Were there any surprises along the way?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com&quot;&gt;Hackers Next Door&lt;/a&gt; was an incredible event, with over 25 speakers and two full days of workshops and talks. Unfortunately, we dramatically underestimated its popularity and as a result quickly ran out of capacity at our 100 person venue. In fact, we had to enlist several friends to act as bouncers as we realized that we would have to more strictly enforce our no-walk-in policy simply out of respect for our hosts and safety concerns at the space. So, until recently, Hackers Next Door was the largest event we ever facilitated. (We recently held an online event called Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour that more than doubled Hackers Next Door’s registration numbers.)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Although it did take a lot of coordination between teams (and, really, our core team went above and beyond the call of duty, personally hauling equipment like loudspeakers on the NYC Subway late into the night), we didn’t do anything particularly special to make the event happen. The biggest hurdle was simply coordinating with speakers, ensuring that all the confirmed speakers were given a time slot that they liked, and making sure that any special requests were taken care of.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Most of the coordination tasks were extremely well-regimented. Communication happened in a bulk and automated fashion. This just means we wrote email templates as the needs arose, and then sent out notices to the speaker or ticket holder lists via mail merge so everyone had the correct information about their specific session or ticket details. This is the kind of thing spreadsheets and computers have been doing since the 60’s and 70’s.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, we think a lot of other groups could (should?) be making events like Hackers Next Door happen a lot more frequently, even with small organizing teams like ours. This message, that small groups of well-organized and skilled individuals can punch way above their weight, was what we hoped to have folks take away from their experience. The event itself was simply proof that it could be done in very little time, with very little money, and with few pre-existing resources.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;the-tlc-is-incredibly-active-with-an-impressive-15-events-planned-for-may-and-even-more-in-june-how-does-your-group-share-this-workload-and-avoid-burnout-among-collective-members&quot;&gt;The TLC is incredibly active, with an impressive 15 events planned for May (and even more in June). How does your group share this workload and avoid burnout among collective members?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;There are three primary techniques we use to do this. These will be familiar to anyone who has ever worked in an office or held a position in management. They are: automation, separation of concerns, and partnerships. After all, just because we are anti-capitalist does not mean we ignore the obviously effective tools and techniques we have at our disposal for realizing our goals.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The first pillar, automation, is really what we are all about. It’s what almost all of our classes teach in one form or another. In a Tech Learning Collective class, you will often hear the phrase, “If you ever do one thing on a computer twice, you’ve made a mistake the second time.” This is a reminder that computers were built for automation. That’s what they’re for. So, almost every component of Tech Learning Collective’s day-to-day operations are automated. This includes updating the Web site, publishing new events to the calendar, sending out Webinar access details to registered guests, adding (or removing) members from our various teams, syndicating (cross-posting) events to partner sites, and more. The only time a human needs to be involved is when another human wants to talk to us. Otherwise, the emails you’re getting from us were written many months ago and are being generated by scripts and templates.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Secondly, separation of concerns: this is both a management and a security technique. In InfoSec, we call this the compartmentalization principle. You might be familiar with it as “need to know,” and it states that only the people who need to be concerned with a certain thing should have to spend any brainpower on it in the first place, or indeed have any access to it at all. This means that when one of our teachers wants to host a workshop, they don’t need to involve anyone else in the collective. They are autonomous, free to act however they wish within the limits of their role. This makes it possible for our collective members to dip in and out whenever they need to, thus avoiding burnout while increasing quality. If one of us has to step away for a while, the collective can still function smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This kind of separation of concerns probably wouldn’t be possible without the automation we’ve put in place to automate the minutia of daily operations. Without that, we would need to at least double if not triple or quadruple the number of people who could devote many hours to managing the logistics of making sure events happen. But that’s boring, tedious, repetitive work, and that’s what computers are for.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Finally, partnerships allow us to do things we could not do on our own. This also helps distribute the overarching workload, like creating practice labs or writing educational materials for new workshops. We work extremely closely with a number of other groups, which is possible because of our unique history in which our core collective members straddle several other activist and educational collectives. For example, one of our curriculum partners is Anarcho-Tech NYC, a collective of self-proclaimed anarchist hackers who provide digital security services for anti-fascist groups in New York City, with whom we collaborate on the bulk of our cybersecurity curriculum. This makes it feasible for us to take advantage of their work, while simultaneously supporting their efforts. It also means our teachers and, more importantly, our students have access to a much wider range of alumni opportunities than they would otherwise have had if we didn’t actively seek out and explore new partnership opportunities like these.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;at-the-time-of-writing-we-are-in-the-middle-of-the-covid-19-health-crisis-many-groups-are-struggling-with-shelter-in-place-but-fortunately-tlc-seems-to-have-adapted-very-well-what-are-some-strategies-you-are-employing-to-continue-your-work&quot;&gt;At the time of writing, we are in the middle of the COVID-19 health crisis. Many groups are struggling with shelter-in-place, but fortunately TLC seems to have adapted very well. What are some strategies you are employing to continue your work?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is almost an unfair question, because the nature of what we do at Tech Learning Collective lends itself well to the current crises.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The biggest change that the COVID-19 pandemic has forced us to adapt to is the shuttering of our usual venues for in-person workshops. Fortunately, we were already ramping up our online and distance learning options even before the pandemic. So we simply put that into high gear. The easily automatable nature of handling logistics for online events also made it possible to do many more of them, which is one reason you’re seeing so much more activity from us these days. The other reason, quite bluntly, is that a lot more people are finally willing to give online events a chance, making it far more worth our time to put them on.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But also, there is widespread agreement within our collective that many effective strategies for organizing, or for continuing with daily work tasks, have actually &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; changed because of the pandemic. Yes, there is huge value in physical events and other in-person efforts, and obviously there is a whole class of labor that simply cannot be done entirely online. After all, this is exactly why “essential workers” are called essential; you may be able to order groceries over the Internet, but you can’t eat them off your laptop screen. That being said, it’s clear to us that the organizing strategies of the 90’s and the mass protest movements of the Occupy Wall Street era have proven largely ineffective against the neoliberal plague sickening society today, and that most white-collar “jobs” are, to paraphrase David Graeber, anthropologist and author of the 2018 book “Bullshit Jobs,” little more than a means of greasing the wheels of capitalist machinery which serves no ethical purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Even before COVID-19 became the nightmare scenario that it has, we knew that effective political organizing required safe and secure telecommunication capabilities. The NSA, FBI, and CIA were spying on Americans long before 9/11 (COINTELPRO anyone?), much less before Zoom meetings became the de-facto “new normal.” And so, just as the Trump election in 2016 finally woke many people up to the things that privacy advocates have been saying for decades (“it’s not about whether you have something to hide, or whether you trust this government, it’s about whether you trust the &lt;em&gt;next&lt;/em&gt; administration”), we are seeing many people who have been under shelter-in-place orders finally wake up to other aspects of this reality that has already been with us for far too long.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In certain ways, for many in our collective, this “new normal” is actually a rather dated 90’s-era cyberpunk dystopia that we’ve been experiencing for many, many years. In that sense, we’re happy that you don’t have to enter this reality alone and defenseless. We kinda built Tech Learning Collective for exactly this scenario. We want to help you thrive here.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;finally-what-does-the-future-look-like-for-tlc&quot;&gt;Finally, what does the future look like for TLC?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We’re not sure! When we started TLC, we never thought it would end up becoming an online, international, radical political hacker school. In just the last two months since we’ve been forced to become a wholly virtual organization, we’ve held classes with students from Japan, Italy, New Zealand, London, Mexico, and beyond, as well as many parts of the United States of course. Many of them are now repeat participants working their way through our entire curriculum, which is the best compliment we could have asked for. We hope they’ll stick around to join our growing alumni community after that. We’re also (slowly) expanding our “staff” outside of New York City, which isn’t something we thought would happen for many years, if at all.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So we’re excited about the possibilities of the future, even as we recognize the horrific state of the present situation. We would like to make new partnerships. We would like to hold more social events. For example, we loved the several Shift-CTRL Space “queer hacker parties” that we got to make some cool tech for and some in our crew are trying to figure out what the best way to replicate or even enhance that experience entirely online would be.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But right now, we’re primarily focused on moving the rest of our in-person curriculum online and creating new online workshops. Many of the workshops unveiled this month or planned for next month are new, like our workshops on writing shell scripts, exploiting Web applications, auditing firewalls and other network perimeter defenses, and an exciting “spellwork” workshop to learn about the “spirits” that live on in the magical place inside every computer called the Command Line. So in the near future, expect to see more workshops like these, as well as more of our self-paced “&lt;a href=&quot;https://techlearningcollective.com/foundations/&quot;&gt;Foundations&lt;/a&gt;” learning modules that you can try out anytime for free right in your Web browser from our Web site.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;After that? Well, some say another world is possible. We’re hackers. Hacking is about showing people what’s possible, especially if they insist it could never happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">In four months&amp;rsquo; time during 2019, Tech Learning Collective produced twelve (12!) free or by-donation digital privacy training events for community groups and grassroots activists recognized by Electronic Frontier Alliance organizers. Only our fellow New Yorkers, the CyPurr Collective, held more events (13 events spread across the full 12 months), narrowly edging us out of first place. Later, we were interviewed by EFF organizers for a featured profile now published in an abridged form on the EFF Deeplinks blog. This post contains the complete unabridged interview.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/tlc-efa.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/tlc-efa.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hacker Trivia Night benefit weekend wraps with reminder for need of revolutionary education in revolutionary times</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/31/hacker-trivia-night-benefit-weekend-wraps-with-reminder-for-need-of-revolutionary-education-in-revolutionary-times.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hacker Trivia Night benefit weekend wraps with reminder for need of revolutionary education in revolutionary times" /><published>2020-05-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/31/hacker-trivia-night-benefit-weekend-wraps-with-reminder-for-need-of-revolutionary-education-in-revolutionary-times</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/31/hacker-trivia-night-benefit-weekend-wraps-with-reminder-for-need-of-revolutionary-education-in-revolutionary-times.html">&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective, with its educational mission, has roots dating back before the current American neo-fascist government was voted into power by a minority of American citizens. Before we came together to create Tech Learning Collective, our members have been at Occupy Wall Street encampments, running &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;digital security workshops&lt;/a&gt; about anti-surveillance tools like TextSecure, which you may recognize today as &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal Private Messenger&lt;/a&gt;. Others in our collective have been steering committee members for internationally-connected social centers, supported street medic operations in numerous American cities, and more. What makes us a collective is that all of us are convinced that the next chapter of the global movement for justice will end tragically if the movement as a whole does not dramatically and immediately invest in digital infrastructure education with a competency and urgency like never before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re doing our part as best we can by responding to rapidly shifting priorities with one eye on our short-term goals of the present moment, and the other firmly trained on our long-term goals. What are those goals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the short term: Nurture our existing students through workshops and other &lt;a href=&quot;/events/calendar/&quot;&gt;educational opportunities&lt;/a&gt; such as &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/05/event-2020-05-29-hacker-trivia-night-restaurant-and-bar-night&quot;&gt;the recent Hacker Trivia Night&lt;/a&gt; so that they become capable of administering enterprise-grade, world-class, state-of-the-art Information Technology systems in support of the existing projects they are already involved in or to support the residents of the neighborhoods they currently live in.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the medium term: Deploy and operate collectively-owned resilient critical telecom and other digital infrastructure supported by former students. Spread digital competencies in an “each one teach one” and “pay it forward” approach in which trainers train other trainers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the long term: smash the State, destroy capitalism, abolish globalized oppression inflicted by government, corporate, institutional, and interpersonal violence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/2020-05-hacker-trivia-night-liberate_United-States.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Hacker Trivia Night challenge: &amp;ldquo;You get a disappearing Signal message from your friend informing you of a new &amp;lsquo;alt-right&amp;rsquo; group whose website claims it is active in your neighborhood. Your friend wants to know the legal identities of the site operators. What is the first tool you run?&amp;rdquo;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given our approach, it’s no surprise we believe that one of the most effective ways to get there from here is to train politically motivated people who already share our ethics and commitment to anti-racism, feminism, police and prison abolition, ecological justice, and other critical issues in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and, yes, defensive and offensive cyber-warfare techniques. (Importantly, we have little to no faith in the political commitments of most existing and often quite liberal “Tech for Social Good” movements, although we would be fools not to accept their material contributions and financial donations.) We know this is a tall order, because these skills take time to develop, and also because organized, politicized efforts to teach these skills came slower and later than they should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fact is, technologies that governments all over the globe deem to be cyberweapons have already been firing at civilians for decades. The only reason resistance was not louder sooner is because, unlike lead or rubber bullets, electronic bullets don’t bruise bodies. At least, not directly. Indirectly, however, they are a critical enabler of mass social control, making it possible for the rich to keep justice away from the poor, from women, from queer and trans people, and particularly from Black and brown people in this country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, as we’ve seen time and time again, ballot boxes on their own don’t result in justice. Politicians simply ratify unjust laws written by lobbyists and police unions. More distressingly, adding laws of our own to the existing political system &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t result in justice, either. Authorities simply ignore the laws, hide their actions to avoid prosecution, or blatantly rewrite them. Not even the lofty concept of democracy, which is the fundamentally and fatally flawed idea of majority rule, does not result in justice. Things are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; going to fundamentally change for the better under a regime of “one person one vote” anymore than it would under the current “one dollar one vote” system the USA has today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/2020-05-hacker-trivia-night-liberate_Australia.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Hacker Trivia Night challenge: &amp;ldquo;Between the dates of January 1, 2015 and May 29, 2020 how many people are known to have been killed by police officers across the United States?&amp;rdquo;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an undeniable challenge, and we think there are many different good approaches we can take to addressing it. That’s why our goal is not to implement or even advocate for a specific approach, but rather to empower you to take actions you feel are appropriate backed, supported, and enabled by the awesomely potent power of the digital devices you already use every day. That computer you’re using to read this very post is arguably your most powerful asset because it—and it uniquely—can be both your pen and your sword at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend, as protests against yet another murderer with a badge were held around the country and around the world, we went forward with our Hacker Trivia Night event in the hopes that participants new to cybersecurity would get a taste of what competent digital dexterity might feel like for them. We never feel able to pin this feeling down with words, so we were happy to see that one of our fellow Electronic Frontier Alliance member groups, DEFCON 201, recorded themselves participating in the event and provided a fantastic and fun introduction to Tech Learning Collective, along with a brief orientation to Hacker Trivia Night, for their own membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than try to recreate the experience in words, we present the first (minimally edited) ten minutes or so of their recording:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/DC201 introduces TLC and Hacker Trivia Night.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/DC201 introduces TLC and Hacker Trivia Night.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as with each prior crisis, we’re seeing renewed interest in digital safety and security as more people recognize both how much more powerful control over digital infrastructure can make their campaigns as well as how central digital security culture is to the success of movement organizing. We’re honored to have been spoken of so highly by our fellow EFA member group, and we look forward to continuing to facilitate educational opportunities on cybersecurity and other IT infrastructure topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must recognize that the American State is a country whose Revolutionary War was premised on the protection of profits for its rich through the Trans-Atlantic Slave Trade. A country that was originally colonized through intentional, barbaric, continental-wide genocide. These are histories it continually seeks to downplay or whitewash, when justice demands exactly the opposite. Since its founding, the American government has made clear time and time again, over more than four centuries of indiscriminate, unaccountable, monstrous oppression, that they will cede &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; (even while they promise everything) without a demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Americans who have sat comfortably in the pot of slowly heating water that the capitalist class prepared for them are now seeing physical weapons once reserved for foreign wars sweep down residential streets. We once again find our firm but peaceful demands for peace, justice, and concrete rather than merely rhetorical equality for Black and brown people met with what would be criminally physical assaults had they not been perpetrated by gangs of badge-wearing executors of white supremacist genocide and terror called the police, an institution invented specifically to combat equality. Some who supported increased funding for either foreign wars or domestic police departments are shocked—shocked!—at the level of physical harm these government-funded legally-protected murderers and abusers in uniform are willing to dole out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all knew they had the weapons. Now we see—yet again—that they’re willing and, in some cases, even eager to use them. We have to become equally ready and able to competently use all the tools available to us: legal, physical, moral, and, once we acquire it, cyber power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s continue training together so that we can bring all our diverse powers to bear against this inhumane and unjust system. All power to the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;44,203 forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/2020-05-hacker-trivia-night-liberate_Egypt.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Hacker Trivia Night challenge: &amp;ldquo;When converted into hexadecimal, the decimal number 44,203 reveals a profound truth. How is the hexadecimal number written?&amp;rdquo;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">The global movement for justice will end tragically if we do not dramatically and immediately invest in digital infrastructure education with a competency and urgency like never before, so we wrapped up our Hacker Trivia Night benefit weekend to support local businesses hit hard by the COVID-19 pandemic with a call to action to ramp up the level of ambition that we have for ourselves in our fight for justice.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/2020-05-hacker-trivia-night-gameboard.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/2020-05-hacker-trivia-night-gameboard.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">As Tech Learning Collective grows, quality is signature of classes and workshops</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/19/as-tech-learning-collective-grows-quality-is-signature-of-classes-and-workshops.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="As Tech Learning Collective grows, quality is signature of classes and workshops" /><published>2020-05-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/19/as-tech-learning-collective-grows-quality-is-signature-of-classes-and-workshops</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/19/as-tech-learning-collective-grows-quality-is-signature-of-classes-and-workshops.html">&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective was &lt;a href=&quot;/about/#our-history&quot;&gt;founded&lt;/a&gt; in an effort to radically increase the cybersecurity effectiveness and other digital capabilities of politically-motivated individuals and groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s incredibly important not to lose sight of larger goals, especially in times of distress. For us at Tech Learning Collective, that means taking stock of how we’re continuing to fulfil our original mission while taking care of ourselves and our communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has always been our intention to find sustainable ways of scaling our educational efforts to more students—increasing &lt;em&gt;quantity&lt;/em&gt;—but we will never feel good about compromising the &lt;em&gt;quality&lt;/em&gt; of a student’s education to achieve that goal. This is particularly relevant for our subject matter, in which quantity &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be delegated to electronic devices and the entire point of education is to make a single, well-trained individual more capable than a hundred untrained operators. &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/07/22/want-to-get-good-with-computers-dont-start-with-code.html&quot;&gt;This stubbornness set us apart from every other code bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; or employment-centric tech education initiative available to potential students since we started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, amid the almost constant bad news coming at us all, we thought we’d take a moment to share some of what’s been going well for us at Tech Learning Collective, and for some of our students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;phenomenal-month-over-month-growth-in-every-area&quot;&gt;Phenomenal month-over-month growth in every area&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective has seen phenomenal month-over-month spikes in student sign-ups, scheduled events, and even workshop offerings ever since March. This has of course coincided with dramatically accelerated online event planning activities. Since we were well-prepared for stay-at-home orders and the sudden surge in demand for Internet video conferencing and remote learning opportunities, we were able to immediately offer many more workshops at much more flexible times during the week, and so we have reached many more students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/post.featured.tech-learning-collective-calendar-2020-05.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a screenshot of our monthly &lt;a href=&quot;/events/calendar/&quot;&gt;calendar&lt;/a&gt; showing our packed schedule from late April through early June. As you can see, we are running (online) workshops or other donation-based events almost every other day now. Our events now vastly outnumber &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; schools who were ranked in Course Report’s “Best Coding Bootcamps 2019–2020” report. Partly, of course, this is because Tech Learning Collective is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a code bootcamp, which means that we provide workshops on topics that include but do not end with or even focus on coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way this new growth can be seen is by simple Web analytics. Although we have never installed any Web bugs or trackers on our Web sites (that means there is no Google Analytics, social media buttons, or any other tracker on any of our pages), our server request logs have shown a sustained upward trajectory of Web traffic for many months running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/post.chart.2020-05-19.cloudflare-web-analytics.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a screenshot of the latest 30-day snapshot covering the period from mid-April 2020 through today (May 19, 2020). In May 2020, we hit 10,000 unique visitors (as measured by Cloudflare) for the month, and while some of this is due to spikes from much larger groups sharing news of our events, the trend is clear and stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet another facet of this growth is to look at where our students are coming from. In 2019, our student population was entirely in New York City because we had no online offerings. While NYC residents are still the majority of our student population, in the last month and a half alone we have welcomed new students from over seven countries including Greece, Spain, Germany, the United Kingdom, Mexico, Japan, and New Zealand, as well as more than ten States ranging from coast to coast within the United States, not including New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To both drive and support this, our small teaching team has been hard at work producing new workshops at breakneck speed. In the past two months alone, we have introduced more than a dozen new &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;online-ready workshops&lt;/a&gt;, as well as additional one-off events that have become several recurring series, such as our &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/04/02/mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour-highlights.html&quot;&gt;wildly popular “Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour” events&lt;/a&gt;. (Our &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/06/event-2020-06-27-mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour&quot;&gt;next Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour will be on June 27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and will also be donation-based.) For a tiny team our size, we feel that this is an astonishing accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things have been so good for Tech Learning Collective as an organization, despite some personal hardships endured by our team members including unemployment and reduced pay or hours at work, that we are slowly beginning to transition apprentices into teaching positions almost a year ahead of schedule. Since everyone at Tech Learning Collective is paid for their time, we were able to support our own collective members through this difficult period in a way that allows us to keep teaching classes. To be blunt, judging by how many other community groups have faced existential crises recently, we are not sure if Tech Learning Collective would have survived without the commitment of our educational team, the skill of our operations team, and the continued participation of our students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And speaking of our students….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;student-retention-and-participation-continues-to-soar&quot;&gt;Student retention and participation continues to soar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that makes Tech Learning Collective so different than code bootcamps, programmer retreats, or certification courses is the unparalleled interactivity and uniqueness of each event, workshop, or course. Thanks to our Socratic pedagogy, there is simply no way other training options can match the quality of a student’s educational experience at a Tech Learning Collective webinar workshop with one of our teachers. As a result, we’ve seen student retention and participation across all skill levels continue to soar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, since January 2020, the average Tech Learning Collective student purchased tickets to 2.58 workshops. But that’s the average, and it turns out that our student retention “bell curve” looks nothing like a bell at all. Here’s a chart showing the mathematical normal distribution of workshop ticket purchases by purchaser since January 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/post.chart.2020-05-19.normal-distribution-of-purchased-tickets.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you’ll notice is that there is a hump between the 2.5 and 4.0 mark. This is because &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; students we’ve had since the start of the calendar year purchased a total of about two and a half tickets. Then there’s a steep drop-off, with very few students buying between between 4 and 6 tickets. But look at that spike over on the right. This shows that a remarkable number of students who attend one workshop return again and again, &lt;em&gt;more than six times in just over four months&lt;/em&gt; to participate in additional workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, since January, while most of our students have attended “only” two and a half paid events, there is a new cadre of students who have so far returned for five, six, and in one comitted student’s case, &lt;em&gt;thirteen&lt;/em&gt; separate webinar workshops. We know of no other tech education experience that is this “sticky,” to use a marketer’s phrase. Moreover, since this data only charts paid events, Tech Learning Collective’s actual retention numbers are even better than depicted here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think the reason Tech Learning Collective workshops are so worth returning to is really pretty simple: we are not focused on marketing! Instead, we make sure that &lt;a href=&quot;/about/#master-more-skills-more-quickly&quot;&gt;students leave class having internalized concepts and principles that will serve them for far longer and in more contexts than they would otherwise acquire&lt;/a&gt;. At code bootcamps, most students are doing little more than memorizing the syntax of some programming language, but at Tech Learning Collective, students are learning how to think critically about every challenge they face in the digital age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our teachers actually teach, instead of simply pointing students towards references that we know they can find on their own using an Internet search engine. The result is an educational experience far more valuable, at far lower cost (both in terms of time and money), than can be achieved elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Tech Learning Collective’s sky-high student retention rate is just one data point in support of this claim. Rather than taking our word for it, here is what a few of our most recent students had to say about the classes they took this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is the best school, hands down, to learn about how to work with your computer. They offer regular workshops and longer courses, and have amazing, self-directed foundation courses about doing more with the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;—Zach, May 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Before taking the “&lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Exploring-Cyberspace-Network-Sniffing-and-Scanning&quot;&gt;Exploring Cyberspace: Network Sniffing and Scanning&lt;/a&gt;” class, I had some passing experience with one or two of the tools the instructor introduced. I would have considered myself a beginner. The instructor managed to take us into deep waters by illustrating small steps, making sure we understood the fundamental terminology, and asking us lots of questions. The scope of the class was thoughtfully limited—enough to make sure we could swim but also realize there is much more to learn. Quite an accomplishment in under two hours!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;—David Schmudde, May 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I found Tech Learning Collective’s “&lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Our-Streets,-Our-Maps-Introduction-to-OpenStreetMap&quot;&gt;Our Streets, Our Maps&lt;/a&gt;” was a highly informative and stimulating workshop. The instructor did an excellent job illustrating the great versatility of OpenStreetMap and demonstrating the wide range of queries it can satisfy. As someone who’d never before used OpenStreetMap, this workshop captured my imagination and has inspired me to plumb the depths of this valuable resource!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;—August West, May 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read about a dozen more reviews published with permission on &lt;a href=&quot;/testimonials/&quot;&gt;our Testimonials page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unwavering-comittment-to-our-mission&quot;&gt;Unwavering comittment to our mission&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet another area that we find encouraging is the demographic breakdown of our student population. As a security-first technology school, we are operating in an extraordinarily militarized and male-dominated environment. However, at our workshops, including and especially our cybersecurity trainings such as our “&lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/World-Wide-Wars-Introduction-to-Exploiting-Web-Applications&quot;&gt;World Wide Wars: Introduction to Exploiting Web Applications&lt;/a&gt;” workshop, Tech Learning Collective consistently sees more women and femmes in attendance than men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An exact demographic breakdown is impossible for us to provide because we don’t ask students to reveal their gender identity, race, or other demographic information as a condition of attendance to our public workshops. Also, our webinars are held online where students may never reveal any additional information about themselves beyond the words they type or nickname they use in class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, in order to keep ourselves accountable to our mission of serving primarily underrepresented communities, we sometimes conduct internal reviews of our progress and make some generic assumptions during the process of analyzing the data we do have. This includes classifying attendees along a coarse gender spectrum with three points (“femme,” “masc,” and “neutral”, in which we also include an implicit “unknown” gender category). The coding is keyed to a student’s preferred name in class, legal first name when their preferred name is missing or unclear, or email address when no other information was available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be sure, this system is not perfect. For example, it offers no direct insight into how many trans people have attended Tech Learning Collective workshops, and we happen to know for a fact that there are trans people among our recurring students. While we obviously take issue with such imperfect schemes when they are used as justifications to make it hard or impossible for an individual to access social, economic, or political resources, we feel that our use of this schema as a rough guide used to ensure that we remain true to our own core educational mission is both ethical and warranted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on our analysis from data collected over the last five months, we can very happily say that we are succeeding like never before. Across all paid events since January 2020, exactly half (50%, or 1-to-1) of students presented in a manner that would be consistent with the mainstream’s understanding of women or feminine as compared with men or masculine (or gender-neutral).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/post.chart.2020-05-19.Estimated Binary Gender Breakdown by Total Students.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when limited to returning students (those participants who have purchased tickets to two or more events), this ratio changes to a dramatic 2-to-1. This means, among recurring students, women and femmes are exactly twice as likely to be present than men or masculine students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/post.chart.2020-05-19.Estimated Binary Gender Breakdown by Recurring Students.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We consider this a huge success because it bucks the trend that, to date, every single other mixed-gender educational environment has had immense trouble shaking. We primarily credit our amazing teaching team, who are themselves majority femme, with making this possible. They have gone to great lengths to ensure that each class is punctuated by what one student called “femme-friendly communications.” Additionally, our sliding scale or tiered pricing structure (borrowed from our experience in the queer party scene) in which straight, cis, white, and other societally privileged demographics are asked to pay more to offset the systemic oppressions prevalent in society and the tech sector especially, is clearly proving a useful technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This data confirms our belief that it is not only possible, but economically sustainable to actually prioritize women and femmes even in what are traditionally viewed as intensely combative and needlessly hyper-masculinized fields such as cyber offense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the above is incredibly encouraging, we are a long way from our goal of a world in which political organizers and movement builders have the digital dexterity (the knowledge and skill, not just the tools) they need to radically reshape the world into a more just and peaceful place. At the end of the day, it will be up to our students, not us, to actually hack back against injustices and inequality using what they learn in our classes and workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for now, Tech Learning Collective remains comitted to completing our transition to a wholly virtual organization. We are continuing to work on bringing our more intensive courses online, and we are adding more online options to the rest of our curriculum very quickly. This month, our &lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/&quot;&gt;Foundations series&lt;/a&gt; of free, self-paced online learning modules has expanded yet again, and this will continue for the forseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re incredibly grateful to everyone who has been supporting us, from our dedicated long-time collective members to our newest partners. As we continue to build out our cybersecurity-focused social justice movement technology education materials, we hope you’ll continue to help us spread the word amongst your friends and comrades about our webinars, workshops, and special events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of your issue, effective advocacy requires competency and skill. Tech Learning Collective is committed to making sure you and your group have the skills you need to work effectively and safely in the digital age.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Tech Learning Collective was founded in an effort to radically increase the cybersecurity effectiveness and other digital capabilities of politically-motivated individuals and groups. It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly important not to lose sight of larger goals, especially in times of distress. For us at Tech Learning Collective, that means taking stock of how we're continuing to fulfil our original mission while taking care of ourselves and our communities.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.tech-learning-collective-calendar-2020-05.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.tech-learning-collective-calendar-2020-05.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Queer All the (Electronic) Things! Our Love for the Command Line</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/09/queer-all-the-electronic-things-our-love-for-the-command-line.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Queer All the (Electronic) Things! Our Love for the Command Line" /><published>2020-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/09/queer-all-the-electronic-things-our-love-for-the-command-line</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/05/09/queer-all-the-electronic-things-our-love-for-the-command-line.html">&lt;p&gt;June is Pride Month, and there’s certainly a lot for us to be proud about. As an entirely queer-run technology school, June is a very personal time for us. We usually take this time of year to reflect on the previous year, to celebrate how far we’ve come, and look forward to making the next year the best yet. This year, of course, things are very different. They are much harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we talk about our upcoming workshops, please permit us the luxury of getting a few things off our chests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the coronavirus pandemic, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nyc-pride.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/Press+Release+04.20.2020.pdf&quot;&gt;NYC Pride has cancelled all in-person events&lt;/a&gt;. Like everyone else, many in our LGBTQIA+ family have lost their jobs, often their only economic lifeline. But as queer and trans folks, we’re also feeling the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newsweek.com/trans-transgender-coronavirus-pandemic-covid-19-youth-students-trevor-project-1493527&quot;&gt;aftershocks from the COVID-19 crisis in ways that straight or cis people don’t even have to think about&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For centuries, LGBT and queer folks have had and continue to need to fight simply to be safe, much less welcomed, into many parts of mainstream society. Everything from walking down the street to showing up for work has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.papermag.com/nomi-ruiz-trans-women-2645743817.html&quot;&gt;tinged with danger&lt;/a&gt; long before mere human contact was itself a “risky” behavior. Even today, trans, non-binary, and gender non-conforming people still &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2016/08/in-michigan-its-totally-legal-to-fire-trans-people-for-their-gender-identity/496559/&quot;&gt;don’t have basic employment protections&lt;/a&gt; under United States law, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/think/opinion/trump-s-fight-make-transgender-discrimination-legal-may-make-sex-ncna1044026&quot;&gt;threatens &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; because &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; it does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is no surprise that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/voices/2019/06/24/pride-month-black-transgender-women-stonewall-marsha-p-johnson/1478200001/&quot;&gt;trans women were rioting against police brutality even before Stonewall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, then came Stonewall and the fight for inclusion into and acceptance—Borg-like assimilation—by a society that still, fifty-one years later, still doesn’t seem to care about whether its essential workers live or die. Forget queerness. When push comes to shove, even if you’re straight, cis, male, and white, your elected leaders would still rather sacrifice you on the altar of the holy United States Dollar to protect their precious “economy.” Get out there, essential worker, and risk your life to defend your “livelihood.” The contradiction in terms could not be more obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was “acceptance” and “inclusion” into &lt;em&gt;this mess&lt;/em&gt; really worth all the effort? What if, instead of fighting for inclusion to and acceptance by a callous system, we had spent the last fifty-one years fighting to break out of this coercive and controlling environment altogether? What if, instead of unquestioningly believing that “this is just how the world works,” we had been able to ground ourselves to the fullest extent of our queerness, confident in our rejection of the sickness of straightness from day one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would we still be job hunting? Would jobs still be the only feasible way most of us could get healthcare? Would so many of us, irrespective of gayness or straightness, be so disappointed in our government’s collective failure to do anything as simple as show some empathy for the almost &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coronatracker.com/country/united-states/&quot;&gt;100,000 preventable deaths&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href=&quot;https://trumpdeathclock.com/&quot;&gt;climbing&lt;/a&gt;) their inaction has surely caused?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine for a moment, just for one moment, what we could have accomplished by now if we had collectively spent the last fifty-one years since Stonewall fighting not for inclusion into this Hell of a society that still doesn’t care if we live or die, but freedom from the obviously wrong and damaging limitations of the supposedly inevitable false choices on which that system is based. That would have been queer power at its finest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Queer power comes from the edges. It begins as the subtle glint of color in an otherwise black-and-white world. It is the unexplained knot in our bellies that we all feel when we take the time to listen to our bodies and notice that something…something &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; is there, just under the surface, waiting for us to call it up. That it &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be there, somewhere, because otherwise none of us would be here in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does any of this have to do with the command line? To us, the command line is the queerest part of our machines. No where in a computer is its natural, innate power exemplified with as much grace or elegance as the command line. It is radically different from the “Desktop” most people experience as the totality of their computing environment. That, in and of itself, is one reason we are so enamored with our terminals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The command line lies beneath the visual surface of your computer, hidden but always present, like sacred wells held in the bases of our heretical cathedrals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To us, the command line is our route to freedom from the coercive paradigm imposed by the &lt;em&gt;industrial business machines&lt;/em&gt; of this society like, say, IBM, Inc. It is a place that is not anywhere specific and also everywhere simultaneously. It can not be accurately described as this or that because it is a third thing altogether. It is made up of pure language, and because of this it can morph into anything you imagine, and many things you cannot—yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern tech culture will describe the command line as an obscure productivity tool; something you learn only to impress other tech folk (a meaningless activity) or to become a “power user” (a meaningless phrase). Conventional tech wisdom will tell you that the command line is an intimidating, obscure, imposing place—impossible to learn and dangerous to use. This is only an attempt to hide its true nature: the command line is a place made entirely of our first occult technology, the word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love our terminals in a way not unlike the way we love our chosen families. We were presented with Windows and walls and folders and stacks of paperwork. It took us a long time to find the terminals buried underneath layer upon layer of lies, misdirections, and obstacles, and longer still to learn how to be comfortable sitting with them. They used strange words we didn’t know. Other people thought we were weird for going there. Sometimes they were even scared of us because of it. But we were nonetheless called back there time and again and, ultimately, being there proved the single most freeing experience we have ever had, reaching far beyond the confines of metal and electrical cable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, experiences like these, they stick with us. And it’ll stick with you, too. These kinds of experiences make you want to change things because, suddenly, you realize how small you had to make yourself to fit in with your previous ideas of what life could be. Admittedly, that’s not something everyone wants to do; some are simply understandably nervous, while others (like “the 1%”) recognize the genuinely existential threat to their way of “life” that such change implies. For many people, jobs and grocery stores are probably familiar. Work for a boss and you will be &lt;em&gt;allowed&lt;/em&gt;, benevolently, to survive. A world with community gardens and hydroponics are probably harder for them to imagine than one with paychecks and exploited, immigrant farm workers. Paperwork and government benefits are predictable, if maddening, byzantine, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gothamist.com/news/coronavirus-unemployment-benefits-in-ny-is-still-a-kafkaesque-mess&quot;&gt;frequently unavailable&lt;/a&gt;, and often unjust. Chosen families who support one another are not utopic, but they are at least based on human connection rather than ICE-cold number crunching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can only get to the command line by asking for it explicitly; it will not make itself known to us on its own. We can only get there from here by demanding, with the necessary force to back it up, that all the existing prisons both literal and figurative be torn down. It will not happen by visiting a ballot box once every four years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with that said, this June, we invite you to join us for these command line workshops that are unlike any other you have probably ever imagined. We know things are all fucked up right now, and we know how intimidating this can all be. But in certain ways, for many in our collective, this “new normal” so many people are suddenly experiencing is actually a rather dated 90’s-era cyberpunk dystopia that we’ve been experiencing for many, many years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that sense, we’re happy that you don’t have to enter this reality alone and defenseless. We kinda built Tech Learning Collective for exactly this scenario. We want to help you thrive here. We want to welcome you to the magical, heretical, transformative, queer world of humanity’s contemporary witchcraft. We want to welcome you to the Command Line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/06/workshop-2020-06-01-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics&quot;&gt;June 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;, at 4:30 PM, &lt;em&gt;Computer Language Foundations: Command Line Basics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You have read about people who can talk to machines. Maybe you imagined secret chambers, hidden away behind locked doors, with dark rooms basking in blue from electric fires. Some of these people seemed friendly, others scary, but all of them were powerful. How did they learn to communicate with their computers? This is your chance to learn the foundations of all computer languages, the command line, and actually begin to talk to a machine yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/06/workshop-2020-06-03-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners&quot;&gt;June 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt;, at 3:30 PM, &lt;em&gt;Writing with Blue Fire: Shell Scripting for Beginners&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Learn how to inscribe your thoughts, dreams, and desires into your computer and take your command line skills to the next level by learning how to write simple programs called shell scripts. In a way, invoking commands one at a time is like writing a program interactively, whereas writing a script inscribes that knowledge into a more permanent form. By learning how to turn commands into simple scripted programs, you can unlock the almost magical potential of your computer and more easily share that potential with others to whom you distribute your scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/06/workshop-2020-06-05-the-map-is-the-territory-a-magical-introduction-to-the-command-line&quot;&gt;June 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, at 9:00 PM, &lt;em&gt;The Map is the Territory: A Magical Introduction to the Command Line&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Get an introduction to interacting with your computer through the terminal, and a hint towards all the beautiful radical power possible there. We will learn some basics by doing spellwork, and by the end you will have literally gathered magical fragments from the ether and cast a spell from a modest digital altar.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome…to the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">At the start of Pride Month in June, Tech Learning Collective is celebrating in the way queer hackers do best. We're dedicating the first week of June as Command Line Interface (CLI) Week and hosting workshops all about breaking free from the hegemonic, oppressive, coercive, and limiting environment of the &quot;Desktop&quot; and its employment-centric office job metaphor for computing. Join us for any of these command line workshops throughout the week to help us bring down bullshit jobs and paperwork-fetishizing bureaucracies and uplift the inherent freedom and power in linguistic creativity and our ability to queer all the (electronic) things!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.rainbow-lolcat-terminal.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.rainbow-lolcat-terminal.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour Highlights</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/04/02/mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour-highlights.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mr. Robot's Hacker Happy Hour Highlights" /><published>2020-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/04/02/mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour-highlights</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/04/02/mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour-highlights.html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, we at Tech Learning Collective, an apprenticeship-based technology school for radical organizers headquartered in New York City that provides a security-first IT infrastructure curriculum to otherwise underserved communities and organizations advancing social justice causes, hosted &lt;a href=&quot;/events/2020/03/event-2020-03-30-mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour&quot;&gt;our first-ever virtual “Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour” online social hangout&lt;/a&gt;. More than 200 people registered, and more than 110 actually showed up, making it the single largest event we have ever hosted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being scheduled to run for only one hour, everyone who came was so engaged (and engaging!) that we continued talking tech, hacking, and discussed elements of the show &lt;cite&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/cite&gt; for more than two and a half hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, most of us had nowhere to go! Gathering places are closed, or suddenly dangerous in a whole new way. This country’s so-called “leaders” chose to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/senator-dumped-up-to-1-7-million-of-stock-after-reassuring-public-about-coronavirus-preparedness&quot;&gt;dump stocks and lie about the country’s pandemic readiness&lt;/a&gt; rather than fund health services, despite receiving daily briefings about the impending crisis. So, we came together last week to say: &lt;em&gt;fuck society!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is it about society that disappoints us so much?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, we don’t know. Is it that we collectively thought Steve Jobs was a great man, even when we knew he made billions off the backs of children? Or maybe it’s that it feels like all our heroes are counterfeit. The world itself is just one big hoax, spamming each other with our running commentary of bullshit masquerading as insight, our social media faking as intimacy. Or is it that we &lt;em&gt;voted&lt;/em&gt; for this? Not with our rigged elections, but with our things, our property, our money. We’re not saying anything new. We all know why we do this, not because &lt;cite&gt;Hunger Games&lt;/cite&gt; books makes us happy but because we wanna be sedated, because it’s painful not to pretend, because we’re cowards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuck society. It’s a world built on fantasy. A kingdom of bullshit! Governments have no respect for their own laws. Society was compromised before we even got here. Election ballots are their exploits. Belief in their good intentions is our zero day vuln. Synthetic emotions in the form of pills. Psychological warfare in the form of advertising. Mind-altering chemicals in the form of…food! Brainwashing seminars in the form of media. Controlled isolated bubbles in the form of social networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To break this cycle of abuse, at Tech Learning Collective, students learn how to extend and enhance the existing capabilities of their projects and communities using free, open, and increasingly ubiquitous digital technologies. And despite the seriousness of the current situation, our ambitious goals, and the overwhelming forces of evil arrayed against those who try to bend the arc of the universe towards justice, we try to have fun while we’re learning how to break free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week’s “Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour” was one tiny success among the mayhem. Below, we’ve shared excerpts of some of our favorite moments from the event. Watch the videos or read the closed captions to see what you may have missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#introduction-and-what-the-virus-said-poem&quot;&gt;Introduction and “What the Virus Said” poem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#mixnets-and-tor&quot;&gt;Mixnets and Tor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#password-hashes-explained&quot;&gt;Password hashes explained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#dfir-ip-addresses-and-framing-terry-colby&quot;&gt;DFIR, IP addresses, and framing Terry Colby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#unlinking-your-data-trail-with-tors-new-identity-button&quot;&gt;Unlinking your data trail with Tor’s “New Identity” Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#covid-19-cybersecurity-industry-response&quot;&gt;COVID-19 cybersecurity industry response&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction-and-what-the-virus-said-poem&quot;&gt;Introduction and “What the Virus Said” poem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Mr. Robot's Hacker Happy Hour Introduction and 'What the Virus Said' Poem.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;track label=&quot;Closed Captions (English)&quot; kind=&quot;captions&quot; srclang=&quot;en&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Mr. Robot's Hacker Happy Hour Introduction and 'What the Virus Said' Poem.vtt&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Mr. Robot's Hacker Happy Hour Introduction and 'What the Virus Said' Poem.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event opened with a brief introduction to Tech Learning Collective, a rundown of some links to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/awesome-social-distancing/tree/master/README.md#readme&quot;&gt;resources elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;, shout-outs to our sister organizations, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lundi.am/What-the-virus-said&quot;&gt;a poem acknowledging the current tragedy unfolding before us&lt;/a&gt; all across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mixnets-and-tor&quot;&gt;Mixnets and Tor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Mixnets and Tor.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;track label=&quot;Closed Captions (English)&quot; kind=&quot;captions&quot; srclang=&quot;en&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Mixnets and Tor.vtt&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Mixnets and Tor.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tor makes its appearance on &lt;cite&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/cite&gt; in the very first scene, even before the opening credits. So perhaps that’s why, for the first thirty minutes of our Hacker Happy Hour, most people asked questions about Tor. In this clip, we discuss one of the foundational operating principles of the Tor network: the fact that it is a cryptographic mixnet. We also touch on why it’s so important to keep your Tor Browser software (and, really, all your software) up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective regularly runs &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Tor-What-is-it-Good-For-(Absolutely-Everything!)&quot;&gt;our in-depth Tor workshop&lt;/a&gt;, which covers this and many more aspects of Tor use, configuration, and administration at various times. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;/events/&quot;&gt;our events calendar&lt;/a&gt; to learn when the next Tor workshop you can sign up for is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;password-hashes-explained&quot;&gt;Password hashes explained&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Password Hashes Explained.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;track label=&quot;Closed Captions (English)&quot; kind=&quot;captions&quot; srclang=&quot;en&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Password Hashes Explained.vtt&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Password Hashes Explained.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every hacker needs to crack a hash at one point or another (although the ecologically conscious hacker simply backdoors login pages), and Elliot is no exception. In this clip, we discuss what password hashes are. We go into far more depth on the topic during &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Password-Superpowers-How-to-Crack-Hashes-and-Stump-Hackers&quot;&gt;our Password Superpowers workshop&lt;/a&gt;, where we show you how to automate the process described in the video using Elliot’s favorite hash cracking program, John the Ripper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dfir-ip-addresses-and-framing-terry-colby&quot;&gt;DFIR, IP addresses, and framing Terry Colby&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/DFIR, IP Addresses, and Framing Terry Colby.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;track label=&quot;Closed Captions (English)&quot; kind=&quot;captions&quot; srclang=&quot;en&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/DFIR, IP Addresses, and Framing Terry Colby.vtt&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/workshops/DFIR, IP Addresses, and Framing Terry Colby.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a cybersecurity engineer by day, Elliot plays hacker defense, which means his job sometimes requires him to perform digital forensics and incident response (DFIR) tasks in order to collect evidence about what hackers did to which systems and when. In this clip, we (partly) answer the question, “How did Elliot frame Terry Colby?” In the process we discuss some DFIR tools, and demystify a bit of hacker jargon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unlinking-your-data-trail-with-tors-new-identity-button&quot;&gt;Unlinking your data trail with Tor’s “New Identity” Button&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Unlinking Your Data Trail with Tor's 'New Identity' Button.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;track label=&quot;Closed Captions (English)&quot; kind=&quot;captions&quot; srclang=&quot;en&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Unlinking Your Data Trail with Tor's 'New Identity' Button.vtt&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/workshops/Unlinking Your Data Trail with Tor's 'New Identity' Button.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hacker or not, everyone has the right to check out books from the library without governments (the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Five_Eyes&quot;&gt;Five Eyes&lt;/a&gt;”), spouses, or parents learning which books we checked out. This is called privacy. On the Internet, Tor Browser provides one of the most robust tools for maintaining privacy as we browse the World Wide Web, our modern Library of Alexandria. In this clip, we discuss an oft-overlooked feature of Tor Browser, the “New Identity” button, why you want to use it more often than you probably are, and why it’s effective at helping you reduce your “digital paper trail.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;covid-19-cybersecurity-industry-response&quot;&gt;COVID-19 cybersecurity industry response&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/COVID-19 Cybersecurity Industry Response.mp4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;track label=&quot;Closed Captions (English)&quot; kind=&quot;captions&quot; srclang=&quot;en&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/workshops/COVID-19 Cybersecurity Industry Response.vtt&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/workshops/COVID-19 Cybersecurity Industry Response.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch video.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pandemics are not new, but the Internet is! There has never been a global pandemic at a time when so much of day-to-day life is conducted through a Web browser. That makes it critical for people to understand how these technologies work, or they risk letting those who do constrain and control their capabilities for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This clip wasn’t really about Mr. Robot, but we couldn’t help pointing out that phishing campaigns immediately took advantage of people’s fear about the coronavirus pandemic. Some ransomware groups are still targeting hospitals and healthcare departments. While it’s great to see some industry responding in a “social good” way, we feel that this is far too little, far too late. The time to help your neighbor is not during an emergency, it is &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the emergency, something very few (if any) cybersecurity firms showed much interest in doing the way they are now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope that ending on this note will remind us all of the vital role digital infrastructure now plays in our everyday lives. Tech Learning Collective’s mission has always been to empower those who are sidelined by Big Tech in ways &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/07/22/want-to-get-good-with-computers-dont-start-with-code.html&quot;&gt;traditional bootcamps don’t and can’t&lt;/a&gt; by providing both world-class technical education coupled with a pedagogical approach that brings immediate benefit to you and your loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much to those of you who were able to join us last week for our first online “Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour.” If we do this again, we’ll focus on Season 1, Episode 2. Who knows? Maybe by the time we finish watching the show together, we will have remade society into a place where “leaders” can’t &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yahoo.com/lifestyle/stimulus-package-hurts-abortion-providers-150002213.html&quot;&gt;take financial advantage of the deaths of thousands of people&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t that be something worth hacking on?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">More than two hundred people registered for our free, first-ever virtual &amp;ldquo;Mr. Robot&amp;rsquo;s Hacker Happy Hour&amp;rdquo; digital security and online privacy crash course at the end of March. Although it was scheduled to run for one hour, we had so much fun that the event lasted almost a full three hours! In this post, we recap some of our favorite moments and share video highlights from the event. Read on for a peek at what you may have missed.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour-elliot.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour-elliot.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcoming students, alumni, and the public to our community chat channels</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/26/welcoming-students-alumni-and-the-public-to-our-community-chat-channels.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcoming students, alumni, and the public to our community chat channels" /><published>2020-03-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/26/welcoming-students-alumni-and-the-public-to-our-community-chat-channels</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/26/welcoming-students-alumni-and-the-public-to-our-community-chat-channels.html">&lt;p&gt;Today, Tech Learning Collective is pleased to invite you to our new community chat channels. These free, online, in-browser chat rooms make it easy to stay in touch with fellow and former students as well as other community members before, during, and after your course or &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;workshop&lt;/a&gt; experiences. We’re starting small, with only one open-to-the-public chat room, but we’ll be adding more as needed. All public channels will be free forever and will offer another way to get ad-hoc tech help from our talented team of technical experts, or just socialize with our welcoming, politically engaged student and alumni community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our public community chat room, accessible by clicking the “Open Chat” tab at the bottom of every page on our Web site, is a semi-moderated chat channel where everyone is welcome to stop by and spend a while. Discussions range from the technical to the humorous to the completely off-topic. &lt;strong&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective spaces, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior will result in immediate removal from this space.&lt;/strong&gt; Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, as we complete the transition to a fully remote educational format so that we can continue to provide best-in-class, affordable, security-first IT training to politically motivated individuals and groups even under &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic.html&quot;&gt;the extraordinary circumstances of the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/a&gt;, we are introducing per-course private chat channels to current and former students. If you are currently enrolled in a Tech Learning Collective course, you should already have an email waiting for you with instructions for how you can access your course’s private chat room. (New students will get a similar message near the start of their own course.) We intend for this new offering to augment our already highly social and Socratic pedagogy by providing opportunities for gatherings like virtual “office hours” for students to interact with one another as well as their instructor(s) in between classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also recognize that many already under-resourced organizations are facing immense pressure to “go virtual” and collaborate with colleagues and constituents completely online. This is why we feel that our decision to begin facilitating live chat and to offer these resources for free to interested members of the public is the next logical step in &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic.html&quot;&gt;our committment to do what we can to support our community&lt;/a&gt; during this extended period of social distancing and other hardships. Although we don’t have the resources necessary for making this a round-the-clock operation, our small teaching team will be taking turns moderating the public channel and doing their best to answer whatever technical questions you have on a volunteer basis (within reasonable limits, of course). If you’d like to support us in this, please consider &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;making a donation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you’ll stop by and say hello to us, and one another, soon! See you at an &lt;a href=&quot;/events/upcoming/&quot;&gt;upcoming webinar&lt;/a&gt; or, now, in the community chat!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Tech Learning Collective is pleased to invite you to our new community chat channels. Current and former students also now have access to private chat channels for staying in touch with their classmates even after their course ends. The semi-moderated public rooms are part of our continuing effort to integrate distance learning opportunities for the general public during the global response to the COVID-19 healthcare emergency.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.chat-rooms-chat-bubbles.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.chat-rooms-chat-bubbles.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">One way we’re doing what we can to support our community during the coronavirus pandemic</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One way we're doing what we can to support our community during the coronavirus pandemic" /><published>2020-03-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic.html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, we at Tech Learning Collective were busy &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/02/28/introducing-live-instruction-webinars-and-free-online-practice-labs.html&quot; title=&quot;Read our webinar introduction announcement.&quot;&gt;adapting&lt;/a&gt; our in-person donation-based and low-cost computer training classes designed for people who are underrepresented in the tech sector to an online training format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; spurred to do this because of coronavirus (we started this process before anyone had heard of the pandemic), but we’re writing now to remind you about it in light of these recent events. Unfortunately, many of our peer groups who do similar work teaching underprivileged people about computer technology have cancelled their events, closed continuing education classrooms, or postponed their educational meetings. Due to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20200315184949/https://www.nypl.org/about/coronavirus&quot;&gt;closure of NY Public Libraries&lt;/a&gt;, for instance, numerous community groups no longer have meeting spaces available to them. It is sad to see so many noble efforts curtailed this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While they have been doing their best to transition to an online learning model, Tech Learning Collective was fortunate in that we began this transition quite a while ago and so we were unexpectedly prepared for the ramifications of “social distancing” without even intending to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that for over two months now, Tech Learning Collective has more than quadrupled the number of total events we run, and we’re continuing to increase our online student capacity every week. We’ve also lowered prices across the board, making it even easier for people who otherwise would not have a chance to get started learning about computer technology or online digital safety to do so affordably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We figured that as New York City and other municipalities begin to further enforce closures of public spaces, and as bars, restaurants, cafes, and other community centers are voluntarily closing to help &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2020/world/corona-simulator/&quot;&gt;flatten the epidemic peak&lt;/a&gt; of COVID-19 and assist our healthcare system in supporting all the people who may need urgent medical care, many people may be experiencing changing social dynamics as they spend more time at home and away from friends, peers, or colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, a climate of fear is ripe for abuse, and that’s exactly what we’ve seen happen. Earlier this week, malware authors have started taking advantage of the panic by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibtimes.com/russians-hack-johns-hopkins-coronavirus-map-steal-user-information-2939424&quot;&gt;working coronavirus information into phishing campaigns&lt;/a&gt; designed to steal personal information and compromise computer accounts. This makes it even more important for individuals to keep their guard up when clicking on links in social media, email, and other remote communications, something that isn’t always easy to remember in times of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of this, we have chosen to &lt;em&gt;further&lt;/em&gt; increase the rate of our online events and, for the foreseeable future, our teaching staff has volunteered to facilitate repeats of workshops across different times of the day and on weekends in order to provide more activities (and, admittedly, some distraction) for anyone who feels up for it. In particular, we are partnering with more groups to host our “&lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Gone-Phishing-How-to-Recognize-Fake-Websites-and-Other-Online-Scams&quot;&gt;Gone Phishing&lt;/a&gt;” awareness training and are preparing additional learning modules that we plan to host for free as part of our open-access Foundations courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Foundations courses, which we are accelerating our work on, is our series of completely free, self-paced, in-browser digital security exercises. You can go through them without ever leaving your Web browser. A couple of these modules are already published on our Web site, and we hope to add more in the coming weeks. You can find them, day or night, on &lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/&quot;&gt;our Web site’s “Foundations” page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please consider joining us for any of &lt;a href=&quot;/events/upcoming/&quot;&gt;these events&lt;/a&gt;, and telling anyone in your social network who feels restless, is having trouble due to cabin fever, or otherwise wants to take the opportunity to spend a couple of hours taking a break from reading the news about our remote workshop options. We’re also happy to extend further discounts on a case-by-case basis. If you have any questions, &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; via email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;/events/&quot;&gt;a full schedule of our online events, including event details, see our Web site’s “Events” page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, of course, if you have any additional ideas for how we can work together to help make the next couple of months easier, please don’t hesitate to reach out about that as well. Take care, give care.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Earlier this year, we at Tech Learning Collective were busy adapting our in-person donation-based and low-cost computer training classes designed for people who are underrepresented in the tech sector to an online training format.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.laptop-table-for-bed.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.laptop-table-for-bed.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing live instruction webinars and free online practice labs</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/02/28/introducing-live-instruction-webinars-and-free-online-practice-labs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing live instruction webinars and free online practice labs" /><published>2020-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/02/28/introducing-live-instruction-webinars-and-free-online-practice-labs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/02/28/introducing-live-instruction-webinars-and-free-online-practice-labs.html">&lt;p&gt;At the end of last year, we invited the Tech Learning Collective community to our year-end conference, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/&quot;&gt;Hackers Next
Door&lt;/a&gt;. It was an &lt;em&gt;incredible&lt;/em&gt; event, with over 100 participants and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/2019/speakers/&quot;&gt;more than 25 speakers&lt;/a&gt; who inspired and challenged us to find new and more effective ways to build power in our communities. After a much needed break to recuperate but also to celebrate, our team is back with an expanded lineup of workshops and events, and more opportunities than ever before for you to take your skills to the next level, with remote/virtual/online-only webinars on topics like &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Collaboration-Across-Universes-Basics-of-Version-Control-with-Git&quot;&gt;collaboration with Git&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Taming-Daemons-System-Administration-and-Operation-Basics&quot;&gt;system administration basics&lt;/a&gt;, and more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-webinar-remote-workshops&quot;&gt;New Webinar (Remote) Workshops&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One unexpected but wonderful thing about the Hackers Next Door conference was how many people came to New York just for our event!  Attendees arrived from places such as Michigan and Colorado and as far away as California. And although the conference still focused on the local issues facing New Yorkers, with speakers from advocacy groups such as the Atlantic Plaza Towers Tenants Association who are fighting the installation of racist facial recognition software in their apartment complex, these otherwise “remote” attendees brought value and perspective all their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, we regularly heard from folks that they would love more opportunities to participate in Tech Learning Collective events, if only they could find the time or, y’know, lived in New York City in the first place! Well, we’ve been working hard to harvest two carrots with one fist (and stop throwing stones at birds). That’s why you’re invited to our upcoming workshop webinars!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective workshop webinars are 100% online events. There are no physical classrooms and so there’s nowhere you need to go, and no need to find clean clothes! Although, y’know, maybe wear clean clothes regardless. Anyway! All you need is access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of Google Chrome or Mozilla Firefox along with a fast Internet connection. In other words, if you can Netflix ’n’ chill, you have all the equipment you need to level up your h4x0r skill by attending a Tech Learning Collective webinar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like all our in-person events, our webinars are facilitated by our team of technical experts and expert teachers. This means that when you sign up, you’ll be joining a video conference with a human instructor, not a bot or a dated recording. You’ll be able to interact with the instructor via voice and video as well as with other students to tackle challenges, solve problems, and learn together. The bi-directional, real-time screen sharing options makes it easy to follow along as the instructor demonstrates how to do things like &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Clearing-Away-the-Clouds-How-Computer-Networks,-Servers,-and-the-Internet-Work&quot;&gt;sniff packets&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/The-Web-as-a-Language-What-No-One-Ever-Told-You-About-HTML-That-You-Didn't-Know-to-Ask&quot;&gt;create Web sites&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/The-Imitation-Game-Introduction-to-Administering-Virtual-Machine-Systems&quot;&gt;manage virtual machines&lt;/a&gt;, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just as with our in-person events, we’ve retained our tiered pricing structure to help ensure queer-identified, femme, PoC, and other people who have traditionally been overlooked in the tech sector have access, too. What’s more, since our own overhead is lower for webinars than they are for physical venues, we’ve decided to pass these savings on to you by dropping the price of tickets for our “remote” events by almost 30% across each price tier. There’s never been a better or less expensive way to learn the foundations of computer technology as solidly as this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;/events/&quot;&gt;our events page&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/events/upcoming/#export-event-calendar&quot;&gt;subscribe to our calendar&lt;/a&gt; to see what workshops we have coming up and to sign up for access. For more information, consult our &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;Workshops and Webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-self-paced-beginners-courses&quot;&gt;Free, Self-paced Beginner’s Courses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of learning the foundations of computer technology, we’ve also been hard at work preparing our first ever self-paced course that we’re calling the &lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s Foundations&lt;/a&gt; series. This is a series of introductory learning modules that you can use to jump-start your learing before you ever join us at one of our events, because they are all offered via our Web site. This means the Foundations courses are available anytime, day or night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s more, since we’ve designed our Foundations series to be entirely self-paced, we’re offering the whole course completely free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our Foundations series is free and always available, you can take as long as you need to work through it. Start with our &lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/#foundations-command-line-basics&quot;&gt;Foundations: Command Line Basics&lt;/a&gt; course, which introduces you to a computer terminal, one of the most important foundations of the rest of our curriculum. We’re launching with a limited selection of free materials, but are planning to expand the free courses with more labs over time, so check back regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-practice-labs-of-advanced-scenarios&quot;&gt;Free Practice Labs of Advanced Scenarios&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’ve decided to reuse the same infrastructure we deployed for our self-paced courses to put together some more bite-sized learning modules of additional, more advanced scenarios such as &lt;a href=&quot;/sample/scaling-ssh-authentication-with-certificates.html&quot;&gt;Scaling SSH Authentication with Certificates&lt;/a&gt;. If you’ve been on the fence about whether or not you should come to one of our instructor-led workshop trainings or have questions about the kind of material we teach in our intensive courses, you can try your hand at these sample scenarios to get a taste for the rest of our curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, nothing can compare to learning directly from a teacher whom you can actually see and ask questions of in real time. That’s why we’re looking forward to continuing to partner with groups around New York City to expand our in-person training, and invite you or your organization to &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; about booking a private group training for your volunteers or colleagues. In the mean time, though, we hope that these self-paced learning modules will whet your appetite until your next (or first) class with us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Tech Learning Collective is excited to offer free, self-paced beginner courses along with new webinar workshops that make it easier than ever before to level up your h4x0r skillz. If you can Netflix &amp;lsquo;n&amp;rsquo; chill, you have all the equipment you need to participate in a webinar and tackle technical problems with our team of technical experts and expert teachers. Learn more about our free online &amp;ldquo;Foundations&amp;rdquo; curriculum series and our new webinar events in this post.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured-image.webinars.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured-image.webinars.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AwesomeNYC announces Tech Learning Collective as winner of its December 2019 grant</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/12/17/awesomenyc-announces-tech-learning-collective-as-winner-of-its-december-2019-grant.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AwesomeNYC announces Tech Learning Collective as winner of its December 2019 grant" /><published>2019-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/12/17/awesomenyc-announces-tech-learning-collective-as-winner-of-its-december-2019-grant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/12/17/awesomenyc-announces-tech-learning-collective-as-winner-of-its-december-2019-grant.html">&lt;p&gt;On the heels of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20191212203844/https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/&quot;&gt;Hackers Next Door 2019&lt;/a&gt; conference, we were excited to learn that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.awesomefoundation.org/en/projects/132070-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;AwesomeNYC has just announced that it will be awarding its December 2019 grant to Tech Learning Collective&lt;/a&gt;! AwesomeNYC is the New York City chapter of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.awesomefoundation.org/&quot;&gt;the Awesome Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, “an ever-growing worldwide community devoted to forwarding the interest of awesome in the universe.” In addition to naming Tech Learning Collective as the winner of their final grant offered in calendar year 2019, AwesomeNYC shared information about Tech Learning Collective programs on their Web site and in their newsletter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. By providing educational opportunities in the form of public &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/pricing/#groups&quot;&gt;private trainings&lt;/a&gt;, and community convergences such as the recent Hackers Next Door 2019 conference, Tech Learning Collective empowers otherwise underserved communities by bringing world-class digital security trainers, legal experts, and experienced activists together with local community groups, neighborhood coalitions, and tenants associations so that they can learn from one another’s experience and perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;At the recent Hackers Next Door 2019 conference generously sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triangleartsnyc.org/&quot;&gt;Triangle Arts Association&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://techahoy.org/&quot;&gt;TechAhoy, Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, a local maker space in Queens, Tech Learning Collective was honored to host, among others, the Atlantic Plaza Towers Tenants Association and a member of their legal team from Legal Services NYC as they shared details of their fight against the implementation of racist facial recognition software in their homes. Conference attendees also heard from organizers of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nonewjails.nyc/&quot;&gt;No New Jails NYC&lt;/a&gt; campaign who are defending New Yorkers from the expansion of the carceral industry, and the Executive Directors of both the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stopspying.org/&quot;&gt;Surveillance Technology Oversight Project&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://torproject.org/&quot;&gt;Tor Project&lt;/a&gt; who are working on improving legal and technical tools to protect privacy and civil rights locally and globally.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In collaboration with artists, hacklabs, makerspaces, independent bookstores, and local businesses, Tech Learning Collective further facilitates direct community participation in the construction and operation of autonomous digital infrastructure services focused on providing for the community’s and neighborhood’s own needs.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s partners and benefiting organizations include projects such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://shiftctrl.space/&quot;&gt;Shift-CTRL Space&lt;/a&gt;, whose work maintaining and expanding hyperlocal digital services supporting social justice movements offers Tech Learning Collective students practical experience in numerous specialized Information Technology fields. Through our partnerships with Shift-CTRL Space and similar community organizations, Tech Learning Collective students can build on their classroom or workshop trainings by getting involved in real-life projects that require skills such as network and site reliability engineering, development operations, and computer security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We at Tech Learning Collective are incredibly grateful to the AwesomeNYC trustees for their support and their contribution. While our team takes some time off over the holidays to recuperate from an intense couple of months of conference organizing, winning this grant renews our commitment to providing the highest quality education in the areas of foundational computer and cybersecurity literacy in order to materially empower our students and workshop participants. We’re looking forward to continuing our work to make sure 2020 looks less like 1984 than the past decade has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d also like to help support Shift-CTRL Space or any of our benefiting organizations through Tech Learning Collective, &lt;a href=&quot;/events/upcoming/#export-event-calendar&quot;&gt;subscribe to our event calendar from the Events page&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;make a direct donation on the Donate page&lt;/a&gt; of our Web site.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Tech Learning Collective is announced as the winner of the latest Awesome Foundation grant provided by the organization&amp;rsquo;s New York City chapter. Read this post to learn more about AwesomeNYC and why they selected Tech Learning Collective as the recipient of their final grant in 2019.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/logo.featured.awesome-foundation.gif" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/logo.featured.awesome-foundation.gif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hackers Next Door featured on It’s Going Down’s podcast, “This Is America” Episode 97</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/11/28/hackers-next-door-featured-on-its-going-down-podcast-this-is-america-episode-97.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hackers Next Door featured on It&amp;rsquo;s Going Down&amp;rsquo;s podcast, &amp;ldquo;This Is America&amp;rdquo; Episode 97" /><published>2019-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/11/28/hackers-next-door-featured-on-its-going-down-podcast-this-is-america-episode-97</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/11/28/hackers-next-door-featured-on-its-going-down-podcast-this-is-america-episode-97.html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, members of the Hackers Next Door and Tech Learning Collective conference organizing team were interviewed for the &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itsgoingdown.org/category/podcast/this-is-america/&quot;&gt;This is America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt; podcast produced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://itsgoingdown.org/&quot;&gt;It’s Going Down&lt;/a&gt;, a digital community center for anarchist, anti-fascist, autonomous anti-capitalist and anti-colonial movements. Featured on the podcast’s 97&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; episode alongside the NYC Anarchist Black Cross’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://nycabc.wordpress.com/fang/&quot;&gt;Project FANG&lt;/a&gt;, the Hackers Next Door conference interview segment touches on topics such as the suppression of queer, femme, and PoC representation in tech, &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/07/22/want-to-get-good-with-computers-dont-start-with-code.html&quot;&gt;resisting the school-to-corporation pipeline’s “learn to code (to get a job)” mentality&lt;/a&gt;, and building collective power beyond mere voter representation through actionable cybersecurity and IT education for local community projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen to the full &lt;a href=&quot;https://itsgoingdown.org/this-is-america-97-notagainsu-project-fang-nyc-radical-tech-conference/&quot;&gt;This Is America podcast episode on the It’s Going Down website&lt;/a&gt;. Our interview segment starts approximately 39 minutes into the episode. We’ve also provided &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/its-going-down-this-is-america-episode-97-hackers-next-door.mp3&quot;&gt;a truncated copy of the episode&lt;/a&gt; with a transcript republished below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;controls&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/its-going-down-this-is-america-episode-97-hackers-next-door.mp3&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0 auto; width: 100%;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/its-going-down-this-is-america-episode-97-hackers-next-door.mp3&quot;&gt;Download the audio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://itsgoingdown.org/this-is-america-97-notagainsu-project-fang-nyc-radical-tech-conference/&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[INTRO MUSIC]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s Going Down: Welcome, to &lt;em&gt;This Is America&lt;/em&gt;, November 27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this episode, first we speak with someone from Project FANG about their project and current fundraising appeal, which seeks to provide direct support and material aid to earth and animal liberation, as well as Standing Rock prisoners.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We then &lt;a href=&quot;https://itsgoingdown.org/hackers-next-door-conference-radical-digital-security-and-privacy-conference-nyc-december-14-15/&quot;&gt;speak with several participants&lt;/a&gt; in an upcoming radical digital security and privacy conference entitled, Hackers Next Door, which will take place in New York in December.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We then launch into a discussion about moving beyond simply “mobilizing” in an age of social media and also a continuing analysis of the Trump impeachment crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;All this and more, but first, let’s get to the news!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[FADE TO NEXT SEGMENT]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s Going Down: Can you introduce yourselves real quick?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Sure, my name is Wirefall.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: You can call me Violet. We’re both from Tech Learning Collective and we’re organizing this Hackers Next Door conference in December.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;IGD: Awesome! So, before we get started talking about the conference, tell us a little bit about how you got involved in tech circles, playing around with computers, how did that start?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Um, yeah! Do you want me to go first?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Go for it, you have a good story.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: I actually have a non-technical background, in a way. I liked playing with computers and in particular making them do things that they weren’t necessarily designed to do, but I was kind of discouraged from exploring that further because the culture around that was so awful. So for the longest time, I shunned everything having to do with digital technology because, again, the people around it were so nasty to me. And then I met Violet and they had a completely different philosophy and a completely different approach to digital technologies, so I started learning a lot from them and it kind of just spiraled out of there ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah. It was partly out of the Tech Learning Collective because I was involved with TLC when the two of us met and I’d been doing cybersecurity trainings, and had kind of been into political circles and privacy rights and this sort of stuff by then for a number of years. So the ability to do something with tech that wasn’t like, “Oh, now I gotta go find a job and work for the fucking surveillance state,” or whatever it is that they’re doing, was appealing and for me it was just a continuation of the other political work that I was doing. I actually got into privacy rights advocacy in digital stuff because I was politically vocal and then I realized that as a target online, I was like, “Oh shit, I have to be serious about this,” and so that’s when I started learning about, y’know, cypherpunk-esque stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;IGD: How did you all come to the point of creating a conference. Like, why should there be a conference about political hacking?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Right! I mean, this is actually something that people in at least the tri-state area have been talking about doing for a little while, and it just hasn’t come together. So, we’ve been wanting to see—we as in Tech Learning Collective itself but y’know also the other groups that are doing this in the city. Tech Learning Collective is an Electronic Frontier Alliance member, there are a lot of other Electronic Frontier Alliance members, this is like an EFF grassroots coalition, and we basically realized that this was a conversation happening amongst EFA member groups and small, like, DSA chapters, and little sort of CryptoParty one-offs that have been going on in the New York and the tri-state area for a while, and it just hadn’t come together in any sort of bigger way. So it felt to us like, y’know, this was a really ripe opportunity. It was something that people already really wanted to do and all that was missing was some group that had the commitment and the space to do it in. And so, as Tech Learning Collective, we have a semi-permanent residency in the DUMBO neighborhood thanks to some really great people and relationships that we have with the Triangle Arts Association and so we were like, “Hey, y’know, we have space for this. It’s just a matter of doing it.” And so, a little earlier this year, we were like, y’know, let’s just fucking do it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So we started sending out invitations to everyone who we respected and knew that was doing some similar work, and also one of the most exciting things about this conference is that it’s not just the sort of, like, y’know, for lack of a diplomatic way to put it, just the incestuous and nepotic circle. This is a conference to which we’ve invited actual people affected by things like facial recognition surveillance. We’ve invited the No New Jails folks, we’ve invited the Atlantic Plaza Towers Tenant Advocates in addition to the people who are sort of already well-known and established in the digital security and privacy rights worlds, like the Freedom of the Press Foundation, and the Tor Project, and the Surveillance Technology Oversight Project, and Calyx Institute, I’m sure there’s someone else that I’m forgetting on this list.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Yeah, and I think that’s like a long list of these kind of major recognizable names, or I should say recognizable in that kind of circle. For me what’s really exciting about doing this conference in the way that we’re doing it is I’m much more interested in seeing what’s happening on a grassroots level and there are a lot of people here who are doing kind of guerrilla grassroots organizing around this topic and to get those people in the same room, based in the same city, as a lot of these larger names is an attempt in a certain way to even the playing field and kind of like bring some sobriety to the larger names and bring some more recognition and also power in a sense to the grassroots organizers.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: And resources! Like actual resources.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: That’s what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah, like, it’s one thing to be donating money to these huge non-profits and it’s a whole other thing to see what people who are actually dealing with cameras in their fucking houses are doing to combat that shit from landlords and stuff. And that is an exciting thing. And having those two conversations, I think, not happening in opposition to each other but being recognized as fueling one another, is something that I don’t see in a lot of privacy rights advocacy. I guess I should say I don’t see enough of in privacy rights advocacy, and certainly not in a cybersecurity sector.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: So putting that together, I think, is I think necessary and also just there needs to be more of that. Otherwise, you’re not going to get this sort of bottom-up approach to online privacy. You’re only going to get the legislative, y’know, “let’s have the government fucking fix things,” and that doesn’t work. We know that doesn’t work! That can not be all of the story. And so, putting that front-and-center—not to say that legislation isn’t useful, it obviously helps, but that happens only as a response to things that people in their local communities are actually doing day-to-day. So putting that together explicitly is exciting, it’s certainly, like I said, not been done enough, and I think it’s actually the thing that fuels both sides of this particular coin really well.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And y’know, the point is, how’d it started? Well, people just said that they needed that. And then we were like, let’s just fucking do it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;IGD: Let’s talk about the conference itself. When is it going to happen? Where is it going to be at? And also, what are the kinds of workshops and sessions that we should expect to see. I looked over the schedule and it looks really exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Yeah, we’re really, really excited about it as well. So, it’s taking place on December 14th and 15th of this year [2019], 11 AM to 10 PM for both days. So it’s a two-full day conference. And then we have different blocks that we’ve placed different speakers in. So, the first block of the first two days is called “Racist Policing Then and Now,” which I just mention that it’s the first block because I’ve been sort of joking about: it’s like people are going to come in, it’s like, “Good morning! Let’s talk about racist policing.” And I kind of like am a fan of that. We’re going to be talking about community initiatives, we’re going to be talking about fighting the surveillance state. People like Albert Fox Cahn from the Surveillance Technology Oversight Project are going to be there, some people are gonna talk about Tor and the quote-unquote “Dark Web,” so we’re going to have Isabela Bagueros, the Executive Director of the Tor Project is going to be there. And then of course, as I said before, I’m very excited to hear from the Tenant Advocates of the Atlantic Plaza Towers, which is a residential building in Brownsville, and they’ve been fighting their landlord on the implementation of facial recognition in their building for a year. So super excited about that. Do you want to talk a little bit about that?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah, so, the whole conference is single-track, which is to say that there’s only one presentation happening at a time. It’s gonna be, as we’ve said, at our semi-permanent residency at Triangle Arts Association in Brooklyn’s DUMBO neighborhood. So that’s basically just on the river accessible via the F train, or the A train I suppose. And it’s, um, gonna be that main presentation room, and a small hallway, and some maybe BoF (Birds of a Feather) sort of tracks, conversations for people to have if they get particularly inspired by one of the presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And the reason we’re doing single-track is because, again, we wanna have that—I’m sure you’ve gone to conferences, right, and there’s a really big-name speaker and a really local advocacy group that not as many people know about, and everyone goes to see the big name speaker and the local advocacy group gets like five people in the room. Y’know, and that’s, we don’t want that to happen. So we’ve elongated the conference’s schedule. We actually had to add like two hours or four hours to the conference because we started getting so many people saying they would like to speak from our invitation list, and decided to go single-track so that you always had a thing that was happening.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And then as people said yes, as the people we were inviting were like, “Yeah, I’d love to speak,” and they responded to our invitations, the topic of the conference sort of formed around that. Obviously, it was skewed because, y’know, I’m a dyed-in-the-wool Anarchist and Tech Learning Collective has a very political bent generally, but the fact that we ended up with, like, “Community Initiatives” as a single block, like “Fighting the Surveillance State” as a block, “Racist Policing Then and Now” as a block for our conversation is because the people who said yes, who we really wanted to see, this is what they’re doing. Black Movement Law Project will be talking about the evolution of the police from Pinkertons all the way to the Police State now. And so, it became clear that these are the topics that grassroots organizations in New York and the tri-state area are working on right now. Anti-surveillance is a big thing. It kind of molded itself around the speakers, which is kind of nice, I think. It made scheduling not that hard!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Yeah, that’s true!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;IGD: One of the things I think that’s interesting is that we’re in a time where social movements right now are using technology now more than ever and it also seems like the stakes are higher in terms of just the threat of online surveillance by corporate actors or States, or people on the far-right. I still feel like there’s still a division between kind of, like, oh there are those nerds over there with their computers and like everybody else. Where there needs to kind of like, we need to find each other and be able to share skills. A lot of us really need to catch up in terms of just building online, electronic self-defense and learning a lot of tech skills. I think a lot of use so much technology all the time, and y’know, hopefully we’re all using things like Signal, and basic practices of self-defense, but I really feel like we need to catch up where the rest of the world is.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah. I mean, yes. For what it’s worth, this is literally what Tech Learning Collective was founded on. TLC, Tech Learning Collective, is sort of the progenitor of this conference, if you will, and it was exactly that sentiment that started not just Tech Learning Collective, but then has guided the mission of TLC to do things like this conference in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Y’know, we’re a small production, we don’t have huge numbers of donors or financiers or anything, so that’s part and parcel of what lets us do things like invite these hyperlocal groups and put front and center “Racist Policing Now and Then.” I mean when was the last time you saw a cybersecurity event, with real hacking demonstrations, y’know, offensive techniques—Anarcho-Tech NYC is going to be there doing actual hacking demos like phishing and ARP cache poisoning and stuff—right with a discussion about how cyberwarfare has also come to be part and parcel of class warfare. Y’know, in the conference’s sort of—when we were conceiving it, one of the things that was very clear was that today, most people in America at least seem to experience technology as a form of class oppression because it’s literally designed to do that from corporations. Like, that’s the point of it. You don’t put a surveillance camera in someone’s home if that person is rich. You only do that to people who are less wealthy. And that’s class warfare, point-blank.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So, yeah, my point being that TLC was designed specifically to help people who needed to catch up catch up. And not catch up to get a job, right? And this is, like, I think an important distinction. It wasn’t like—there’s this narrative of “get a good tech job, go into an office, and be comfortable, and that’ll get you out of poverty.” It’s bullshit, for so many reasons, but not least of which is that that doesn’t help your community. Y’know, now you’re literally working for Jeff Bezos or some other person building tools that are actively extracting time, effort, money, from local communities that need it. But that doesn’t mean that technology itself is the problem there. It means that the way that technology is being used is extractive and not valuable for the people who are actually living under oppressive regimes.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We can also use technology to help out, and I kind of want to get back to this point of Tech Learning Collective was founded by a bunch of radicals who basically got arrested and were like, “Shit, our phones are compromised, how do we figure this out?” So we started just teaching each other about exactly that thing back before the Trump election even, and then shortly thereafter Trump got elected, and what happened was that we started getting this inundated flood of like, what do we do now? Signal became suddenly a big deal, and then there was a bunch of Signal trainings, right? Like, get off txt, use Signal. So that was the beginning of the catching up. And it was very clear very early on that those of us who have been self-educating about this for a little while, those of us who have had a bit more experience such as myself could not meet the demand. It was just too many people having too many questions about too many things to work if it was all gonna be put on a small group of individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So, that is where originally Anarcho-Tech NYC’s Train the Trainers project came from, from there Tech Learning Collective got formed specifically to address those needs. So Tech Learning Collective students are primarily people of marginalized communities, people of color, women, queer folks, femmes. Our pricing structure reflects that, y’know, the conference has a reduced price tier. Almost like, I don’t know if you’re familiar with queer parties often have two tiers. Y’know, cismen, and queers and femmes? We basically took that model and applied it to cybersecurity education. So if you come to a Tech Learning Collective workshop, one of the things you’ll notice is that our donation-based scale has two suggested tiers. One for queers and femmes and other folks who are marginalized from mainstream cybersecurity education, and everybody else. And that’s not like a wall, we’re not policing people’s gender identity when they walk in the room, but it’s a very strong signal that this what we’re about and this is what we’re for and this is why we exist. And it’s exactly to address that thing that you mentioned, where there’s this huge digital divide, a big gap, between who’s been able to take advantage of the better parts of technology, the way it can actually make our lives better, get us to be more efficient, have more individual power, and then actually build collective actions from that as opposed to just “get out the vote campaigns” and everyone else who’s now, y’know, working at fucking Palantir and building cyberweapons while telling themselves they’re stopping sex trafficking and patting themselves on the back or some shit like that.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So…. I realize that was a bit of rant, I apologize.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: I was also just going to say, too, that you got really close to saying the thing that I like to say about the pricing tiers and things like that, sliding scale stuff, which is that it’s a banner, not a wall.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: And it actually has been a really effective signal to tell other people that we are really serious about our politics and mostly also about our culture and what kind of culture we want to have when we’re teaching this kind of stuff. I think there’s two things that come to mind as we’re talking about this for me, one of which is that a lot of the training that’s out there is purely defensive and very surface, which is fine, because sometimes you just need a bandaid. Like, sometimes, you just need to do something now. But I think where TLC likes to come in is to try to drill down and to get deeper into these things so that the people who are interested in doing so can actually start to self-empower rather than just be constantly responding to a threat. And in that sense, we hope that, y’know, this tooling can be reappropriated for building autonomy, actually. And the culture thing is really important, like I said. I didn’t touch computers for the longest time because I hated the people that were around them, and it’s sort of this weird balance between, exactly what you were saying, like, “those nerds over there” or whatever. And especially on the Left, there’s a lot of technophobia because it’s this giant, aww, it’s this massive thing that’s everywhere and it’s scary and it’s always in the context of colonization, and it’s always like this. And it’s like, well, what if we could carve out our own path to these things. We could use them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah. I think that’s a really good point, actually. I just wanna double-down on what you were saying. Y’know, one of the unique things about Tech Learning Collective is that we actually have offensive classes. That’s not to say, well, it’s always for quote “educational purposes only,” but y’know, if you don’t know what a punch is, trying to show people how to defend against a punch is going to be very hard because you’ve never actually talked about the thing that you’re trying to defend against. So if you don’t show somebody how to throw a punch, it’s going to be very hard to teach them how to block one. And it’s the same thing in cybersecurity. If you don’t know how to steal a username and password, then you’re not really going to be as sensitized to when that is happening to you. So we show both sides. We will show phishing attacks, and we will show how to defend against those same attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And this is exactly what, y’know, corporations do when they have internal Red Teams and pentests and this sort of stuff. They do that, too. Just because a corporation does it doesn’t mean we shouldn’t do it. We should do it for different ends and we should do it with a better culture, but we still need to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;IGD: Past the conference, what kind of things do you hope to see to kind of get some of this stuff that we’ve been talking about in place?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: For me there are a couple of things. This conference, it’s the first iteration. And for me I’m treating it like a little bit of a sapling that I’d like to see grow into a forest. And I think that that’s going to happen by creating these opportunities to build these relationships. And I really wanted to say to the people who come—I’m probably going to mention this at the opening remarks at some point—that, y’know, I think a lot of conferences in particular have this model where it’s like, “We’re all here together for this day,” or these two days, or this week or whatever it is, and then once it’s over you have to go back to your quote-unquote “real life” or whatever. And I want this to not be that. I want this to feed into, like, what our real lives actually already are.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah, I think we have a benefit in that respect because we have so many local groups that are talking.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: So it’s not like, y’know, people are gonna come over to DUMBO and then disperse across necessarily the entire globe again. The majority of people presentation, the majority of people who are coming are tri-state area locals. And that was intentional and it’s good because it means that, like, we can basically try to avoid con-drop by just keep doing this after the fact. Y’know, all these groups that we’ve invited, they have regular meetings many times a month, including TLC. Y’know, we have workshops almost every weekend. So, um, what I hope will come of this is that there will be this continuation.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And I will also say, y’know, especially to folks who don’t have a technical background, that’s okay. No one’s expecting anyone to come out of either this conference or a workshop or a CryptoParty or anything being some kind of, uh—&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Leet superhacker!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah! But in the same way that you wouldn’t expect to go to, like, a two-hour workshop about residential electrical wiring and then expect to be able to, like, wire a house.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Yes!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: It’s an absurd expectation because it’s a skill just like any other. And also, just like electricians, who by the way are an example of a profession that I think is wildly under appreciated in society as opposed to, say, bankers, who are wildly over appreciated, right? You don’t need every single person in your community to be the electrician, or the plumber, or the carpenter. You need those things, you need carpenters, you need plumbers, you need electricians, but you don’t need every single person in your community or group or campaign or movement or whatever to have the same skills. So, it’s not about making sure everyone can be a leet super hacker, it’s about making sure that there is enough of a foundation—like in the same way that you have unions of carpentry workers, or an electrician’s union or whatever, the reason you have that is because you have enough of them to sustain the thing that you’re doing in society, which in this case in this example I guess is wiring houses for electricity. Similarly, we need more people who do have some cybersecurity background, who do have system administration experience, who can be the sort of technical go-tos, and better yet, a lot of people from many different groups do want to be and are excited about being the person who people ask tech questions of, so Tech Learning Collective is intended to train those people. That’s our real front-runners.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Insofar as there is a, like, “those nerds over there” and everybody else dichotomy, then we want those nerds over there who are the nerds who are not just interested in optimizing database queries and making things super fast and cool and talking about crypto endlessly for hours, we want the people who are doing other shit who are also interested or excited, self-motivated, about something to do with computers and we want to train them so that when they go back to whatever campaign or advocacy effort that they are involved, they now have a far better baseline to both explain and train up the people that they’re working with. And also to learn on their own so that we can have more of these equivalents to electricians, if you will, in society generally, and in movements generally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective would like to thank the It’s Going Down team for taking the time to highlight our efforts in support of revolutionary struggles and giving us the opportunity to speak about &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/&quot;&gt;the Hackers Next Door conference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Organizers of Tech Learning Collective&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Next Door conference were interviewed by It&amp;rsquo;s Going Down about the event, how they got involved in digital security education, and the need for more collaborative, in-depth cybersecurity training for activists. Read a transcript of the interview segment here.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.2019-12-14.hackers-next-door-an-infosec-conference.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.2019-12-14.hackers-next-door-an-infosec-conference.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>