<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2020-03-26T20:18:09-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">Welcoming students, alumni, and the public to our community chat channels</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/26/welcoming-students-alumni-and-the-public-to-our-community-chat-channels.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcoming students, alumni, and the public to our community chat channels" /><published>2020-03-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/26/welcoming-students-alumni-and-the-public-to-our-community-chat-channels</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/26/welcoming-students-alumni-and-the-public-to-our-community-chat-channels.html">&lt;p&gt;Today, Tech Learning Collective is pleased to invite you to our new community chat channels. These free, online, in-browser chat rooms make it easy to stay in touch with fellow and former students as well as other community members before, during, and after your course or &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;workshop&lt;/a&gt; experiences. We’re starting small, with only one open-to-the-public chat room, but we’ll be adding more as needed. All public channels will be free forever and will offer another way to get ad-hoc tech help from our talented team of technical experts, or just socialize with our welcoming, politically engaged student and alumni community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our public community chat room, accessible by clicking the “Open Chat” tab at the bottom of every page on our Web site, is a semi-moderated chat channel where everyone is welcome to stop by and spend a while. Discussions range from the technical to the humorous to the completely off-topic. &lt;strong&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective spaces, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior will result in immediate removal from this space.&lt;/strong&gt; Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, as we complete the transition to a fully remote educational format so that we can continue to provide best-in-class, affordable, security-first IT training to politically motivated individuals and groups even under &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic.html&quot;&gt;the extraordinary circumstances of the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/a&gt;, we are introducing per-course private chat channels to current and former students. If you are currently enrolled in a Tech Learning Collective course, you should already have an email waiting for you with instructions for how you can access your course’s private chat room. (New students will get a similar message near the start of their own course.) We intend for this new offering to augment our already highly social and Socratic pedagogy by providing opportunities for gatherings like virtual “office hours” for students to interact with one another as well as their instructor(s) in between classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also recognize that many already under-resourced organizations are facing immense pressure to “go virtual” and collaborate with colleagues and constituents completely online. This is why we feel that our decision to begin facilitating live chat and to offer these resources for free to interested members of the public is the next logical step in &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic.html&quot;&gt;our committment to do what we can to support our community&lt;/a&gt; during this extended period of social distancing and other hardships. Although we don’t have the resources necessary for making this a round-the-clock operation, our small teaching team will be taking turns moderating the public channel and doing their best to answer whatever technical questions you have on a volunteer basis (within reasonable limits, of course). If you’d like to support us in this, please consider &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;making a donation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you’ll stop by and say hello to us, and one another, soon! See you at an &lt;a href=&quot;/events/upcoming/&quot;&gt;upcoming webinar&lt;/a&gt; or, now, in the community chat!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Tech Learning Collective is pleased to invite you to our new community chat channels. Current and former students also now have access to private chat channels for staying in touch with their classmates even after their course ends. The semi-moderated public rooms are part of our continuing effort to integrate distance learning opportunities for the general public during the global response to the COVID-19 healthcare emergency.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.chat-rooms-chat-bubbles.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.chat-rooms-chat-bubbles.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">One way we’re doing what we can to support our community during the coronavirus pandemic</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One way we're doing what we can to support our community during the coronavirus pandemic" /><published>2020-03-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic.html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, we at Tech Learning Collective were busy &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/02/28/introducing-live-instruction-webinars-and-free-online-practice-labs.html&quot; title=&quot;Read our webinar introduction announcement.&quot;&gt;adapting&lt;/a&gt; our in-person donation-based and low-cost computer training classes designed for people who are underrepresented in the tech sector to an online training format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; spurred to do this because of coronavirus (we started this process before anyone had heard of the pandemic), but we’re writing now to remind you about it in light of these recent events. Unfortunately, many of our peer groups who do similar work teaching underprivileged people about computer technology have cancelled their events, closed continuing education classrooms, or postponed their educational meetings. Due to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20200315184949/https://www.nypl.org/about/coronavirus&quot;&gt;closure of NY Public Libraries&lt;/a&gt;, for instance, numerous community groups no longer have meeting spaces available to them. It is sad to see so many noble efforts curtailed this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While they have been doing their best to transition to an online learning model, Tech Learning Collective was fortunate in that we began this transition quite a while ago and so we were unexpectedly prepared for the ramifications of “social distancing” without even intending to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that for over two months now, Tech Learning Collective has more than quadrupled the number of total events we run, and we’re continuing to increase our online student capacity every week. We’ve also lowered prices across the board, making it even easier for people who otherwise would not have a chance to get started learning about computer technology or online digital safety to do so affordably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We figured that as New York City and other municipalities begin to further enforce closures of public spaces, and as bars, restaurants, cafes, and other community centers are voluntarily closing to help &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2020/world/corona-simulator/&quot;&gt;flatten the epidemic peak&lt;/a&gt; of COVID-19 and assist our healthcare system in supporting all the people who may need urgent medical care, many people may be experiencing changing social dynamics as they spend more time at home and away from friends, peers, or colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, a climate of fear is ripe for abuse, and that’s exactly what we’ve seen happen. Earlier this week, malware authors have started taking advantage of the panic by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibtimes.com/russians-hack-johns-hopkins-coronavirus-map-steal-user-information-2939424&quot;&gt;working coronavirus information into phishing campaigns&lt;/a&gt; designed to steal personal information and compromise computer accounts. This makes it even more important for individuals to keep their guard up when clicking on links in social media, email, and other remote communications, something that isn’t always easy to remember in times of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of this, we have chosen to &lt;em&gt;further&lt;/em&gt; increase the rate of our online events and, for the foreseeable future, our teaching staff has volunteered to facilitate repeats of workshops across different times of the day and on weekends in order to provide more activities (and, admittedly, some distraction) for anyone who feels up for it. In particular, we are partnering with more groups to host our “&lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Gone-Phishing-How-to-Recognize-Fake-Websites-and-Other-Online-Scams&quot;&gt;Gone Phishing&lt;/a&gt;” awareness training and are preparing additional learning modules that we plan to host for free as part of our open-access Foundations courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Foundations courses, which we are accelerating our work on, is our series of completely free, self-paced, in-browser digital security exercises. You can go through them without ever leaving your Web browser. A couple of these modules are already published on our Web site, and we hope to add more in the coming weeks. You can find them, day or night, on &lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/&quot;&gt;our Web site’s “Foundations” page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please consider joining us for any of &lt;a href=&quot;/events/upcoming/&quot;&gt;these events&lt;/a&gt;, and telling anyone in your social network who feels restless, is having trouble due to cabin fever, or otherwise wants to take the opportunity to spend a couple of hours taking a break from reading the news about our remote workshop options. We’re also happy to extend further discounts on a case-by-case basis. If you have any questions, &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; via email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;/events/&quot;&gt;a full schedule of our online events, including event details, see our Web site’s “Events” page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, of course, if you have any additional ideas for how we can work together to help make the next couple of months easier, please don’t hesitate to reach out about that as well. Take care, give care.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Earlier this year, we at Tech Learning Collective were busy adapting our in-person donation-based and low-cost computer training classes designed for people who are underrepresented in the tech sector to an online training format.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.laptop-table-for-bed.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.laptop-table-for-bed.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing live instruction webinars and free online practice labs</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/02/28/introducing-live-instruction-webinars-and-free-online-practice-labs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing live instruction webinars and free online practice labs" /><published>2020-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/02/28/introducing-live-instruction-webinars-and-free-online-practice-labs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/02/28/introducing-live-instruction-webinars-and-free-online-practice-labs.html">&lt;p&gt;At the end of last year, we invited the Tech Learning Collective community to our year-end conference, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/&quot;&gt;Hackers Next
Door&lt;/a&gt;. It was an &lt;em&gt;incredible&lt;/em&gt; event, with over 100 participants and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/2019/speakers/&quot;&gt;more than 25 speakers&lt;/a&gt; who inspired and challenged us to find new and more effective ways to build power in our communities. After a much needed break to recuperate but also to celebrate, our team is back with an expanded lineup of workshops and events, and more opportunities than ever before for you to take your skills to the next level, with remote/virtual/online-only webinars on topics like &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Collaboration-Across-Universes-Basics-of-Version-Control-with-Git&quot;&gt;collaboration with Git&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Taming-Daemons-System-Administration-and-Operation-Basics&quot;&gt;system administration basics&lt;/a&gt;, and more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-webinar-remote-workshops&quot;&gt;New Webinar (Remote) Workshops&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One unexpected but wonderful thing about the Hackers Next Door conference was how many people came to New York just for our event!  Attendees arrived from places such as Michigan and Colorado and as far away as California. And although the conference still focused on the local issues facing New Yorkers, with speakers from advocacy groups such as the Atlantic Plaza Towers Tenants Association who are fighting the installation of racist facial recognition software in their apartment complex, these otherwise “remote” attendees brought value and perspective all their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, we regularly heard from folks that they would love more opportunities to participate in Tech Learning Collective events, if only they could find the time or, y’know, lived in New York City in the first place! Well, we’ve been working hard to harvest two carrots with one fist (and stop throwing stones at birds). That’s why you’re invited to our upcoming workshop webinars!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective workshop webinars are 100% online events. There are no physical classrooms and so there’s nowhere you need to go, and no need to find clean clothes! Although, y’know, maybe wear clean clothes regardless. Anyway! All you need is access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of Google Chrome or Mozilla Firefox along with a fast Internet connection. In other words, if you can Netflix ’n’ chill, you have all the equipment you need to level up your h4x0r skill by attending a Tech Learning Collective webinar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like all our in-person events, our webinars are facilitated by our team of technical experts and expert teachers. This means that when you sign up, you’ll be joining a video conference with a human instructor, not a bot or a dated recording. You’ll be able to interact with the instructor via voice and video as well as with other students to tackle challenges, solve problems, and learn together. The bi-directional, real-time screen sharing options makes it easy to follow along as the instructor demonstrates how to do things like &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Clearing-Away-the-Clouds-How-Computer-Networks,-Servers,-and-the-Internet-Work&quot;&gt;sniff packets&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/The-Web-as-a-Language-What-No-One-Ever-Told-You-About-HTML-That-You-Didn't-Know-to-Ask&quot;&gt;create Web sites&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/The-Imitation-Game-Introduction-to-Administering-Virtual-Machine-Systems&quot;&gt;manage virtual machines&lt;/a&gt;, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just as with our in-person events, we’ve retained our tiered pricing structure to help ensure queer-identified, femme, PoC, and other people who have traditionally been overlooked in the tech sector have access, too. What’s more, since our own overhead is lower for webinars than they are for physical venues, we’ve decided to pass these savings on to you by dropping the price of tickets for our “remote” events by almost 30% across each price tier. There’s never been a better or less expensive way to learn the foundations of computer technology as solidly as this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;/events/&quot;&gt;our events page&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/events/upcoming/#export-event-calendar&quot;&gt;subscribe to our calendar&lt;/a&gt; to see what workshops we have coming up and to sign up for access. For more information, consult our &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;Workshops and Webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-self-paced-beginners-courses&quot;&gt;Free, Self-paced Beginner’s Courses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of learning the foundations of computer technology, we’ve also been hard at work preparing our first ever self-paced course that we’re calling the &lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s Foundations&lt;/a&gt; series. This is a series of introductory learning modules that you can use to jump-start your learing before you ever join us at one of our events, because they are all offered via our Web site. This means the Foundations courses are available anytime, day or night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s more, since we’ve designed our Foundations series to be entirely self-paced, we’re offering the whole course completely free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our Foundations series is free and always available, you can take as long as you need to work through it. Start with our &lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/#foundations-command-line-basics&quot;&gt;Foundations: Command Line Basics&lt;/a&gt; course, which introduces you to a computer terminal, one of the most important foundations of the rest of our curriculum. We’re launching with a limited selection of free materials, but are planning to expand the free courses with more labs over time, so check back regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-practice-labs-of-advanced-scenarios&quot;&gt;Free Practice Labs of Advanced Scenarios&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’ve decided to reuse the same infrastructure we deployed for our self-paced courses to put together some more bite-sized learning modules of additional, more advanced scenarios such as &lt;a href=&quot;/sample/scaling-ssh-authentication-with-certificates.html&quot;&gt;Scaling SSH Authentication with Certificates&lt;/a&gt;. If you’ve been on the fence about whether or not you should come to one of our instructor-led workshop trainings or have questions about the kind of material we teach in our intensive courses, you can try your hand at these sample scenarios to get a taste for the rest of our curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, nothing can compare to learning directly from a teacher whom you can actually see and ask questions of in real time. That’s why we’re looking forward to continuing to partner with groups around New York City to expand our in-person training, and invite you or your organization to &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; about booking a private group training for your volunteers or colleagues. In the mean time, though, we hope that these self-paced learning modules will whet your appetite until your next (or first) class with us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Tech Learning Collective is excited to offer free, self-paced beginner courses along with new webinar workshops that make it easier than ever before to level up your h4x0r skillz. If you can Netflix &amp;lsquo;n&amp;rsquo; chill, you have all the equipment you need to participate in a webinar and tackle technical problems with our team of technical experts and expert teachers. Learn more about our free online &amp;ldquo;Foundations&amp;rdquo; curriculum series and our new webinar events in this post.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured-image.webinars.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured-image.webinars.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AwesomeNYC announces Tech Learning Collective as winner of its December 2019 grant</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/12/17/awesomenyc-announces-tech-learning-collective-as-winner-of-its-december-2019-grant.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AwesomeNYC announces Tech Learning Collective as winner of its December 2019 grant" /><published>2019-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/12/17/awesomenyc-announces-tech-learning-collective-as-winner-of-its-december-2019-grant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/12/17/awesomenyc-announces-tech-learning-collective-as-winner-of-its-december-2019-grant.html">&lt;p&gt;On the heels of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20191212203844/https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/&quot;&gt;Hackers Next Door 2019&lt;/a&gt; conference, we were excited to learn that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.awesomefoundation.org/en/projects/132070-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;AwesomeNYC has just announced that it will be awarding its December 2019 grant to Tech Learning Collective&lt;/a&gt;! AwesomeNYC is the New York City chapter of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.awesomefoundation.org/&quot;&gt;the Awesome Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, “an ever-growing worldwide community devoted to forwarding the interest of awesome in the universe.” In addition to naming Tech Learning Collective as the winner of their final grant offered in calendar year 2019, AwesomeNYC shared information about Tech Learning Collective programs on their Web site and in their newsletter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. By providing educational opportunities in the form of public &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/pricing/#groups&quot;&gt;private trainings&lt;/a&gt;, and community convergences such as the recent Hackers Next Door 2019 conference, Tech Learning Collective empowers otherwise underserved communities by bringing world-class digital security trainers, legal experts, and experienced activists together with local community groups, neighborhood coalitions, and tenants associations so that they can learn from one another’s experience and perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;At the recent Hackers Next Door 2019 conference generously sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triangleartsnyc.org/&quot;&gt;Triangle Arts Association&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://techahoy.org/&quot;&gt;TechAhoy, Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, a local maker space in Queens, Tech Learning Collective was honored to host, among others, the Atlantic Plaza Towers Tenants Association and a member of their legal team from Legal Services NYC as they shared details of their fight against the implementation of racist facial recognition software in their homes. Conference attendees also heard from organizers of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nonewjails.nyc/&quot;&gt;No New Jails NYC&lt;/a&gt; campaign who are defending New Yorkers from the expansion of the carceral industry, and the Executive Directors of both the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stopspying.org/&quot;&gt;Surveillance Technology Oversight Project&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://torproject.org/&quot;&gt;Tor Project&lt;/a&gt; who are working on improving legal and technical tools to protect privacy and civil rights locally and globally.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In collaboration with artists, hacklabs, makerspaces, independent bookstores, and local businesses, Tech Learning Collective further facilitates direct community participation in the construction and operation of autonomous digital infrastructure services focused on providing for the community’s and neighborhood’s own needs.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s partners and benefiting organizations include projects such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://shiftctrl.space/&quot;&gt;Shift-CTRL Space&lt;/a&gt;, whose work maintaining and expanding hyperlocal digital services supporting social justice movements offers Tech Learning Collective students practical experience in numerous specialized Information Technology fields. Through our partnerships with Shift-CTRL Space and similar community organizations, Tech Learning Collective students can build on their classroom or workshop trainings by getting involved in real-life projects that require skills such as network and site reliability engineering, development operations, and computer security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We at Tech Learning Collective are incredibly grateful to the AwesomeNYC trustees for their support and their contribution. While our team takes some time off over the holidays to recuperate from an intense couple of months of conference organizing, winning this grant renews our commitment to providing the highest quality education in the areas of foundational computer and cybersecurity literacy in order to materially empower our students and workshop participants. We’re looking forward to continuing our work to make sure 2020 looks less like 1984 than the past decade has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d also like to help support Shift-CTRL Space or any of our benefiting organizations through Tech Learning Collective, &lt;a href=&quot;/events/upcoming/#export-event-calendar&quot;&gt;subscribe to our event calendar from the Events page&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;make a direct donation on the Donate page&lt;/a&gt; of our Web site.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Tech Learning Collective is announced as the winner of the latest Awesome Foundation grant provided by the organization&amp;rsquo;s New York City chapter. Read this post to learn more about AwesomeNYC and why they selected Tech Learning Collective as the recipient of their final grant in 2019.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/logo.featured.awesome-foundation.gif" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/logo.featured.awesome-foundation.gif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hackers Next Door featured on It’s Going Down’s podcast, “This Is America” Episode 97</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/11/28/hackers-next-door-featured-on-its-going-down-podcast-this-is-america-episode-97.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hackers Next Door featured on It&amp;rsquo;s Going Down&amp;rsquo;s podcast, &amp;ldquo;This Is America&amp;rdquo; Episode 97" /><published>2019-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/11/28/hackers-next-door-featured-on-its-going-down-podcast-this-is-america-episode-97</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/11/28/hackers-next-door-featured-on-its-going-down-podcast-this-is-america-episode-97.html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, members of the Hackers Next Door and Tech Learning Collective conference organizing team were interviewed for the &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itsgoingdown.org/category/podcast/this-is-america/&quot;&gt;This is America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt; podcast produced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://itsgoingdown.org/&quot;&gt;It’s Going Down&lt;/a&gt;, a digital community center for anarchist, anti-fascist, autonomous anti-capitalist and anti-colonial movements. Featured on the podcast’s 97&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; episode alongside the NYC Anarchist Black Cross’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://nycabc.wordpress.com/fang/&quot;&gt;Project FANG&lt;/a&gt;, the Hackers Next Door conference interview segment touches on topics such as the suppression of queer, femme, and PoC representation in tech, &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/07/22/want-to-get-good-with-computers-dont-start-with-code.html&quot;&gt;resisting the school-to-corporation pipeline’s “learn to code (to get a job)” mentality&lt;/a&gt;, and building collective power beyond mere voter representation through actionable cybersecurity and IT education for local community projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen to the full &lt;a href=&quot;https://itsgoingdown.org/this-is-america-97-notagainsu-project-fang-nyc-radical-tech-conference/&quot;&gt;This Is America podcast episode on the It’s Going Down website&lt;/a&gt;. Our interview segment starts approximately 39 minutes into the episode. We’ve also provided &lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/its-going-down-this-is-america-episode-97-hackers-next-door.mp3&quot;&gt;a truncated copy of the episode&lt;/a&gt; with a transcript republished below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;controls&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/its-going-down-this-is-america-episode-97-hackers-next-door.mp3&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0 auto; width: 100%;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/its-going-down-this-is-america-episode-97-hackers-next-door.mp3&quot;&gt;Download the audio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://itsgoingdown.org/this-is-america-97-notagainsu-project-fang-nyc-radical-tech-conference/&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[INTRO MUSIC]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s Going Down: Welcome, to &lt;em&gt;This Is America&lt;/em&gt;, November 27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this episode, first we speak with someone from Project FANG about their project and current fundraising appeal, which seeks to provide direct support and material aid to earth and animal liberation, as well as Standing Rock prisoners.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We then &lt;a href=&quot;https://itsgoingdown.org/hackers-next-door-conference-radical-digital-security-and-privacy-conference-nyc-december-14-15/&quot;&gt;speak with several participants&lt;/a&gt; in an upcoming radical digital security and privacy conference entitled, Hackers Next Door, which will take place in New York in December.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We then launch into a discussion about moving beyond simply “mobilizing” in an age of social media and also a continuing analysis of the Trump impeachment crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;All this and more, but first, let’s get to the news!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[FADE TO NEXT SEGMENT]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s Going Down: Can you introduce yourselves real quick?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Sure, my name is Wirefall.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: You can call me Violet. We’re both from Tech Learning Collective and we’re organizing this Hackers Next Door conference in December.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;IGD: Awesome! So, before we get started talking about the conference, tell us a little bit about how you got involved in tech circles, playing around with computers, how did that start?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Um, yeah! Do you want me to go first?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Go for it, you have a good story.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: I actually have a non-technical background, in a way. I liked playing with computers and in particular making them do things that they weren’t necessarily designed to do, but I was kind of discouraged from exploring that further because the culture around that was so awful. So for the longest time, I shunned everything having to do with digital technology because, again, the people around it were so nasty to me. And then I met Violet and they had a completely different philosophy and a completely different approach to digital technologies, so I started learning a lot from them and it kind of just spiraled out of there ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah. It was partly out of the Tech Learning Collective because I was involved with TLC when the two of us met and I’d been doing cybersecurity trainings, and had kind of been into political circles and privacy rights and this sort of stuff by then for a number of years. So the ability to do something with tech that wasn’t like, “Oh, now I gotta go find a job and work for the fucking surveillance state,” or whatever it is that they’re doing, was appealing and for me it was just a continuation of the other political work that I was doing. I actually got into privacy rights advocacy in digital stuff because I was politically vocal and then I realized that as a target online, I was like, “Oh shit, I have to be serious about this,” and so that’s when I started learning about, y’know, cypherpunk-esque stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;IGD: How did you all come to the point of creating a conference. Like, why should there be a conference about political hacking?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Right! I mean, this is actually something that people in at least the tri-state area have been talking about doing for a little while, and it just hasn’t come together. So, we’ve been wanting to see—we as in Tech Learning Collective itself but y’know also the other groups that are doing this in the city. Tech Learning Collective is an Electronic Frontier Alliance member, there are a lot of other Electronic Frontier Alliance members, this is like an EFF grassroots coalition, and we basically realized that this was a conversation happening amongst EFA member groups and small, like, DSA chapters, and little sort of CryptoParty one-offs that have been going on in the New York and the tri-state area for a while, and it just hadn’t come together in any sort of bigger way. So it felt to us like, y’know, this was a really ripe opportunity. It was something that people already really wanted to do and all that was missing was some group that had the commitment and the space to do it in. And so, as Tech Learning Collective, we have a semi-permanent residency in the DUMBO neighborhood thanks to some really great people and relationships that we have with the Triangle Arts Association and so we were like, “Hey, y’know, we have space for this. It’s just a matter of doing it.” And so, a little earlier this year, we were like, y’know, let’s just fucking do it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So we started sending out invitations to everyone who we respected and knew that was doing some similar work, and also one of the most exciting things about this conference is that it’s not just the sort of, like, y’know, for lack of a diplomatic way to put it, just the incestuous and nepotic circle. This is a conference to which we’ve invited actual people affected by things like facial recognition surveillance. We’ve invited the No New Jails folks, we’ve invited the Atlantic Plaza Towers Tenant Advocates in addition to the people who are sort of already well-known and established in the digital security and privacy rights worlds, like the Freedom of the Press Foundation, and the Tor Project, and the Surveillance Technology Oversight Project, and Calyx Institute, I’m sure there’s someone else that I’m forgetting on this list.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Yeah, and I think that’s like a long list of these kind of major recognizable names, or I should say recognizable in that kind of circle. For me what’s really exciting about doing this conference in the way that we’re doing it is I’m much more interested in seeing what’s happening on a grassroots level and there are a lot of people here who are doing kind of guerrilla grassroots organizing around this topic and to get those people in the same room, based in the same city, as a lot of these larger names is an attempt in a certain way to even the playing field and kind of like bring some sobriety to the larger names and bring some more recognition and also power in a sense to the grassroots organizers.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: And resources! Like actual resources.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: That’s what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah, like, it’s one thing to be donating money to these huge non-profits and it’s a whole other thing to see what people who are actually dealing with cameras in their fucking houses are doing to combat that shit from landlords and stuff. And that is an exciting thing. And having those two conversations, I think, not happening in opposition to each other but being recognized as fueling one another, is something that I don’t see in a lot of privacy rights advocacy. I guess I should say I don’t see enough of in privacy rights advocacy, and certainly not in a cybersecurity sector.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: So putting that together, I think, is I think necessary and also just there needs to be more of that. Otherwise, you’re not going to get this sort of bottom-up approach to online privacy. You’re only going to get the legislative, y’know, “let’s have the government fucking fix things,” and that doesn’t work. We know that doesn’t work! That can not be all of the story. And so, putting that front-and-center—not to say that legislation isn’t useful, it obviously helps, but that happens only as a response to things that people in their local communities are actually doing day-to-day. So putting that together explicitly is exciting, it’s certainly, like I said, not been done enough, and I think it’s actually the thing that fuels both sides of this particular coin really well.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And y’know, the point is, how’d it started? Well, people just said that they needed that. And then we were like, let’s just fucking do it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;IGD: Let’s talk about the conference itself. When is it going to happen? Where is it going to be at? And also, what are the kinds of workshops and sessions that we should expect to see. I looked over the schedule and it looks really exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Yeah, we’re really, really excited about it as well. So, it’s taking place on December 14th and 15th of this year [2019], 11 AM to 10 PM for both days. So it’s a two-full day conference. And then we have different blocks that we’ve placed different speakers in. So, the first block of the first two days is called “Racist Policing Then and Now,” which I just mention that it’s the first block because I’ve been sort of joking about: it’s like people are going to come in, it’s like, “Good morning! Let’s talk about racist policing.” And I kind of like am a fan of that. We’re going to be talking about community initiatives, we’re going to be talking about fighting the surveillance state. People like Albert Fox Cahn from the Surveillance Technology Oversight Project are going to be there, some people are gonna talk about Tor and the quote-unquote “Dark Web,” so we’re going to have Isabela Bagueros, the Executive Director of the Tor Project is going to be there. And then of course, as I said before, I’m very excited to hear from the Tenant Advocates of the Atlantic Plaza Towers, which is a residential building in Brownsville, and they’ve been fighting their landlord on the implementation of facial recognition in their building for a year. So super excited about that. Do you want to talk a little bit about that?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah, so, the whole conference is single-track, which is to say that there’s only one presentation happening at a time. It’s gonna be, as we’ve said, at our semi-permanent residency at Triangle Arts Association in Brooklyn’s DUMBO neighborhood. So that’s basically just on the river accessible via the F train, or the A train I suppose. And it’s, um, gonna be that main presentation room, and a small hallway, and some maybe BoF (Birds of a Feather) sort of tracks, conversations for people to have if they get particularly inspired by one of the presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And the reason we’re doing single-track is because, again, we wanna have that—I’m sure you’ve gone to conferences, right, and there’s a really big-name speaker and a really local advocacy group that not as many people know about, and everyone goes to see the big name speaker and the local advocacy group gets like five people in the room. Y’know, and that’s, we don’t want that to happen. So we’ve elongated the conference’s schedule. We actually had to add like two hours or four hours to the conference because we started getting so many people saying they would like to speak from our invitation list, and decided to go single-track so that you always had a thing that was happening.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And then as people said yes, as the people we were inviting were like, “Yeah, I’d love to speak,” and they responded to our invitations, the topic of the conference sort of formed around that. Obviously, it was skewed because, y’know, I’m a dyed-in-the-wool Anarchist and Tech Learning Collective has a very political bent generally, but the fact that we ended up with, like, “Community Initiatives” as a single block, like “Fighting the Surveillance State” as a block, “Racist Policing Then and Now” as a block for our conversation is because the people who said yes, who we really wanted to see, this is what they’re doing. Black Movement Law Project will be talking about the evolution of the police from Pinkertons all the way to the Police State now. And so, it became clear that these are the topics that grassroots organizations in New York and the tri-state area are working on right now. Anti-surveillance is a big thing. It kind of molded itself around the speakers, which is kind of nice, I think. It made scheduling not that hard!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Yeah, that’s true!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;IGD: One of the things I think that’s interesting is that we’re in a time where social movements right now are using technology now more than ever and it also seems like the stakes are higher in terms of just the threat of online surveillance by corporate actors or States, or people on the far-right. I still feel like there’s still a division between kind of, like, oh there are those nerds over there with their computers and like everybody else. Where there needs to kind of like, we need to find each other and be able to share skills. A lot of us really need to catch up in terms of just building online, electronic self-defense and learning a lot of tech skills. I think a lot of use so much technology all the time, and y’know, hopefully we’re all using things like Signal, and basic practices of self-defense, but I really feel like we need to catch up where the rest of the world is.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah. I mean, yes. For what it’s worth, this is literally what Tech Learning Collective was founded on. TLC, Tech Learning Collective, is sort of the progenitor of this conference, if you will, and it was exactly that sentiment that started not just Tech Learning Collective, but then has guided the mission of TLC to do things like this conference in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Y’know, we’re a small production, we don’t have huge numbers of donors or financiers or anything, so that’s part and parcel of what lets us do things like invite these hyperlocal groups and put front and center “Racist Policing Now and Then.” I mean when was the last time you saw a cybersecurity event, with real hacking demonstrations, y’know, offensive techniques—Anarcho-Tech NYC is going to be there doing actual hacking demos like phishing and ARP cache poisoning and stuff—right with a discussion about how cyberwarfare has also come to be part and parcel of class warfare. Y’know, in the conference’s sort of—when we were conceiving it, one of the things that was very clear was that today, most people in America at least seem to experience technology as a form of class oppression because it’s literally designed to do that from corporations. Like, that’s the point of it. You don’t put a surveillance camera in someone’s home if that person is rich. You only do that to people who are less wealthy. And that’s class warfare, point-blank.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So, yeah, my point being that TLC was designed specifically to help people who needed to catch up catch up. And not catch up to get a job, right? And this is, like, I think an important distinction. It wasn’t like—there’s this narrative of “get a good tech job, go into an office, and be comfortable, and that’ll get you out of poverty.” It’s bullshit, for so many reasons, but not least of which is that that doesn’t help your community. Y’know, now you’re literally working for Jeff Bezos or some other person building tools that are actively extracting time, effort, money, from local communities that need it. But that doesn’t mean that technology itself is the problem there. It means that the way that technology is being used is extractive and not valuable for the people who are actually living under oppressive regimes.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We can also use technology to help out, and I kind of want to get back to this point of Tech Learning Collective was founded by a bunch of radicals who basically got arrested and were like, “Shit, our phones are compromised, how do we figure this out?” So we started just teaching each other about exactly that thing back before the Trump election even, and then shortly thereafter Trump got elected, and what happened was that we started getting this inundated flood of like, what do we do now? Signal became suddenly a big deal, and then there was a bunch of Signal trainings, right? Like, get off txt, use Signal. So that was the beginning of the catching up. And it was very clear very early on that those of us who have been self-educating about this for a little while, those of us who have had a bit more experience such as myself could not meet the demand. It was just too many people having too many questions about too many things to work if it was all gonna be put on a small group of individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So, that is where originally Anarcho-Tech NYC’s Train the Trainers project came from, from there Tech Learning Collective got formed specifically to address those needs. So Tech Learning Collective students are primarily people of marginalized communities, people of color, women, queer folks, femmes. Our pricing structure reflects that, y’know, the conference has a reduced price tier. Almost like, I don’t know if you’re familiar with queer parties often have two tiers. Y’know, cismen, and queers and femmes? We basically took that model and applied it to cybersecurity education. So if you come to a Tech Learning Collective workshop, one of the things you’ll notice is that our donation-based scale has two suggested tiers. One for queers and femmes and other folks who are marginalized from mainstream cybersecurity education, and everybody else. And that’s not like a wall, we’re not policing people’s gender identity when they walk in the room, but it’s a very strong signal that this what we’re about and this is what we’re for and this is why we exist. And it’s exactly to address that thing that you mentioned, where there’s this huge digital divide, a big gap, between who’s been able to take advantage of the better parts of technology, the way it can actually make our lives better, get us to be more efficient, have more individual power, and then actually build collective actions from that as opposed to just “get out the vote campaigns” and everyone else who’s now, y’know, working at fucking Palantir and building cyberweapons while telling themselves they’re stopping sex trafficking and patting themselves on the back or some shit like that.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So…. I realize that was a bit of rant, I apologize.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: I was also just going to say, too, that you got really close to saying the thing that I like to say about the pricing tiers and things like that, sliding scale stuff, which is that it’s a banner, not a wall.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: And it actually has been a really effective signal to tell other people that we are really serious about our politics and mostly also about our culture and what kind of culture we want to have when we’re teaching this kind of stuff. I think there’s two things that come to mind as we’re talking about this for me, one of which is that a lot of the training that’s out there is purely defensive and very surface, which is fine, because sometimes you just need a bandaid. Like, sometimes, you just need to do something now. But I think where TLC likes to come in is to try to drill down and to get deeper into these things so that the people who are interested in doing so can actually start to self-empower rather than just be constantly responding to a threat. And in that sense, we hope that, y’know, this tooling can be reappropriated for building autonomy, actually. And the culture thing is really important, like I said. I didn’t touch computers for the longest time because I hated the people that were around them, and it’s sort of this weird balance between, exactly what you were saying, like, “those nerds over there” or whatever. And especially on the Left, there’s a lot of technophobia because it’s this giant, aww, it’s this massive thing that’s everywhere and it’s scary and it’s always in the context of colonization, and it’s always like this. And it’s like, well, what if we could carve out our own path to these things. We could use them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah. I think that’s a really good point, actually. I just wanna double-down on what you were saying. Y’know, one of the unique things about Tech Learning Collective is that we actually have offensive classes. That’s not to say, well, it’s always for quote “educational purposes only,” but y’know, if you don’t know what a punch is, trying to show people how to defend against a punch is going to be very hard because you’ve never actually talked about the thing that you’re trying to defend against. So if you don’t show somebody how to throw a punch, it’s going to be very hard to teach them how to block one. And it’s the same thing in cybersecurity. If you don’t know how to steal a username and password, then you’re not really going to be as sensitized to when that is happening to you. So we show both sides. We will show phishing attacks, and we will show how to defend against those same attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And this is exactly what, y’know, corporations do when they have internal Red Teams and pentests and this sort of stuff. They do that, too. Just because a corporation does it doesn’t mean we shouldn’t do it. We should do it for different ends and we should do it with a better culture, but we still need to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;IGD: Past the conference, what kind of things do you hope to see to kind of get some of this stuff that we’ve been talking about in place?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: For me there are a couple of things. This conference, it’s the first iteration. And for me I’m treating it like a little bit of a sapling that I’d like to see grow into a forest. And I think that that’s going to happen by creating these opportunities to build these relationships. And I really wanted to say to the people who come—I’m probably going to mention this at the opening remarks at some point—that, y’know, I think a lot of conferences in particular have this model where it’s like, “We’re all here together for this day,” or these two days, or this week or whatever it is, and then once it’s over you have to go back to your quote-unquote “real life” or whatever. And I want this to not be that. I want this to feed into, like, what our real lives actually already are.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah, I think we have a benefit in that respect because we have so many local groups that are talking.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: So it’s not like, y’know, people are gonna come over to DUMBO and then disperse across necessarily the entire globe again. The majority of people presentation, the majority of people who are coming are tri-state area locals. And that was intentional and it’s good because it means that, like, we can basically try to avoid con-drop by just keep doing this after the fact. Y’know, all these groups that we’ve invited, they have regular meetings many times a month, including TLC. Y’know, we have workshops almost every weekend. So, um, what I hope will come of this is that there will be this continuation.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And I will also say, y’know, especially to folks who don’t have a technical background, that’s okay. No one’s expecting anyone to come out of either this conference or a workshop or a CryptoParty or anything being some kind of, uh—&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Leet superhacker!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: Yeah! But in the same way that you wouldn’t expect to go to, like, a two-hour workshop about residential electrical wiring and then expect to be able to, like, wire a house.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wirefall: Yes!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Violet: It’s an absurd expectation because it’s a skill just like any other. And also, just like electricians, who by the way are an example of a profession that I think is wildly under appreciated in society as opposed to, say, bankers, who are wildly over appreciated, right? You don’t need every single person in your community to be the electrician, or the plumber, or the carpenter. You need those things, you need carpenters, you need plumbers, you need electricians, but you don’t need every single person in your community or group or campaign or movement or whatever to have the same skills. So, it’s not about making sure everyone can be a leet super hacker, it’s about making sure that there is enough of a foundation—like in the same way that you have unions of carpentry workers, or an electrician’s union or whatever, the reason you have that is because you have enough of them to sustain the thing that you’re doing in society, which in this case in this example I guess is wiring houses for electricity. Similarly, we need more people who do have some cybersecurity background, who do have system administration experience, who can be the sort of technical go-tos, and better yet, a lot of people from many different groups do want to be and are excited about being the person who people ask tech questions of, so Tech Learning Collective is intended to train those people. That’s our real front-runners.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Insofar as there is a, like, “those nerds over there” and everybody else dichotomy, then we want those nerds over there who are the nerds who are not just interested in optimizing database queries and making things super fast and cool and talking about crypto endlessly for hours, we want the people who are doing other shit who are also interested or excited, self-motivated, about something to do with computers and we want to train them so that when they go back to whatever campaign or advocacy effort that they are involved, they now have a far better baseline to both explain and train up the people that they’re working with. And also to learn on their own so that we can have more of these equivalents to electricians, if you will, in society generally, and in movements generally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective would like to thank the It’s Going Down team for taking the time to highlight our efforts in support of revolutionary struggles and giving us the opportunity to speak about &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/&quot;&gt;the Hackers Next Door conference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Organizers of Tech Learning Collective&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Next Door conference were interviewed by It&amp;rsquo;s Going Down about the event, how they got involved in digital security education, and the need for more collaborative, in-depth cybersecurity training for activists. Read a transcript of the interview segment here.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.2019-12-14.hackers-next-door-an-infosec-conference.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.2019-12-14.hackers-next-door-an-infosec-conference.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to start catching phishermen before they catch you</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/11/05/how-to-catch-the-phishermen-before-they-catch-you.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to start catching phishermen before they catch you" /><published>2019-11-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/11/05/how-to-catch-the-phishermen-before-they-catch-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/11/05/how-to-catch-the-phishermen-before-they-catch-you.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s note: This is a guest post by Anarcho-Tech NYC, who will be presenting at Tech Learning Collective’s year-end event, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/speakers/#anarcho-tech-nyc&quot;&gt;Hackers Next Door 2019 conference&lt;/a&gt;. Tech Learning Collective is excited to include them on the program this year and to have this opportunity to learn more about their work. Be sure to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/tickets/&quot;&gt;get your con tickets&lt;/a&gt; today so you don’t miss your chance to see them speak at the conference in December!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the “tech antifa,” one of Anarcho-Tech NYC’s missions is defending against the rise or spread of fascism in New York City and the surrounding area. In addition to digital security education, members of our collective often conduct security assessments of an allied group’s cybersecurity posture. When asked, we take a look at how easy it might be to infiltrate antifa communications channels such as secret or closed Facebook groups, Signal threads, e-mail listserves, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-attackers-go-phishing&quot;&gt;How attackers go phishing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps unsurprisingly, the weakest link is often &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the communication tools activists use, like Facebook groups—although if you don’t consider Facebook an enemy of fascism, we have some deeper concerns about your organizing principles. Rather, the weak point in their security is how they use those tools. It’s surprisingly difficult to get activists to pay close enough attention to the warning signs of an attack as it’s happening, probably because even though most antifa know how to throw and defend against a punch, they don’t have any equivalent experience while using their computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, breaking into Facebook or GMail is far harder than tricking you into giving us your Facebook or Google Account password. Bad operational security (“OPSEC”) practices like sharing passwords insecurely are forgivable if the people involved don’t have any cybersecurity education, but activist groups need to start taking online safety seriously if they ever hope to be effective organizing forces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the easiest and most common ways attackers get username and password combinations for other people’s accounts is by getting their targets to try to log in to “spoofed” websites. These are websites that look similar enough to the legitimate website to make the target believe they truly are logging in at the correct place when in fact the site they’re logging in to is actually a fake controlled by the attacker. Once the target types their password into a look-alike website instead of the real one, the game is over and the attacker wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This technique, called &lt;em&gt;phishing&lt;/em&gt;, has become so prevalent that according to several cybersecurity companies there are now more than one and a half million &lt;em&gt;phishing websites&lt;/em&gt; launched every month. Of course, most of these phishing sites are not targeting &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; domains. Instead, they’re creating fake PayPal, Facebook, or other big-name websites. And believe it or not, it’s just as easy to spoof Facebook’s login page as it is to spoof the login page for your group’s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/events/gone-phishing-recognize-online-entrapment-and-other-scams-by-learning-how-to-launch-your-own-phishing-attack-website&quot;&gt;one of our &lt;em&gt;Hackers Next Door&lt;/em&gt; conference sessions, “Gone Phishing: Recognize Online Entrapment and Other Scams by Learning How to Launch Your Own Phishing Attack Website,”&lt;/a&gt; we’ll show you step-by-step how we can compromise the Facebook and social media accounts of our fellow activists by using this same technique. Our goal is to make sure you’ve been exposed to all the dirty tricks attackers try to play to get you to give them your account credentials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’re going to take it one step further and briefly explain how your organization can easily and freely monitor the Internet for signs that phishermen—and yes, the kinds of people who attack anti-fascist and anti-racist activists are usually men—are preparing to go after your members. This advanced defensive technique relies on watching a public ledger called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.certificate-transparency.org/what-is-ct&quot;&gt;Certificate Transparency Log (CTL)&lt;/a&gt; for suspicious issuances of website security certificates and is particularly helpful for groups that maintain their own domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-certificate-transparency-log&quot;&gt;What is the Certificate Transparency Log?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.certificate-transparency.org/_/rsrc/1472780090452/what-is-ct/ct_intro_system.png&quot; alt=&quot;Interaction between CT log servers, monitors, and auditors.&quot; style=&quot;float: right; margin-left: 1em; width: 25%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time, to successfully spoof a target website an attacker needs to first get a security certificate for the website in question. This website security certificate, called a Transport Layer Security (TLS) certificate, is what your Web browser is checking for whenever it shows the padlock icon indicating that you’re visiting a “secured” (HTTPS) website. Each time you load a secured Web page (using HTTPS), your browser compares the domain name of the page you loaded with the domain name embedded in the security certificate. If they match, you see the lock icon. If they don’t, you see a security error page instead of the page you were in the process of loading, and alarm bells start going off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to fool you into thinking that you’re loading your own website’s secured pages, attackers have to get look-alike security certificates. For example, if you run a WordPress site at &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exampleactivist.com&lt;/code&gt;, then an attacker might try getting a certificate for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exampleactivist.com-wp-login-php.com&lt;/code&gt;. This is a completely different website, but after merely a glance at the URL bar, the difference between the URL of the login page to your WordPress blog (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exampleactivist.com/wp-login.php&lt;/code&gt;) and the domain of the phishing site (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exampleactivist.com-wp-login-php.com&lt;/code&gt;) might not immediately stand out to you. This is doubly true if you’ve only been taught to pay attention to the healthy-looking padlock icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, each time a website security certificate is issued by reputable companies, that company records its issuance in a public ledger called the Certificate Transparency Log (CTL). The CTL is a decentralized database, not unlike the BitCoin public ledger. In fact, the implementations of both BitCoin and the Certificate Transparency Log are closely related to the much-hyped “blockchain” technology. The purpose of the CTL is to create a publicly shared, append-only record of every single HTTPS website security certificate ever issued so that the entire Internet community (which includes you!) can see for themselves what domain names have been issued security certificates along with when and by whom those certificates were issued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-certificate-transparency-helps-catch-the-phishers&quot;&gt;How Certificate Transparency helps catch the phishers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under normal circumstances, you or your team should be the only ones requesting certificates for your domain. If you are monitoring the CTL and notice a certificate issued for your domain that you did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; intend, you can be pretty sure something is wrong. Similarly, because the CTL gives you visibility into &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; security certificate issued across &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; domain name, you can search the log looking for certificates issued for domain names that look similar to your own or that match patterns often used to phish members of your group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even better, since the log records certificate issuances in near real time, you can be alerted to a potential phishing site that is going to, but has not yet had the opportunity to actually, target your members. This lets you pre-emptively alert your group’s members that an attack is being prepared before it even gets a chance to phish you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;monitoring-the-ctl-for-suspicious-certificate-issuances&quot;&gt;Monitoring the CTL for suspicious certificate issuances&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the technology’s initial release in 2013, many Certificate Transparency monitoring tools have been developed. Perhaps the simplest is &lt;a href=&quot;https://sslmate.com/certspotter/&quot;&gt;SSLMate’s CertSpotter&lt;/a&gt;. Simply sign-up with a free account and SSLMate will send you an email every time a new certificate for one of your domain names is issued. Unfortunately, the service limits you to monitoring a maximum of 5 domain names. To monitor more than five, you have to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SSLMate/certspotter&quot;&gt;self-host the CertSpotter code yourself&lt;/a&gt;. This makes the free SSLMate service more useful for spotting duplicate certificates than it is for finding look-alike certs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the latter case, we’ll use a free tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/x0rz/phishing_catcher&quot;&gt;Phishing Catcher&lt;/a&gt;, which itself relies on a free service called &lt;a href=&quot;https://certstream.calidog.io/&quot;&gt;CertStream&lt;/a&gt;. The CertStream service is simply a firehose of all new certificates recorded in the CTL wrapped up in a simple to use Application Programming Interface (API). You don’t need to do any coding to use the service, though, because they also supply a command line tool (predictably named &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;certstream&lt;/code&gt;) as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://certstream.calidog.io/static/img/demo1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;CertStream demo showing simple usage from a command line.&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;certstream&lt;/code&gt; command, you can get a running tally of every new TLS certificate recorded in the CTL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the very first things you’ll notice is that there are &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of certificates being issued. Too many, in fact, to manually make sense of. This is where Phishing Catcher comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phishing Catcher reads data from the same firehose, but scores each new record it sees using a simple algorithm to determine if that certificate is “suspicious.” If Phishing Catcher determines that the certificate is not suspicious, the record is ignored. Otherwise, the certificate is deemed either “potentially,” “likely,” or “suspiciously” similar to a possible phishing domain and gets logged to a file. At your earliest convenience, you can then examine this subset of issued certificates to see if they are indeed phishing domains that have been set up to target you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use Phishing Catcher, you must have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; installed on your computer, and then you have to &lt;a href=&quot;https://packaging.python.org/installing/&quot;&gt;install the Python package management tool, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. With those requirements satisfied, Phishing Catcher itself is a simple download from GitHub and a standard &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt; requirements installation invocation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot; data-lang=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;git clone https://github.com/x0rz/phishing_catcher.git
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;phishing_catcher
python &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-m&lt;/span&gt; venv venv      &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Optional, but nice.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;source &lt;/span&gt;venv/bin/activate &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Only necessary if you did the above.&lt;/span&gt;
pip &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-r&lt;/span&gt; requirements.txt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have Phishing Catcher downloaded, you’ll want to edit its configuration file, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;external.yaml&lt;/code&gt;, to customize Phishing Catcher’s behavior for your needs. The tool loads sensible defaults from a second file (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;suspicious.yaml&lt;/code&gt;), but you can adjust or add to both the keywords it contains and the score assigned to each keyword by editing the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;external.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file. For example, in the default file, you’ll see a snippet like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# In file `suspicious.yaml`&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;keywords&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;login'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, a score of 25 “suspicion points” is added to the TLS certificate record when the generic keyword &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;login&lt;/code&gt; is found in its domain name. Increasing this value will raise the level of suspicion against domains with the string &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;login&lt;/code&gt; in them, thus allowing you to subject these certificate issuances to increased scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing from the example above, if you are running an activist group with the domain name &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exampleactivist.com&lt;/code&gt;, then you will probably want to add the string &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exampleactivist&lt;/code&gt; into Phishing Catcher’s &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;keywords&lt;/code&gt; dictionary and give it a pretty high score by adding this string as a key to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;external.yaml&lt;/code&gt; configuration file’s &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;keywords&lt;/code&gt; dictionary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# In file `external.yaml`&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;keywords&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;exampleactivist'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;60&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll also want to include certain permutations of your domain names common in phishing attacks, such as misspellings, letter transpositions (e.g., replacing &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;i&lt;/code&gt;’s with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;l&lt;/code&gt;’s), and so on. (Have a look at tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/elceef/dnstwist&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dnstwist&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to automatically generate this list for you.) Once configured to your liking, running Phishing Catcher is as simple as invoking its main &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;catch_phishing.py&lt;/code&gt; script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot; data-lang=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;./catch_phishing.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/4BGuXkR.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Screencast of example Phishing Catcher usage.&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the terminal output, Phishing Catcher also writes a log file of all certificate issuances it sees that it thinks are suspicious based on the configuration file you supply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we hope you can see, monitoring the Certificate Transparency Logs like this is something cybersecurity Blue Teams of any size can do easily and cheaply as part of an early warning system to detect imminent cyber attacks and potentially alert or better defend the users whose online safety they are partly responsible for protecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re looking forward to going into more detail on this and other techniques that both attackers and defenders in the cybersecurity space use on a daily basis at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s Hackers Next Door conference&lt;/a&gt;. See you then!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Anarcho-Tech NYC</name></author><summary type="html">Remember, remember the tech antifa on the fifth of November! Antifa activists defend against the rise or spread of fascism by combating threats to anti-fascist groups, anti-racist organizers, and others for whom fascist groups pose a clear and present danger. The NYC chapter of the Anarcho-Tech Collective provides computer training for activists and advocacy groups, direct assistance with digital components of advocacy efforts, and private audits of an ally&amp;rsquo;s security posture when requested. At Tech Learning Collective&amp;rsquo;s Hackers Next Door conference in December and in this blog post, anonymous members from Anarcho-Tech NYC will show you how attackers work and think so you know how to first spot and then stop them in their tracks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.gone-phishing-how-to-recognize-fake-websites-and-other-online-scams.blue.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.gone-phishing-how-to-recognize-fake-websites-and-other-online-scams.blue.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">At Hackers Next Door, national tech and policy groups meet with local privacy activists and cybersecurity experts</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/11/01/press-release-hackers-next-door-2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="At Hackers Next Door, national tech and policy groups meet with local privacy activists and cybersecurity experts" /><published>2019-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/11/01/press-release-hackers-next-door-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/11/01/press-release-hackers-next-door-2019.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracy Whelan&lt;br /&gt;
Tech Learning Collective Media Relations Associate&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:techlearningcollective@riseup.net?subject=PRESS%20INQUIRY:%20Hackers%20Next%20Door%202019&quot;&gt;techlearningcollective@riseup.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At Hackers Next Door, national tech and policy groups meet with local privacy activists and cybersecurity experts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;November  1, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BROOKLYN, New York&lt;/em&gt; — For two full days from 11AM to 10PM on December 14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; and 15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, New Yorkers fighting against invasive corporate and dragnet government surveillance will share the stage with national technology law and policy watchdogs at &lt;em&gt;Hackers Next Door 2019&lt;/em&gt;, an information security and social technology conference featuring presentations by the best of the tri-state area’s cybersecurity trainers, privacy rights advocacy groups, activist networks, and their constituencies. The weekend conference will be hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective&lt;/a&gt;, an apprenticeship-based technology school via their semi-permanent residency with &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/sponsors/#triangle-arts-association&quot;&gt;Triangle Arts Association&lt;/a&gt; located at 20 Jay Street in Brooklyn’s DUMBO neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conference organizers cite the need to help grassroots campaigns and local community groups put more pressure on lawmakers and the for-profit technology sector to protect the civil and privacy rights of tenants and other Internet users as a driving force behind the event. “We chose to feature the work of local, grassroots activists alongside more established non-profits because we believe in the power of ‘bottom-up’ organizing,” said Tracy Whelan, a spokesperson for the conference. “The national conversation is ultimately driven by what happens on the local level, and we wanted to highlight that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference’s speaker lineup includes representatives from &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/speakers/#freedom-of-the-press-foundation-fpf&quot;&gt;Freedom of the Press Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, which maintains the SecureDrop open source whistleblower submission system and names NSA whistleblower Edward Snowden as a member of its Board of Directors; Isabela Bagueros, Executive Director of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/speakers/#tor-project&quot;&gt;Tor Project&lt;/a&gt;, makers of the Tor Browser; Davi Ottenheimer, Chief Security Architect for World Wide Web inventor Sir Tim Berners-Lee’s new venture, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/speakers/#inrupt-inc&quot;&gt;Inrupt, Inc.&lt;/a&gt;; and Executive Director of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/speakers/#surveillance-technology-oversight-project-stop&quot;&gt;Surveillance Technology Oversight Project (S.T.O.P.)&lt;/a&gt; Albert Fox Cahn, Esq., who has been a frequent commentator on civil rights for publications such as The New York Times, Slate, NBC Think, Newsweek, and the N.Y. Daily News and whose organization helps craft privacy laws such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stopspying.org/post-act&quot;&gt;Public Oversight of Surveillance Technology (POST) Act&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also on the program are &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/speakers/#atlantic-plaza-towers-tenants-association&quot;&gt;tenants of the Atlantic Plaza Towers complex&lt;/a&gt;, who are fighting against their landlord’s plans to force them to submit to facial recognition algorithms to access their homes; members of the semi-elusive &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/speakers/#shift-ctrl-space&quot;&gt;Shift-CTRL Space&lt;/a&gt; hacklab who are building community-owned Internet and intranet infrastructure in Queens; and Brooklyn-based creative technologist &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/speakers/#afrotectopia&quot;&gt;Ari Melenciano, who founded the AFROTECTOPIA new media festival&lt;/a&gt; on a shoestring budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the many sessions about legal policy or anti-racist and anti-oppressive organizing, the conference stays true to its name by including numerous digital security workshops facilitated by world-class cybersecurity trainers, classic hacking demos such as phishing and Machine-in-the-Middle (MITM) attacks by “anonymous members” of self-proclaimed anarchist tech collective &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/speakers/#anarcho-tech-nyc&quot;&gt;Anarcho-Tech NYC&lt;/a&gt;, and even an exploration of unlicensed and illegal broadcasts by legendary Brooklyn-based pirate radio station founder &lt;a href=&quot;https://hnd.techlearningcollective.com/speakers/#brooklyn-pirate-radio-sound-map-bprsm&quot;&gt;DJ Cintronics, courtesy of the Brooklyn Pirate Radio Sound Map (BPRSM)&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizers said that scheduling hacking demos back-to-back with policy strategy sessions was an intentional choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For us at Tech Learning Collective, it’s important to have both uncompromising pro-social politics and unparalleled technical competency so that we can go further than just imagining a more just, less unequal future, but also build power beyond mere voter representation to enact that vision ourselves,” they said. “As activists, journalists, and tenants, we need to see first-hand exactly what threats government-funded hackers and cyberwarfare units—and especially cyber-augmented class warfare—pose to our work, or we won’t be able to exercise our rights, communicate freely, or organize safely. This conference gives us a better chance to win all the legal, cultural, and technical battles we’ve been forced to fight.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About the Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;# # #&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.2019-12-14.hackers-next-door-an-infosec-conference.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.2019-12-14.hackers-next-door-an-infosec-conference.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">This little-known trick lets you use Signal without giving out your phone number</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/10/29/this-little-known-trick-lets-you-use-signal-without-giving-out-your-phone-number.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This little-known trick lets you use Signal without giving out your phone number" /><published>2019-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/10/29/this-little-known-trick-lets-you-use-signal-without-giving-out-your-phone-number</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/10/29/this-little-known-trick-lets-you-use-signal-without-giving-out-your-phone-number.html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal Private Messenger&lt;/a&gt; app has become the de-facto standard for end-to-end encrypted messaging. Its battle-tested encryption protocol is licensed for use by the likes of Facebook in WhatsApp, and it has been adopted by the XMPP Standards Foundation for use as the basis of &lt;a href=&quot;https://conversations.im/omemo/&quot;&gt;OMEMO Multi-End Message and Object Encryption&lt;/a&gt;. In short, Signal is great, except for the fact that you need a phone number to use it. Or do you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most common reasons some people cite for not using Signal is because they don’t want to give out their phone number to the same people they want to send encrypted messages to. In situations where you need both privacy &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; anonymity, this reluctance makes a lot of sense. But what they may not know is that Signal does not require you to use &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; phone number at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Signal-and-Surveillance-How-to-Exercise-Digital-Civil-Liberties-in-a-Surveillance-State&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/workshop.signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state.rectangle.png&quot; alt=&quot;Poster image for Tech Learning Collective&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Signal and Surveillance&amp;rdquo; workshop.&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our instructors explain in more depth during our &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Signal-and-Surveillance-How-to-Exercise-Digital-Civil-Liberties-in-a-Surveillance-State&quot;&gt;Signal and Surveillance workshop&lt;/a&gt;, what most people don’t realize is that Signal “phone numbers” are not really phone numbers. They are more like &lt;em&gt;numeric user names&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to popular belief, your Signal account is not linked to your phone number, but rather to an automatically generated number called a &lt;em&gt;private key&lt;/em&gt;. In order to make the app easy to use, this private key or cryptographic identity is then associated with some arbitrary other number that again, for convenience’s sake, just happens to be a phone number. The reason it’s a phone number is so that the Signal service can send you a verification code in a text message during the sign-up and account registration process. But there’s no reason you have to give Signal your real phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By providing Signal with any phone number at which you can receive an SMS or text message, you can register a Signal account at that other phone number.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, you can create a pseudonymous Google account, register a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/voice&quot;&gt;Google Voice&lt;/a&gt; VoIP number, and use that as your Signal number. Or you can even use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Disposable-SMS-services&quot;&gt;free throw-away SMS account&lt;/a&gt; and use that number when you sign up for your Signal account instead of your real phone number. The Signal service will happily send the throw-away number a text message with the verification code, letting you complete the account sign-up process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a Signal account registered to a phone number other than your own, you should &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.signal.org/hc/en-us/articles/360007059792-Registration-Lock&quot;&gt;set a Signal Registration Lock PIN&lt;/a&gt; so that no one else can register the same number as you without knowing your PIN. To do this, access the Signal setings menu and select &lt;em&gt;Privacy&lt;/em&gt; → &lt;em&gt;Registration Lock PIN&lt;/em&gt;. Enter a strong PIN, and consider using a secrets management app such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://keepass.info/&quot;&gt;KeePass&lt;/a&gt; to write it down in a secure location. And if you’re new to secrets management apps or password managers, Tech Learning Collective’s &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Password-Superpowers-How-to-Crack-Hashes-and-Stump-Hackers&quot;&gt;Password Superpowers workshop&lt;/a&gt; has your back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://support.signal.org/hc/article_attachments/360008169991/registration_lock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo of Signal Registration Lock PIN setting on an iOS device.&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, you can give out your Signal number independently of your real phone number. Messages sent to your phone number will arrive as they normally would, and messages sent to your dedicated Signal number will arrive in the Signal app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective covers this and many more advanced privacy and cybersecurity techniques related to Signal use at our Signal workshop. Be sure to check out our &lt;a href=&quot;/events/&quot;&gt;events calendar&lt;/a&gt; to make sure you don’t miss your chance to attend our next Signal workshop.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">The Signal Private Messenger app has become the de-facto standard for end-to-end encrypted messaging. Its battle-tested encryption protocol is licensed for use by the likes of Facebook in WhatsApp, and it has been adopted by the XMPP Standards Foundation for use as the basis of OMEMO Multi-End Message and Object Encryption. In short, Signal is great, except for the fact that you need a phone number to use it. Or do you?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/photo.signal-private-number.1280x720.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/photo.signal-private-number.1280x720.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Joining the Electronic Frontier Alliance</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/08/13/joining-the-electronic-frontier-alliance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Joining the Electronic Frontier Alliance" /><published>2019-08-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/08/13/joining-the-electronic-frontier-alliance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/08/13/joining-the-electronic-frontier-alliance.html">&lt;p&gt;Today, the Tech Learning Collective is happy to announce our intent to join the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/&quot;&gt;Electronic Frontier Foundation&lt;/a&gt;’s network of community organizations who support digital rights, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/electronic-frontier-alliance&quot;&gt;Electronic Frontier Alliance (EFA)&lt;/a&gt;. As radical queers and femmes, we viscerally understand the importance of having access to secure and private communication tools every time we use our computers. That’s why, as &lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot;&gt;a technology school whose mission is to empower marginalized groups&lt;/a&gt; by enabling them to access all the digital age has to offer, &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/08/10/how-we-approach-cybersecurity-topics-at-the-tech-learning-collective.html&quot;&gt;our security-first approach to education&lt;/a&gt; places a premium on security and privacy from day one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Electronic Frontier Alliance has five core principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free Expression: People should be able to speak their minds to whoever will listen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Security: Technology should be trustworthy and answer to its users.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Privacy: Technology should allow private and anonymous speech, and allow users to set their own parameters about what to share with whom.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creativity: Technology should promote progress by allowing people to build on the ideas, creations, and inventions of others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Access to Knowledge: Curiosity should be rewarded, not stifled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right from our start, the Tech Learning Collective has worked to ensure that we uplift and advance these principles in everything that we do. Where code bootcamps and certification courses are primarily focused on job placement and reward task-completion, TLC courses focus on foundational skill building and reward curiosity by engaging students through Socratic discussion and kinetic, experience-based training. Rather than having a strict syllabus handed down from on high, our teachers provide different materials to a given class when they would add to the learning experience, fostering a more creative environment in our classrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us, this creativity isn’t merely a happy byproduct of our pedagogy, but a focal point of it. In order to succeed, the next generation of revolutionaries will need more than just strong technical skills and secure digital tools. They’ll also need an unwavering commitment to compassionate ethical foundations and the creativity to hack a society that often treats property better than people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As radicals, we recognize that the structure of today’s society maintains systems of power that benefit a minority who already have a lot at the expense of the majority of people who are forced to get by with far less than is just. As revolutionaries, we aim to break this structure apart and reshape it so that everyone can enjoy a more just, more optimistic life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we act on this truth, we face real threats. Whether those threats are instigated simply by speaking our mind, expressing our gender identity or sexuality, or standing up to schoolyard bullies, abusive corporations, or corrupt politicians, we know we’ll need all the help we can get to make the massive change we need to see in the world. So as teachers and mentors, we feel an even stronger obligation to equip our students with all the tools they’ll need to face those threats with grace and poise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best places we can be to achieve these goals is part of the EFF’s Electronic Frontier Alliance, especially since some of our existing partners are already &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/electronic-frontier-alliance/allies&quot;&gt;EFA members&lt;/a&gt;! By joining this expansive coalition of like-minded community organizations working to defend our digital rights, we will be better able to continue fostering new opportunities to educating people about the undeniable impact on and importance in our lives that today’s digital technologies have.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Today, the Tech Learning Collective is happy to announce our intent to join the Electronic Frontier Foundation’s network of community organizations who support digital rights, the Electronic Frontier Alliance (EFA). As radical queers and femmes, we viscerally understand the importance of having access to secure and private communication tools every time we use our computers. That’s why, as a technology school whose mission is to empower marginalized groups by enabling them to access all the digital age has to offer, our security-first approach to education places a premium on security and privacy from day one.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/efa-2_1.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/efa-2_1.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How we approach cybersecurity topics at the Tech Learning Collective</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/08/10/how-we-approach-cybersecurity-topics-at-the-tech-learning-collective.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How we approach cybersecurity topics at the Tech Learning Collective" /><published>2019-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/08/10/how-we-approach-cybersecurity-topics-at-the-tech-learning-collective</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2019/08/10/how-we-approach-cybersecurity-topics-at-the-tech-learning-collective.html">&lt;p&gt;One thing that makes the Tech Learning Collective &lt;a href=&quot;/about/#our-difference&quot;&gt;different than other technical schools&lt;/a&gt; is our explicitly political approach. Our teachers have to be more than just competent technologists, they must also be politically engaged. Similarly, we prioritize enrollment for students who are committed to social justice and have demonstrated that commitment through concrete actions. This makes our classrooms sites of political praxis, sharpening our student’s ability to critically scrutinize the implications of modern technologies and the impact of tech companies from an ethical standpoint. Practically speaking, it also means that we introduce computer security topics far earlier in our programs than most other schools do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, politics and computer security or online privacy are inseparable. From prime time reporting like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russian_interference_in_the_2016_United_States_elections&quot;&gt;Russian intelligence agency intervention in the so-called election “hacking” scandals of 2016&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/mar/17/the-cambridge-analytica-scandal-changed-the-world-but-it-didnt-change-facebook&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica’s ethically questionable data mining of Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, to an endless stream of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2019/aug/08/fbi-oregon-anti-pipeline-jordan-cove-activists&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; showing &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/03/19/black-lives-matter-fbi-surveillance/&quot;&gt;targeted surveillance of activists by federal United States law enforcement agencies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2015-walmart-union-surveillance/&quot;&gt;corporations&lt;/a&gt;, most news outlets (finally!) routinely run stories about these issues. Moreover, marginalized groups simply face more risk than others. Given all this, and given the fact that the Tech Learning Collective was created specifically to empower the people who are not well-served by the tech mainstream, we feel an even stronger obligation to prepare our students for the hostile reality they will face while using their computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To meet this challenge, the Tech Learning Collective has adopted a security-first approach to technology education. This means that even our “beginner” workshops often contain some security content, and many of our public &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt; either have security-forward materials or are entirely about online security and privacy topics. This approach is a sharp departure from most tech bootcamps in which security considerations are a footnote, an afterthought, or simply omitted because it’s not the subject of the class. And even when security is the subject at hand in a traditional classroom, that environment itself, with all its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/14/opinion/cybersecurity-education-skills.html&quot;&gt;predetermined course objectives, becomes a barrier to a good cybersecurity education&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integrating security content for novice students taking starter classes isn’t easy, because security vulnerabilities are often subtle bugs or design flaws that aren’t always immediately apparent to even highly experienced technologists. However, such flaws are also often illustrative of how a given technology works. By looking both at how something functions correctly &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; in what situations it fails or is vulnerable to manipulation, we give students a far more complete understanding of the underlying technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that we always teach cybersecurity topics from both an offensive and a defensive perspective. From &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Open-Doors-Introduction-to-the-Art-of-Lockpicking&quot;&gt;picking locks&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Gone-Phishing-How-to-Recognize-Fake-Websites-and-Other-Online-Scams&quot;&gt;launching phishing attacks&lt;/a&gt;, we teach our students what attackers know along with how attackers think in order to better prepare our students to counter these threats. On the other side of the coin, we also offer deep dives into defensive tools that help students of all skill and experience levels protect their privacy online, such as workshops detailing how to make the most out of &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Tor-What-Is-It-Good-For-(Absolutely-Everything)&quot;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Securing-Email-Protecting-Everyday-Communications-from-GMail-to-ProtonMail&quot;&gt;secure email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, students are introduced to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Address_Resolution_Protocol&quot;&gt;Address Resolution Protocol&lt;/a&gt; early in our &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/net/&quot;&gt;networking courses&lt;/a&gt;. This fundamental component of traditional TCP/IP networking associates a physical network interface controller (NIC) with a logical network address (IP address) and is a topic that is covered by every decent network engineering course. However, ARP is an unauthenticated protocol, so many &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/researchers-hack-surveillance-systems-to-show-fake-video-feed/&quot;&gt;sophisticated attacks start by manipulating a computer’s ARP cache with tools like Ettercap&lt;/a&gt;. Actually seeing an ARP cache poisoning attack in action and understanding how such a technique can trick a computer into communicating with a device it doesn’t intend to can be super helpful for internalizing exactly how ARP works. Plus, it clarifies the situations in which you might want to take extra precautions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help students judge which cyberattacks they should be concerned about in their day-to-day lives, and also simply to keep folks from getting too overwhelmed, we &lt;a href=&quot;/about/persona-matrix/&quot;&gt;chose to adopt&lt;/a&gt; the Anarcho-Tech NYC Collective’s “Persona-based training matrix.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Persona-based-training-matrix#the-matrix&quot;&gt;The persona-based training matrix is a teaching tool&lt;/a&gt; consisting of a three-by-three (3×3) grid. Each cell of the grid represents a level of risk that you might be facing. On our site, the persona matrix looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;persona-training-container&quot; style=&quot;float: none; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;
    Persona matrix:
    &lt;div class=&quot;persona-training-graph&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-row&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-col&quot; title=&quot;Individuals versus Random Assholes&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div title=&quot;Individuals versus Assholes with Resources&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div title=&quot;Individuals versus The State&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-col&quot; title=&quot;Organizers and Jouranlists versus Random Assholes&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div title=&quot;Organizers and Jouranlists versus Assholes with Resources&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div title=&quot;Organizers and Journalists versus The State&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-col&quot; title=&quot;Targeted Activists versus Random Assholes&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div title=&quot;Targeted Activists versus Assholes with Resources&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div title=&quot;Targeted Activists versus The State&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    (&lt;a href=&quot;/about/persona-matrix/&quot;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s this?&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!-- .persona-training-container --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you might have noticed, many of our workshops now have descriptions that include a “persona matrix” in order to help you assess whether the topic of the workshop is relevant to your particular situation. In this model, risk levels are evaluated based on a coarse grouping of who you are and who you are defending yourself from. Each row of the grid represents a coarse grouping of defender profiles, with people at the least risk in the top or first row and people at the most risk in the bottom or last row. Meanwhile, each column represents a similarly coarse grouping of adversaries who pose a risk to you. The weakest or least-resourced attackers are represented by the first or left-most column, while the most powerful adversaries are represented by the last or right-most column.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, once you identify in which defender group (row) you belong and which level of adversarial power you are threatened by (column), you should concern yourself with the cell at which those concerns intersect as well as all the cells above and to the left of that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A given cyberattack or defensive technique, such as ARP cache poisoning, is loosely associated with one or more cells in the grid. If the attack technique lands in a cell that is relevant to your risk profile, we recommend you take some time to learn about it. Otherwise, don’t stress too much. You probably have enough on your plate!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://prism-break.org/&quot;&gt;so many good and free tools available to you&lt;/a&gt;, along with a whole &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/enaqx/awesome-pentest/blob/master/README.md#readme&quot;&gt;arsenal of cyberweapons available to attackers&lt;/a&gt;, this framework provides an easy way for you to gain some clarity and cut through the fear, uncertainty, and doubt generated by the frenetic news cycle and the latest Internet privacy listicle. To be sufficiently safe, most people only need to pick up a few basic, easy to learn, and easy to use privacy tools: a secure messaging application (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt;), a password manager (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://keepass.info/&quot;&gt;KeePass&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://lastpass.com/&quot;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt;), and a few of the built-in features of their existing computers, like the full-disk encryption software available for free on every modern laptop and smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the more you learn about cybersecurity and the more proficient you become with the tools available to you, the safer you can be. Moreover, since we take our politics and our mission seriously, some of the Tech Learning Collective’s workshop materials are designed for activists and advocacy groups that are at a higher risk of cyberattack than others. It’s important to us that these students also receive the training they need to stay safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As more cells in our persona matrix for a given workshop turn red, people in more varied situations will find the workshop materials relevant to them. For example, the persona matrix for our &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Gone-Phishing-How-to-Recognize-Fake-Websites-and-Other-Online-Scams&quot;&gt;Gone Phishing&lt;/a&gt; workshop is all red:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;persona-training-container&quot; style=&quot;float: none; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;
    Persona matrix:
    &lt;div class=&quot;persona-training-graph&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-row&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-col&quot; title=&quot;Individuals versus Random Assholes&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-col&quot; title=&quot;Individuals versus Assholes with Resources&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-col&quot; title=&quot;Individuals versus The State&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-row&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-col&quot; title=&quot;Organizers and Jouranlists versus Random Assholes&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-col&quot; title=&quot;Organizers and Jouranlists versus Assholes with Resources&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-col&quot; title=&quot;Organizers and Journalists versus The State&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-row&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-col&quot; title=&quot;Targeted Activists versus Random Assholes&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-col&quot; title=&quot;Targeted Activists versus Assholes with Resources&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;persona-match-col&quot; title=&quot;Targeted Activists versus The State&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    (&lt;a href=&quot;/about/persona-matrix/&quot;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s this?&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!-- .persona-training-container --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because personally-targeted phishing campaigns (known as “spear phishing” in cybersecurity jargon) are often &lt;a href=&quot;https://citizenlab.org/2016/08/million-dollar-dissident-iphone-zero-day-nso-group-uae/&quot;&gt;used by governments to hack into activist’s personal devices&lt;/a&gt;. However, phishing is &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; a technique frequently used by petty theives to rob people whose only missteps are having a bank account and not being wary of, or not being able to identify, fraudulent emails. Since the persona matrix for this workshop is all-red, it means that &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt;, regardless of their risk level, can benefit from the material presented in this workshop. Put another way, it means that the workshop covers both introductory material and also touches on more sophisticated material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope that this gives you a clearer idea of how we approach cybersecurity topics at the Tech Learning Collective. To learn more about our approach to computer security and how we use the Anarcho-Tech NYC Collective’s persona matrix, read “&lt;a href=&quot;/about/persona-matrix/&quot;&gt;About our Persona-based Training Matrix&lt;/a&gt;,” or book our introductory workshop, “&lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Digital-Defenses-for-the-People-Practical-Digital-Security&quot;&gt;Digital Defenses for the People: Practical Digital Security&lt;/a&gt;,” for your group or at your venue.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">One thing that makes the Tech Learning Collective different than other technical schools is our explicitly political approach. Our teachers have to be more than just competent technologists, they must also be politically engaged. Similarly, we prioritize enrollment for students who are committed to social justice and have demonstrated that commitment through concrete actions. This makes our classrooms sites of political praxis, sharpening our student’s ability to critically scrutinize the implications of modern technologies and the impact of tech companies from an ethical standpoint. Practically speaking, it also means that we introduce computer security topics far earlier in our programs than most other schools do.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>