<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2021-04-05T11:27:35-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">LibrePlanet 2021: Beyond ‘Learning to Code’</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2021/03/25/libreplanet-2021-beyond-learning-to-code.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LibrePlanet 2021: Beyond ‘Learning to Code’" /><published>2021-03-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2021/03/25/libreplanet-2021-beyond-learning-to-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2021/03/25/libreplanet-2021-beyond-learning-to-code.html">&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago we were excited to learn that our LibrePlanet 2021 conference proposal was accepted and that we’d be speakers at the Free Software Foundation’s annual conference this year. The theme of this year’s LibrePlanet conference is “Empowering Users.” From day one, Tech Learning Collective’s mission has been to meaningfully improve the capabilities of our students in ways that go far beyond metrics of employability, so we were particularly eager to attend this year’s LibrePlanet conference and get a chance to share our radical vision of a more empowering relationship with technology with other Free Software advocates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a video capture of our LibrePlanet 2021 presentation, along with a (somewhat rushed) transcript of the speakers, and a link to download our presentation slides in PDF format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;controls&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/LibrePlanet-2021-Beyond-Learning-to-Code.mp4&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/LibrePlanet-2021-Beyond-Learning-to-Code.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch &quot;LibrePlanet 2021: Beyond 'Learning to Code'.&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/LibrePlanet-2021-Beyond-Learning-to-Code.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF slides for “LibrePlanet 2021: Beyond ‘Learning to Code’.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;LibrePlanet facilitator: Okay. This talk is titled “Beyond ‘Learning to Code’: How Tech Learning Collective Merges IT Training with Emancipatory Political Action,” and will be presented by members of the &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective&lt;/a&gt;, an apprenticeship-based technology school for radical organizers. Founded and operated exclusively by radical queer and femme technologists, they offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to computer hacking techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this talk, they’ll describe their holistic approach to IT education, which is creating communities of activist sysadmins out of people who wouldn’t otherwise have called themselves “techies,” opening the world of free computing to people who will apply its advantages their other liberatory goals. With that, I’ll turn it over to TLC.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective: Thanks so much for that intro. Hi, everyone. Thank you so much for coming to our talk, do you have any trouble just, um, you know, hearing obviously, just throw that into the IRC chat room, and our wonderful tech team from FSF is going to help us out.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I am representing Tech Learning Collective today. I want to talk a little bit about why we’re doing what we’re doing and why we’re doing what we’re doing in the way that we’re doing it. And why it may be different than what you might expect.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This talk is called Beyond learning to code, in large part because one of the things that’s unique about Tech Learning Collective is that we don’t really teach coding per se, we teach a lot of IT infrastructure. And this, of course, overlaps with learning to code. But it’s not, it’s not the same thing. And so, likewise, if you have any questions, please throw those into the chat as you have them. And I hope that by the end of this, what I want to leave you with is a different way of thinking about what would be useful to do today, in your personal life as an individual or as someone who is maybe part of an affinity group, part of a small community group, small neighborhood group, small PTA group, small education group, small club, y’know, something on a scale that is sort of more immediate to your personal life, that will materially impact and improve the situations that you find yourself in, and the situation that you find your loved ones in. That’s sort of really where our focus lies.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so to start that off, to start the conversation off, I kind of want to just begin this notion by talking about, like, why care about technology in the first place, right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of people who have technology interests for many, many different reasons. There’s fun and hobbies and curiosity, right? Just kind of like casual interest. There’s a lot of people who need to care about technology for their livelihood, right, it’s part of their job, part of their work. It’s something that they feel is going to help them become more capable than they currently are. So there’s individual capability, right? And then of course, there’s that Silicon Valley slogan, right “make the world a better place.” It has this sort of utopian vision of all the things that can be improved with better technology. And if we just have the right tools, you know, everything will be fine and wonderful. And, so we like to say that this is sort of the techno capitalist view of what how things are happening, right? Most people, right, in Silicon Valley, like to say that they’re making the world a better place. It’s literally a TV show, right? That you can watch it like a Mike Judge production, “&lt;em&gt;Silicon Valley&lt;/em&gt;,” that jokes about this throughout five very, very incredibly ridiculous seasons.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;What Silicon Valley and tech companies tend to actually be doing, though, in our view, right is making it possible for individuals to get a job. And that’s fine. There’s nothing particularly wrong with that. It’s just that it’s not really what they claim to be doing. Largely.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Of course, what most people and I don’t mean to suggest that most people here [at LibrePlanet] but I mean, most people writ large in the world want to do with technology, in large part, is that it’s a curiosity. We’re not necessarily sure what to do with technology, it’s just that there’s some cool things and it’s of interest. So it can be a fun weekend project. And how many times have you had someone you know, or know someone, perhaps, who bought a Raspberry Pi for a weekend project, but they never really got around to the weekend project, you know what I mean?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So all these things are really happening to some degree or another. But it’s important to sort of identify what people think that they’re doing, not just what they say that they are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In contrast, right, our sort of view of the same thing is, this is sort of what we actually aim to do is make the world an actually better place. And again, this is why I started by talking about like, what does that mean with respect to your personal life, right, that’s a that’s a place to start that is a little bit more understandable than the larger scale of the whole world. It is also true that if you come through to TLC, Tech Learning Collective, right, you will gain capabilities that you might not have had before because you will be exposed to technologies that you might not have seen. You will have an opportunity to learn from mentors and people with some more experience than perhaps you have about technologies that you don’t necessarily know as much about, and that can, of course result in, for example, getting a job, or other things. But, you know, for us, that’s also part and parcel of the community aspect to it. So we at TLC, right, find technology fun in and of itself, but we find it primarily useful as a medium to do something else.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In other words, we’re less interested in optimizing our database queries to the nanosecond level, right, than we are in having a database. Because what that means is a materially different reality for someone, regarding you know, what they would like to do, then if they didn’t have that same capability that technology provides. So that’s what we care about.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So we have these two primary missions at TLC, TLC being the technology school, right? One is to simply provide meaningful technology education to underserved communities. And in brief, what we mean by that is that in a grandiose vision, we do not believe that a humane society should require you to do any kind of labor for the privilege of having a livelihood, in all the ways that I mean that word. You should not have to work to be able to have food, if that work is for somebody else. Right? You should have an autonomous life, free to make your own choices and all the ways that freedom means and that means at a grand scale, it means that we are working towards hopefully, you know, seeing a world where we can abolish the idea of employment as a prerequisite for survival in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It also means, of course, that that’s a pretty far off vision. And we’re not, you know, unrealistic about how far away that necessarily is. And so right now, by necessity, perhaps, at an individual level, it means that we want to try to enable this immediate material improvement in people’s lives, students lives in our case. And of course, the lives of you know, the people who are involved in their communities. Importantly, that means that we have to do this in a way that doesn’t rely or require the cooperation of existing capital, like large companies like state and local regulators. Because those are institutions primarily born from a status quo. And obviously, abolishing employment is a radical departure from the status quo. And so what that means that we have to, you know, survive in a world where the status quo is not aligned with our goals. So we have to not require or rely on that work.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The other primary goal for TLC, the secondary objective, right, is to fund existing community-owned technology projects that are built and maintained and implemented, right, for radical social good. And what we mean by that is that we want to materially support so that means either with money or with hardware or with you know, people’s skill and time, the projects that are doing the political work that we find valuable. So this is, for example, hardware, right, as I said, right, physical infrastructure installations, I can talk a little bit about some examples of that later on. The operating costs, right, from proceeds of workshops and courses that we teach. And then of course, we tried to do this in a way where we’re also able to survive in the existing system, which means that we’re trying to avoid the construction through our process of any kind of exploitative volunteering arrangements. And which means that everyone who is involved in a, you know, in a serious time committed way is being paid for their time, when they when they are involved in TLC. That means teachers, and marketing staff, and so on, and so forth. So those are sort of the two primary, two primary goals there.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And this can kind of all be summed up right by this idea that there is a lot of work that needs to be done to write parentheses, “make the world a better place.” But most of that work cannot be done quote “at work,” right? You cannot change the world in the 30 minutes that you have for lunch. So that’s sort of, uh, that’s the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In a super zoomed out view, this is kind of where we see this happening. This is kind of how we see the potential for change starting. This is called what we call the Tech Learning Collective flywheel. Ironically enough, this is actually a business concept invented or at least popularized by Jeff Bezos of Amazon. And the idea is simply that there is a value, right, that we offer, that we can feed into other values that already exist elsewhere, that once we take advantage of, we can continue to feed into this circular process that starts this so called “flywheel effect” that, while it takes a lot of energy to sort of begin to make this happen, once the flywheel is moving, its own momentum continues the process of getting things further and further, further along.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So in our case, right in the case of TLC, you know, we are a school. We use free software, right? And in using free software, right, it means that we can offer the same things as a lot of other schools with lower financial costs, but it also means that we enable our students to do things with a lot lower financial cost. It also means that we potentially have more accessible tools, right? In both cases that combination drives student enrollment, which drives engagement with our courses, which means that of course we can create more courses and workshops from that, and feed that back into TLC, which, again, is then supportive of both as users and in some cases as contributors to some free software projects, which then drives lower financial cost and onwards and onwards, right. But it also means that we have this opportunity after creating an alumni network, and a set of folks who have a shared baseline understanding of the technology that we’re using right to construct and to offer, right, hyper-local infrastructure projects and other community work. That this benefits how, for example, right, they can do the things that they want to see done that they can advocate for their own goals. What that means is that we can create political impact, right? From a grassroots level, which of course, we’ll also be using and supporting the free software movement, which means that we’ve got lower financial costs to drive student engagements to drive workshops to get more hyperlocal infrastructure projects, and onwards and onwards. And so this in a nutshell, right, is basically the 10,000 foot vision of why we think that starting from an infrastructure school, which I’m going to talk about a little bit more in just a minute, rather than a coding school, we can actually enable this in a way that if you start on the other side, like a coding school, right, you end up actually supporting a status quo instead of resisting it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So let’s dig into this a little bit more, right? Like, what are the flywheel components that we’re talking about here?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;First of all, you have to see a bunch of these things called practice labs. I mean, this is not a super big surprise, anytime that you’re learning something, you’re going to want to play around with it hands on, perhaps, right? And so for us, what that means is that we build it on GNU/Linux, we build it on repeatable infrastructure that we can create as infrastructure as code. Two examples of that are, you know, locally installed VirtualBox, use Vagrant to automate it. These are DevOps tools primarily used in the industry for development operations, right, style work, but we use it for education.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We also, of course, have our own infrastructure, primarily built as IaC, which in some cases, we share with other groups who want to do something similar, primarily this means Ansible, Terraform. We also host internal services primarily over Onion services, to collaborate internally. So we have our own sort of internal calendars, running free software, implementations, CalDAV servers, basically, we have some file servers again, all behind Onion services. Actually, authenticated Onion services in most cases, because we can use IaC, infrastructure as code, to automate a lot of the processes around adding or removing members and giving them appropriate access permissions, and so on and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The hyperlocal infrastructure projects I mentioned, just very briefly, right, there’s a, we were started in about 2015 or so in New York City, sort of got a boost after the November 2016 election, for reasons. And the core group of us sort of dispersed into a number of other projects around New York City primarily at the time. And what that means, right is that we now have connections to these hyper local infrastructure projects or other sort of groups that are doing things in and around New York City. And again, this is where it comes back to that alumni community, that flywheel effect, right. So what they’re doing can then feed into other groups, and so on and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;From there, right, as alumni share visions with one another, and they experience this sort of alternate approach to empowering technologies, then we create more possibility for mentors, which creates more possibility for apprentices and then onwards and onwards to that effect. I hope that makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So, when considering a school, right, there are a lot of ways one can go about learning, because the whole point of a school is a place to learn, right. And so, the model that we take here is that we are not trying to the be all and end all of everything, we are trying to be one of several options. Here’s a different couple ways of thinking about what those options are: we have this sort of infographic here where “goal oriented” is on one axis, and the opposite of that is “exploratory.” “Unstructured” versus “guided” is the other axis. And the idea here is that we are sort of both goal oriented and guided. Right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So what we are kind of competing against, but more just trying to be an alternative to I should say, is a bootcamp or a university model of education, which is the other sort of goal oriented and guided approach to learning a lot of technology things that you probably have seen; computer science courses, you know, Turing School, Flatiron School, or General Assembly, you know, any code bootcamp, that kind of stuff, right? We’re not really trying to be alternative to things like hack fests and social clubs and really Wikipedia articles and stuff. We think those are great and wonderful ways to learn if you have this sort of, you know, personality for it. But for a lot of people goal oriented and guided learning is both familiar and also to a big extent, right, is sort of a more, the thing that they would like to spend their time on, especially synchronous time, right when you’re with a human as well. So if we can zoom in on that a little bit like what is what is it makes it what makes us different than, for example, the bootcamp on the university model?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And to talk about that, I’d like to sort of introduce this idea, right, where we have here, this sort of trapezoidal shape, where we think that’s how we think about learning, here are all the possible things that you can learn, right. And at the very base of this trapezoid, we have these concepts, these foundational pieces of understanding that sort of are relevant regardless of which specific technology you use, right. Above that, we have competencies, which are skills with specific tools, or familiarity with a shared culture in those tools. And you have of course capabilities, which are these higher level abilities to do things with those skills. And this sort of runs the gamut between things that can be fun for, for hobbies, right all the way through the mutual aid and political activism. And in the middle there, there’s this sort of like individualistic idea of like, well, “I need to get a job.” And this is not again, this is not an all encompassing view, this is in essence an example.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So let’s fill this area, right, with things that we learn at TLC.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so if we start with just filling in some of the concepts that we talk about, right? You’ll notice that there’s some things that are probably very familiar to a lot of, you know, highly technical people, right? There are things like the physical networking of the OSI layer, of the OSI model of internetworking, right? There are things like for example, censorship and anti-censorship, right? Circumvention tools, anonymity, privacy, right? There’s also stuff like, for example, hypermedia and nonlinear writing, right, which is, we think, a concept foundational to, for example, the Internet and the web, in particular, the hyperlink, right? That isn’t exactly teaching about the Web. There were things that predated HTML, for example, that discussed hypermedia and nonlinear writing, that are useful to know about that are not necessarily taught if you go to, for example, a code boot camp that immediately introduces you to the newest version of the Rails framework as an example. And all of this stuff is what we consider, right, the foundational pieces of the things that we’re learning. And we really take a lot of time and focus on making sure that these things are discussed as first class citizens, if you will, of a curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So from there, once you understand that, you know, these things are things that you can learn, right, you can start utilizing specific tools and technologies to implement your understanding of these things. So for example, cloud APIs, right? Or HTML, CSS, and JavaScript or you know, GPG, and password managers and how to use virtualization and the command line and GNU/Linux and infrastructure as code, and all this sort of stuff, right? We don’t really necessarily have too much of a, you know, puritanical view, per se of like, what you should do here (competences, tools), we care more about here (concepts, foundations). And the reason for this right is because if you understand hypermedia and nonlinear writing, then you have a much better approach, or you have a much better way of approaching any single one of these things. Git, for example, right, it’s sort of a nonlinear way of writing a history about a project. But HTML has links, which is sort of, you know, the introduction to like wikis, which is, both of these are sort of ways to do nonlinear things. If that makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And then, of course, once you have some skill in one or more several technologies, right, then you can actually do meaningful things in your life, like, share, or explore or publish or collaborate or advocate, right? Or be a leader, create some self direction. And finally, of course, you know, act collectively with others who also have similar skills, and visions, and, like, appropriate views about, you know, where they’re where they’re, how they are viewing the acts that they take with the values that they have.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So if you look at this sort of way that we approach this curriculum building idea, right, and you compare this with, for example, right, like, for example, a code boot camp, or like, for example, a university course, most of which are trying to get you to, you know, be employable, what you see is that there’s a much larger vision about what it is a student needs and what supports a student needs in a guided and goal directed way to actually accomplish those larger things than a code boot camp actually provides, right? That smaller trapezoid is where the book code boot camp focuses its energy. And you can see that we as Tech Learning Collective, right, have started from a much more foundational place, and ended up with a much broader view of what’s possible for students &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; we started out at that much more foundational place.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So just as another comparison, right, the other part of it is price. I know someone right now who’s trying to engage with a code bootcamp and unfortunately they want you but can’t, because it’s just too expensive. In their case, it’s even more expensive than this. And this, what’s shown on the slide is about $14,000. This is based on data from a sampling of CourseReport.com’s “Best bootcamps for 2020.” In contrast, Tech Learning Collective courses, you’re taking the course right, is literally an order of magnitude less expensive. It’s like and if you take standalone workshops for just particular things, right like that’s even less expensive. So part of the point here is that that this comes back to that flywheel where the things that we’re doing, and the way that we’re doing it allows us to do stuff in a much, much, much less expensive way, that will provide a lot more accessibility to a lot more, a lot more people. This is, of course, particularly important for women who are bearing the brunt of, for example, child caring, you know, requirements, or, you know, things during the pandemic, and you know, all that shit that rolls downhill, excuse me.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Um, the other thing that’s unique about us is that, you know, we started this as a political project, not a school. And so we were very, very mindful from the get go about, like, “Who are we teaching?” And, “What do they want to do with what we’re teaching?” And what that sort of has resulted in is an approach that has, as you can see from this slightly now dated, internal survey, is that we end up getting a lot more repeat students. In other words, people who come to one workshop and then a second, and then third and the fourth and so on, right, who are on the sort of like femme-of-center spectrum, in their gender identity, then the masculine-of-center, sort of side of that spectrum. And this is, you know, as for the industry, writ large is kind of unheard of. For a school in particular, also kind of unheard of, which we’re very proud about.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Um, the other thing that’s different, right, is that we provide this through an apprenticeship based learning experience rather than a sort of rote, rote memorization or like task based learning experience. And what that means is that the people who are teaching are actually expert teachers, not just experts on the subject matter that they are teaching. For us what that means is that every TLC instructor was a TLC student in the past, right. And on top of that, that every TLC instructor is actively involved, right, in the other projects that TLC is sort of like a sister organization about. It also means that the teachers themselves, right, are doing this in a particular style, it is not a lecture approach, it is not a, y’know, sit and watch the presentation, unlike actually what we’re doing right now, where you have slides, right? In classes, it’s really live. So that there are no pre-recorded materials, everything is live in that in that screen share that, you know, sharing of the terminal together. And what that means is that you’re actually doing a lot more kinetic things than you would otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The other thing that’s different is that we try to learn together, right? So you learn from experts, but you learn together after the fact and with that expert. And so what that means is that we have this sort of series of ways of getting more and more involved in the school that starts with maybe just a public workshop. But that can continue through, for instance, a set of, a curated sequence of classes, that we call “cohorts,” that are that is what make up a particular run of a course. And then once you have sort of gone through that run, of course, right, the next step, if you want to continue being engaged with is, for example, the alumni learning community, where there are a bunch of clubs and other groups that have dispersed out of Tech Learning Collective sort of baseline course material. And so that, that both gives people an on that that’s sort of like lets them dive as deeply as they want, but not deeper. And that means that they can much more quickly move from learning about something technical, to doing the thing that they want in the physical world, in the real world, in the political impact, political sphere, even, based on what it is that they want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So this is sort of like, I want to leave a lot of time for discussion, but it really is maybe a larger issue. But I wanted to just sort of highlight some things that some students have said about TLC so far. And I just want to sort of point at those sort of differences, right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Like, so one student, Chantelle, who was a computer science undergrad, right says that “the amount I’m learning in Tech Learning Collective workshops is way more than what I was learning in my college classroom.” And the reason I want to highlight this is because this is in combination with the fact that Tech Learning Collective workshops and courses are shorter. In other words, you spend less time in TLC classes but you still end up learning way more than you might in, for example, a university course or, for example, a code bootcamp.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The other thing I want to highlight is someone named Snow who said, “this class was immensely valuable,” right, And this is the big point: “changed my core beliefs about my technological proficiency and potential.” And what I want to highlight in this is this idea that a lot of people who would otherwise be very involved with these sorts of technologies, just for personal projects, just for, you know, things that they want to see done in the world aren’t not because we need for example, necessarily better tools and better documentation. Although of course, we do need all these things. Everything can be made better all the time, but rather because they have through whether it be systemic impacts caused by inequalities out in the world or just sort of preconceived notions about maybe earlier technologies that they’ve encountered, right, this belief about themselves, that an environment that is more social, that is more supportive that is more apprenticeship-based, as we say, right actually changes how they view themselves in that world. And that makes it more possible for them to do all those things that we talked about, that we want to see people, you know, change, lead, and collaborate and share, and explore, and all that sort of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So that is, you know, getting this kind of this getting this feedback is really, really meaningful to us.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so again, back to this, right, back to this flywheel: for us right now, right, through primarily, necessarily individual impact, because of where we are in this process. You know, we are trying to do this by offering the sort of alternative to the rush-to-employment way of learning about technology, where, for example, right now, if you go to a lot of code, boot camps, you are almost introduced to the technology as though the current technology is the beginning of history for that technology. There’s not really a lot of discussion, right, about where terms came from, what the history was of a given technology, right? Why that’s important. And for us, right, starting that way gives you a narrative that you can then see yourself not necessarily as simply memorizing a bunch of facts or learning a bunch of sort of standard operating procedures for how to take, you know, a command line and then end up with a website. But it lets you create, in your mind almost, a story, right of what happened before you arrived, what’s going on now. And importantly, because it’s a story, and you have now the tools to write the next chapter, you can actually understand where you’ve come from, understand how you fit into what’s happening now, understand the forces that are that are at play in, for example, the job market or in for example, just the free software movement, generally, and then have the capability, right, of taking that metaphorical pen, and defining what you want to see as the next chapter about it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so that, that’s it for my presentation part. I would love, love, love to see questions. I have a lot of things I could say about this. But I wanted to distill this down to just those main ideas, because I’m really hoping that this is at least intriguing to some people. And I’m sure that I probably didn’t cover everything, almost intentionally. And so if you have questions, now would be a great time to sort of let me know about what you’re more curious about, what you want hear more about, and then the rest of this can really just be, right, talk and, um, talk and discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;LibrePlanet facilitator: Yeah, so we have about a little over 15 minutes left.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Great!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Facilitator: We have some really great quick, noisy to ask, talking about the femme of center and masc of center. What do you mean by of center? Why is it a good thing? That they’re not equal? Like, why do you see that as a positive?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah. Good point. So of center basically just means, right, like, the—this is a bit of Gender Theory 101. And so I don’t wanna spend too much time on it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But to answer the question, right, the notion of having simply, men and women in the world right now a binary gender dynamic, where you have a male and a female, and that’s all you can ever be right? creates this literally binary right view, you have either your 1 or a 0, right? Like, literally, I think the, there was some—I wasn’t sure if it’s an IETF standard, or there’s some standard that literally describes like, you know, gender representation in databases. And it’s, and it’s, you know, one for a male, a zero for female. And they explicitly say, like, we don’t mean to, to this to be any sort of, like, you know, ranking system, it’s just, that’s how, like, you know, this binary field has decided to be stored. But the point is, is that that’s not how people experience the world.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so the way to sort of add granularity to some of this, right is to take that sort of binary notion of having two points, or I just don’t know, one, one bit that you can flip, and then having it be instead a range, a scale, right? from let’s say, instead of, like, you know, zero to one, zero, right, you know, zero to 100, as an example. And so if in that, you know, schema, right, binary female is zero, and binary male is 100. Right? Then you have a center point, 50, right, which is what you might have described before as “androgynous,” or as sort of “bigender,” right, or some other sort of mix of the two. And so the idea is that there is a, that that’s the point from which we, from which we measure the sort of like relationships back to binary gender. And as you saw in the slide, I can go back to even right, we basically were like, this is a guess we didn’t actually ask people, right, this is sort of a, you know, a sort of a relatively admittedly like, imperfect and somewhat problematic, right, like, representation of what we assumed based on people’s, you know, self, you know, their own sort of like presented behaviors and such. The reason why it’s good that it’s not sorry, go ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Facilitator: No, that’s I was just gonna ask about you know, why what do you see as positive?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Right, yeah. And so the reason we see this as positive is because the specific goal of TLC, right is to affect change in the status quo. So if you imagine, so it’s, so the status quo right now is effectively flipped, right? Most companies in most technology positions, right for most companies have primarily men or people who are masculine-of-center, right, in those roles. That is then replicated in all the schools that we’re aware of, right. I mean, look at the whole STEM, you know, thing, and so on. And so by seeing this breakdown, be the opposite of the status quo to us that signals that we are actually making inroads to the progress we want to see. And so we want this as skewed as possible with that respect, without necessarily like, you know, like, it’s not like, you know, there’s a course for femme-of-center people in a course for masc-of-center people, because the material is the same. But seeing the skew this way tells us that we’re reaching the right people, and that the which is to say the people who are not reached elsewhere, right? And that we’re providing that avenue for people who don’t have as perhaps a safe or comfortable or just useful way of going about learning these things in existing paradigms through another alternative. If that makes sense?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Facilitator: Okay, Jack, [unintelligble] thank you so much for your question. Jack Hill, I’m also interested, how would one bootstrap a new TLC organization, especially with the heavy emphasis on relationships with organizations and alumni?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah, that’s also a good question. So it’s, it’s not so much that we are hoping to create a bunch of TLCs. Although if you wanted to, you know, that would be more than welcome, right? Like the more people who are teaching this, the better. It’s more that what we see our role as is providing a sort of anchor point, right, if you imagine this as a literal flywheel, then that center stick, right that holds the flywheel together that provides that anchor, is also a piece of the puzzle that you need. And so we are hoping—what we are hoping to do is to inspire people to do projects around their abilities that they find important for their local communities. And to have, and we want, particularly the people who are doing those are people who would not have otherwise approached those projects with, for example, the notion of “Oh, I can self host this particular service,” or “Oh, for example, I can create a service that is, you know, relevant to the 10,000 people in my neighborhood, as opposed to the 10 million people in my country,” right? There’s a lot of focus on scale as a marker of success. And what we’re hoping to do is get people to think of success, not in the form of, you know, I’ve started a company that now serves 10 billion people, I guess 10 million people since there aren’t 10 billion people yet, but rather, a marker of success being my life is now better, and my spouse’s life is better, and my family’s life is better in some material way. I have more time; I have more money; I have more ability to effect change in my local city council; that kind of thing. Because I have more data to do it with or if presented, you know, information that I got, you know, from open data sources and this kind of stuff, using tools that perhaps we learned at TLC like Web scraping, and so on, right? That’s the goal. That being said, if you like what we’re doing, and you want to try it out too, do it. Like, we’re not, you know, we’re not in any way precious about that. But it does take a lot of existing relationships. And, you know, it was specifically the affinity group that started around the 2015-2016, sort of digital security stuff that began this particular iteration of TLC.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I hope that answers the question.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Facilitator: I think so, seems to me at least, D-lib asks, Where do your first cohorts come from? I assume that’s asking about first time attenders?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah, I guess that could be there might be two questions in there. I’ll answer both because I think both they’re interesting, right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So back to the sort of like the slides around like, what are some people saying, what we actually find is that a lot of people coming to TLC are people who, for example, have some touchpoint with technology education, but have found it wanting. And that actually means that we have a lot of people signing up for workshops, who are either sort of working in nonprofits, or have taken sort of, for example, they’ve gone to a CryptoParty, for instance, right? But they didn’t really do much after the crypto party. Right? So they kind of learned about PGP and GPG. But then they didn’t actually implement it. And so they come to one of our GPG workshops, right to see it from another perspective. Or, for example, they’ve gone to a code boot camp. Actually, a lot of our workshop attendees were people who have gone through a code boot camp and found themselves still unsure about the fundamentals of like what a computer is and why we would be interested in it and, where did all this thing come from? And like why is Ethernet called Ethernet, right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Like in our description, we talked about like, why is Ethernet like what is what is the Gnostic influence of Ethernet, right? And if you think about it, if you go back in time, to the notion of the “ether,” right? The notion of ether was this gnostic superstition about a permeating force that connected all things very much like The Force in like Star Wars or something. And so when Bob Metcalfe was creating Ethernet, right, like that naming choice was important because he wanted to create a link layer, networking protocol that would connect all digital things. And so he called it the ether-net, right. And so now we have Ethernet. And that’s what that is, right. And so again, having that sort of, like foundational understanding is not something that you get quite as, as I think a lot of people would hope for, from, for instance, a CCNA course, right? Because you’re getting basically getting pelted with a lot of facts. And if you can memorize them, that’s great. But that’s a much harder thing to do for humans because we are story based, and we, you know, like to connect things to metaphor, and ideology, and emotion, right and sense. And so that’s how we approach the pedagogy itself, which is different.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So a lot of people are are people who have come from places where they would otherwise have been, they know that this stuff exists but they also know that they don’t actually know it as well as they’d like. So that’s what the first question that could have been answered by that.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The second question, I think, was maybe in there was, how did we start out? Right, like, what was the first cohort for us? You know, what I mean? And the short, there’s an about page on our website, which I’ll point you to &lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com/about&lt;/a&gt;, which talks about this a little bit. But the short answer to that question is basically, we were a mutual self education group that started in a bunch of anarchist occupied spaces in New York City, shortly before the 2016 presidential election, somewhat involved with a number of different groups. And so a lot of us have sort of deep history with the activist Left, and decided that we just needed to be particularly good at this stuff. Some of us had more experience than others. And so what that meant was that we started basically a, you know, semi-private education group. And over the course of several years, having done several projects, what we’ve discovered is that there is actually a repeatable way of sort of presenting this material and learning this material, that is much more likely to result in the kind of skill that we’d hope our comrades to have than, for example, learning through the black hole of you know, videos, you know, or reading Wikipedia articles, or going through existing courses that are primarily geared towards employability as opposed to bluntly competency.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Facilitator: Okay, [unintelligible] minutes left.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Oh, time flies!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Facilitator: Yeah, decentraleyes asked, “With the proliferation of, quote, free services, like Signal chats, Google Docs, etc. Do you spend time on explaining why those things are not ideal? Before you can get into the ‘Okay, let’s fire up our own community server to do this?’”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: That’s a great question. Yeah, the short answer is we do but the longer answer is that it’s not a distinct topic, right? We don’t present free software as an alternative to anything, what we present it as is simply the best option that we currently have. And the reason for that is because it is the best option that we currently have, I don’t think I need to tell this audience [at LibrePlanet] that thing, but the reason for that is because by starting there, right, what we start with is a baseline that is always available, regardless of what you are, like, I can walk up to any computer in the world, and as long as it’s running a free software operating system, right, where I have access to a command line and the Internet, I know what to do, and I can also then make use of that computer, that machine, right? That is not possible if I have to ask for permission anywhere else. Right? And so like, again, that metaphor that we put in the description, which is, you know, “What good is your pen if the paper that you’re writing on, like, can refuse to show its ink,” right? If you are beholden to anybody else at any point, right, then you don’t actually have the level of autonomy that you need to do the things that we want to see done. And so we start with free software, because if you don’t have anywhere to start at all, then why not start with the software? Someone who’s—Maria was speaking just before us, right? Was saying about like, you know, why not, you know, learn, you know, the GNU Image Manipulation Program instead of Photoshop. And our point is, yeah, if you don’t know how to use Photoshop, then what’s the difference? Right, you might as well start with the Free Software thing, and you’ll be better off for it for many, many, many reasons. Does that make sense?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Facilitator: Mhm! Angie has a question: “If someone has followed the bootcamp flow, focusing on employment, how does TLC help re-establish the foundations?”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: That’s also a great question. So mostly what happens is that a lot of people who have come from boot camps tend to sort of ignore our sort of 101-level or introductory things. And then what they do is they end up coming to a course that’s somewhat more intermediate and they realize how over their head a lot of stuff has gone, right? And so that’s when they tend to be like, Oh, wait a second, what? What came before this right? What am I missing here? And, and, and then they sort of jump back to some of the earlier earlier topics, in part because like when we start talking about computers, we don’t start our conversations with bits and bytes per se, we start out with like, for example, we have a workshop called “&lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Taming-Daemons-System-Administration-and-Operation-Basics&quot;&gt;Taming Demons&lt;/a&gt;,” which is our introduction to System Administration workshop, and we don’t start talking about, you know, computers as machines, we talked about computers as like what is their purpose? Like, why are they here? Right. And for us, that means that they start, we start talking about it as a writing instrument, right? When you write when you press a key on your keyboard, k, l, whatever, right? H, g, whatever, or another language, or a different keyboard, when you are actually doing is inscribing, right into silicon using a medium, in this case, electricity, right, some physical artifact, that’s a change in the physical world exactly like you know, leaving a lead mark on paper is a physical change. So you’re actually physically leaving your mark somewhere, you’re just writing with a different medium. And so the question as system administrators that we should be thinking about right, is how much do we want to write? How much space will that take? How quickly can we write it? Right? And even before we even talk about computers, you can immediately see the parallel to things like RAM and hard disk size, right? And so that’s where we start. And so those are the kinds of things we talked about when we talk about fundamentals. Because when you start talking about it in that way, what you end up with is the possibility of effecting sort of this transfer of skill across things that are not even computer related. And so it’s much more about teaching as much of a philosophy, which is why we call it apprenticeship-based, in part, as it is a specific technical skill, if that makes any sense.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Facilitator: We just have three minutes left, so this might be our last question. “How might the support of ecology and environment fit into that flywheel model for TLC?”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: So, the support of ecology. Um, I think I need a little more clarification of what that means. Do you mean like sustainable infrastructure, like solar-power ARM chips and this kind of stuff? Or…?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Facilitator: That was my assumption from the structure of the question.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah, I mean, for us that’s sort of, in this simplistic diagram that would sort of partly be free software, right? Like, we need open hardware, open software, we need to be able to have freely accessible designs for all of these things and of course all of this is underpinned by the need to power it. So we actually have to have some energy to power the devices that we’re using for this. And that’s also of course another problem.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Not to be glib, but that’s a little bit outside of the scope of what we’re trying to do in part because we see ourselves as trying to start this process. But that doesn’t mean that people who are part of our alumni community don’t find that interesting. In fact, we were just talking before the livestream started that there’s another collection of alumni I’ll say, in a group called the Solarpunk Magic Computer Club, that has um—you can look it up, I think just do any Internet search will find the Solarpunk Magic Computer Club—and they talk a lot about that kind of more literally interweaving of sustainable, ecologically sound principles with modern technology, so that for example, we’re not using Python primarily or only to attack Microsoft Exchange servers, but we’re using it to for example be partly responsible for helping us grow basil that we’re going to then use in our pasta, because that’s how the flowerpot works. It has Python code that we can hack on, that we can modify, because it’s all free software. That kind of thing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So that’s very, very fun, very cool, and again it has come out of a number of people who have taken classes and courses with TLC to get a baseline understanding of a technology that is not inherently then immediately funneling them into a metaphor of, for example, this skeuomorphic desktop that we have on a computer.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Right, like, we’re all using “desktop environments,” but if you look at a laptop there’s no desk in it. This is not a desktop. It’s on a desk, but there’s no desk in the laptop. So what is that desktop actually? It’s a metaphor. And if you start understanding that it’s a metaphor then you can start imagining what else you can do with computers because you begin to use different metaphors to interact and think about what the computer actually is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Facilitator: Thank you so much, that is our time.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Okay, thank you so much for having us at LibrePlanet, and thank you to the FSF, and to you for helping us with the slides earlier. We hope everyone will check out TechLearningCollective.com. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;contact page&lt;/a&gt;. There’s an email address there, and we have a PGP key as well that you can use if you want more private communication. There’s even an Onion site that we mirror our Web site to, so, thanks for coming and, y’know, change the world with us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">What good is a pen if the paper it touches can refuse to show its ink? What good is your app when your API key is revoked? Through metaphor and with a unique apprenticeship-based pedagogy, Tech Learning Collective (TLC) is empowering users by doing exactly what code boot camps and corporate-funded &quot;learn to code&quot; programs don't: TLC tells students to ignore new Web frameworks and focus instead on the lowest layers of an IT stack like physical network and hardware storage devices. At this LibrePlanet 2021 talk, Tech Learning Collective describes how we are creating communities of activist sysadmins out of people who wouldn't otherwise call themselves &quot;techies,&quot; opening the world of Free Software to help people advance their other liberatory goals.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/libreplanet-beyond-learning-to-code-tech-learning-collective-flywheel.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/libreplanet-beyond-learning-to-code-tech-learning-collective-flywheel.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Deplatforming Parler will have consequences for which we must immediately prepare</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2021/01/26/deplatforming-parler-will-have-consequences-for-which-we-must-immediately-prepare.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deplatforming Parler will have consequences for which we must immediately prepare" /><published>2021-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2021/01/26/deplatforming-parler-will-have-consequences-for-which-we-must-immediately-prepare</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2021/01/26/deplatforming-parler-will-have-consequences-for-which-we-must-immediately-prepare.html">&lt;p&gt;Two days after the American far right’s failed fascist coup on January 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2021 that left five people dead in Washington, DC, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2020/suspension.html&quot;&gt;Twitter (finally) permanently banned the would-be dictator&lt;/a&gt; responsible for inciting the mob from their platform. Shortly thereafter, the social media network most closely affiliated with the racist reactionaries, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/09/technology/apple-google-parler.html&quot;&gt;Parler, was kicked off its cloud provider’s hosting platform&lt;/a&gt;, Amazon AWS. This meant Parler’s servers were shut down, bringing the social media platform down with them, at least temporarily. While de-platforming Trump and Parler is undoubtedly a good thing in the short term (and should have happened a long time ago), the sheer visibility of such high-profile bans is likely to dramatically accelerate the adoption of certain communication technologies that are much harder to shut down the same way Parler was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we don’t immediately begin seriously preparing for an Internet in which digital deplatforming will be much harder than it is now, pro-democracy movements and progressive activists will find themselves in the crosshairs of these same Big Tech behemoths even more often than they are now. It will be much harder for the Left to combat the reactionary forces embedded in neoliberal governments and evidenced by the Capitol Riots than it already is. What was once the inherently anti-fascist strategy of deplatforming will be appropriated by the powers that be and used to maintain their power and suppress dissent under the guise of stability and security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, digital de-platforming can take many forms. An individual can become persona non grata and have their accounts banned from one or many platforms, as happened to Trump. A platform’s servers can be shut down by that platform’s own platform (on the Internet, it’s platforms all the way down), as happened to Parler. But many other methods exist as well. A Web site’s domain name can be &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name#Seizures&quot;&gt;seized&lt;/a&gt; by law enforcement or revoked by the registrar itself to prevent visitors from learning the site’s IP address; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalattackmap.com/&quot;&gt;distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks&lt;/a&gt; can overwhelm a site to make it unable to respond to connection requests; technological censors can intercept Internet traffic intended for a certain destination or originating from a given source based on keywords, addresses, or other metadata; or in the most extreme cases, a target’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Pirate_Bay_raid&quot;&gt;physical computing assets can be confiscated&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are in fact many more pressure points that digital deplatforming campaigns can press on than their campaigners tend to be aware of. This means the success or failure of a given campaign against a target, like Parler, using traditional Web and telecommunication infrastructures, like Amazon AWS, is largely a matter of political, legal, or social prowess. Bring enough pressure to bear against the right people at the right time in the right way, and getting a user or a company deplatformed is not particularly difficult. Yes, it almost always takes an enormous amount of time, energy, and even money for activists to convince the self-interested likes of Facebook to do the right thing by deplatforming hate groups but, once persuaded, all Facebook needs to do is press a literal button. Likewise, it was not a technical challenge for Amazon to turn off Parler’s servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if there were no servers to shut down? This question is not one of science fiction. The next hate-spewing platform could very easily be one with no servers to shut down given the state of the art in social networking software freely and widely available today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most of the people who use the Internet spend all of their time online using “centralized” websites like Facebook, Twitter or, until recently, Parler that are vulnerable to any number of pressures on the availability of the content they host, there have long been alternative networks that are built in entirely different ways. These “decentralized” alternatives are much, much harder to bring down. Some of these alternatives have even been around for much longer than the popular centralized services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://freenetproject.org/&quot;&gt;Freenet&lt;/a&gt;, a self-described “peer-to-peer platform for censorship-resistant communication,” has been actively and continually developed since March of 2000, making it one of the oldest P2P services on the Internet. This predates even BitTorrent, the technology most famous for being the file sharing protocol of choice for Internet “pirates” and the bane of music and movie copyright holders for decades. Since the place a BitTorrent user gets the data they’re seeking is other users, not a centralized server, “deplatforming” a torrent is not as easy as shutting down a single computer system. Instead, &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; computer systems sharing a given file (what BitTorrent calls a “swarm”) must be disconnected both from each other and from any other interested peer. Moreover, if any new user obtains and begins sharing that same data over BitTorrent, that user becomes a new “seed” able to re-proliferate that same content across the network once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 2000s, it was hard to use BitTorrent for anything other than “file sharing,” but a lot has changed since then. Today, a tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://zeronet.io/&quot;&gt;ZeroNet&lt;/a&gt; uses BitTorrent under the hood to publish Web sites, replacing the need for traditional Web servers like those sold by Amazon. ZeroNet sites, or “ZeroSites” as they’re called, can also contain user generated content just like more familiar Web 2.0 sites such as Twitter, and its default distribution ships with a list of bookmarks that contain forums and other sites that feature an interface very similar to today’s social media platforms. Since ZeroNet sites are distributed via BitTorrent, there are potentially as many servers as there are users of a given platform at a given time. Good luck digitally deplatforming that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many more tools like these. &lt;a href=&quot;https://beakerbrowser.com/&quot;&gt;Beaker Browser&lt;/a&gt; is a “peer-to-peer Web browser” that makes it trivial for anyone to clone and re-share entire websites, just this week &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/ipfs-support/&quot;&gt;Brave announced support for loading Web sites hosted on a distributed file system called IPFS&lt;/a&gt; instead of traditional HTTP servers, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://maidsafe.net/&quot;&gt;MaidSafe&lt;/a&gt; is a project that combines a cryptocurrency-based economy with an autonomous and decentralized data storage network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, such systems are relegated to the most extreme fringe. However, the more frequent and visible deplatforming actions become, the more attractive these more resilient alternative technologies will be to those who are deplatformed, whether they are on the political Left or Right. That means we need to be ready to grapple with the very real likelihood that deplatforming fascists like Trump and the white supremacists who flocked to Parler will not only serve to oust them from online public squares in the short term (a very good thing indeed), but over the long term will also inadvertently cause the more committed among them to learn to use some of the very same censorship-resistant technologies that were built to protect dissidents, journalists, and marginalized groups from them in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has already started happening. In 2017, after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2019/06/28/736915323/neo-nazi-who-killed-charlottesville-protester-is-sentenced-to-life-in-prison&quot;&gt;neo-Nazi James Fields Jr. murdered Heather Heyer in Charlottesville&lt;/a&gt;, white supremacist site &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2017/08/29/waning-storm-stormfrontorg-loses-its-domain&quot;&gt;Stormfront was brought offline after their domain registrar revoked their domain registration&lt;/a&gt;. But it didn’t take long for the site to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/evvxvz/white-supremacist-website-daily-stormer-goes-offline&quot;&gt;reappear on the dark Web&lt;/a&gt; with an “onion domain,” bypassing the need for a domain name registration by using a feature of the Tor network called &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.torproject.org/onionservices/&quot;&gt;Onion services&lt;/a&gt;. This is the exact same feature used by the best newsrooms’ online anonymous tip lines enabled by software like &lt;a href=&quot;https://securedrop.org/&quot;&gt;SecureDrop&lt;/a&gt;, including those of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://securedrop.org/directory/new-york-times/&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://securedrop.org/directory/guardian/&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://securedrop.org/directory/intercept/&quot;&gt;The Intercept&lt;/a&gt;. We at &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective&lt;/a&gt; have &lt;a href=&quot;http://lpiyu33yusoalp5kh3f4hak2so2sjjvjw5ykyvu2dulzosgvuffq6sad.onion/&quot;&gt;our own Dark Web site with our own Onion domain&lt;/a&gt;, which we maintain specifically to make it possible for those who share our anarchist and autonomist politics to browse our site more privately. We are not advocating for the removal of this capability. Quite the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem at hand is not the availability of censorship-resistant technology—itself a good thing in general—but rather the level of technical proficiency of the fascists relative to the anti-fascists. As social media technologies continue to evolve, they will become increasingly difficult to police, which is worth cheering. But that reality brings with it a profound responsibility for those of us whose actions are guided by humane ethical principles to command the utmost competency with those tools on the level of technical implementation, to understand their societal impact on the level of governance, and to embody the ideals of our principles on the level of our interpersonal interactions. Put simply, we must not let fascists leapfrog us in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A future in which most Left-leaning activists are (still) on Twitter while most right-wing Trump cultists are using next-generation P2P technologies puts the Left, and only the Left, &lt;a href=&quot;https://roarmag.org/essays/capitol-riot-social-media-police/&quot;&gt;at the mercy of the neoliberal centrist establishment&lt;/a&gt; while simultaneously being unable to curtail the deranged misinformation fueling the fascists. That’s not a position from which we can effectively organize against either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact is, the further we are from center along any political axis, the more important it is for us to adopt more technologically resilient tools. This means &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/13/we-have-only-four-years-to-prevent-a-fascist-usa-heres-what-we-need-to-do-now.html&quot;&gt;committing to learning about and using decentralized social media, anonymity networks, and encrypted messengers seriously&lt;/a&gt;. To do so, we’ll have to change some of our habits and take the time to practice using some new tools. Thankfully, that &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/01/05/imagining-an-optimistic-cyber-future.html&quot;&gt;task is worth the effort&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We simply cannot be content to merely no-platform racists without also increasing our own telecommunication competencies. Doing so may win us the battle on Twitter today, but it will surely cost us the war they’ll start tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Two days after the American far right’s failed fascist coup on January 6th, 2021 that left five people dead in Washington, DC, Twitter (finally) permanently banned the would-be dictator responsible for inciting the mob from their platform. Shortly thereafter, the social media network most closely affiliated with the racist reactionaries, Parler, was kicked off its cloud provider’s hosting platform, Amazon AWS. This meant Parler’s servers were shut down, bringing the social media platform down with them, at least temporarily. While de-platforming Trump and Parler is undoubtedly a good thing in the short term (and should have happened a long time ago), the sheer visibility of such high-profile bans is likely to dramatically accelerate the adoption of certain communication technologies that are much harder to shut down the same way Parler was.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://web.archive.org/web/20210126023043if_/https://utiglobal.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/server-room.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://web.archive.org/web/20210126023043if_/https://utiglobal.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/server-room.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Imagining an optimistic cyber-future</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2021/01/05/imagining-an-optimistic-cyber-future.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Imagining an optimistic cyber-future" /><published>2021-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2021/01/05/imagining-an-optimistic-cyber-future</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2021/01/05/imagining-an-optimistic-cyber-future.html">&lt;p&gt;(Image credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://detroit.curbed.com/2016/12/1/13807672/urban-agrihood-detroit-mufi&quot;&gt;America’s first sustainable urban agrihood is growing in Detroit&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mastering most things humans do requires lifetimes of practice. Woodworking, gardening, and painting are just a few crafts whose histories stretch back thousands of years. But modern telecommunication, the act of communicating nearly instantaneously with someone from afar, is different. Its history is so short that there is relatively little of it: the very first electric telegraph is not even 200 years old, the first telephone patent was granted in 1876, and the World Wide Web was invented in 1989—a mere 32 years ago. The very newness of digital telecommunication means that the Internet we know today is still in a sort of genesis moment. Cyberspace has barely cooled from its initial big bang. The nature, shape, and ultimate utility of our galaxy of computerized (inter)networks are still being formed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyberspace’s infancy partially explains its volatility. In the last half century, computing power made at least three great migrations. It first existed solely at specialized, isolated campuses. These early, lonely mainframes were like stars in a mostly empty sky. Then came the Personal Computer (PC) revolution of the 1980’s, which rapidly dispersed compute power among homes as though the corporate mainframes burst into millions of pieces. Most recently, compute power has coalesced into datacenters like planetary bodies forming from so much stardust. Consumers know this latest formation as “The Cloud,” in which multinationals like Google and Facebook are the strongest gravitational forces. The pendulum swung from centralized to decentralized, and then back to (kind of) centralized again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time the pendulum swings—and it will—what might the catalyzing event be? What shape might the networks that connect our modern world take? And to what ends might we apply such a shift in compute power?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such questions are critical exercises for honing our collective imagination. They help us refine the language we’ll use to describe the future we want to make real. Unlike the trajectories of stars in the sky, what computers do and how they connect to one another are not choices preordained by God. We decide. And since the impact computers will have on our lives is ultimately up to us to determine, imagining an optimistic cyber-future is the first step towards improving our relationship with digital technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;social-media-and-its-role-in-society&quot;&gt;Social media and its role in society&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is civilization if not knowledge concretized into the physical world around us? Homes have running water because of piping first laid years ago. We call this “plumbing.” But plumbing is an activity only possible because of thousands of years spent refining the practice of moving water from one spot to another, an activity so important to so many follow-on activities that our civilization built increasingly specialized tools and water-handling infrastructures to make the task easier, like aqueducts, reservoirs, and water pumps. Modern hydraulic engineering techniques would probably seem magical to early plumbers, but each improvement was relatively obvious when it was first introduced. Most of this “obvious” knowledge no longer exists directly in any living plumber’s memory because it is instead embodied by the very tools plumbers use; an S-trap pipe “knows” how to create a liquid seal under a sink whether or not those using the sink realize its importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, what is society if not the aggregate of communication between individuals? Social life is defined by—and exists within—the abilities one has to communicate with other people. Love letters sent to a sweetheart, dinner conversation with friends, watching the nightly news, or waiting in your car at a red light are all examples of society taking shape in real-time: they are communiqués from one individual or group to another reinforcing or reshaping their position in society. Some social norms erode, others strengthen, and new ones appear as people interact. Society therefore depends on the ability of its participants to contact one another, which means it needs to have a medium over which its participants can engage in expressly social behaviors. Framed in this light, the term “social media” could be understood in the profound way it needs to be if we are to use it as a collective social good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the Social Media™ of today, which stimulates an imminent need for human connection but is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/the-dilemma/&quot;&gt;never meant to fulfill it&lt;/a&gt;, the social media of our optimistic cyber-future will fulfill existing needs for human connection but will not be designed to stimulate a need for more. Imagine no more notifications pressuring you into meaningless interactions. No more “happy birthday” reminders from people you friended decades ago and haven’t talked to since. An end to newsfeeds full of FOMO-inducing selfies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, social media will support pro-social community interactions, and eschew hollow engagement. Its purpose will be stimulating human(e) connections that prioritize the emotional/mental, spiritual/intellectual, and physical/material needs of the people connecting. This simply means that time spent using online platforms will be primarily intended to support &lt;em&gt;offline&lt;/em&gt; metrics, rather than being designed to addict users to the online activity itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cacophonous distractions of Facebook and Twitter notifications will be gone not because selfies aren’t ever taken or shared, but because the “front page” of social networks more honestly serve the needs of actual life. As you log in, instead of being encouraged to doomscroll, imagine being presented with a tip on homemade bread-making posted by the proprietors of your neighborhood bakery. Perhaps you are acquainted with them through their 50th anniversary video call “party” some months back, an event that had simultaneous in-person and virtual meeting spaces as has become commonplace. Also, you don’t “follow” the bakery account to receive the update any more than you stalk an individual across town as they go about their day. Rather, you simply happened to be in the same (cyber)space at the same time and “overheard” them in the middle of a public discussion about bread-making. This mimics the way your ear naturally tunes in to a conversation between people you know when you walk by them on a crowded street. Browsing social media will feel more like strolling downtown, and less like quietly wiretapping a distant target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A social medium that serves rather than subverts the social needs of individuals is also by definition more capable of providing society with a healthier connective tissue, or social fabric, from which positive connection can more readily grow. By recognizing social media as a critical shared resource worthy of protection in the same way rivers and streams are, our social networks can return to being sites of communal engagement over community matters that are defined more prominently by events that shape our day-to-day lives rather than distant celebrity, the way neighborhood centers, town squares, and even marketplaces are today. This does not mean we imagine a total absence of long-distance communication, but rather a restoration of healthy priorities in which the embodied human condition is reflected in the digital technologies we use to go about our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engaging with our friends, neighbors, and communities will focus once again on concerns over physical space and matters that are relevant to our material lives, rather than some future afterlife, incorporeal existence, or sensational spectacle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;privacy-property-and-abundance-for-everyone-everywhere&quot;&gt;Privacy, property, and abundance for everyone everywhere&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Property laws have long been used as a strategy to manage the working class. During the Industrial Revolution, labor militancy was at times effective at disrupting property’s supremacy. Union organizing could resist the most exploitative aspects of industrial capitalism because a boss’s dependency on the workforce offered workers a means to slow the widening gap in power and control over material resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Big Tech employs a similar strategy, though its logic is stretched past absurdity. Workers rent access to online services laced with behavioral trackers from electronic strip malls, where they buy stuff they don’t need, hawked by “influencers” using social networks designed to addict them to hatred, fear, and disinformation. All this user data is sold to corporations as fuel for powering AI systems capable of replacing and outperforming us in both manufacturing and service jobs. Data itself is now treated as a form of property, &lt;em&gt;intellectual&lt;/em&gt; property, even though the logic of ideas is incompatible with the logic of material things. In this new “attention economy” we are making the machines who are buying our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In “A Hacker Manifesto,” Mackenzie Wark identified the enabling characteristic of such an economy: the way &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Hacker_Manifesto#Main_ideas&quot;&gt;information is being commodified&lt;/a&gt;. Intellectual property, she writes, is an abstraction of capital, which is itself an abstraction of land. In the industrial age, economic value was tied directly to the limited amount of land that could be owned. By abstracting value from land, landowners were the first to generate intangible wealth as stocks and bonds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But abstractions cut both ways: take abstractions too far and their concrete forms lose their immediate potency. For example, a group of workers alienated from their land have few capital resources with which to stage a rebellion, but a group of &lt;em&gt;telecommunicating&lt;/em&gt; workers need not rely on the concreteness of physical place to generate value and can thus access new and different resources with potentially fewer constraints. The ability to telecommunicate, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?t=6m44s&amp;amp;v=HjTWxnBbKbU&quot;&gt;Andrew Feenberg observed, “shifts the boundaries of the personal and the political,” extending “politics into daily life”&lt;/a&gt;; events as varied as the Arab Spring, the Black Lives Matter movement, and the formation of patient advocacy coalitions such as recent COVID-19 Long Haulers groups are all examples of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is the people capable of developing a telecommunications network who benefit most from its physical deployment, it is the network’s topology that determines who will ultimately benefit most from the doubly-abstracted currency of the data-as-property generated by activity on the network. In a centralized system like Facebook, Facebook is the main beneficiary because all activity is directly mediated by Facebook. By design, mere activity on Facebook’s network inevitably enriches Facebook. This is analogous to the way the rentier class extracts money from renters, preventing them from building wealth through home ownership. With the emergence of digital subscription services like Netflix and Spotify, workers must contend with the legal regime of (intellectual) property, technical centralization, and the economics of rent-seeking all at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the same activities made possible by existing centralized systems are also possible on decentralized infrastructures precisely &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; of data’s abstractedness. Decentralized networks provide another benefit: they enable coordination with no single command center, which is itself an obstacle to acquiring data-as-property. Mesh topologies do not inherently enrich an existing monopoly, but rather the participants themselves. A group of telecommunicating workers organizing on a centralized system might be able to use tools unavailable to early 20th century labor unions, but their organizing still won’t produce wealth of their own. By switching to a decentralized system, the act of organizing itself becomes an act of self-enrichment with no theoretical limit in the data/attention economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine how such a communications network could make political discourse of immediate material benefit to those who engage in it. Reclaiming speech from being a data-product mined from our minds will return it to our communities as social cohesion, creating a virtuous circle enriching our collective consciousness. Discourse will highlight reasonable argumentation, aided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.diigo.com/&quot;&gt;collaborative annotations&lt;/a&gt; and speedy fact checking tools to help people avoid regurgitating misinformation, opening up opportunities for more productive interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community-oriented discourse inherently favors local businesses, keeping local wealth in the community. As social ties grow stronger within the bounds of physical proximity, the line between public and private property will inevitably blur. Neighborhood wellbeing systems will grow out of these ties, too, connecting and strengthening interactions where we look after each other to provide security. Rather than outsourcing our individual safety to Ring cameras sending video streams of our homes to police departments, neighborly telecommunication is used to supercharge existing physical-world alternatives like people letting their neighbors know if they need someone to look after their kids or pets. The “neighborhood network,” no longer wholly operated by Amazon Sidewalk, will become a way to break the ice between neighbors and encourage community engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, as the value of data increases, the notion of “property” will continue to evolve from describing objects we own to describing knowledge we share. The most valuable things in life are already those things that are worth as much “used” as they are “new,” a distinction that no longer exists in cyberspace. And so the endless replicability of digital things, once punished as “piracy,” will be embraced as a way to create new wealth rather than suppressed in the pursuit of rent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-rise-and-fall-of-techno-feudalism&quot;&gt;The rise and fall of techno-feudalism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the Internet embeds itself into more elements of daily life, more people recognize that the gap between State and Corporation is closing. The global economy has already become increasingly codependent with multinationals who are amassing State-like powers and developing bureaucratic governance structures. Critical government functions already rely on corporate operators who are increasingly defining the same government policies they operationalize. Government has all but abandoned its sovereignty as it merges with industry, since government relies on industry to function. Meanwhile, industry is aggressively grafting itself to government since it relies on the functions of the State to police its labor force and to legalize exploitative employment practices. Over time, Silicon Valley will replace everything with robots, and politicians will turn to ever more draconian measures to quell rebellions against the technocracy on which their governments depend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As glaciers melt, wildfires rage, and government services fail, we imagine more and more of us will recognize the need to decentralize power to push back against this dystopian chimera. We will establish many new heterogeneous infrastructures for networking, storing, and sharing information, because this is important for regaining our autonomy. It has in fact already begun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many &lt;a href=&quot;https://roarmag.org/essays/freeing-space-building-worlds-outside-of-state-and-capital/&quot;&gt;dual-power projects&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://roarmag.org/essays/win-back-the-internet/&quot;&gt;self-owned telecoms networks&lt;/a&gt; are exploring ways to thrive while minimizing their cooperation with existing capital. The material conditions and physical components necessary for such success are becoming more accessible. For example, physical telecoms infrastructure—radios, cabling, and internetworking devices (routers)—are now almost as ubiquitous in cities as wild grass on ancient plains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the Internet is at its core a set of interconnected computers, many people in dozens of countries already have all the materials they need to service many of their day-to-day needs without involving large companies or sums of money, like keeping phone numbers synchronized across multiple devices, planning their days with a digital calendar, or drafting documents. We need only take a few steps beyond such modest origins to imagine far more impactful uses for the same equipment where security, autonomy, and activism are interwoven. This realization is leading more and more people to abandon monopolistic corporate services by providing the services they need for themselves using “&lt;a href=&quot;https://homebrewserver.club/&quot;&gt;home-brew servers&lt;/a&gt;” running Free Software, like a generation of pioneering digital homesteaders. Even better, in cyberspace, newcomers need not displace an indigenous people to settle cyber-land because the metaphorical “land” itself is virtually infinite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet as we know it today collapses the experience of distance, making every location in cyberspace feel as near as any other location. But in our optimistic cyber-future we will have resisted the temptation to abandon the physical realm, and thereby the Earth, by focusing instead on interconnecting our own servers and local networks with those of our neighbors. This will have been a key step in building the community-owned and surveillance-resistant networks that eventually give rise to powerful autonomous territories, having enabled us to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techlearningcollective.com/2020/11/13/we-have-only-four-years-to-prevent-a-fascist-usa-heres-what-we-need-to-do-now.html&quot;&gt;conduct local coordination on local infrastructure, rather than on Facebook’s&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the earliest stars in the emptiest skies, these pockets of freedom will grow out of &lt;a href=&quot;https://roarmag.org/essays/dean-spade-mutual-aid-excerpt/&quot;&gt;mutual aid networks&lt;/a&gt; and good old fashioned neighborly camaraderie. There, an economy organized around freedom and care rather than production and consumption will mean certain needs—food distribution, educational pedagogy, and more—will be fulfilled differently than in the surrounding bureaucracy. The autonomous pockets will quickly seek to interconnect, covering more ground as their practices and networks mature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the techno-feudalist State will continue intentionally destroying its citizens’ lives through overwork and fascist concentration camps, weakening its ability to extract labor and enforce dogmatic ideology. Its citizenry will face an increasingly stark choice between ecological harmony and autonomy or eventual extinction and serfdom. Surrounded by technology that has turned everything around them into a tool and anything into a weapon, &lt;a href=&quot;https://inhabit.global/&quot;&gt;they betray the State, choosing liberty over patriotism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fleeing the &lt;em&gt;ancien regime&lt;/em&gt; grants us access to new spaces for learning and more “free time” for filling with our own curiosity and desires. In-person connection will be encouraged by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.urbanlibraries.org/resources/makerspaces-in-libraries&quot;&gt;merging physical resources like tool lending libraries with intellectual resources like traditional book libraries&lt;/a&gt;, further enabling cross-disciplinary exchanges that propel a neighborhood’s development. In some cases, certain data stores could be most easily accessed in-person at one of these next-generation community hubs, reminiscent of the best parts of religious gatherings or nightclubs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Borders separating rural and urban areas will fade as telecommuting will become more feasible in more jobs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.raspberrypi.org/en/projects/build-your-own-weather-station&quot;&gt;Weather monitoring equipment&lt;/a&gt; will be installed at inner-city community gardens. It will be maintained with the same care and by the same team that ensures the crops there are properly watered by the weather-sensing irrigation system hooked up to the region’s intranet. Such geographical consciousness also makes it easier to imagine more ecologically sustainable futures, in which anti-racist modes of energy production rebalance the burden of climate disaster more equitably across the Global North and the Global South, perhaps by encouraging both individual and institutional action that brings solar energy production costs down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having rejected the absurdity of intellectual property, the autonomous regions will be covered by a near total mesh network like an electronic circulatory system. Important public archives, like Wikipedia, will be automatically copied in full to numerous locations in each neighborhood. This will make the notion of paying for Internet access obsolete because residents won’t want to pay to reach a distant server when the majority of what we need is readily available in one of a number of nearby locations freely accessible via myriad routes. Horizontally scaling out data stores also dramatically reduces the strain on long-distance links, enabling the autonomous regions to more easily establish &lt;a href=&quot;https://freenetworks.org/about/&quot;&gt;free peering relationships&lt;/a&gt; with one another. This enmeshed communication will further support anti-colonialist practices of inter-communal, inter-generational, and even international activism that continues to fuel the downfall of the former techno-feudalist society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Automation will continue to economically devastate the techno-feudalist State due to its zeal for punishing idleness, causing bread lines to grow to horrific lengths. In contrast, the autonomous regions will use increased automation to reap productivity out of shortening work weeks. Eventually, as more economic activity is automated, organized asynchronously, or people simply become willing to embrace new methods of work (without being forced to do so by a traumatic global pandemic), everyone will finally be free to make their own choices about how they spend their time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Empty city lots and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foodnotlawns.com/&quot;&gt;residential lawns will be transformed into food forests&lt;/a&gt;. Next door to each of the food lots, social knowledge hubs will be built because food will be revered as the center of social life. These hubs will host seed-swap events for other urban farmers, replete with seed library catalogues, food share and organic waste systems, and eco-education events. They will publish digital calendars, and the same system will be used to coordinate work schedules among community members. This infrastructure could also catalyze in-person encounters by combining digital resources such as poetry libraries with a platform to participate in poetry readings and writing workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No longer will the social function of something like a garden be made separate from its material function. Telecommunication can facilitate their rejoining. Perhaps it was always meant to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">In the last half century, computing power made at least three great migrations. The pendulum swung from centralized to decentralized, and then back to (kind of) centralized again. Next time the pendulum swings—and it will—what might the catalyzing event be? What shape might the networks that connect our modern world take? And to what ends might we apply such a shift in compute power?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://web.archive.org/web/20200509054116if_/https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/15SEQOYBZIpfRpqwY6g8DhGvFNM=/0x115:2400x1465/1600x900/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/52088969/2I1A4480__2_.0.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://web.archive.org/web/20200509054116if_/https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/15SEQOYBZIpfRpqwY6g8DhGvFNM=/0x115:2400x1465/1600x900/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/52088969/2I1A4480__2_.0.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Winning back the Internet by building our own</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/11/18/winning-back-the-internet-by-building-our-own.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Winning back the Internet by building our own" /><published>2020-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/11/18/winning-back-the-internet-by-building-our-own</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/11/18/winning-back-the-internet-by-building-our-own.html">&lt;p&gt;When mentioning the year 2001, most people may think of the attacks on 9/11. But five months prior to that historic date, another event occurred that would continue to shape history in less dramatic but equally profound ways. In April that year, American computer programmer Bram Cohen began designing BitTorrent, a new file sharing protocol that would almost single-handedly change the music, TV and movie industries for decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology was not in itself a completely new idea. After all, similar technologies like the well-known File Transfer Protocol (FTP) had been designed and deployed for copying files between computers before. What made this one so potent was the way it reflected the fractured, organic structure of its underlying medium, the Internet itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of treating each file as a single monolithic whole, this new technology broke each file apart into a set of similarly-sized pieces and treated each piece independently of any other piece. Unlike earlier client-server technologies like FTP, this new “peer-to-peer” technology could retrieve any piece of the whole from any other peer who already had a copy of that piece, even if that peer did not have all the pieces like a traditional server would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BitTorrent and its segmented-file transfer technology is to this day the bane of corporate gatekeepers like the Record Industry Association of America (RIAA) and Motion Picture Association of America (MPAA). Like the earlier emergence of the Internet, BitTorrent catalyzed a wave of rebellious activity from ordinary people who were disadvantaged by punitive legal and oppressive political regimes. Most of these rebels probably would not have described themselves that way, or identified what they were doing as a form of “direct action” or “civil disobedience,” but like most successful revolutions, the cyber rebellion that BitTorrent ignited started in the cracks where existing regimes cannot easily see or police behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fighting-for-the-freedom-to-share&quot;&gt;Fighting for the freedom to share&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With BitTorrent, there is no more famous example than The Pirate Bay, which its founders proudly intended as a way for everyday people to simultaneously improve their lives and fight against globalist organizations such as the World Intellectual Property Organization (WIPO). By making the simple act of sharing without regard to copyright laws or global trade agreements easy and normal, people were more easily able to access the things they needed without being forced to ask or pay for permission to have them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyleft#Copyleft_principles&quot;&gt;freedom to share&lt;/a&gt;” was one of the early promises of the Internet we must win back. Many onlookers heralded the early Internet as an inherently democratizing tool that would inevitably lead to a reformation of society with equality and justice for all. Of course, it did not turn out that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some will remember the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcmag.com/news/crypto-wars-why-the-fight-to-encrypt-rages-on&quot;&gt;Crypto Wars&lt;/a&gt; in the 1980s and 1990s, in which governments reserved encryption technology solely for military use. Cypherpunk and early “Hacker” culture sprang from this era. Sadly, techno-utopians at the time like the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://reason.com/video/2020/10/07/before-the-web-the-1980s-dream-of-a-free-and-borderless-virtual-world/&quot;&gt;High Tech Hayekians&lt;/a&gt;” mostly focused on new and shiny gadgets, centering pro-capitalist market economics while ignoring the forces of industrialization poisoning the soil on which they were building their Cyberspace Garden of Eden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short order, Internet access itself was commercialized and the telecom industry waged legislative war against community groups and municipal governments that prevented them from erecting their own networking infrastructures. The logic of the telecom monopolies was simple and devastatingly effective: to share, you must first connect, so instead of losing the battle to share, they would win the war of connectivity. In other words, they recognized that they could not win against a rapidly rising number of increasingly sophisticated people using ever-improving encryption and privacy tools, but they could install themselves as toll collectors for Internet access itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how the modern Internet as we know it today was shaped. For years, we have seen the Internet used to surveil, divide and control people. Would-be dictators like Trump and others across the globe use the Internet to bend both people and institutions to their will using misinformation and fear. Today, for most of us the Internet is little more than a heavily surveilled, over-policed Electronic Strip Mall in which we are carefully herded from one company’s property to another. But this, too, is not an inevitable outcome of the digital internetworking technologies we have at our disposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BitTorrent succeeded not only as a technology in its own right, but also in frustrating efforts to police digital rebellions largely because it mirrored the decentralized nature of the network on which it was deployed; the Internet. BitTorrent and the software that makes the Internet possible are technologies that do not require any special permission or product to connect to, interoperate with, or extend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a very long time, no one paid for Internet access because Internet access was not something that was sold. It was like a public beachfront at the ocean. If you were near it, you could jump in, no credit card required. The nature of the technology itself meant that if you had a computer running an operating system with a TCP/IP software stack installed, like any modern Windows, macOS, or GNU/Linux distribution, you could extend the Internet. All you had to do is connect your computer to another computer already pre-attached to it. As with BitTorrent, there was no other special software or hardware required, and everyone who wanted to download files could, by definition, also upload files. And, more importantly, this is still true about internetworking software today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can we learn from BitTorrent’s success 20 years later? If we want to accept the Internet’s “&lt;a href=&quot;https://c4ss.org/content/53608&quot;&gt;offer of freedom&lt;/a&gt;,” as envisioned by optimistic earlier generations, we must (re)learn this vital lesson: the Internet we are made to pay for is not the only way to connect to one another. We merely need to pave our own digital pathways, to create our own lowercase-i “internets.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, you might think this is a lot of work, but in reality much of the work has already been done. The resources this actually requires in terms of money and equipment are minimal and becoming ever more ubiquitous. There is also no need to write new code or build new apps to make this happen. Since there is so much existing software freely available already, nearly &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/awesome-selfhosted/awesome-selfhosted/blob/master/README.md#readme&quot;&gt;every imaginable need&lt;/a&gt; is accounted for. We already have all the raw materials we need to get the job done. The only thing we lack is broader commitment from neighborhood residents and community members, themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-our-own-internets&quot;&gt;Building our own internets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet (capital-I) is the name of a specific network, the one in which specific computers and familiar services with names like Google, Facebook and the Wall Street Journal reside. In contrast, the word internet (lowercase-i) describes any network of interconnected networks. An internet of your own can host everything else: data you want to keep to yourself, posts that would be banned on corporate-controlled media (like many antifa groups have recently found with Facebook), or simply creative works you make for fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can put such things on the computers owned by Google and accessed via the toll roads owned by Verizon, Rogers or Comcast, but the point is that you do not have to. Our own (lowercase-i) internet is also capable of providing the services most people use for many of their day-to-day needs, such as keeping phone numbers synchronized across multiple devices, planning their days with a digital calendar, or drafting documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meaningful difference between that (capital-I) Internet and our own (lowercase-i) internet is &lt;em&gt;who owns the computers between us&lt;/em&gt;, not the software on either end nor the software in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This distinction between features (like “document sharing”) and ownership is absolutely critical. Before the Internet was “The Internet,” it was simply one of several networks built in exactly the same way and using exactly the same technology as others were. Creating such networks today has never been easier, or less expensive. Indeed, today there are already many internets that you can connect to for free, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://guifi.net/&quot;&gt;Guifi&lt;/a&gt; in Spain, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://nycmesh.net/&quot;&gt;NYCMesh&lt;/a&gt; in New York City. For many years, Cubans have had their own internet they built themselves called the “street network” or SNET. The Personal Telco project maintains &lt;a href=&quot;https://personaltelco.net/wiki/WirelessCommunities&quot;&gt;a list&lt;/a&gt; of many dozens more across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is important to understand is that these networks were built with the same tools as the ones that built the Internet you pay for today: commonplace Ethernet cable, commodity computer hardware and the labor from people excited about spending their time sharing their digital creations with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Cubans, who were barred from connecting their own internets to the globally-networked Internet due to the US embargo, SNET provided everything you would expect to get through your computer, like news, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polygon.com/features/2017/5/15/15625950/cuba-secret-gaming-network&quot;&gt;games&lt;/a&gt;, blogs, social networking and more. It had all this even though it did not connect to the Internet we are most familiar with. Meanwhile, both Guifi and NYCMesh offer its users a combination of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://nycmesh-docs.netlify.app/intra-mesh-services/&quot;&gt;intra-mesh services&lt;/a&gt;” and content for local residents similar to SNET along with more traditional Internet access, highlighting the fact that building our own internets is not an either-or proposition, nor a zero-sum game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the Internet fulfill the promise of its earlier incarnations and beat back the forces of industrialization suffocating the promise of freedom online, we must first build new, local internets. The Internet collapses our experience of distance because every location in cyberspace feels no further than any other location. But we must resist the temptation to abandon the physical realm, and thereby the Earth, by focusing instead on interconnecting our local networks with the local networks of those around us. This enables local coordination on local infrastructure, rather than on Facebook’s, which is a key step towards a community-owned and surveillance-resistant network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only by breaking the Internet and our understanding of it into pieces, just like BitTorrent segmented files, can we begin to collaboratively reconstruct it anew, and in the process threaten the literal marketshare and metaphorical mindshare that these monopolies currently have over us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;owning-our-own-infrastructure&quot;&gt;Owning our own infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it take to build an internet? We will need computers, of course, but not especially powerful or expensive ones. As the &lt;a href=&quot;https://homebrewserver.club/choosing-a-homebrew-server.html#benefits-and-disadvantages-of-laptops-as-servers&quot;&gt;Homebrew Server Club explains&lt;/a&gt;, “laptops make good homebrew servers since they are widely available, relatively powerful and energy efficient.” Wire up two laptops together using a commonplace Ethernet (RJ-45) cable and you have the beginnings of an internet. Add a third laptop, or perhaps a card-sized &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raspberrypi.org/&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, and you can run a dedicated service such as a website or shared address book or calendar. You can even create a Wi-Fi connection for roaming clients — perhaps your new tiny internet is in an infoshop — all without ever connecting to The Internet proper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we’ll need imagination. Your internet may be small right now, but it can grow, just like the original internet grew to become The Internet we know today. Perhaps you publish a website of resistance poetry as part of a collection of ebooks (you are at an infoshop after all) and your neighbors want to browse the collection, too. Get another Ethernet cable and plug them in, no user account required. One way to think about these interconnected pockets of computers is the same way as you would think about the multiple computers connected to the Wi-Fi network in your house: you only need one connection leading to other people’s computers, but you can connect many hundreds if not more computers to that one connection at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internetworking technologies, like BitTorrent, are built on the notion of smaller pieces, each of them individually-addressable segments, that can be composed together to create a larger whole. Neither the Internet nor BitTorrent file transfers are actually monoliths. That means we do not need any person’s or any company’s permission, license key or commercial product to create our own, to interconnect them to our peers, and to run and maintain useful services on them. It is long past time for us to stop asking or paying for permission to build the world we want to live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join enough individually operated internets together — that is, run another Ethernet cable to the next building, and the next, and the next — and we will have a newly minted “Internet” to rival the current one. Except, this time, we will own it outright instead of renting access to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you live too far away from the infoshop or the buildings in our example, above? We mentioned earlier that having or using our own internets does not require disconnecting from the global Internet because connecting to other networks is always optional. This means you can still securely piggy-back on an existing capital-I Internet connection to knit your own networks together by using Virtual Private Networking (VPN) and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.torproject.org/onion-services/&quot;&gt;Tor (Onion service)&lt;/a&gt; routing technologies until such time as the people who own the computers in between you and your desired destination connect their computers to yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These more infrastructural components of telecom autonomy are the first prerequisite steps we must take to secure the Internet’s earlier promises and take it out of the hands of its corporate and governmental owners. That is why radical tech education efforts such as those by the &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective&lt;/a&gt; focus on infrastructure, not coding. Instead of learning to become programmers useful only for large companies who already control your access to digital information, students are taught fundamental internetworking skills overlooked by the rush-to-employment programs of various school-to-corporation pipelines. It is why projects like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/shiftctrlspace/library&quot;&gt;Shift-CTRL Space Library&lt;/a&gt;, which offers a pre-packaged collection of software to more easily share collections of e-books — PDFs, zines and more — are built using widely available Free Software and without consideration for available capital-I Internet access as it is traditionally envisioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already have the power, the materials and the motive to fight and win back the Internet. But we cannot start at the last step of building — even more — “new” apps. We have to start with the first step first: owning our own infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">We already have the power, the materials and the motive to win back the Internet. But we have to start with the first step first: owning our own infrastructure.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/win-back-the-internet-2K-1920x1046.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/win-back-the-internet-2K-1920x1046.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">We have only four years to prevent a fascist USA: Here’s what we need to do now</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/11/13/we-have-only-four-years-to-prevent-a-fascist-usa-heres-what-we-need-to-do-now.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We have only four years to prevent a fascist USA: Here’s what we need to do now" /><published>2020-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/11/13/we-have-only-four-years-to-prevent-a-fascist-usa-heres-what-we-need-to-do-now</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/11/13/we-have-only-four-years-to-prevent-a-fascist-usa-heres-what-we-need-to-do-now.html">&lt;p&gt;Trump lost. Last weekend we celebrated the electoral defeat of a US president undeniably behaving as an openly fascist dictator. Yet we must remember that elections are for choosing the &lt;em&gt;targets&lt;/em&gt; of our political pressure, not for choosing our saviors. Only we the people, not the president-elect, can meaningfully bring that pressure to bear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hate movement that carried Trump to the presidency is bruised but not broken. Writing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/2020-presidential-election/2020/11/7/21554114/trump-election-2020-voter-fraud-challenge-recount-biden&quot;&gt;at &lt;em&gt;Vox&lt;/em&gt;, Ezra Klein notes&lt;/a&gt; “[t]he conditions that made Trump and this Republican Party possible are set to worsen,” pointing out that not only have Democrats failed to flip the Senate as the polls predicted, but that Republican politicians still control redistricting efforts in statehouses across the country. They will surely use that control to further entrench anti-majoritarian rule for another decade. Then there’s the new 6-3 &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2020/11/alito-federalist-society-speech-insane.html&quot;&gt;conservative and partisan&lt;/a&gt; majority on the Supreme Court, to say nothing of the well over two hundred conservative judges that have been added to the judiciary with &lt;em&gt;lifetime&lt;/em&gt; appointments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turkish-born technologist and sociologist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/11/trump-proved-authoritarians-can-get-elected-america/617023/&quot;&gt;Zeynep Tufecki warns in &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that “[this] situation is a perfect setup, in other words, for a talented politician to run on Trumpism in 2024. […] Make no mistake: The attempt to harness Trumpism—without Trump, but with calculated, refined, and smarter political talent—is coming. And it won’t be easy to make the next Trumpist a one-term president.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the success of a Democratic presidential ticket alone won’t stop the right wing’s anti-democratic onslaught from pushing this country towards undiluted fascism. What it &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; do is buy us some time to consolidate, strategize, and then push back. If we are to avoid an openly fascist USA come 2024, we’ll need to actually use all the time that’s been given to us to prevent the rise of the next American autocrat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is much that needs to be accomplished between now and then. Thankfully, we already have many heroes who deserve support, none more so than voters in the four Black-majority cities that flipped the Electoral College: Milwaukee, Detroit, Atlanta and, of course, Philadelphia. Supporting them properly requires acknowledging the importance of a wide array of tactics in our shared fight against white supremacy and racist autocracy. Some people will be better positioned to engage in the electoral process itself than others, and that’s okay. Although voting, petitioning, and other legal measures are all highly visible and important pieces of the puzzle, they are &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/10/08/the-internet-was-always-anarchist-so-anarchists-must-learn-to-become-responsible-for-operating-it.html&quot;&gt;mostly seeded by earlier efforts like investing in communities&lt;/a&gt; and building infrastructures that are too often shortchanged on budget sheets and lack the attention, understanding, or appreciation they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, we’ve seen the Internet used to surveil, divide, and control people. There’s no doubt would-be dictators like Trump and others across the globe are able to bend both people and institutions to their will using misinformation and fear spread at Internet speed. What’s new this decade is that no one doubts the power of our modern computer networks any longer. What the people doubt now is their own ability to use it for good instead of ill, and that’s what we’re determined to make change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before our next opportunity to repudiate the fascists and their apologists in the political “center” at the ballot box four years from now, we’re focusing our efforts on helping as many people as possible build power in their personal lives and in their communities by accomplishing four key goals. Viewed individually, these are apolitical objectives beneficial for everyone across every political spectrum, regardless of any single issue. Taken together, however, they actualize a strong Anarchist and Autonomist ethic animating everything we do at Tech Learning Collective and at many of our partner organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;one-become-your-own-google-contacts-calendar-docs-etcetera&quot;&gt;One: Become your own Google (Contacts, Calendar, Docs, etcetera).&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the common services that most people use for many of their day-to-day needs, such as keeping phone numbers synchronized across multiple devices, planning their days with a digital calendar, or drafting documents can be easily accomplished without involving large companies or sums of money. Abandon the search for “a more trustworthy alternative” to Google by providing the services you need for yourself. Just as one might learn to grow a small portion of one’s own food in a garden or greenhouse, commit to increasing your digital self-reliance over time as you hone your digital green thumb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be prepared for this to take some time. If you’re unsure where to start, join us for any &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt; that sound fun to you! There’s no need to change all your habits at once. Instead, take note of the many daily activities that don’t require an Internet connection or even a Web browser to accomplish at all. Then simply, well, simplify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some cases, such as intra-office file sharing, streaming music from a personal library, or loading your favorite e-books to read at night, a local network rather than a connection to the global Internet is very often sufficient. Install a &lt;a href=&quot;https://homebrewserver.club/&quot;&gt;home-brew server&lt;/a&gt; to fill this simple role. It’s like the digital equivalent of potting a clipping of your favorite herb on your windowsill. The more you care for it, the more it will reward you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In those situations where the Internet is truly necessary or dramatically more practical, Free, Libre, and Open Source Software is capable of providing many more features than those offered to you by the data-mining corporations, and more privately. There’s no need to code new apps or even to learn much if anything about how to code at all. Since there is so much existing software available already, nearly &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/awesome-selfhosted/awesome-selfhosted/blob/master/README.md#readme&quot;&gt;every imaginable need&lt;/a&gt; is accounted for. In fact, internally, Tech Learning Collective operates on self-hosted Free Software tools, like a CalDAV server for meeting schedules and reminders (replacing our need for Google Calendar), and an XMPP server for group chats (replacing our need for Slack).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very soon, you will have taken your first step into a larger world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;two-gather-others-and-practice-connecting-and-communicating-securely-with-them&quot;&gt;Two: Gather others and practice connecting and communicating securely with them.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you can provide for even some of your own digital needs, you will find that you have surplus capacity (extra disk space, compute power, and/or bandwidth) that you can provide to others. (At Tech Learning Collective, we use old models of the cheapest computers available, such as the single-board &lt;a href=&quot;https://raspberrypi.org/&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, and we still have plenty of room to grow.) Use this excess as an opportunity to bring others you care about along in this journey with you. If they’re like you, pay it forward by showing them how to set up their own home-brew server as you did. Otherwise, share the excess by inviting them to make use of the services you once provided solely for yourself. The more you share, the more you’ll be continuing to hone your skills as a system administrator, becoming an ever more practiced and experienced “digital farmer” or tradesperson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things change dramatically when you begin to involve others, so you’ll have to start considering inter-user protections in a way you haven’t had to before. Security becomes (even more) important. You’ll have responsibilities not only for your own data, but someone else’s, too. This should feel new and different to you, because it is. Practice communicating about what, when, and why you’re taking certain actions that may affect other people, and do it using secure and private communications channels, like &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Signal-and-Surveillance-How-to-Exercise-Digital-Civil-Liberties-in-a-Surveillance-State&quot;&gt;Signal Private Messenger&lt;/a&gt; groups or, of course, a self-hosted chat or federated microblogging service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;three-embrace-physical-proximity-by-interconnecting-individually-owned-infrastructure&quot;&gt;Three: Embrace physical proximity by interconnecting individually-owned infrastructure.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet collapses the experience of distance because every location in cyberspace appears to be no further than any other location. Resist the temptation to abandon the physical realm, and thereby the Earth, by focusing instead on interconnecting your home-brew server or local network with the home-brew servers or local networks of those around you. This enables local coordination on local infrastructure, rather than on Facebook’s, which is a key step towards a community-owned and surveillance-resistant network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making such connections can start as simply as sharing your Wi-Fi password with a neighbor in exchange for splitting the monthly Internet bill, but soon you’ll want to go faster and reach farther. Replace weak wireless signals by running physical Ethernet cable across apartments (an easy task in older multi-family houses) or practice “roof-hopping” over longer distances in your neighborhood with more specialized radio equipment. In Detroit, for example, you can work with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.detroitcommunitytech.org/&quot;&gt;Detroit Community Technology Project&lt;/a&gt; to gain hands-on experience doing exactly this. Many other cities have similar opportunities, and in those that don’t you can start your own more modest internetworking projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you reach your physical limits, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Two-Places-at-Once-Understanding-Virtual-Private-Networks&quot;&gt;use Virtual Private Networking (VPN)&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Tor-What-is-it-Good-For-(Absolutely-Everything!)&quot;&gt;Tor (Onion service) routing&lt;/a&gt; to connect your fledgling network with a more geographically distant friend’s, creating a proper &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/11/11/how-we-can-win-back-the-internet-by-creating-lowercase-internets.html&quot;&gt;(lowercase-i) internet&lt;/a&gt; among yourselves. You may need to piggyback on the existing (capital-I) Internet for this, or you may not, but in either case you’ll be building physical and digital power above and beyond merely electoral and representational power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage, you will likely benefit from &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/What's-in-a-Name-Understanding-the-Domain-Name-System&quot;&gt;installing Internet-like infrastructure, such as Domain Name System (DNS) servers&lt;/a&gt;. Since these are your own, you need not adhere to the familiar “dot-com” or “dot-org” domain names, nor must you register with and pay an external company for permission to be known by a given name. On your internet with your friends, everything is free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;four-grow-communities-by-extending-infrastructure-and-strengthen-community-power-by-building-coalitions&quot;&gt;Four: Grow communities by extending infrastructure and strengthen community power by building coalitions.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reject the idea that successful mobilizations must be large, or that to do anything meaningful you must first do it “at scale.” Instead, build coalitions with neighbors and others in your locality by building on relationships already established through earlier work building physical infrastructure together. You can coordinate public actions that are small at first and scale over time as you gain experience working on and solving problems collectively. Coalition means scaling &lt;em&gt;out&lt;/em&gt;, not scaling up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Trump lost last weekend, he didn’t just lose one election. He lost many individual State elections. What we witnessed this past week was only possible because of a cooperating coalition of individual actors and institutions moving in concert. That cooperation is what every lowercase-d democratic institution is in its essence. The same principle holds for the Internet, and that principle is the reason the Internet still has the potential to serve as a foundational platform on which we can continually choose to refute fascism. But not if we do so only on Twitter. &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/08/29/democracy-is-bankrupt-id-like-an-extra-large-i-voted-sticker-with-a-side-of-political-sedative-please.html&quot;&gt;Not if we limit our toolkit only to ballot boxes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people are probably just starting to work towards the first goal on this list. Others may be further along. No matter which goal you’re currently aiming for, Tech Learning Collective’s goal is to offer guidance to those of you willing to go on this journey with us. Together, there is nothing we can’t do.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Trump lost. Last weekend we celebrated the electoral defeat of a US president undeniably behaving as an openly fascist dictator. Yet we must remember that elections are for choosing the targets of our political pressure, not for choosing our saviors. Only we the people, not the president-elect, can meaningfully bring that pressure to bear.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.we-have-only-four-years-to-prevent-a-fascist-usa-heres-what-we-need-to-do-now.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.we-have-only-four-years-to-prevent-a-fascist-usa-heres-what-we-need-to-do-now.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How we can win back the Internet by creating lowercase internets</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/11/11/how-we-can-win-back-the-internet-by-creating-lowercase-internets.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How we can win back the Internet by creating lowercase internets" /><published>2020-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/11/11/how-we-can-win-back-the-internet-by-creating-lowercase-internets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/11/11/how-we-can-win-back-the-internet-by-creating-lowercase-internets.html">&lt;p&gt;In April 2001, five months before 9/11, Bram Cohen began designing a new file sharing protocol that would almost single-handedly change the face of the music, TV, and movie industries for the next two decades. The technology was not in itself a completely new idea. After all, similar technologies like the well-known File Transfer Protocol (FTP) had been designed and deployed for copying files between computers before. What made this one so potent was the way it reflected the fractured, organic structure of its underlying medium, the Internet itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of treating each file as a single monolithic whole, this new technology broke each file apart into a set of similarly-sized pieces and treated each piece independently of any other piece. Unlike earlier client-server technologies like FTP, this new “peer-to-peer” technology could retrieve any piece of the whole from any other peer who already had a copy of that piece, even if that peer didn’t have all the pieces like a traditional server would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new technology was called &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/File-Sharing-for-Fun-and-Profit-How-BitTorrent-Works-and-What-You-Can-Do-With-It&quot;&gt;BitTorrent&lt;/a&gt;, and its segmented-file transfer technology is, to this day, the bane of corporate gatekeepers like the Record Industry Association of America (RIAA) and Motion Picture Association of America (MPAA). BitTorrent succeeded because it mirrored the decentralized nature of the network on which it was deployed, the Internet. BitTorrent and the Internet are both technologies that do not require any special permission or product to connect to, interoperate with, or extend. If you have a computer running an operating system with a TCP/IP software stack installed, like any modern Windows, macOS, or GNU/Linux distribution, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Clearing-Away-the-Clouds-How-Computer-Networks,-Servers,-and-the-Internet-Work&quot;&gt;you can extend the Internet&lt;/a&gt;. All you have to do is connect your computer to another computer already pre-attached to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we still learn from BitTorrent’s success twenty years later? If we want to accept &lt;a href=&quot;https://c4ss.org/content/53608&quot;&gt;the “Internet’s offer” of freedom&lt;/a&gt;, as envisioned by optimistic earlier generations, we must (re)learn this vital lesson: the Internet is tangential. We merely need to create &lt;em&gt;an internet&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet (capital-I) is the name of a specific network. The Internet “hosts” computers with names like Google, Facebook, and the Wall Street Journal. In contrast, the word internet (lowercase-i) describes any network of interconnected networks. An internet can host everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This distinction is absolutely critical. To connect your computer to the Internet, you are required to pony up fiat currency to a company like Comcast, Verizon, or Rogers. There are, however, many internets that you can connect to for free, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://guifi.net/&quot;&gt;Guifi&lt;/a&gt; in Spain or &lt;a href=&quot;https://nycmesh.net/&quot;&gt;NYCMesh&lt;/a&gt; here in New York City. Unlike the Internet, you can even create a new internet on your own, optionally connecting it to any other internet willing and able to connect back to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the Internet was The Internet, it was simply an internet. To win the Internet back from the forces of industrialization suffocating the promise of freedom online, we must focus first on building new internets: we must break the Internet and our understanding of it into pieces, just like BitTorrent segmented files, so that we can collaboratively reconstruct it anew, and in the process threaten the literal marketshare and metaphorical mindshare that these monopolies currently have over us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, you might think this is a lot of work, but in reality much of the work has already been done. The resources required in terms of money and equipment are minimal and becoming ever more ubiquitous. There is also no need to write new code or build new apps to make this happen. We already have all the raw materials we need to get the job done. The only thing we lack is broader commitment from neighborhood residents and community members themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it take to build an internet? We’ll need computers, of course, but not especially powerful or expensive ones. As the &lt;a href=&quot;https://homebrewserver.club/choosing-a-homebrew-server.html#benefits-and-disadvantages-of-laptops-as-servers&quot;&gt;Homebrew Server Club explains&lt;/a&gt;, personal “[l]aptops make good homebrew servers since they are widely available, relatively powerful and energy efficient.” Wire up two laptops together using a commonplace Ethernet (RJ-45) cable and you have the beginnings of an internet. Add a third laptop, or perhaps a &lt;a href=&quot;https://raspberrypi.org/&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, and you can run a dedicated service such as a Web site or shared address book or calendar. You can even create a Wi-Fi connection for roaming clients (perhaps your new tiny internet is in an infoshop), all without ever connecting to The Internet proper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we’ll need imagination. Your internet may be small right now, but it can grow, just like the original internet grew to become The Internet we know today. Perhaps you publish a Web site of resistance poetry as part of a collection of ebooks (you are at an infoshop after all) and your woke neighbors want to browse the collection, too. Get another Ethernet cable and plug them in, no credit card required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internets like this already exist. We mentioned Guifi in Spain and NYC Mesh in New York City, but there are also smaller pockets of neighborhood-scale internets that offer local services in exactly this fashion. Some even connect back to the Internet proper (like NYCMesh does), so that they can simultaneously offer &lt;a href=&quot;https://nycmesh-docs.netlify.app/intra-mesh-services/&quot;&gt;local-only services&lt;/a&gt; as well as more traditional Internet access. One way to think about these interconnected pockets of computers is the same way as you would think about the multiple computers connected to the Wi-Fi network in your house: you only pay for one connection, but you can connect many hundreds if not more computers to that one connection at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internetworking technologies, like BitTorrent, are built on the notion of smaller pieces, each of them individually-addressable segments, that can be composed together to create a larger whole. Neither the Internet nor BitTorrent file transfers are actually monoliths. That means we do not need any person’s or any company’s permission, license key, or commercial product to create our own, to interconnect them to our peers, and to run and maintain useful services on them. It’s long past time for us to stop asking or paying for permission to build the world we want to live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you live far away from the rad infoshop in our example, above? It turns out that creating new internets is not an either-or proposition, nor a zero-sum game. Internets that are physically distant from one another can still securely piggy-back on an existing capital-I Internet connection to knit themselves together by using Virtual Private Network (VPN) and/or Tor (Onion service) networking technologies. Again, this is exactly how physically disjointed pieces of community-owned and cooperatively-run networks like those we’ve mentioned earlier are re-connected. Join enough individually operated internets together—that is, run another Ethernet cable to the next building, and the next, and the next—and we’ll have a newly minted “Internet” to rival the current one. Except, this time, we’ll own it outright instead of renting access to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flow of data over telecom links is much like the flow of electricity over a wire or water through a pipe, not just in its technical mechanics, but in its human dependencies, too. The electric grid could not exist without electricians. Running water in your apartment would not be possible without competent plumbers. System administrators and network engineers, not programmers, code bootcamps, or Big Tech diversity initiatives, are needed to create and then to maintain independent internets like we’ve described here. Moreover, it is these more infrastructural components of telecom autonomy that are the first prerequisite steps we must take to win back the Internet from its corporate and governmental masters. Put another way, there are too many programmers and not enough system administrators precisely because &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/07/22/want-to-get-good-with-computers-dont-start-with-code.html&quot;&gt;more programmers are what corporations need in capitalism&lt;/a&gt;, but more system administrators are what revolutionary communities need for a just and equitable future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why radical tech education efforts such as those by &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective&lt;/a&gt; focus on infrastructure over code, where students are taught fundamental internetworking skills overlooked by the rush-to-employment programs of various school-to-corporation pipelines. It’s why projects like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/shiftctrlspace/library&quot;&gt;Shift-CTRL Space Library&lt;/a&gt;, which offers a pre-packaged collection of software to more easily share collections of e-books (PDFs, zines, and more), are built using widely available Free Software and without consideration for available capital-I Internet access as it’s traditionally envisioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already have the power, the materials, and the motive to &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/10/08/the-internet-was-always-anarchist-so-anarchists-must-learn-to-become-responsible-for-operating-it.html&quot;&gt;fight and win back the Internet&lt;/a&gt;. But we can’t start at the last step of building (even more) “new” apps. We have to start with the first step first: owning our own infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/k0Ru47BXrtY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;encrypted-media; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k0Ru47BXrtY&quot;&gt;Listen to this post in Portuguese&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">In April 2001, five months before 9/11, Bram Cohen began designing a new file sharing protocol that would almost single-handedly change the face of the music, TV, and movie industries for the next two decades. The technology was not in itself a completely new idea. After all, similar technologies like the well-known File Transfer Protocol (FTP) had been designed and deployed for copying files between computers before. What made this one so potent was the way it reflected the fractured, organic structure of its underlying medium, the Internet itself.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.how-we-can-win-back-the-internet-by-creating-lowercase-internets.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.how-we-can-win-back-the-internet-by-creating-lowercase-internets.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Internet was always anarchist, so Anarchists must learn to become responsible for operating it</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/10/08/the-internet-was-always-anarchist-so-anarchists-must-learn-to-become-responsible-for-operating-it.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Internet was always anarchist, so Anarchists must learn to become responsible for operating it" /><published>2020-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/10/08/the-internet-was-always-anarchist-so-anarchists-must-learn-to-become-responsible-for-operating-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/10/08/the-internet-was-always-anarchist-so-anarchists-must-learn-to-become-responsible-for-operating-it.html">&lt;p&gt;The fundamental tenet of Anarchism is the resistance to an Archos, Greek for “master.” To advocate for anarchism is to position oneself in opposition to a master, i.e., to claim the fundamental right of self-determination, autonomy, and freedom from a centralized system of (especially coercive) control. To act anarchically simply means to act independently of a master. It does not mean acting in an uncoordinated or unorganized fashion, nor does it always mean a total absence of layered responsibilities, more commonly known as “hierarchy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is anarchist because the above describes not only the actual operation of basic Internet network protocols such as Ethernet and TCP/IP, but also its designers’ original intentions. When Bob Metcalfe invented Ethernet in the 1970’s, he intentionally designed his system in a way that would function anarchically. Unlike competing technologies of the day such as Token Ring, in which individual participants deferred to one another based on which one held all the power to speak at that time (the network’s “token” holder), Metcalfe’s Ethernet instead purposefully permitted any participating device to say anything on the network at any time it wanted. Collisions and conflicts were handled independently, by the individual devices creating the conflict through a simple set of rules (carrier sense multiple access with collision detection, or CSMA/CD), a process unmediated by external controllers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many engineers believed this approach was too chaotic to succeed. How could a system of coordination function with no command center? It would be pure anarchy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, every Internet connection, local network, telephone uplink, datacenter backhaul, and Wi-Fi signal to your computer uses Ethernet. The anarchist approach proved simpler, more efficient, and ultimately more successful. This is no surprise to any practicing anarchist, although many practicing anarchists still won’t recognize the anarchism in action when they post their next Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people, including and arguably especially most digital technologists, can intuitively understand the principles of anarchic coordination. There are myriad examples of modern technologies with names such as consensus algorithms, cluster orchestration, and distributed ledgers (like “blockchains”) that are, when you actually stop to examine them, fundamentally anarchic approaches to solving complex problems in environments with various degrees of trust between participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large-scale cluster orchestration tools like Kubernetes, a Google invention, function primarily thanks to a coordinating set of components each with very specific horizontally organized responsibilities that act autonomously of one another, merely responding to changes in their environment as they occur. The Internet’s own Certificate Transparency Log (CTL), which audits the issuance of website security certificates such as those offered for free to website owners by Let’s Encrypt, is a massively distributed consensus database run by many independent organizations that uses the same underlying technology as Bitcoin. The backbones of the Internet itself, like the Domain Name System (DNS) and the Border Gateway Protocol (BGP), are each delegatable systems in which anyone, at any time, can participate simply by connecting a computer with free and open source software to the Internet and claiming responsibility over a new autonomous region, called a “domain” in DNS’s lingo or an “autonomous system number” (ASN) in the language of BGP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the newly initiated, this all seems remarkably fragile. And yet, somehow, the Internet has proven surprisingly resilient. But most technologists aren’t able to see the parallels between their beloved technology and the anarchist viewpoint largely because they simply do not spend much of their time thinking about social organization or politics. At least, not beyond the next four-year election cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This must change. And we’re going to change it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How? Such a change will not happen through the proliferation of code bootcamps or “learn to code” initiatives. It will not happen through diversity campaigns sponsored by and centered within the tech industry. Technologists, like most people in a comfortable and financially privileged societal position and class stratification, are not generally willing to examine their biases or change their worldview. It is both unreasonable of us and strategically foolhardy of us to ask them to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, the cost of radicalizing technologists is enormous. Changing an individual’s worldview is a very heavy lift. As a strategy writ large, it is a failing one. The “battle over hearts and minds” is not a battle worth fighting, at least not directly, because what changes hearts and minds is not reason, but experience. Not reciting facts about the present, but taking actions that inspire imagination about the future. Not engaging in debates, but actually making concrete changes in someone’s material circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the cost of training radicals in modern information technology, on the other hand, is negligible. It is of course also difficult, but it is nowhere near as difficult to learn a new set of skills as it is to learn an entirely new and paradigmatically different worldview. As a strategy writ large, “technicalizing radicals” is one with boundless potential, while “radicalizing techies” has proven to be a disastrous waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s activist landscape looks very different from the days of Civil Rights marches, the Anti-War Movement, or even the Anti-Globalization Movement prior to 9/11. If we are to traverse this different terrain, we require a different kind of vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a particularly new idea. Some will remember the Crypto Wars in the 1980’s and 1990’s, in which governments reserved encryption technology solely for military use. Cypherpunk and early “Hacker” culture sprang from this era. But neither cypherpunk nor “Hacker” communities were particularly anarchist, in either ideology nor practice. Instead, they largely imported and mirrored mainstream ideas such as gender, economic, and racial stereotypes, spending most of their time naively imagining themselves in a far-flung utopia in which the mere existence of technologies relying on anarchic methods would inevitably lead to a reformation of society with equality and justice for all even as reality turned increasingly towards nightmarish dystopias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By and large, technically skilled hackers wrapped themselves in the glow of their terminals the way politicians wrap themselves up in their country’s flags. They mostly ignored the forces of industrialization re-centralizing the Internet and turning it into massive digital strip malls like Facebook. By the time they awoke from their Matte-fueled reveries several decades later, their world had been colonized and their comrades would be targeted as criminals under laws like the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act enacted a decade or more earlier. Famous exceptions such as Pirate Bay founder Peter Sunde notwithstanding, the earlier generation of hackers fumbled because they failed to recognize and center the importance of the anarchist principles underlying the very technologies they wrongly treated as inherently liberating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they had brought a more explicitly anarchist lens with them, they would have recognized that neither anarchy nor liberation are states that can be described by their state machines, but rather they are constant processes in which individuals must repeatedly take action to reaffirm their resistance against the formation of an Archos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today that means politically conscious Anarchists must take responsibility for the operation and administration of interconnected networks of communication, if not also the capital-I Internet itself, in order to ensure that fascism is constantly beaten back. This goes beyond merely “no-platforming” fascists and coding the next much-hyped Web app, social network platform, or encrypted messenger. That’s not enough. Not by a long shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, anarchists must make ourselves capable of physically running networking cable from one neighborhood into another. We must learn to administer critical internet functions like the Domain Name System ourselves, independently from commercial providers. We must work to scale out, rather than scale up, massive datacenter operations and place them physically in the communities that rely on them instead of halfway around the globe, for exactly the same reason we must abolish police departments whose patrols are often conducted by personnel who don’t live in the neighborhood they are responsible for policing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a lot of work, but not as much as one may at first think. Best of all, the resources it actually requires in terms of money and equipment are minimal and becoming ever more ubiquitous. There is also no need to write new code or build new apps to make this happen. We already have all the raw materials we need to get the job done. The only thing we lack is broader commitment from anarchists, themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In New York City, several Anarchist and anarcho-autonomist collectives have been slowly converging to provide technological and digital infrastructure support services to anti-fascist, anti-racist, and anti-capitalist organizations in a repeatable, reproducible way. These services range from computer training for activists and advocacy groups to direct assistance with digital components of advocacy efforts, and even private audits of an ally’s security posture when requested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some groups, like Anarcho-Tech NYC, are entirely volunteer-run organizations operating without any licensing or legal recognition and a financial budget intentionally as close to zero as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others, like Tech Learning Collective, provide frequent free, by-donation, and low-cost technical training to otherwise underserved communities and organizations advancing social justice causes in an effort to help fund projects for radical social good while simultaneously “upskilling” politically motivated and technologically-curious students. An apprenticeship-based and security-first technology school founded and operated exclusively by radical queer and femme technologists, Tech Learning Collective hosts virtual (remote/online) computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together with technology-centered community groups like Shift-CTRL Space who connect local, grassroots organizers with free resources on technology, this growing “digital rainbow coalition” focusing on a range of IT and telecoms infrastructure and education initiatives is demonstrating how to have an outsized impact on anti-fascist organizing in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As anarchists, we like to say that another world is possible. The truth is, another world has been here all along. It’s in the palm of our hand every time we read a text from our friends. All we have to do is learn how it actually works.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">When Bob Metcalfe invented Ethernet in the 1970's, he intentionally designed his system in a way that would function anarchically. Many engineers believed this approach was too chaotic to succeed. How could a system of coordination function with no command center? It would be pure anarchy! Today, every Internet connection, local network, telephone uplink, datacenter backhaul, and Wi-Fi signal to your computer uses Ethernet. The anarchist approach proved simpler, more efficient, and ultimately more successful. This is no surprise to any practicing anarchist, although many practicing anarchists still won’t recognize the anarchism in action when they post their next Tweet. Meanwhile, most Big Tech insiders aren't able to see the parallels between their beloved technology and the anarchist viewpoint. This must change, and we're going to change it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.circle-a-ascii-art.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.circle-a-ascii-art.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective interview at An Artist’s Guide to Computation</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/09/25/tech-learning-collective-interview-at-an-artists-guide-to-computation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tech Learning Collective interview at An Artist’s Guide to Computation" /><published>2020-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/09/25/tech-learning-collective-interview-at-an-artists-guide-to-computation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/09/25/tech-learning-collective-interview-at-an-artists-guide-to-computation.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s note: This post was &lt;a href=&quot;https://artistsguidetocomputation.substack.com/p/community-featurette-tech-learning&quot;&gt;originally published&lt;/a&gt; at Martha Hipley’s “&lt;a href=&quot;https://artistsguidetocomputation.substack.com/&quot;&gt;An Artist’s Guide to Computation&lt;/a&gt;,” which is a posi vibes mailing list for artists and creative coders. If you choose to subscribe, you’ll receive inspiring projects and tutorials from diverse creators, upcoming events from around the world, and information about open calls and other opportunities for beginners through experts. We’re grateful to Martha for continuing to support Tech Learning Collective by sharing our events and, this time, for featuring our work in this new feature issue.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first met some of the Tech Learning Collective team what now feels like a million years ago, in my former life in the, um, murky world of startups. I was immediately impressed by what felt like a strong and specific agenda to their work, a pleasant and welcome surprise during a time when I was mostly feeling sad and overwhelmed by the culture and cults of Silicon Valley. Amidst weeks of vapid conversations about “disruption” and “agility,” I had an immediate sense of, oh, &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; team is really committed and doing something pointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve since been able to check out some TLC workshops in person and online, as well as some other events they’ve hosted. They tap into a particularly urgent niche: accessible, affordable, welcoming instruction around critical topics of cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks, TLC is offering some workshops particularly centered around Tor and the Dark Web, and I had the opportunity to reach out to the team with some questions about their curriculum. Check out some of their &lt;a href=&quot;/events/upcoming/&quot;&gt;upcoming sessions&lt;/a&gt;, and stick around for some exclusive content re: their mission and objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a meaty interview, but it’s worth the read! I was gonna condense it initially but, in the spirit of my personal fav rant of late in favor of longer, more thoughtful reading, I’m including all of TLC’s extremely thorough and thoughtful answers to my questions. Block a lil time to read and digest this one! If you care about technology education, it’s important to interrogate our educators, and understand their goals. Chopping up their answers into soundbites wouldn’t feel in service to that spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What makes Tech Learning Collective different from bootcamps and other organizations that teach subjects like computer literacy or digital security?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks so much for asking this question, because it’s both the most important and most difficult for a lot of people to internalize. There are a lot of differences across many metrics ranging from pedagogy and curriculum to personnel and outcomes but, in a word, the core difference is our mission. To really understand what we mean by this, you have to understand that, by and large, there are two categories of “tech education” organizations out there each with their own mission that we’d like to distinguish ourselves from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first group are the ones you’ve identified: bootcamps, which are basically just Internet-era versions of for-profit trade schools, and more traditional schooling institutions (colleges, night schools, freelance trainers on YouTube, and so on). Put bluntly, the goal for these institutions is to help you get a job. They are trying to help you “use technology” in order to “get ahead in life.” There’s nothing inherently wrong with this, but &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/08/03/return-the-magic-to-computers-radio-statler-hope-2020-interview-with-tech-learning-collective.html&quot;&gt;we think that’s a rather unambitious goal and a massively missed opportunity&lt;/a&gt;. They’re also trying to shoehorn a traditional educational approach—teaching to a test, getting certifications, reading books—to a topic that really requires a far more interactive and immersive experience to gain any meaningful skill in. &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/07/22/want-to-get-good-with-computers-dont-start-with-code.html&quot;&gt;Learning how to get good with computers is more like learning a language than memorizing a bunch of facts about binary arithmetic&lt;/a&gt;. We think the approach most schools take doesn’t sufficiently acknowledge this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second group we’d like to distinguish ourselves from are the more policy-focused “community” or “advocacy” groups that have sprung up around the world in the wake of political revelations such as the Snowden documents. The goal for these communities is primarily awareness-raising. They tend to be good at introducing people to the political relevance of the topic, but routinely fall short of providing education in a way that is all of accessible, actionable, and thorough. Most of these groups have their heart in the right place, but don’t have the expertise or the structure necessary to do a sufficient job training students who want to see more than the tip of the iceberg because they are organized in an extremely ad-hoc way that responds to the news cycle and focuses on non-technical things such as legal petitions, fundraising campaigns, or social initiatives. While certainly helpful, we don’t think any of those actions can be performed sufficiently well to make a meaningful difference without first truly understanding the fundamentals of the problem domain, which these groups often lack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s mission is neither job acquisition nor awareness-raising. Rather, our mission is revolutionary, even insurrectionary political change. Practically, this means we teach things that other schools don’t, and you can see this reflected in our curriculum, in which even the “beginner” courses cover topics with a heavy focus on system reliability engineering (IT infrastructure) and cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, most schools will teach you how to build a Web app but don’t teach you much about the environment in which Web apps operate, because they just assume you’re going to rent some space on a Web hosting provider or purchase a compute cluster from Amazon AWS. At Tech Learning Collective, you’ll learn how to make your own Amazon AWS-equivalent infrastructure and run a world-class, multi-node, highly-available datacenter infrastructure yourself, but we won’t show you how to build a custom Web application. This is because the world doesn’t need yet another Web application, to say nothing of how superfluous such a thing is for the global movement for justice. What it needs is more system administrators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By eschewing employment, our students are also free to focus on the technical underpinnings of communication technologies in ways that will help them understand the modern world at a much deeper level than other educational curriculums. When you are focused on practicing how to pass a test, so that you can get a certification, so that you can get an interview, so that you can get a foot in the door at a company, so that you can make a living wage, you are many miles away from community building, &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/08/29/democracy-is-bankrupt-id-like-an-extra-large-i-voted-sticker-with-a-side-of-political-sedative-please.html&quot;&gt;prefigurative political change&lt;/a&gt;, or even personal fulfillment in many cases. Besides, numerous Tech Learning Collective students have in fact had more success in getting jobs in the tech industry thanks to this more foundational approach than they had at prior bootcamp-style institutions precisely because of the deeper understanding they gained with us; many &lt;a href=&quot;/testimonials/&quot;&gt;students routinely tell us&lt;/a&gt; they learned more in one of our two-hour workshops than in full semesters at college on the same topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We understand that jobs are important for survival in the current society, but the fact of the matter is that many companies now automatically disqualify most bootcamp graduates out of the hiring process because of how technical training schools—including the expensive, name-brand ones—routinely fail to prepare students for a real-life work environment. (See, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2016-12-06/want-a-job-in-silicon-valley-keep-away-from-coding-schools&quot;&gt;Sarah McBride’s feature article on the topic in Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;.) In contrast, at Tech Learning Collective, students gain experience exclusively with Free and Open Source software in ways that are immediately valuable to them regardless of whether they end up using that skill in their personal life, at a future office job, or as part of an advocacy project outside the realm of techno-capitalism. This versatility, coupled with the fact that Tech Learning Collective courses and workshops are, on average, approximately ten thousand dollars less expensive than most technical trade schools, makes Tech Learning Collective a dramatically different experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other distinction to draw is that because we are not trying to convince students of the importance of certain political issues the way many community education projects are, we can spend more time focusing on how the technology actually works. To be blunt, this means students actually get a meaningful technical education in addition to the ambient political education they would get at a one-off community event, for example. Most of our students who return to take multiple workshops are actually people who have been to one or more community advocacy groups, but quickly found those groups unable to provide deeper technical instruction when they began asking questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, not everyone wants to take that next step beyond simply being aware of an issue, and that’s okay, too. But Tech Learning Collective was designed from the ground-up to be a place where people with political motivations can learn the kinds of skills they’ll need to confront adversaries to their political dreams, whether those adversaries are government agencies like the NSA, CIA, FBI, or corporate security teams, professional hackers (penetration testers), political opposition groups, or simply cybercriminals looking to do harm to their organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you build a school with that goal in mind, what you end up with is an extremely serious divergence from the kinds of places that cooperate with the existing paradigm, either by encouraging employment, or by re-enacting the same awareness-raising campaigns that have more or less failed to make meaningful policy changes for far too long. Once you understand that our goals are not the same as many of these other groups, our other differences, such as our 100% Socratic pedagogy (e.g., there are no slideshows or PowerPoints in any of our workshops, ever) or choice of software platforms (we never use closed-source or proprietary commercial products, including in our “cloud” workshops) start to make a lot more sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other differences, of course: &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/05/09/queer-all-the-electronic-things-our-love-for-the-command-line.html&quot;&gt;we take great care to make our workshops welcoming to political radicals, trans people, femmes, and BIPOC folk&lt;/a&gt;. At the same time, we work to be actively hostile to Trump supporters and white supremacists, for example. (Many of our in-class exercises feature political messaging as a kind of background music.) But these choices all stem from our core mission, which is to empower you and your political affinity groups with the kind of powerful capabilities that go far beyond mere electoral representation. We want you to have the kind of power usually reserved for multi-national corporations, and never before has such asymmetrical power been within reach for small groups of competent, well-trained, committed, politically motivated people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s not squander the opportunity to do something grand with that possibility. You can read more about what makes Tech Learning Collective so different on &lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot;&gt;our Web site’s About page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Privacy and digital security seem like such critical topics right now, given the political climate, but also seem to be pretty misunderstood. Why is it important to TLC to be sharing these particular skills right now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Safe and secure communication is a prerequisite to political change. If you can’t coordinate actions, brainstorm strategies, or receive feedback without those who would oppose you listening in, then you can’t realize your goals. Without the ability to communicate securely, you can’t make use of any power you might otherwise have. It’s that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s probably helpful to know that Tech Learning Collective instructors have been practicing digital security for literally decades. A lot of people first heard about the kinds of mass surveillance and other illegal behavior on the part of law enforcement like parallel construction when the Snowden leaks made the news in 2013. However, it’s important to remember that there was a verifiable parade of whistleblowers who sounded the alarm about the same things Snowden did well before Snowden was even out of High School.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whistleblowers like Thomas Drake, William Binney, John Kiriakou, and many more came many years before Snowden. A lot of what Snowden had to say simply added detail to information that those of us who have been in these trenches already had even before 9/11. Unfortunately, the public didn’t really understand the importance of what these early whistleblowers were saying. Large swaths of the public probably still don’t really get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, sure, for a lot of people, these are critical topics “right now,” but for those of us involved in Tech Learning Collective, these have been critical topics for well over twenty years. The core members of Tech Learning Collective have also been involved in anti-surveillance organizing and cybersecurity education for decades. From our perspective, these topics are more well-understood than they ever have been before. It’s equally important to be sharing these particular skills now as it was back in 1993, when the same basic technology to, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Securing-Email-Protecting-Everyday-Communications-from-GMail-to-ProtonMail&quot;&gt;encrypt emails&lt;/a&gt; that we use today (modestly called “&lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/OpenPGP-How-to-Protect-Everything-with-Pretty-Good-Privacy&quot;&gt;Pretty Good Privacy&lt;/a&gt;”) was first made available to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t feel disheartened if you’re just coming around to this now, though. Better late than never!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Something I’ve been experiencing is that I have been having more and more conversations with friends and peers who feel frustrated with or concerned by big tech companies like Google or Facebook, or with government use of technology, but don’t seem ready to take the leap into using tools like Tor. What would you say to someone who thinks that Tor isn’t for them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we’d rather spend our time talking to folks who are willing to learn something new than those who are unwilling or unable to consider doing that. So, if you’re asking for our advice, we would tell you simply to let your friends be. We suspect you are more likely to change their behavior by changing your own than by debating the merits of your choices with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, when someone tells us they don’t understand why we use privacy-enhancing technologies like Tor, we tell them we do so for the same reason we won’t give them all our passwords. The disconnect for them usually stems from an under-appreciation of how impactful a privacy violation really is. This is why, in our cybersecurity workshops, we focus on teaching offensive (“hacking”) techniques just as often, if not more often, than we focus on defensive techniques. It’s one thing to have a conversation with someone else in the abstract about “not letting anyone see your browsing history.” It’s quite another to show them how a hacker or a government agency can view their personal browsing habits simply by &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Gone-Phishing-How-to-Recognize-Fake-Websites-and-Other-Online-Scams&quot;&gt;performing a Machine-in-the-Middle or browser hooking attack&lt;/a&gt; against them, personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had a lot more luck showing people why they might want to use Tor after we show them how we can snoop on Internet traffic. For that reason alone, we think it’s useful to learn about network packet sniffing, for example. We have &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Exploring-Cyberspace-Network-Sniffing-and-Scanning&quot;&gt;a whole workshop dedicated to these topics&lt;/a&gt; for exactly this reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One silver lining of the pandemic I’ve experienced is that I’ve been able to take online classes with organizations who previously primarily offered in-person workshops. Has the shift to online offerings impacted your curriculum or mission?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shift to online offerings hasn’t changed our mission or our curriculum a lot, but it has absolutely changed our own infrastructure. We used to focus on in-person classes, but &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/15/one-way-we-re-doing-what-we-can-to-support-our-community-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic.html&quot;&gt;between February and April 2020 we transformed ourselves into an entirely virtual (online) school&lt;/a&gt;. Every workshop now happens online in one of a variety of video conferencing platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has also prompted us to create some new workshops. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/File-Sharing-for-Fun-and-Profit-How-BitTorrent-Works-and-What-You-Can-Do-With-It&quot;&gt;our workshop about how BitTorrent works (and how to share files with it)&lt;/a&gt; was spurred by the introduction of lockdown and the observation that many people were watching a lot more streaming media. Similarly, the recent absurdity over the potential ban against TikTok has spurred &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Two-Places-at-Once-Understanding-Virtual-Private-Networks&quot;&gt;our workshop on VPNs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, for us, the shift to “online-everything” has been a huge boon, because the logistics of organizing a digital classroom instead of a physical one is far easier to automate. Last year, we hosted on average three or four workshops a month. This year, we routinely host upwards of fifteen workshops each month because what once took hours of preparation and lots of emails to coordinate with classroom venues now takes literally seconds and we can do it entirely on our own. So in that sense, we were actually happy that people became more willing to give online classes a shot. We just wish the circumstances had not been so painful and tragic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we want to point out that this dramatic increase in our capacity and its simultaneous reduction in menial labor (going from three to fifteen workshops a month is, like, a &lt;em&gt;massive&lt;/em&gt; difference!) is the kind of thing that computers are supposed to do for all of us. It’s almost criminal that most people experience the expansion of digital technology into their lives as a stressor rather than a blessing. We were able to take advantage of the move to online learning because we are already automation experts familiar with the digital systems mediating the majority of everything from financial to social interaction in society writ large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal at Tech Learning Collective workshops and classes is to make that possible for you, too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">This week's issue of Martha Hipley's &quot;An Artist's Guide to Computation&quot; features an interview with Tech Learning Collective. We answer questions about what makes us different from code bootcamps and even other advocacy/community groups (short answer: we're not doing what they're doing), why we focus on communications security at every step of our curriculum (safe and secure communication is a prerequisite to political change), what to do if your friends say they hate Facebook but still aren't ready to take action to protect their privacy online (change more of your own behavior first rather than debating the merits of your choices with them), how the year 2020 has radically transformed Tech Learning Collective's own infrastructure (we're 100% online now), and more.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.an-artists-guide-to-computation-community-featurette-2020-09.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.an-artists-guide-to-computation-community-featurette-2020-09.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Democracy is Bankrupt: I’d like an extra-large ‘I Voted!’ sticker with a side of political sedative, please</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/08/29/democracy-is-bankrupt-id-like-an-extra-large-i-voted-sticker-with-a-side-of-political-sedative-please.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Democracy is Bankrupt: I’d like an extra-large ‘I Voted!’ sticker with a side of political sedative, please" /><published>2020-08-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/08/29/democracy-is-bankrupt-id-like-an-extra-large-i-voted-sticker-with-a-side-of-political-sedative-please</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/08/29/democracy-is-bankrupt-id-like-an-extra-large-i-voted-sticker-with-a-side-of-political-sedative-please.html">&lt;p&gt;As the United States &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2019/01/presidential-emergency-powers/576418/&quot;&gt;continues its decent toward an overt autocracy that it began many decades ago&lt;/a&gt;, there’s no mistaking the fact that electoral representation is not a substitute for material power. As the nation gears up for what is arguably one of the most highly contentious General Election seasons in a long time, permit us a few moments to share some timely thoughts with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want you to vote (to help soundly oust Trump from the Presidency), but we want you to do it while recognizing the reality that voting is &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; the least you can do in pursuit of that goal. To vote while incorrectly believing that your vote is more meaningful than basically anything else you can do to establish material power in your life and community is to mentally ingest a toxic political sedative that poisons your participation in society and degrades your material power. Recognize that the “I Voted!” sticker you’re bound to see on people’s backpacks and phones this November is usually not a badge of genuine political engagement, but rather a tranquilizer patch doling out time-release political anesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look, vote all you want. (Really!) But don’t naively assume your vote will meaningfully change how, why, or when the Amerikkkan government will still spy on us, its jar-headed, jack-booted government-funded white supremacists who traded their white cloaks for their camo fatigues or their badges will still terrorize us, and its social services will still turn us away due to lack of funding, lack of competency, lack of empathy, or all three. Red or Blue might as well be Coke or Pepsi, with maybe a touch of cyanide in one or the other depending on which Facebook filter bubble the Zuck has decided your timeline should show you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the facts: you have one chance to vote for your representative as President every four years, but you have at least 365 chances to increase your material power in this world each and every year. Seen in that light, elections matter a lot less than they’re made out to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people wrongly think voting is the most profound political act they can take because it somehow directly determines their future, when in reality all it amounts to is at best a false choice between one poison pill or another. Freedom doesn’t come from a ballot box. On the ballots most people talk about, no candidate gives a shit about you. Why should they? The entire apparatus of Nation State government is designed to reward people who don’t give a flying fuck whether what they do with the power of their office is legal, ethical, or even sensible. Importantly, that fact isn’t a Trump phenomenon, either. Powerful people in government have been brazenly boasting about this since at least 1975, when contemporary Mr. Realpolitik himself, Henry Kissinger, is quoted in one conversation saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I used to say at meetings, ‘The illegal we do immediately; the unconstitutional takes a little longer.’ [laughter]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2013/apr/11/wikileaks-kissinger-cables-bradley-manning&quot;&gt;The US diplomatic cables provided to the world by Chelsea Manning&lt;/a&gt;. Look it up.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So people vote, but little if anything improves in their lives as a result. Then, by the millions, frustratingly, they just wait. For &lt;em&gt;four years&lt;/em&gt;. Even most of the “activists” who aren’t just sitting around twiddling their thumbs start doing…what, exactly? Oh yeah, their much-lauded, highly publicized, celebrity-backed Get Out The Vote campaigns. This is not the behavior of a body politic actively engaged in their own governance. This is a body politic addicted to societal-scale political sedatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to change your political reality, you need to start by becoming more powerful than you currently are. What do you have that is actually real, meaningful, political power? Do you have money? Do you have connections to or influence over a lot of other people? Do you have remarkable individual skill that you actually use in your personal or communal spheres to improve your life and the lives of the people you care about? If you don’t have those things and, let’s face it, most voters don’t, then you don’t have any actual power. And without any power, hard as it is to hear, everything you do—even and arguably especially your vote—doesn’t make a dent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, with all that said, we still think it’s important to remind you to vote early and by mail this year if you can. Why? Because voting is &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; the least you can do. We want you to vote, but we want you to recognize that voting matters &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt;, not more, than literally &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; other act you take every day of your life. Voting matters less, not more, than whether you’re chatting with your friends on Facebook Messenger or &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Signal-and-Surveillance-How-to-Exercise-Digital-Civil-Liberties-in-a-Surveillance-State&quot;&gt;Signal Messenger&lt;/a&gt;. Voting matters less, not more, than whether you spend your $5 at Starbuck’s or at the BIPOC-owned local coffeehouse two blocks further away from the bus station. Voting matters less, not more, than whether you read your Twitter feed or a book from the library when you get home tonight. Voting matters less, not more, than who you choose to smile at on the street, to talk with, to get to know, to spend your time around. Voting matters less, not more, than spending a moment alone, eyes closed, phone switched off, listening to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voting is not how you express your politics. Voting is, at most, one tiny and relatively insignificant artifact that &lt;em&gt;results&lt;/em&gt; from your true political expressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Tech Learning Collective, our goal is to make it easier for you to do the far more meaningful political work of building real, material, concrete power in your own life through mastery over digital tools and information systems. Creating an autonomous infrastructure that can obsolete this whole rotten system from its root is obviously more impactful, and thus arguably more important, than voting. But so is just asking the question, “Wait, how does this &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; work?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put another way: Fuck Trump? Well, duh. But fuck having Presidents? Now you’re speaking our language. Your vote can be—and &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be—ignored. Your resistance can’t be.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">As the United States gears up for what is arguably one of the most highly contentious General Election seasons in a long time, we wanted to share our thoughts about the importance&amp;mdash;and limitations&amp;mdash;of voting, and how our political credo in this arena shapes our curriculum and our priorities. Our goal, as always, is to make it easier for you to succeed at truly impactful political work through mastery of digital and information systems. But before we have a chance in Hell of making a dent there, it's important to have an accurate understanding of how things actually work in the world, so we understand where to focus our limited resources.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.democracy-is-bankrupt.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.democracy-is-bankrupt.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Return the Magic to Computers: Radio Statler/HOPE 2020 interview with Tech Learning Collective</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/08/03/return-the-magic-to-computers-radio-statler-hope-2020-interview-with-tech-learning-collective.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Return the Magic to Computers: Radio Statler/HOPE 2020 interview with Tech Learning Collective" /><published>2020-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/08/03/return-the-magic-to-computers-radio-statler-hope-2020-interview-with-tech-learning-collective</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/2020/08/03/return-the-magic-to-computers-radio-statler-hope-2020-interview-with-tech-learning-collective.html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://hope.net/&quot;&gt;Hackers On Planet Earth (HOPE) conference&lt;/a&gt; is a staple of The Hacker Community™ that has been happening bi-annually since 1994. It’s a huge, well-renowned event that regularly brings international superstars like Edward Snowden to their stage. This year, due to the Covid-19 pandemic, the conference was moved entirely online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the wholly-virtual conference format was a disappointment for many regulars, it was a very welcome change for us at Tech Learning Collective. It was specifically because of the decision to move the conference online that Tech Learning Collective members felt comfortable enough to submit workshop proposals for consideration. Had the conference been held in person, we would have chosen not to participate because of the fact that mainstream “hacker community” spaces are not spaces where we feel particularly comfortable or safe. Offering an alternative to those more mainstream spaces is, after all, one of the main reasons Tech Learning Collective exists!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were happy to have all of our proposals accepted by the HOPE 2020 workshops selection committee and are grateful for the opportunity they gave us to showcase our different cultural, pedagogical, and philosophical approaches to classic hacking topics such as &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Gone-Phishing-How-to-Recognize-Fake-Websites-and-Other-Online-Scams&quot;&gt;phishing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Password-Superpowers-How-to-Crack-Hashes-and-Stump-Hackers&quot;&gt;hash cracking&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/World-Wide-Wars-Introduction-to-Exploiting-Web-Applications&quot;&gt;Web exploitation&lt;/a&gt;. And while we hope the three two-hour workshops we facilitated for HOPE 2020 ticketholders were educational or at least fun for everyone who showed up, our own deeper hope is that people who are looking for something liberatory and ambitious, beyond but overlapping with the famous hacker ethos exemplified by the HOPE 2020 conference and community, found us through our workshops at the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why, when we were further invited to be interviewed by Erin and Mel of the Nerdy Duo for HOPE 2020’s Internet radio broadcast, &lt;a href=&quot;https://radio.hope.net/&quot;&gt;Radio Statler&lt;/a&gt;, we accepted quickly. What follows is our (somewhat rushed) transcript of the far-reaching interview, along with an audio recording, of our hour-plus segment on Radio Statler during HOPE 2020 in which we discuss the mission and vision of Tech Learning Collective, our philosophical approach to computer technology, hacking, anarcho-autonomism, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;controls&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/tech-learning-collective.radio-statler-hope2020.mp3&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0 auto; width: 100%;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/tech-learning-collective.radio-statler-hope2020.mp3&quot;&gt;Download the audio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;TLC interviewee: Thanks so much for having us on. Which one of you is Beaches? Do you mind my asking that?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel (interviewer 1): Beaches isn’t here right now. Beaches has to work.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Oh, well, Beaches has been very helpful in helping us organize logistics for this. So just shout-out to whoever that is.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin (interviewer 2): Oh, he’s the greatest.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Beaches is the greatest. I’m very fond of Beaches. So I think my first question for you guys is, Oh, my gosh, how have I not spent a million hours with you?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC Interviewee: Um, that’s, uh, probably because for a long time, we were only doing in person things in New York City. So if you were not in New York City, you were probably not as aware of us. We began in, well, a little actually before 2016. But we sort of officially became more open to the public or inviting folks who we didn’t already have some sort of preconceived connection with to workshops and things that we were holding in person classes, at around 2016-ish, just after the Trump election for some obvious reasons. And, so, the result is that for the past, only for the past about eight months or so have we really been sort of pushing a lot of online things. And that of course, is a result of a pandemic. So it’s possible that you didn’t know about it simply because maybe I don’t know if you’re in New York City or not, but if you aren’t, that would be a good reason why not, and also—&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Up the river. We’re up the river, across the river from Sing-Sing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: I see. Yeah, so we never quite ventured that far North personally, obviously, New York City is a huge, huge town and it has a ton of spaces. And so we’ve basically been very inner city focused for a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Um, I’m so excited to like meet you guys.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: Tell us about you your mission…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: …what you’re up to lately.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Sure. So, um, I mean, the sales pitch, if you will, is simply that we take a security-first approach to all this tech education that we think is vital for, bluntly, any kind of revolutionary or insurrectionary politic. We have a very different approach than a lot of other schools primarily because we don’t focus on things like jobs, we don’t focus on things like interviews or coding skill, particularly. There’s a huge as you know, of course, you know, boot camp style initiative happening ever since, you know, the mid, early, really 2010s. And there’s just been this focus on, like, learning to code.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And that for a while, this is a—I don’t know how much of this history you’re actually interested in, so I’m sort of all over the place. But, this really started from the notion that Tech Learning Collective began as a mutual self education group.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So back in 2015 and early 2016 it wasn’t for the public. It was for us, it was for people who felt alienated from code boot camps, felt alienated from the tech scene, who didn’t really have an interest in technology for the perspective of getting jobs or changing a career or this kind of thing. And so what that meant was that a huge amount of education that was focused around that approach just wasn’t really relevant. Like we didn’t really care about the things that were being taught not because those things aren’t important or useful, or in some way, for example, can be used in in non-job contexts, but because the instruction around it was entirely too narrow-mindedly focused on here’s how you get a job, here’s how we’re going to help you get a job, here’s how you’re going to then make money in this career. Here’s the best way is to, for example, get your certifications and your licenses and all this sort of stuff, right. And so we didn’t we didn’t care about that.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We cared about helping our communities and our friends, put up websites about their activist efforts, we cared about getting food distribution networks set up we cared about helping people like Food Not Bombs or CopWatch and this sort of stuff. And those skills, while overlapping, take a very different approach, or you need a very different approach to sort of take someone who hasn’t had any background in technology, and make it possible for them to do things like those community efforts with technology, than one in which you’re constantly telling them to like work for Amazon, you know, or get a job at Google, or learn how to do, you know, sort of huge global scale infrastructures. Like, that isn’t relevant to a neighborhood of 100,000 people even, right, you don’t need, if you don’t have a million active users, you know, per hour, you don’t need half the things that you’re being taught in these sort of, you know, schools.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The other part is that we don’t have the money! A lot of that software’s proprietary, if you’re going to network engineering, you’re probably going to get a Cisco iOS certification of some form or another right, CCNP, or something like this, and that’s going to cost you some money, you’re going to need to get the software for that, you’re gonna need the licenses for that, you’re going to need the hardware for that. And, but you don’t need for example, a Cisco iOS device if you’re setting up a mesh network amongst a five block radius, right? OSPF and BGP are not licensed software, right? You can use a VyOS router, you can use this open source stuff that exists, you can use a pfSense box for your edge. And all this stuff you don’t need that kind of material for. So the other aspect of it was just financial cost and accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And finally, of course, the other big thing is that there’s a cultural sort of obstacle. And I don’t just mean about the job thing in this sense. I mean, the sorts of people who we are trying to teach don’t tend to get along very well with the sorts of people who are sort of like, you know, engineering managers at big companies. I just mean interpersonally, like we have different philosophies, we have different politics, we have different gender expressions, all sorts of all sorts of issues, race, of course, right. And so there was really a lot of challenges in order to get—like, it’s harder to get—I think this is something that I’ve heard several times in this conference now, some of the speakers have said it’s harder to get technical people without a political awareness to sort of change their political awareness. But it’s relatively easy to train politically aware individuals in technical skill. It’s not easy, but it’s easier, maybe even changing a worldview, right? You don’t have to, for example, change a worldview to understand HTML or to understand JavaScript or to learn to code or to, you know, figure out how to sort of example, do key rotation on SSH servers or set up SSH certificates as opposed to host keys, like none of that, right, that doesn’t require a worldview change. For that you—&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: The tools are kind of agnostic.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Say that again? Sorry.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: The tools are kind of agnostic.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: The tools don’t care what philosophy you have, right? They don’t care what political position you have. And so it’s much easier to sort of technical-ize radicals than it is to radicalize techies, if those two things are considered mutually exclusive groups. And they aren’t, of course, I mean, look at us, but they certainly are approached that way in a lot of other educational or activist efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And the other, the last sort of part of this was that while there were many other groups doing a lot of education around this sort of stuff, digital security, anti-surveillance, this sort of stuff. Um, there’s not really a lot of groups that are explicitly trying to create a, we call it a “train the trainer’s” model, where they are, where people are coming to these groups asking about, you know, how do I keep myself safe at protests? How do I not get picked up by cops in a regime, right, or, like, in Portland today? Or, you know, and there are a lot of good, sort of 101[-level] answers to that. There’s a lot of, well, check your phone settings and make sure that you do a factory reset if you think that your devices been compromised, this sort of stuff, but then there’s not a like, then what, how do I then build from that? What do I do next? Where’s my 201? Where’s my like, like, if I want to build some infrastructure, as opposed to just react to things that are happening to me, where do I learn to do that?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so again, the only answer was, well get a job. And that doesn’t work for the kinds of things that we’re trying to do because often what happens when you get a job is that you now spend—like The Onion article right? You follow your dreams in your 30 minutes for lunch. And 30 minutes on your lunch break doesn’t really have enough resources really, in terms of time and attention to actually build an infrastructure for any sort of meaningful movement. So, so there had to be some place to go after you, you know, found yourself in a, for example, anti-surveillance workshop, and then wanted some more information about how this technology worked. And what you could do with it, how to defend against it, how to build something out of the foundational layers, and that ended up becoming Tech Learning Collective, through sort of a series of unfortunate external events and sort of figuring trying to figure out how a group of anti-capitalist Anarchists could sort of coexist with an educational model that required, for example, resources, like space and time. And, the last four years has been sort of the, the work of making that possible. So that’s, that sort of where we come from. I hope that answered your question, in maybe a little bit of a roundabout way.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: Very thorough.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Very cool. Good.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So, you know, for more information about that, obviously, I should point you at TechLearningCollective.com/about, I’m not going to read the website to you, obviously you can, you know, look at the website and read it yourself but that story is repeated there on our about page. And it has some details about, you know, precisely where in 2016 we started and what groups we started working with and this sort of stuff. So there’s more information about that there.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;As well as workshops and events and classes and our calendar. Now we do almost one workshop every other day.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: Wow.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: I think we have upwards of 15 to 16 workshops a month now that are on a scale of either free, by donation, or low cost. And by low cost I mean, there’s a sliding scale for even paid workshops are for as low as $25 for about two hours.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: That’s amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah, and it’s all, you know, it’s kind of—we’re very proud that we have actually stayed active is one thing, but the other thing is that that we are growing at a rate that we didn’t expect to. So now we have workshops that not only range in sort of a sliding scale costs, but also are on topics based everywhere from like, you know, what is a computer? What is the CPU? What are the resources and admin is working with, right? And we really start at the level of, you’re really working with time and space, right, you’ve got a certain amount of space and a certain amount of time to process some information. And that’s really your constraint. So what are the resources in a computer that allow you to do that, right? You have a speed in your computer, that’s time, you have amount of space that you can store something that’s your hard disk, that’s your RAM, etc, right? The network storage, and so on and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So that’s where we start, and everything from there all the way through to, for example, working with Docker containers and exploiting web applications. Some of the workshops that we’re doing here obviously are very focused on the offensive security side of things is stuff that we cover. So I think we have over like 35 workshops, individual workshops now and four course tracks that we offer. The workshops and the courses are all based on each other. So it was the case that courses actually were sort of like the main focus of we did, like I mentioned in person classes and sort of the cohort that met with each other, you know, week after week. The pandemic has radically changed how we do this. And now, mostly it’s actually workshops that we’re focusing on. But the material in both the workshops and the courses are the same. So if you for example, signed up for a SYS10 course with us, then basically what you’d be getting is a logistically different presentation of the same topics that we teach and for example, our Taming Daemons workshop, which is one of our one on one courses, our Securing our Servers workshop, which is a deep dive into SSH, this sort of stuff so it’s sort of, they’re parallels of each other, they’re just sort of presented differently at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: We totally understand that big shift. We are—well, first of all, I got totally distracted by oh my gosh, no, I’m not Beaches. I have I have no right to call myself that, Beaches is amazing. And, we are we are artists first and art educators second so the switch from classes to like short bite sized workshops is totally the same shift we’ve had to do. Sometimes we teach overlapping stuff like since we do a lot of digital art like and video and post production stuff we’re tend to be the artists in a space who know anything about tech even though like we’re not always the greatest. I have people I can call for that. Thank goodness!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah, you have—it’s important to have people who know how to do a thing if you don’t. This is part of thesocial aspect of learning. It’s part of the infrastructure, right? I mean, other people are an infrastructure as well. And I think part and parcel of what you’re saying is like, there’s you know, there’s, there’s a, it’s when you’re in a classroom, when you’re in a certain kind of educational environment, we think of that educational environment being simply a matter of a collection of materials that you then consume. But that’s not at all how education works, right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: No.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: It’s really about an interaction between who’s there and how they’re approaching the material, and you, and how you can plug into that. And so our workshops are like, we get this question a lot like, what how should I prepare for like my SYS101 course? Or how do I prepare for my like, you know, my first Clearing Away the Clouds workshop, something we’re doing later today, not at this conference, but just is happening later today, which is like a NET101 intro. And we always tell people don’t! The point is not to come prepared. The point is to not know when you arrive, and then leave having a clear idea of what to do next. And when you approach things that way, we can take advantage of the time that we have, as in a synchronous workshop, right? Like why pay for stuff that you can read on Wikipedia? That makes no sense as a school.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so when we look at these other sort of educational pedagogies one of the things that didn’t make sense to us was that we didn’t have A) the money and B) the inclination to just, you know, get this specific school’s book that contain the same information as all these other online guides or all these other. You know, I mean, even the RFCs, right, they’re just kind of repeating information in their way. And that’s not bad, you can argue that that’s a value add for some people. But if you’re then spending, for example, two or three hours in a class with somebody, and they’re just showing you that material, then you’re not taking advantage of the fact that you have a human with their own decision making ability, their own ability to sort of, you know, improvise and respond to your questions in person, or I guess over video chat. However you do it. And that’s really going to be where most of the “Aha!” moments can come from, especially if you’re the kind of person who needs some structure in the first place. Right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So people who are really like, the self taught, “I don’t need to, I don’t need anyone’s help. I want to do this entirely on my own. I don’t want to talk to anyone,” right, those are not our students. And that’s because they don’t need to go to any class to learn this stuff. It might help in terms of a small speed boost to get sort of like a guide, if I’ve never worked with, for example Kubernetes or DevOps material. And I don’t know anything about configuration management, you know, maybe our Faster Than Light workshop, which is all about Ansible, and RBAC using AWX Tower and the Red Hat, sort of open source offerings, is a good thing to go to, because you spend two hours in a class where that’s the topic, instead of spending maybe 18 to 20, reading a book and you get more or less the same material, and you can begin, then, you know, to do things on your own. But the community aspect of the learning is when we see the same students come back in again, and again, and again. These are the ones who tend to want to either learn in a social environment or who want the kind of structure that the black hole of YouTube just doesn’t offer, because the recommendation engine has its own interests and it’s certainly not yours. Right? So, so that that’s a really important part of it. Otherwise, go read a book.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Yeah, that that one-to-one interaction with students is the thing I’ve missed the most all COVID. Yeah, that little lean over the shoulder. And let me just show you this one little trick that’ll speed up what you’re doing. I missed that so much.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: Just swoop your mouse, just hold this key here. There, you got it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Right. Did you know about this command? Let me show you this particular vim shortcut or like, check out, you know, control-a when you’re in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;screen&lt;/code&gt;, right, like this stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Yeah. And that’s sort of the other big difference is that when you give someone for example, a checklist to follow like a lab guide, and that’s sort of all the material that they offer is that sort of interactivity, then you don’t get those opportunities. But if you can create a conversation around the topic that you’re teaching, and so one thing when I teach, for example, is that I tell people, if you’ve never ever done what we’re about to do before, I know there’s going to be a VM that you can follow along with, you know, download and run it and you know, you’ll have the same terminal that I have, but if you’ve never done this before, try to ignore that because you’re going to be seeing the same exact thing that I’m going to be seeing on my screen. So for the time being like for the first time, the first time you’re exposed to this, you’ll probably get more just watching me use the tools in the same way that you could, for example, watch a master craftsman or a craftsperson, right, create a wooden toy, right by watching them work, rather than trying to replicate their movements, sort of by hearing what they tell you to do, and not watching their hands. And so it’s the same exact process. If I, for example, I’m using my terminal in a way that you know, you haven’t seen before. Maybe you never use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tmux&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;screen&lt;/code&gt;, or haven’t seen a multiplexed terminal before, that alone is going to be like, “Whoa, what is this?” And you’re not necessarily going to get that by following a lab’s sort of checklist of hit this goal, then this goal, then this goal.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And this is particularly important for security concepts, because security, more than almost any other, is a field in which you don’t want to restrict someone’s thinking to just the steps that are on paper. Right? The security principle of—there’s, I don’t know if it’s a joke or what, but I’ve heard it over and over and over again, which is you as a pentester, right, the thing you want to do is read the requirements docs. And then every time that they, that the requirements docs say, or the RFCs say that something must be the case, check to make sure it is, cuz it’s probably, it might not be! Every time where it or something says “optional,” check both cases, see if it’s on or not, right? And that’s basically just, like, the RFC is your beginning pentest guide. But if you’re trained in school, to think only, “okay, well, if I do this, then I’m good, then this and I’m good, then this and I’m good,” then what you’re not doing is reading between the lines.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so for that, you really have to have a Socratic discussion, you have to have a sort of more, you have to have the back and forth, right in the OSSTM model of pentesting, we’re talking about induction, right we induce the system to do a certain thing based on input that we send. Right. And so that doesn’t come from the checklist. That’s not on the paper. You have to do that part. So you have to generate it yourself. You have to generate what it is that you want the system to respond to. And you’re not going to get that in, I think, most classes where this is primarily stuff that is being taught to a test so that you can get a certification so that you can get a job and therefore, so that you can have a career switch and change, you know, and again, I’m not going to tell an individual “don’t do that, that’s bad.” But I am saying that that’s not going to lead then to societal change. That’s not—or at least I should say, that is, at best, insufficient for the kind of radical changes that a group like Tech Learning Collective was based to help inspire. So that’s why everything from there has to be a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Teaching people who have been through any portion of the education system to like read between the lines is so critical. Teaching them to like, try stuff, to not doubt themselves, like…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: We teach like little kids and grandmas how to use Photoshop most of the time. So like, and even we’re like, consistently trying to do that to be like, “No, no, just try it. Just mess with it.” Like—&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: I’ll be really proud of you if you break it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Yeah, if you break this file, go for it, I’ve got another copy, don’t worry.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: That’s a huge part for technology, particularly for digital technology particularly, right, because a lot of people are so accustomed to an experience in which if they fuck up, something is there in forever broken. Like maybe they’ve lost some data in the file or something, right, or their browser crashed. And that’s sort of a real visceral experience in the digital realm. But the reason that happens is because they’re not they’re treating digital like analog, right, and they’ve never been taught about the actual like what hypermedia really means. Tech Learning Collective says that “we teach students the arts of hyper media Information Technology and radical political practice,” all-in-one. And the notion there right is that a digital calendar is not an analog calendar, right? A file, like there’s no desks in your computer. We call it the “Desktop Environment.” But, your computer might be on a desk but, it’s not! It’s not actually a desk. There’s no desk in the computer. It’s not like that Zoolander moment where like, “Oh, the files are in the computer!” You know, that’s not, that’s not real.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And yet we have all these graphical symbols, right? Like folder icons and paper icons with little curls on them to sort of give us this metaphor that we’re dealing with something analog. And these metaphors weren’t inevitable, right? This isn’t necessarily how today’s computers had to be. Right? Look at, for example, the 60’s presentation with Engelbart and the way that he’s using that so called mouse or pre-mouse, right? It’s almost like an instrument. And he describes it as an instrument, actually, right. The keyboard is an instrument. It’s more musical than that. And so, when people today look at their computer, right, they’re often seeing an environment that they already have these associations with, not just with physical objects, but with physical objects that are useful in a particular context, which is primarily the office job, because that’s where, right, the industrialization of Business Machines really came from. Look at for example, IBM, right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: Paperless office.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: There you go.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so that’s why we have write things like file icons on graphical GUIs, that you sort of are, in that, try to help you understand what this object can do or what properties of this object are. But that’s just a metaphor. Right? And so we should think of the entire desktop environment as really a metaphor, because that’s what it is. The terminal is a different metaphor, right? So that is a chatroom metaphor. It’s an assistant metaphor, right? Back in the day, before we had sort of computers, before we thought of computers as physical objects, “computers” was the job title of mostly women who were basically secretarial, right, labor, and they were computers. That’s what their job title was. I’m a computer for IBM. That’s what they said. That was their job role. And the reason, right, that we now have a command line, right, is because that command line became that job role. That’s not that people, you know, in the political spectrum. “Oh my gosh, automation. Things are terrible.” I’m like, yes automation, and things are terrible. But like automation doesn’t have to be terrible, right? The terrible thing about automation is that the person whose job you’re automating the system doesn’t give a shit about, right? We could care about that person and offer a huge range of other things for them to do, not least of which is just be in a community and be social with other people, which is its own value. Right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;One of the reasons that we’re against the whole notion of jobs—we’re not, I should say, against helping you find a job. Obviously, if you come to these workshops and learn these skills, it can help you get a job. But the point is that that’s not really our goal. And the reason for that is because we think it’s barbaric to have a society in which you have to work for somebody else, in order to have the basic dignity of shelter and food. That’s insane in 2020 with the technologies that we have available today, it’s absolutely ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: That how important your job is, you know, defines the level of healthcare you get.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah, exactly, that even your job is tied to healthcare, which again, you know, big issue now in the pandemic, we’re the only industrialized nation in the world. Right? “Industrialized,” I should say in quotes, where that’s even sort of…everyone else thinks that’s insane! Right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: I’m—right. This is the thing we get on all the time. That, like, we as a country and like capitalism inherently doesn’t value the people and that’s so short sighted because you do so much long term good when you invest in your people, when you invest in your citizens, because then they’re going to come up with like, amazing stuff that the system would never produce on its own.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Jaron Lanier just the other day was talking about this in his keynote, right where he was saying that the Deming model of production basically said, Hey, you know, these are humans who are in factories, why don’t we ask these humans about what the best way to do their job is and they will probably come up with some examples of things that we can improve. And then that became the Toyota model, right, of for example, Kaizen. And that was now what we talk about as [the genesis of] Agile software development. So these concepts of like human dignity are really ingrained in Just the history of what we could have made possible with computers, but chose not to. And I suppose when I say we here, I mean, you know, the powers that be at any given moment.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so it’s really important for people to understand, I think that, you know, the systems that we have today are not bad systems inso far as they don’t work, that they are not intentionally built this way. But it’s exactly the opposite, right? It’s not like we have a broken system. It’s that we have a system that explicitly chose to do these things in these ways, because it benefits people who were able to bend the will of others to that end.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: It’s not a bug, it’s a feature.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Of course, yeah, of course, it’s a feature, right? If you are, for example, taught to only think of your desktop environment in the context of your office job, you’re never going to think about what power you have at the tip of your fingertips to build something other than what your employer says is necessary for you to keep your job. And that’s really what we’re about. So that’s also why don’t we don’t focus on things like coding so much, but rather on sysops and system administration and DevOps and sort of all the infrastructural components, network engineering and security. That’s really the focus of Tech Learning Collective, specifically because it’s not a good place to start building a new world if you have to build it on the infrastructure of a one that is designed to hurt you. Right, you have to build a different infrastructure. And from a technology perspective, from a hacker perspective, right, that means things like self-hostability, re-decentralization, and all these sort of fancy buzzwords that we talked about at HOPE, and elsewhere for many years now, right.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we’ve seen that that doesn’t, or that hasn’t historically been very successful, right. I think Aelon Porat put it in an earlier talk at HOPE 2020 pointed out very bluntly that like the advocacy community, for example, digital privacy rights advocates, haven’t been historically very successful, which is his very diplomatic way of saying failed miserably to get a lot of people to understand the criticality of data privacy and security. And so, again, that’s where we sort of have this schism, as Tech Learning Collective, with a lot of these other sort of tech initiative groups or these NGOs, a lot of these sort of, you know, sort of policy focused endeavors. We think policy is important but insufficient, and ultimately without resources placed in things like truly we would go so far to say insurrectionary infrastructures, we think it’s also doomed. And so that’s why we focus primarily on helping people who are already starting from the mindset of what can I do to radically change how my life is organized in the society and how society sort of creates the building blocks of mutual self regard for one another, right, with the tools that, you know, we have available and for us because we’re hackers, that means technology.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And it turns out technology is actually a really fantastic vehicle for this because never before in the history of humanity has a single individual had as much asymmetric power as we do today, right? 50 really competent hackers can in fact do the same things as what used to take 100,000, 200,000, 300,000 human individuals to do. And that’s becoming more true the more we attach the IoT, right, Internet of Things, to power plants and to, you know, shopping carts and whatever Amazon else is doing. Right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so we have to think really, about what environment that mean, what does that mean for activism? Because the old ways no longer work. If we live in a world of a global passive adversary, like the NSA for example, we have to think through what strategies may have been useful in 2010 or 2000 that are no longer useful in 2020. And you know, Bruce Schneier talks about this, another speaker at HOPE, where he talks about the security gap as a concept where there’s like a sliding window of things you can do as a small nimble organization, right, that a larger, sort of, more entrenched entity, like a government or like a corporation, right, multinational corporations and governments are kind of the same thing really, today, there’s so much collaboration between the two of them that it’s a little bit ridiculous to sort of talk about one without the other. But if you can sort of stay in that security gap, then you can actually effect change in a way that is far outsized, based on how small your number is.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And that’s really all we need. We don’t need right 100% participation in sort of social change, like we do with maybe mask use, right? What we actually need is something like maybe 5% participation, there’s some statistic that I’ve never looked up to see if it’s true, because it makes me really happy and I don’t want to know that it’s not true that the Civil Rights movement was participated in by only 2% of the United States’s adult population. And if that’s true, then that shows you, right, that, that really, it’s not about getting the masses or changing hearts and minds. We don’t really care about that. Because that’s not actually what’s going to make larger change. What’s actually going to make larger change is committed groups of competent individuals who understand the reality in which they exist today, learn from the past, but don’t replicate the past in, you know, in order to create these more autonomous and more self governing and more, you know, you know, for those who, for those whom this word is not already tainted, a more anarchistic future because that’s actually what the internet was that we all like.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This whole decentralized Internet that we miss? That was effectively an anarchic construction. And if we can apply that, just in sort of an understanding of the of the political implications, the imbued politics of what that was, whether it was intentional or not, but the structure of it, to how we are trying to work today, we should match our social behaviors or social constructions to the technical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Right now, that’s not the case. You have to go to maybe France or Tennessee, right? If you want to talk to someone who’s literally next door over Facebook. Why? Because you have to transit your ISP, which then goes to an Internet backbone, which then ends up at a CDN, which then ends up at Facebook servers, and then comes all the way back so that you can talk to the person that’s in the room that’s next to you. That’s absurd from any kind of, from any position of—the only way that’s not absurd is how do I centralize or create toll roads for this particular traffic so that I can then create choke points and control that communication, right? It’s clearly more—it’s useful, if that’s your perspective, which is the perspective of Verizon, and the NSA and so on and so forth, and Facebook, right. It’s not the perspective of the actual person. So there’s this misalignment between the ways that the system is built infrastructurally and what people actually want to do with it, actually want it to do for them. And the only way to realign those, in our opinion, is not through laws because laws follow behavior, they don’t they don’t preceed behavior. Laws are the code of conduct that we all are sort of socially bound to, but doesn’t actually prevent us for from doing something that only punishes us if we don’t do something or reward us if we do do something. So laws follow behavior, they don’t preempt behavior. That sort of thing, just as a, if you take that as a given.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so the way to do this, right, is to, in the same way that we have, for example, many, many, many electricians and many, many, many plumbers and many, many trade, you know, workers and people so-called “essential workers,” right, whose lives apparently the government could care less about because ALEC, right now, is lobbying for anti-Coronavirus, death lawsuits, right? They’re trying to claim that they don’t have liability if employers kill their workers because of coronavirus. So, there’s that happening. But the point is, is that we have so few relative to how many other essential workers, we have so few sysadmins relative to how many other essential workers we have, that in our view, the much more important thing, much more important than learning JavaScript or learning how to code or learning how to make a back end, you know, three-tier website or whatever—Anytime someone says, “web app” I just can’t stop thinking “surveillance apparatus”—but anyway, right, much more important than that is who is building the infrastructure? Who’s controlling that? Because if you want to actually re-decentralize the Internet, you need more sysadmins than you have now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You actually need people to at least understand that when they turn on the faucet in their bathroom, that water doesn’t just magically appear there and and at the, at the drain. That there’s something before and something after they see the water in their sink. Right. And similarly—&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: The world doesn’t go away when you close your eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Precisely. And so that’s just as true with technology and with the bits that’s transiting over your network link, as it is with water. And that means we need the equivalent plumbers and electricians. And so that’s how we approach things like teaching system administration and network engineering. And that’s not glamorous, right, like that’s a humble position to put us to put a technologist in. And if you look at, for example, the amount of money that jobs like, for example, you know, senior engineering managers or even for instance, developers, right, are making in comparison to what electricians and plumbers are making. You see a very clear difference in class. Right? There’s a huge amount more money if you are for example, running a, or coding, you know, the Twitter UI, right, then if you are making sure that the building in which that those programmers were working before Coronavirus, or even now at their homes, right, has electricity. If you’re the electrician for that person, you’re not making probably as much. If you’re the plumber for that person, you’re probably making even less.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We value water even less than electricity which is weird because we’re gonna have a water crisis, right, coming up in the next five to 15 years. And you know, we can live without electricity for many, many, many days, we can live without water for only maybe two or three. So the entire economic incentive schemes are also inverted, badly so. Right? And that, you know, will require not only an understanding of sort of this system as, as something that these choices were sort of, that these were actually chosen, choices people made, and that they weren’t mistakes, that these weren’t bad choices. This is the point of creating a status symbol that’s associated with the kind of jobs that technologists have.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I’m not trying to say that technologists don’t deserve the praise for doing the work that they do. What I am saying is that plumbers electricians deserve just as much praise. As technologists, we have to lift that up. And so when we approach teaching about system administration and network engineering as a trade, rather than as some sort of like high tech, laudable skill, for us, that’s a sign of huge respect, rather than diminishing the skill that it is, because it’s just as important in the information age to have the flow of communications be well monitored, secured, you know, reliable, available, you know, integrious, right, the CIA triad that we talk about: Confidentiality, Integrity and Availability principles from the infosec world, right? That is stuff that any Junior System Administrator should know. But typically, even if you’re in the tech field, you don’t really hear about those infosec concepts until you’re already bluntly brainwashed by an educational institution that’s trying to make sure that you are taking part and parcel of the perverted incentives that ends up with you having a CCNP or an OSCP certification that then gets you you know, $200,000 a year and that you are now divorced from the community that you might have even came from. Right? And that you’re no longer really incentivize to give back to.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So that’s an extractive model in the same way that we think about, for example, rare earth minerals being extracted from mines and sort of strip mining of land. And that being a horrific thing for the environment, there’s a similar thing happening with code boot camps and with the educational system around technical skill, because now those extractive models are being applied to people, and those “human resources” as we weirdly call them, right, are being treated in exactly that same way. Let’s take out everyone who wants to—let’s take out from communities, everyone who wants to learn about technology and put them in the the sort of like power generators of Amazon, Google, and Facebook. Right? In order to mine more data, we literally call it “data mining” from those exact same communities. And yeah, there are some exceptions, of course, where, you know, an extraordinary person will go through this thing and end up with, you know, with huge success and create an NGO, but now their left hand is fighting their right hand. So where’s the infrastructure that’s different than this, to actually make something else?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And that’s again, what because, you know, we know there are sort of here or there, there’s, there’s some good examples. And again, you know, NGOs are doing some amount of good work, but they’re still beholden to the same system.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So we see ourselves as kind of like the separatist group of, of hacker educators that came with this analysis and are trying to do something completely different. And that, for us, currently, in this phase of our, because of the history that I was talking about earlier, starts from this notion of, we need more sysadmins, and so we have to make them by educating them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And it turns out, there’s actually a lot of people who are interested in that exact thing. They don’t often know it most people who come to TLC come because they want to “learn how to code.” And then once they see the power in a couple of workshops, of all the other things that are there, like once they see that, oh my god, I don’t even really know what a socket was, but I was doing network programming this whole time. Okay, well, let’s talk about, you know, the network layers. You know, let’s talk about the OS. Let’s talk about Unix domain sockets. Here’s another way, right? In fact, if you’re a security minded person, you know that if you are looking at a server that’s running on your machine, for example, an Nginx machine, right next server, you might want to use something like a Unix domain socket, because it could be, in some context, way more secure than using a TCP socket. But you have to know what that is. Right? And if you if you’ve never heard the term socket, because you’ve only maybe heard the term WebSocket, or you only ever heard the term, you know, web server, because you’re only ever coding, then you can never even code well for that context. So anyway, that’s our that’s our that’s our spiel. That was a bit of a rant, I hope that’s okay.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: I’m so excited to know you exist now, because you’ve just touched on in like 20 minutes, like three days worth of conversations we’ve been having here.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Oh, awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Like, utility issues and issues with protests and racism and just trying to get people to see that no, this system is designed to be this way. It’s designed to like, like, capitalism doesn’t work without an underclass the way we have it set up. Yeah, like, all of these huge, huge issues that like, deeply bother like almost everyone I’ve met under 40. And you just have them all here at the front of like your thing like, you guys are really exciting. I’m like really excited to know you exist. I can’t wait to spend like a week crawled up inside your website.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Please, that would be really cool. It’s exciting for me to hear about your excitement because normally this is not the kind of conversation that well, I should say this: it is becoming more frequently the kind of conversation that, you know, ends up with the sort of excitement of what let’s do something and how do we kind of do that next. But for a long time, I will say that like you know, this was not generally speaking the kind of conversation that was that—I’m hesitating a little bit to say welcome, but, for lack of a better word, I’ll say welcome in spaces that were primarily technical, right. And I think that it’s important to remember that even though that, that, you know, it, this comes back to that sort of cultural divide, right, like a lot of people had some, a lot of, you know, “technical” people insofar as again, there’s this distinction between technical and non technical, but, um, there’s a lot of folks who, you know, may not—they have this sort of intuitive sense of like, this is sort of wrong, or this is not how I want the Internet to be or something, you know, like something went awry somewhere. But what they don’t, I think, realize is that part of what, at least when at least part of what went awry, if not, most of it is that most of the people who are actually really lucky from the 90s in the in the early 2000s. Right, the an earlier generation of hackers. They didn’t do a lot of teaching in comparison to how much basically employing they did, right. And so there’s a huge culpability in that.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That’s not to paint every hacker community as something that is sort of evil, obviously, because there’s, you know, there’s epistemic forces, and systemic forces, and individual horses, and they all have their own, you know, sort of shares of this thing. But it is to say that if we, like Aelon Porat said earlier, right, like, we’ve done a bad job as a hacker community, primarily, and I think part of it, you know, even Moxie Marlinspike blogged about this in the early days of TextSecure, where he was like, I looked around and all of a sudden, these sort of people I was making fun of for coming to DEF CON from the military are now basically running the show what the hell happened? It’s like a blink of an eye. But really what happened was, and he points this out, right, is we didn’t pay attention, that was a huge mistake. And so we lost that security gap moment, right? Where the cyberpunk future we envision where we could actually have privacy, where nations were no longer important, look at “beauty of the baud”, and Declaration of Independence of Cyberspace, and Hacker Manifesto, right, from Phrack days. We lost that. We basically just fumbled.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: We showed them our hand and they took it away.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Literally dropped the ball.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Right! And now if you want to go into security, right, what’s the only legal way to do that? Right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Yeah, you have to go through the training and get the certificate.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: And what do we call that? What’s the name for…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Indoctrination?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Well, I mean, yes, but I was thinking what do they they call it? Right, that the word for hacking legally?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Is that pentesting now?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah. And that, it is. That’s right. And that practice, they call it “ethical hacking.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Mm hmm. Right. Right. Certified Ethical Hacking?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yes. Think of the perversion of language. How 1984 is that? You can’t get more doublespeak than this. It’s literally the the epitome of hacker doublespeak to call that ethical hacking. Right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: It’s like when I figured out as a child that, no you don’t get to be an astronaut without joining the military.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Right. So they have this monopoly of violence that they’ve now extended into the cyber realm they explicitly talk about in those terms, and anything other than a direct confrontation with that, ideologically, I mean, is not enough to overcome it. Because you cannot have something that is anathema to the very existence of other ideas and claim that that is in any way inclusive or diverse. It’s just not possible, you have to actually put a stake in the ground at some point, in order for things that are opposed to that ideology, to have a chance. The only ideology—and the thing about that, is that any ideology other than one of diversity, right, is one against diversity, by definition, and so if you actually believe in that the thing about your so called inclusive ideology that you must maintain as a red line, your line in the sand, is you cannot allow anything that is anti-diverse in that. It must not be permitted.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: So I have a question from the Discord. This person asking is a teaching adjunct who teaches creative tech and web tech at a large university. And they’re looking, they’re hoping you might know of any talks or video clips or good ways of discussing the corporate state of the web that you think can aid in illustrating the decentralized nature of its origins to Gen Z?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Oh, that’s a really good question. Um, I happen to really like a book called A Prehistory of The Cloud. It’s by an MIT author, Asian American, whose name I’m blanking on right now, but we can look it up. But it’s MIT Press, A Prehistory of The Cloud. It talks a lot about where the current notion of the Internet, as we know it today in terms of cloud services, and, you know, the sort of massive centralized companies that are running data centers, where it came from. And it’s a good read, it’s not the only thing that I think is relevant along those lines, but it’s probably one of the best primers and starters.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Another really good book, and I think this is sort of maybe a little askew to the question, but is an approach that we take Tech Learning Collective very often, which is to simply use different metaphors when we talk about the technologies that we have and a good book for this is one by Eric Davis known as Techgnosis, T-E-C-H-G-N-O-S-I-S. Techgnosis, as in the Gnostic traditions of technology. Because if you look back far enough in places like for example, Ethernet networking, when Bob Metcalfe created Ethernet, right, the name Ethernet was not a mistake. It was not just, you know, this is what we call it. Now, we don’t even think about where you know what an Ethernet is, but in the early 20th century and the 19th century, right, the notion of “the ether” was an idea that came from the Gnostic traditions that there were these, there was this thing, almost like The Force in Star Wars, right? Where it, where this thing called ether permeated everything and everyone, it was sort of part of what held the universe together. And so when Metcalfe was trying to come up with a universal networking technology, he used that word to describe his Ethernet technology because it was going to be a network of devices that held other networks together. And now of course, we have Ethernet as sort of the de facto layer two networking technology in any network you can think of, more or less. And that came from this sort of like, gnostic metaphor of the ether.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so when we teach at Tech Learning Collective, mostly what we do is we go back to the sort of early metaphors and early understandings of what was possible rather than what is in its concrete form now because that opens up the imagination of students to think about what they could do with the capabilities that we teach them in sort of the later half of workshops and courses. So when we talk about networking, for example, we talk about the notion of a relatively ubiquitous, magical, right, like Force-like, ability that we now have, right? When you’re browsing a website, you’re not, you know, we think of it as saying for example, you’re visiting a website, you’re going someplace, but really what it’s more like, if you look at the technologies, you’re conjuring you’re bringing, you’re pulling to you, you’re downloading&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: The mountains coming to Muhammad.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Right? If you want to use the Dune analogy, right, you’re like folding space so that you end up, right, or rather, it ends up in the place where you are. And so whatever metaphor you want to use, right, starting to use, a more poetic, a more, a more fantastical language, I mean, even the terms of programming today, right? In the 90s, we had this sort of big shift towards industrial language with Java and sort of factory patterns and this kind of stuff when we talk about programming, but if you look at the words that were used to describe elements of syntax and code, for example, the dollar sign in a bash variable, right? That’s known as a sigil. A programming sigil, right, is a specific glyph that is used to denote something magical about the word following that particular symbol. And the word sigil comes from magic. It comes from literal, like, you know, like witch and wizard magic. And so if you return the magic to computers, and I think that’s relatively easy to do, because a lot of people do think of them almost as magical devices, then you open up the imagination for students to think about what else could have been possible rather than just sort of accepting this received notion of what is now and therefore sort of what other people have already to, you know, use the word that’s now been used several times, right, indoctrinated people to think should be.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so a good book for that as Techgnosis. A good, more technical book around these things, sort of historical context, is A Prehistory of The Cloud. There are others but those are two pretty good ones as well. Obviously, I would also highly recommend Jaron Lanier’s works, you know, the keynote speaker from earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: That’s, that is awesome. That is a great resource list.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: I was always surprised that people didn’t call Wi-Fi sub ether.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah, or any other new, or even radio, right, just in general, when when we think about—the other thing that we like to do with Tech Learning Collective that I think is also a missed opportunity in other places is sort of this more foundational look at the technologies that we have. So for instance, when we talk, we don’t have to go into physics too much, right, to understand how Wi-Fi works. But it’s interesting to think about radio as basically just electricity in the air, right? Because those same sort of, the when you look at for example, electric current you’re looking at, for example, a radio wave, you’re still seeing at the physics level, those same sort of like IQ, you know, spinning, you know sine waves that you’re talking about when you look at at the physics side of things.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: The more we learn, the more we learn about it, the more we go, no electromagnetism, they are more tied together than we could possibly imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah, there aren’t that many kinds of energy or matter that, you know, humans know how to use in the world, right? There’s, you know, light, there’s sound vibration, which is physics, right. And there’s electromagnetism or energy, right? Or electrical energy of that kind. And that’s also radio. And so when people, for example, understand that that’s what wireless is. Wireless is radio. That’s it. Right? Then they can understand the electromagnetic spectrum. And they can have an understanding that’s more intuitive of, for example, a 2.4 gigahertz radio and maybe an 800 megahertz cell tower. Right? So that now that makes more sense, because it’s actually just the same physical matter.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so again, when we start networking courses, we talk about physical links, right? That’s where we need to start. So that you know how things are connected. Why do we need physical links? Well, because right, we live in a physical world and computers still live in this physical world. So as magical as I just described it is, right, the other side of that coin and sort of at the same time, there’s sort of a, you know, there’s a challenge in this for teachers, because you have to sort of, on the one hand, give the analogy give the sort of magical or metaphorical side of things, but then also compromise it at the same time. And so, if we’re doing these, these two tasks, but it’s in much the same way that, for example, science and religion is often, you know, viewed as opposites when they’re not, right, we have this sort of weird cultural understanding of opposites. Like dog and cat. Those are not opposites at all. Right? they’re actually just two different species of animals. But similarly, like, science and religion might be seen as opposite. There might be some tension involved in that but they’re not opposites. And so likewise, if we look at for example, radio, and you know, understanding that any wireless technology is ultimately radio, now, right if you talk about for example, a cable right, so we have like an ethernet, with an RJ-45 jack cable, right, where you are, a Registered Jack 45 where you have a you know you have an eight line ethernet cable, connects from one computer to another. Right you turn off the Wi-Fi link, you can still talk to them their computer, but now you’re talking over physical cable. Well inside that physical cable, it’s just basically radio on copper. Right? Or whatever. Fiber? Well, not fiber, as that’s light. But on copper.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: It’s a modern telegraph.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah, exactly. It is a modern telegraph. And that it’s actually the same thing as the telegraph just for the new way. Right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: Really fast.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah, it’s a very efficient telegraph. And so, so we need that physical link because whether we’re doing it wirelessly or physically, right, whether it be radio waves, or sort of radio on the cable, like cable, electricity, electrical link, there’s still actually a link. A physical link.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And so, in order to talk to, for example, Facebook, there must be a physically unbroken link whether that is entirely over a copper cabling, or if some bits of that link end up being over the air via radio. Right? There’s still a physical process happening from me to Facebook. And that’s just the same as if, for example, you’re 12 years old, and you are trying to talk to your friend across the street with a can and string. Drop the can, and you can no longer talk, right? Or, for example, with light and ships in the sea, right? If there is not a physical way for that light to reach you, you don’t have line of sight, right? When you’re doing Morse code on the sea, you’re not going to get the message. This is just as true in computers as it is everywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So really understanding those foundations is what makes it really easy for people to pick up and sort of apply that knowledge to other realms, which means that they don’t have to spend 20 years, you know, at a job to get good at a particular set of skills. And I think that’s the other thing that people sort of mistake. Another thing I like to say is that, you know, there’s a lot of this feeling of being overwhelmed when people come to TLC. There’s a lot of, you know, how am I ever going to learn this stuff? There’s so much and yeah, there’s a lot, but it’s not like there’s thousands of years of human history and like craftsperson-ship to learn you know, and become really good at, right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s not like you have to learn about if you were learning herbalism or cooking or you know literature, you’ve got thousands and thousands of years of human history to catch up on as someone who was born in 2000, right, or 2005, whatever. Now, if you’re, from today, if you are looking to be good at technology, which is to say digital technologies, right computer technologies, you’ve got maybe 70, 80 years, you know, meaningfully of history to catch up on and you can totally do that in a committed two to three year stint, right? That’s not nothing. It’s still work, but it’s not a rest of your life endeavor. It’s far from it. And so this notion of like, only the, you know, super committed, you know, people who’ve been doing this for their whole lifetime since the age of 12. You know, back in the 80’s could get good at it. That’s absurd. That’s ridiculous. The only reason it takes so long, typically for so many people is because they don’t have the resources because most of their resources are spent right trying to get their employer’s problems  solved, not their own problem solved. They don’t have the guidance. Because again, right, I mean, I used to work in the IT industry, I quit after—I hated it for several reasons. But the point is that, like, I remember employers constantly promising things like professional development courses and time off for learning, and I never got that shit.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: Oh, yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: I mean, it’s, it’s an endemic issue in the industry. So there’s that. And so they don’t have that. And then also, on top of all that, they don’t have good resources when they go looking for something because it’s either the black hole of YouTube or blog searches that have become worse and worse and worse over time, or answers that don’t actually tell you about the underlying technologies that you’re trying to look up. They tell you how to solve the problem. They tell you how to, you know, like, you know, copy and paste this code from Stack Overflow is the programmers example, or here the two commands that you need is the sysadmins example. Right? But they don’t actually tell you why it works.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Erin: I can’t tell you how many threads I’ve read for hours and hours and hours that say “solved” and at the bottom, it’s by a new Mac. That’s the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah. And so that too, right, that comes from the sort of like, let me give you the worksheet to follow, the checklist to do the thing, like, let me give you the playbook without necessarily explaining to you or showing you, letting you go under the hood of that same playbook. That’s up to you. And, look, most people don’t have the time to do that, because most people are doing this in the context of a job where they’ve already got these other pressures, which, again, is why we don’t focus on people who are trying to get careers or jobs from this, not again, not to say that you can’t or shouldn’t, but that, you know, that’s not our focus. And because it’s not our focus, it means that we have a lot of space and a lot of resources to do the sorts of education that actually gets you a foundational knowledge base from which you can then, you know, do whatever you want, really, because that’s the whole point.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;For us, it’s about autonomy building, not about sort of, it’s not even about personal empowerment, right? That’s great. We want that but personal empowerment leads to “Well, I’m gonna get a $200,000 a year job and then you know, work for Palantir.” That’s not really the goal here. The real goal is if you know these skills, and you’re in an environment where you’re apprenticing right? Or learning with other people who know these skills with some way of sort of sharing ideologies around this. And this is can be anything from like, super hardcore, radical anarchist political stuff, all the way to, isn’t it cool that programming languages use magical terms like sigil? And let’s talk about that! And let’s make a pagan group around computer use, for example, that’s also another way to sort of build autonomy. But it’s not just about you.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: I’d love to spend more time with you.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: I know it’s probably, we’re probably running out of time. But thank you so much for letting me talk about this and for asking the questions you did and for inviting us to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: I do have one more question if you have another few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Oh, sure.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Any thoughts on how the discuss the shift from the web being a disembodied anonymous space to one made of profiles tied directly to your real life identity, and all the ways that has impacted queer and radical subculture on the net?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Whoo, that is a that is a whole other hour, right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Right, so much silencing, like, just like the Facebook real name requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah. So I think—&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Radio Statler producer: We don’t have anything coming up the next hour.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Like, yeah, we have time. I don’t know if you do.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: I actually have, I’m booked to teach a workshop actually in about half an hour, so I have to go soon. But I can stay for a little bit longer. So maybe we’ll go until another maybe 10-15? And then I really have to rush.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: Yeah, cool. You’d be delighted to have you.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Well, hey, thanks for the extended invitation then, um, but so the answer this person’s question, or maybe not to answer, but maybe to think about a little bit, I think it’s important to recognize the sort of cause and effect that we’re seeing. Right, like what that person describing is a, is an effect of something that came before. Right. And you mentioned the Facebook Real Name requirements, right? That is a, you know, a choice Facebook made and they knew what they were doing when they when they made it. I don’t necessarily think that they made it maliciously, I’m not trying to inscribe intent there, although, you know, we can certainly have a debate about whether or not it was malicious. And I might fall on that side. But that doesn’t really matter.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The point is they had reasons, right? And they weighed those reasons. And they made a specific choice. And so the question we have to ask ourselves is, why is it that the Internet sort of at large, and we know it today, and the people who are sort of responsible for making decisions on the Internet has consistently seem to make choices that hurt queer and marginalized and racialized populations? And so on right? Because there is a clear pattern that that has been true. So what’s going on with that? Like, what why is that sort of the decisions? Why do things keep falling on that side?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And I think one of the most important, I think, philosophical notions to think about, or lenses from which we can think about that is that we perceive ourselves, right, to have this existence in society that is democratic, lowercase D democratic so, Okay, so what is democracy? Right? Well, one person, one vote sort of thing, right? And the fact of the matter is that we don’t actually live in a country in America anyway. Right? The United States, it’s not really a democracy, it’s really a Republic. Right? You don’t actually vote for the president, you vote for an elector who then votes for the President. Right. So you vote for representative. And so there’s this huge effort amongst primarily liberal policies to get more representation, right. Whether it be media, whether it be in politics, through electors, or Congress, people, Congress Critters and so on, right. And the problem there is that you have indirection, right? You are not actually in control with anything, you are only indirectly able to influence something. So that’s Problem number one, we don’t really live in a democracy. We live in a sort of Republic system of government.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Number two is let’s say we did live in democracy, right. So now we know that just imagine that there weren’t in any sort of indirect intermediaries that we actually had full and like immediate control over the the levers of power through our votes. Well now right, we have a way one person one vote scenario where you know, the power is in the hands of any majority. But we know that that’s also not the best way to structure a society if you are not a majority, right? If you are the minority, then you clearly don’t have, you know, that’s not the best necessarily situation for, you know. Now, you can maybe hope for, you know, the kindness of other people and the generosity of the majority so that they don’t crush you at the ballot box, but ultimately, from a technologist point of view, we understand that that’s a promise not not really a implemented right aspect of the system.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And we can have reasonable debates about whether or not that’s good or bad or whether or not, you know that that’s sufficient. But if you look at it from the perspective of tech, right that a hacker would look at it, we have to think about, is this susceptible to a failure mode that an attacker would take advantage of? And the obvious answer is, it is, right? There is no system on Earth, in which humans interact with where its input will be given by people who all have the same intent. Right? And so, now we have to think about, okay, if democracy itself, right, as in one person, one vote, majority rule, will everyone describe it is not going to serve us in this way? How do we build systems which can?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And I think that that first shift, right, we are so far away. Most people think, right in America that we live in a democracy that you know, you elect the president, and this is so far away from how it actually works, that there’s this sort of pre-work that has to happen to just educate people about what reality they’re actually living in.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And this is something that hackers should be very good at, because the whole notion right of hacking should be to show people what’s possible, rather than what’s polite. Right? Here, I can do this! Maybe you didn’t want me to do it. That’s possible. Look, I used this thing in a different way, or I subverted this rule. Right, again, Bruce Schneier says that hacking is about subverting rules. So using the current context, or the current rule set, right, in a way that the system, the system’s designers didn’t expect. That is a hack, right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Also, by the way, there’s a great piece I think it was published on Aeon.com at some point recently, or a couple years ago, it was called “How Yuppies Hacked the Hacker Ethos.” And it’s a great piece about this sort of, this, dillusion of the term “hacking,” which has now sort of become like, you know, you’re a hacker, if you, for example, work at the Google offices and you know, you work on protobuf or something, maybe. Not to single that out, in particular, like, that’s cool, right. protobuf is great, or whatever it is, right, that you want to work on. You used to work on Google Wave. You hacked together a new product. Fantastic, great. That’s not what it originally meant. And that’s not to say that it can’t mean that I know language evolves and all that stuff. But the point is, is that it we sort of lost this more you know, beauty of the baud style ethos from the 90s of what hacking could have been for us. Not even to say that the 90s was was great that was already after the period in the 80s when women were told that, you know, for example, that they shouldn’t deal with math and computers, because only that’s, that’s boy stuff. So that’s already exactly not a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But the point is, is that that’s, you know, you want to go back through these these thoughts, whether it is historically, you know, through a chronology to find some place where you can fork, right? Like, if you look at the GitHub history, and you see like, well, I don’t really like what happened after this commit. Fine, fork from the previous commit, and then start again, right? We don’t have to always append to the things that came before us in the technical realm. We shouldn’t have to then—we should be able to jettison the things that we don’t like culturally as well. And so for us, it’s like, Okay, well, for me, personally, I should say, right. I love this notion of Metcalfe’s Ethernet, this sort of magical permeating network, this sort of Solarpunk vision of technology working with people. Jaron Lanier, again, talked a lot about how there was this debate about whether AI—Artificial Intelligence—was going to replace humans, or whether AI—Augmented Intelligence—right, or Aggregate Intelligence, was going to sort of provide a mechanism for humans to work more closely with other humans in increasingly collaborative ways. And that was a debate that was happening in the 70’s. So I like those ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And I think that, you know, a lot of stuff that happened in the 80s and 90s and early 2000s, that was this sort of very industrial very, you know, we basically industrialized, all the ideas that that that didn’t have to be industrialized, right? Again, Java, as a programming language has enormous amount of metaphor in it. And it’s, and its metaphor is the factory. Literally, there’s a there’s a programming concept called the factory pattern, right? Where you generate a bunch of objects based on an on one another object that’s a generator for that object, right? In Python, we have generators. In JavaScript now we have generators, right? And again, where did these words come from? What was the mindset of the people who made those choices to call it that? And again, it’s not a I’m not blaming them as individuals but I am saying that they lived in a context where they made certain choices that then we never questioned 10 years, 20 years later. But we could! We can!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And if we do, that we can do the same, you know, for these for these concepts, we can do the same thing with these other sort of more abstract notions of things like democracy, right? Do we really want a one vote one, one, you know, one person, one vote system directly, right? In a world where any Sybil attack can be 100,000 people? Probably not a good choice as an infrastructure to build a society or a voting society, because you have bad actors that can then take advantage of that as a vulnerability. So, you know, I’m not gonna, say this is the answer. But I am going to say that I think that if you approach it in that sense, then you look at the choices people like Facebook make, and you can clearly see the motivations behind it. And you can even understand and empathize with those motivations, even as they harm you.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Right, us as queer people, right, us as poor people, Facebook is harming us. There’s no question about that. But I understand exactly where they’re coming from. And I have to understand where they’re coming from in order to come up with any means that has a chance in hell of combating it. Because if I don’t know my enemy, right, there’s no way I’m going to be able to strategize in a meaningful way. And so the more that you ask those questions, I think further away, you find yourself from solutions, like policy solutions, like, solutions like law, like hope, and solutions, like, for example, you know, relying on the kindness of a majority. And the further away you get from believing that these sort of naive notions of political systems such as you know, lowercase-d democracy, where you have a majority rule, are that ambitious or even worth aspiring to.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And then and only then can you come up with, you know, can you start asking yourself questions like, “How should we really organize ourselves?” “What is what is an effective way?” And then once you ask yourself those questions, you have to experiment, and fail. A lot. Like a lot! Right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: That’s how you learn best, right? Through failure.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah. And the other thing on that is that with TLC, right, the first thing one of the first things that we do when we when we create lab environments for folks is that we say we’re not even going to talk about doing something in the lab environment, we’re going to talk about creating the lab environment. And the reason for that is because when you fuck up—not if—but when you fuck up, it’s going to be okay because you did it in a safe area. And so that, that is you know, you have to be able to create environments for yourself where you can make mistakes where you can fail, and where it can be okay to do so. And I should say also, where it’s okay to do that non-publicly. Where it’s okay to fail private.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: That’s, that’s such a big piece of the classroom Erin and I try to build, too. We just, we try to give our students a place to fail, so they can learn more, so they can learn better so they can gain confidence and be willing to change try and try again.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah, that I think is one of the things that was the most damaging to what we would call, you know, capital TH The Hacker community, capital THC, The Hacker Community, in the 90s, where we had, you know, a lot of people being ridiculed for not knowing stuff. And I think there was this huge movement. Movement is maybe the wrong term, but there was a lot of motivation amongst people who were very technically skilled, but were not very emotionally mature, to raise themselves up by putting other people down. And that’s exactly the wrong approach for an empowering education. Of course, that wasn’t their intent, right? These weren’t self described teachers. So again, I empathize, and I understand, but it wasn’t perhaps a strategically good move. Because the result was those you know, military folks who everyone laughed at at the early DEF CONS, right? and you can hear. What’s the CloudFlare CEO’s name? Matthew something or other? Maybe it wasn’t him. Maybe I’m misnaming somebody, but I remember hearing a story where they were describing, you know, one of these CEOs, infosec CEOs, was describing going to DEF CON and, you know, he and his buddies were sort of laughing at the, at the army people who, like failed all the CTFs, they just didn’t know how to do anything. You know, like, haha, it’s gonna, you know, they don’t even know what they’re doing. And then literally, within five years, they were the top team or one of the top teams. And, you know, that’s got to be, you know, that that was an invasion. It was a cultural invasion. And it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You know, when we put out when Tech Learning Collective hosted our first conference last December, within days of publishing it, we were approached by a military recruiter, and, you know, way earlier than we were approached by any queer group, you know. It took our side weeks to find us, but it took, you know, ostensible enemy’s side days. And so I think, we’ve ceded a lot of ground in that case. And I think that we have to think bigger than things.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The, like all the supposedly ambitious statements that people are making, even these large national nonprofit groups where they’re like, you know, saying, Oh, you should, you know, you know, we have to ban facial recognition. Yes. Agree let’s ban facial recognition. But that’s, that’s such an unambitious goal. And it’s not that like, it’s a bad thing to do. There’s no reason for us to get in the way of that kind of effort. All we’re saying is that if you look strategically at where we’re going and how slow we’re making progress against this and how quickly our enemies’s capabilities and capacities are increasing, we have to pick a different prioritization of where our resources are going in order to have any hope of doing anything meaningful. And this sort of over reliance on policy, this over reliance on lowercase-d democracy, this over reliance on sort of the promises that our enemies are making to us is a doomed strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So, I don’t know if that answers the question, but I hope that gives us some sense of how to think maybe a little bit bigger about why it is that these choices continuously sort of hurt, you know, trans people, and queer people, and Black people, and Brown people.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mel: It was it was really a wonderful education in and of itself, like, and I have a lot to think about. I think our listeners have a lot to think about. And I think we have a really good reading list. And I really appreciate you spending the extra time with us.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;TLC: Yeah, thank you so much, again, for inviting me. I do have to get going because I’m teaching a networking class. So you know, if folks want to learn more: TechLearningCollective.com. We have an email address, PGP key, we also have a Signal number. We publish our Safety Number, our Signal Safety Number as well. So if you want to verify that before you send a Signal message to us, you could do so. We’ve got a couple of workshops coming up at HOPE. But also, again, if you go to TechLearningCollective.com and just click on the Events Calendar page, you’ll see either a list or a month view of all the events that we have coming up. Some are free, some are by donation, some are at cost, a sliding scale cost. We tend to limit class sizes to something that’s under 20 folks, because that helps discussion. We try to be, sort of, interactive with students, but we do a lot of them. So feel free to come to any of them, and please tell your friends, and if this kind of stuff speaks to you, either politically or philosophically or technically, you know, we’re here to make it possible to take those next steps after you begin, you know, finding an interest in this or after you begin maybe attending like your first digital security workshop or a CryptoParty or that, like, you know, “What next?” We hope that that answer is us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">In a far-reaching interview on the Hackers On Planet Earth 2020 conference's Internet radio broadcast, Radio Statler, Tech Learning Collective discusses our philosophical approach to computer technology, hacking, anarcho-autonomism, and more. We also lead three offensive cybersecurity workshops at the HOPE 2020 workshops track this year, made possible by the conference organizer's decision to make the event a wholly-virtual one. Our own hope for the event is that people who are looking for a liberatory and ambitious direction that goes beyond but overlaps with the famous hacker ethos exemplified by the HOPE 2020 conference and community can find what they're looking for in the form of Tech Learning Collective's approach to queering hackerdom and returning the magic to computers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.tech-learning-collective-hope-2020.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/post.featured.tech-learning-collective-hope-2020.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>