<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2020-06-16T20:30:40-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective | Events</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">Automate All the Things: A Primer to Infrastructure as Code</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-18-automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automate All the Things: A Primer to Infrastructure as Code" /><published>2020-07-18T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-18T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-18-automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-18-automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to make your own Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), automatically install software on the servers in your cloud, and write executable runbooks to automatically perform upgrades and other maintenance with the press of a button. With today’s modern automation toolkits, a two-person hobby project can outperform a 100-person company, as long as they use the right tools the right way. In this workshop, you’ll get a practical introduction to cloud infrastructure automation with tools like Ansible, Vagrant, and Terraform, and a chance to solidify your understanding of fundamental DevOps skills that every IT professional needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In today’s IT environments, application servers, databases, file shares, and even network devices are too numerous for any individual or team to provision, configure, and administer one at a time. To deploy, maintain, and secure large digital fleets, site reliability engineers leverage the inherent power of computerized automation to perform everything from daily tasks (patching, updating code) to critical but rare operations (migrations, incident response). But even small groups can take advantage of this sort of automation to massively amplify their impact; today, a two-person hobby project can outperform a 100-person company if they use the right tools the right way.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Generically called &lt;em&gt;Infrastructure as Code (IaC)&lt;/em&gt;, modern configuration management tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ansible.com/&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chef.io/&quot;&gt;Chef&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://saltstack.com/&quot;&gt;SaltStack&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://puppet.com/&quot;&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt; make it possible for a single operator to paralellize executing Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) like initiating backups or performing blue-green deployments on hundreds or thousands of machines at once. By using virtualization through IaC tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://vagrantup.com/&quot;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt;, entire “cloud” environments can be emulated for heterogenous development teams, massively streamlining everything from software development, to R&amp;amp;D, to education and onboarding. (Tech Learning Collective’s own course exercises and practice labs are defined in code as Vagrant configurations!) Encoding your organization’s infrastructure requirements in standard, vendor-neutral, open formats such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://terraform.io/&quot;&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt; means you can switch from one infrastructure provider to another with ease. But perhaps most important of all, “automating all the things” means that potential disasters like ransomware extortion attempts, outages, or even mere accidents can be audited, diagnosed, and remediated in a matter of minutes instead of days or weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop, you’ll get a practical introduction to cloud infrastructure automation. You’ll learn how to create your first virtual private cloud (VPC), add multiple machines to it, automatically install server software on those machines, and write exectuable runbooks to automatically perform upgrades and other maintenance tasks on your new infrastructure. Whether you’re already administering a fleet of servers at work, or just want to slim your “weekend project” time down to size, this far-reaching workshop will solidify your understanding of the development operations (DevOps) skills every IT professional needs to hone to have success with modern digital infrastructure projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-07-18-automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to make your own Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), automatically install software on the servers in your cloud, and write executable runbooks to automatically perform upgrades and other maintenance with the press of a button. With today’s modern automation toolkits, a two-person hobby project can outperform a 100-person company, as long as they use the right tools the right way. In this workshop, you’ll get a practical introduction to cloud infrastructure automation with tools like Ansible, Vagrant, and Terraform, and a chance to solidify your understanding of fundamental DevOps skills that every IT professional needs.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tor: What is it Good For? (Absolutely Everything!)</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-16-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tor: What is it Good For? (Absolutely Everything!)" /><published>2020-07-16T16:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-16T16:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-16-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-16-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything">&lt;p&gt;Come learn how the free Tor Web Browser can be your gateway to the Dark Web while simultaneously keeping you safer and your personal info more private as you browse web sites big and small. In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From illegal online drug stores like Silk Road to DDoS botnet command and control headquarters, media attention has long painted “the Dark Web” as though nothing good can come of it. But learn just a little bit more about how Tor and “hidden services” work and you’ll find a treasure trove of valuable possibilities for day-to-day Internet use. The same technology that can hide the location of a drug ring can also serve as a free VPN-like service to protect your privacy while you browse the Internet, make censored websites available again, and even let you host your own Internet services for free, all without opening a single port on your firewall!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool. They’ll demonstrate numerous Tor features such as Tor authentication, target service load balancing, and NAT-punching. In the process, you’ll finally understand—on a technical level—what the “Dark Web” actually is and how it works. Bring a laptop to class, and you’ll leave having run your own Dark Web site. This class is for everyone; whether you’re a veteran black hat or a timid newbie, this class will shine a light on the Dark Web once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-07-16-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Come learn how the free Tor Web Browser can be your gateway to the Dark Web while simultaneously keeping you safer and your personal info more private as you browse web sites big and small. In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Exploring Cyberspace: Network Sniffing and Scanning</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-14-exploring-cyberspace-network-sniffing-and-scanning" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring Cyberspace: Network Sniffing and Scanning" /><published>2020-07-14T16:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-14T16:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-14-exploring-cyberspace-network-sniffing-and-scanning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-14-exploring-cyberspace-network-sniffing-and-scanning">&lt;p&gt;Come exploring with us as we show you how to map out interconnections between computers, trace packet routes across network gateways, and find information about network operators. In this workshop all about the voyages of frames, packets, and segments, we use tools like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt; to send probes into cyberspace and tap into the wire with Wireshark to understand how they function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered what’s between your computer and the websites you visit? Are you curious about where your messages actually go in order to get from here to there? Do you wonder what a map of computer networks really looks like? Come exploring with us as we embark on a journey into cyberspace, the final Final Frontier! In this beginner-friendly workshop, we’ll throw a metaphorical message in a bottle into the expanse of cyberspace, and learn how to sense and track its movement as it makes its way back to us—or not!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;These are the voyages of frames, packets, and segments—our messages—as they make their way across the vast reaches of the Internet. On the way, they’ll encounter both friendly and unfriendly devices, such as routers, firewalls, traffic inspectors, or NAT tables. At each step of their journey, a complex series of decisions are made to determine where they’ll be routed to next, or if their journey is at an end. By using network mapping tools such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://nmap.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; along with digital wiretapping tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wireshark.org/&quot;&gt;Wireshark&lt;/a&gt; we can sense what happens on the far side of a network connection in much the same way as looking at the ripples on the surface of a river can tell us something about the shape of the riverbed.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Join us to explore strange new networks, to seek out new devices and new organizations, to boldly go where only packets have gone before!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-07-14-exploring-cyberspace-network-sniffing-and-scanning&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Come exploring with us as we show you how to map out interconnections between computers, trace packet routes across network gateways, and find information about network operators. In this workshop all about the voyages of frames, packets, and segments, we use tools like nmap to send probes into cyberspace and tap into the wire with Wireshark to understand how they function.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.exploring-cyberspace-network-sniffing-and-scanning.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.exploring-cyberspace-network-sniffing-and-scanning.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Free Guided Tour of Tech Learning Collective Foundations</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/event-2020-07-12-free-guided-tour-of-tech-learning-collective-foundations" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Free Guided Tour of Tech Learning Collective Foundations" /><published>2020-07-12T17:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-12T17:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/event-2020-07-12-free-guided-tour-of-tech-learning-collective-foundations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/event-2020-07-12-free-guided-tour-of-tech-learning-collective-foundations">&lt;p&gt;Just getting started learning computer technologies? Join Tech Learning Collective instructors for this free, guided tour of the Tech Learning Collective Foundations curriculum. These self-paced courses and practice labs are great for jump-starting your learning as they introduce you to the most important foundations of Tech Learning Collective course material, such as command line basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;We are asking for a $10 suggested &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;donation&lt;/a&gt; if you can afford it. Help support our incredible teachers and expert support teams! No one will be turned away for lack of funds.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot;&gt;Click here to support Tech Learning Collective with your donation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;form action=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;cmd&quot; value=&quot;_s-xclick&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;hosted_button_id&quot; value=&quot;PW4TUNMA53J3J&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_donate_LG.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; name=&quot;submit&quot; alt=&quot;Donate with PayPal&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or scan or click this QR code to donate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot; style=&quot;display: block; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/qr-code.donate.paypal.png&quot; alt=&quot;QR code for PayPal donation.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for your support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our online events, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gobrunch.com/events/106620&quot;&gt;CLICK HERE TO JOIN THE EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Just getting started learning computer technologies? Join Tech Learning Collective instructors for this free, guided tour of the Tech Learning Collective Foundations curriculum. These self-paced courses and practice labs are great for jump-starting your learning as they introduce you to the most important foundations of Tech Learning Collective course material, such as command line basics.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.generic.tech-learning-collective.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.generic.tech-learning-collective.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing with Blue Fire: Shell Scripting for Beginners</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-11-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing with Blue Fire: Shell Scripting for Beginners" /><published>2020-07-11T16:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-11T16:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-11-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-11-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to inscribe your thoughts, dreams, and desires into your computer and take your command line skills to the next level by learning how to write simple programs called shell scripts. In a way, invoking commands one at a time is like writing a program interactively, whereas writing a script inscribes that knowledge into a more permanent form. By learning how to turn commands into simple scripted programs, you can unlock the almost magical potential of your computer and more easily share that potential with others to whom you distribute your scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At their core, digital computers are very complex writing instruments. Like pen and paper, they allow us to record our thoughts, dreams, and desires for later review. Unlike pen and paper, they allow us to do this at the speed of electricity and at a scale never before imagined possible, and their ability to directly manipulate the physical world through servomotors, industrial control systems, biomedical devices, and other robotic prosthesis means they can potentially supercharge every facet of our humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When a system administrator or programmer uses a computer, they often issue instructions one by one using a special-purpose, text-only interface called a &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/&quot;&gt;command line&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Individually, these instructions are called &lt;em&gt;invocations&lt;/em&gt;. (Yes, that’s their technical term!) In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll learn how to write whole spells, rituals, or (sacred) texts called &lt;em&gt;shell scripts&lt;/em&gt; to inscribe your own thoughts, dreams, and desires in the electrified silicon and minerals of your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;By saving your scripts in files, you can invoke arbitrarily complex routines to reproduce tasks or automate complex procedures with a single command. Writing scripts also makes it possible to share what you can do with others and, as such, are one the simplest forms of computer program that you can write and distribute. Come learn how the magic of digital inscription can help you do your work, and increase your power to accomplish your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-07-11-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to inscribe your thoughts, dreams, and desires into your computer and take your command line skills to the next level by learning how to write simple programs called shell scripts. In a way, invoking commands one at a time is like writing a program interactively, whereas writing a script inscribes that knowledge into a more permanent form. By learning how to turn commands into simple scripted programs, you can unlock the almost magical potential of your computer and more easily share that potential with others to whom you distribute your scripts.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Digital Defenses for the People: Practical Digital Security</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-10-digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Defenses for the People: Practical Digital Security" /><published>2020-07-10T16:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-10T16:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-10-digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-10-digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security">&lt;p&gt;This beginner-friendly introduction to digital safety will cut through the fear, uncertainty, and doubt generated by the frenetic news cycle and the latest Internet privacy listicle, and offer an opportunity to ask the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers your most pressing online privacy and digital security questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Learning how to stay safe online is on many people’s minds, but how do you start this process? With so many tools and suggestions from “experts,” how do you know which tool to use, when, and in what situation? Do you really need a VPN? (And what even is that?) What are the tools you really &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; use, and which tools aren’t worth it? Moreover, without being a cybersecurity expert yourself, how do you learn to sniff out the useful stuff from the placebos?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This beginner’s workshop taught by the &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective&lt;/a&gt;’s cybersecurity trainers offers &lt;a href=&quot;/about/persona-matrix/&quot;&gt;a simple framework&lt;/a&gt; anyone can use to understand what risks they might face and how to protect themselves from those risks. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Persona-based-training-matrix&quot;&gt;Developed and maintained by the Anarcho-Tech NYC Collective&lt;/a&gt;, an independent cybersecurity research group that provides digital security services to anti-fascist groups in New York City, this framework now forms the basis of many digital safety workshops. It is a simple three-by-three grid in which you can place both yourself and your online safety concerns by answering a few intuitive questions like “How likely is it that I will be targeted?” and “How many resources (money, people, etcetera) does my attacker have?”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Although &lt;a href=&quot;https://prism-break.org/en/&quot;&gt;there are many good and free tools available&lt;/a&gt;, most people only need to use a few basic ones: a secure messaging application (like &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Signal-and-Surveillance-How-to-Exercise-Digital-Civil-Liberties-in-a-Surveillance-State&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt;), a password manager (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://keepass.info/&quot;&gt;KeePass&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://lastpass.com/&quot;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt;), and a few of the built-in features of their existing computers, like the full-disk encryption software available for free on every modern laptop and smartphone. This short, calming introduction to digital safety cuts through the fear, uncertainty, and doubt generated by the frenetic news cycle and the latest Internet privacy listicle. You’ll leave this workshop with a security plan in place, and a much clearer picture of the first few steps you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; take to protect yourself and your information both online and offline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-07-10-digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">This beginner-friendly introduction to digital safety will cut through the fear, uncertainty, and doubt generated by the frenetic news cycle and the latest Internet privacy listicle, and offer an opportunity to ask the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers your most pressing online privacy and digital security questions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Faster Than Light: Getting Started with Configuration Management</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-08-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Faster Than Light: Getting Started with Configuration Management" /><published>2020-07-08T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-08T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-08-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-08-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to beat back configuration drift on your servers by leveraging automation tools like Ansible in this deep dive workshop demonstrating modern DevOps practices for deploying, maintaining, and auditing compute clusters. Whether for a Web application, big data processing, or other project, you need to turn old-school runbooks into computerized playbooks that can execute Standard Operating Procedures quickly and reliably so you can deploy complex systems simply and predictably. Come learn about key concepts like idempotence and change control, and learn how giant corporations implement security principles like RBAC, all using free and open source software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today, all but the most trivial of computer systems rely on an interdependent set of servers working in concert. You don’t just have one server, you have a group of them. Commonly called a &lt;em&gt;cluster&lt;/em&gt;, these servers need to be managed as a group, ensuring that their software configurations, security patches, and installed packages are deployed, maintained, and eventually updated or retired in a predictable way.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this deep dive workshop, we’ll set up our own small cluster and use &lt;a href=&quot;https://ansible.com/&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt;, which is an agentless, cross-platform, enterprise-grade, free software &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Configuration_management&quot;&gt;Configuration Management (CM)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Automate-All-the-Things-Infrastructure-as-Code-Primer&quot;&gt;Infrastructure as Code (IaC)&lt;/a&gt; framework used by giant corporations like IBM and Cisco, to turn old-school operator runbooks into computerized playbooks that can be executed quickly and easily even by novice operators. Through several hands-on exercises, you’ll learn about the entire CM lifecycle from planning through auditing so that you understand critical CM concepts like idempotence, change control, and more, which are common to all CM systems including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chef.io/configuration-management/&quot;&gt;Chef&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://puppet.com/use-cases/configuration-management/&quot;&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.saltstack.com/en/latest/topics/states/&quot;&gt;Salt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Along the way, you’ll be exposed to key concepts such as &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Ship-Shape-Computing-Working-with-Containers-and-Containzerizing-Digital-Workloads&quot;&gt;containerization&lt;/a&gt; through Ansible’s support for automating container builds, &lt;a href=&quot;/con&quot;&gt;Role-Based Access Control (RBAC)&lt;/a&gt; via Ansible’s AWX Project, and more. By adopting configuration management workflows with tools like Ansible, you can reduce operator errors, and beat back configuration drift on any long-lived infrastructure components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-07-08-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to beat back configuration drift on your servers by leveraging automation tools like Ansible in this deep dive workshop demonstrating modern DevOps practices for deploying, maintaining, and auditing compute clusters. Whether for a Web application, big data processing, or other project, you need to turn old-school runbooks into computerized playbooks that can execute Standard Operating Procedures quickly and reliably so you can deploy complex systems simply and predictably. Come learn about key concepts like idempotence and change control, and learn how giant corporations implement security principles like RBAC, all using free and open source software.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Signal and Surveillance: How to Exercise Digital Civil Liberties in a Surveillance State</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-03-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Signal and Surveillance: How to Exercise Digital Civil Liberties in a Surveillance State" /><published>2020-07-03T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-03T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-03-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-03-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state">&lt;p&gt;This introductory cybersecurity workshop will show you why Signal, a free, secure, private message app is simple enough to schedule drinks with, yet secure enough to use for planning a protest. As dragnet surveillance practices are legalized at alarming speed, there has never been a more important time to flex your digital civil liberties muscle than right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whether you’re an individual chatting with friends or an organizer planning a political action, all effective coordination depends on safe and reliable communication. Lacking integrity for our communications dooms any effort from the outset, whether mundane or revolutionary. As dragnet surveillance practices are legalized at alarming speed and continue to be fueled by a dramatic expansion of the law enforcement and private defense contractor economies, there has never been a more important time to flex your digital civil liberties muscle than right now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; is the name of a Free Software, secure, private message application built on a cryptographic protocol of the same name. Formerly known as the Axolotl Ratchet or, more commonly, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Double_Ratchet_Algorithm&quot;&gt;Double-Ratchet Algorithm&lt;/a&gt;, its features are robust enough for the revolutionary activist (i.e., end-to-end encryption, message authentication, plausible deniability or message repudiation, perfect forward secrecy, and more) and yet simple enough to use as a drop-in replacement for your existing text messaging application. Signal also sports Skype-like voice and video calling, location- and file-sharing features, and even iMessage-style large font emojis!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you’ve never heard of Signal before, now’s the time to switch. If you think you already know how to use Signal, let us show you some pro-tips (trusted third-party Safety Number verification, disappearing messages, registering Signal accounts with pseudonymous phone numbers, inactivity lock-outs, and Signal relay server IP address protection). This introductory cybersecurity workshop will show you why Signal is simple enough to schedule drinks at the bar with, yet secure enough to use for planning a protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-07-03-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">This introductory cybersecurity workshop will show you why Signal, a free, secure, private message app is simple enough to schedule drinks with, yet secure enough to use for planning a protest. As dragnet surveillance practices are legalized at alarming speed, there has never been a more important time to flex your digital civil liberties muscle than right now.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">File Sharing for Fun and Profit: How BitTorrent Works and What You Can Do With It</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-01-file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="File Sharing for Fun and Profit: How BitTorrent Works and What You Can Do With It" /><published>2020-07-01T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-01T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-01-file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/07/workshop-2020-07-01-file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it">&lt;p&gt;BitTorrent, the wildly popular but often maligned file sharing protocol, is now being used in everything from (legal!) video streaming sites to corporate software update servers, but you wouldn’t know that if you only listened to Big Media groups like the RIAA. In this beginner-friendly workshop, we’ll bust BitTorrent myths and set the record straight about what “torrenting” actually is, how it works, and what you can do with it. You’ll see how next generation “decentralized” Web applications are making use of the technology, how companies like Facebook and Blizzard, Inc. use it every day, how to make your own “torrents” to share files of your own, and how and why some people take protective measures to torrent more privately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you’ve heard anything about “downloading free movies on the Internet,” you probably heard of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BitTorrent&quot;&gt;BitTorrent&lt;/a&gt; or its more colloquial synonym, “torrents.” You have also probably heard of companies threatening BitTorrent users with Internet service bans, financial penalties, and even lawsuits for “stealing intellectual property.“ Through expensive and coordinated disinformation campaigns, companies like Disney and other “Big Content” media conglomerates represented by special interest groups like the Record Industry Association of America (RIAA) and the Motion Picture Association of America (MPAA) have linked BitTorrent with music and movie piracy in the public mind. They continue to try convincing people that BitTorrent is hard, immoral, and unsafe to use, but the reality is far less one-sided.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BitTorrent&lt;/em&gt; refers to a file transfer technology that has been around since 2001 and is designed to make it easy for you to more quickly share very large files across a computer network, even if your computer lacked a high-speed Internet connection. It worked so well that by the end of 2013 there were more than a quarter billion individual BitTorrent users on the Internet. While the media painted this as an epidemic of criminal behavior, most BitTorrent uses were and still are both legal and mundane. Moreover, the heaviest BitTorrent users were actually companies who built the technology into their own products, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.howtogeek.com/141257/htg-explains-how-does-bittorrent-work/&quot;&gt;Blizzard, Inc. (the World of WarCraft company), who used BitTorrent to deliver updates of its game software to players&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today, BitTorrent is still one of the most popular, cost-efficient, and speediest large-file transfer technologies available to both individuals and multinational corporations alike. Cash-strapped Free Software projects such as GNU/Linux distributions use BitTorrent to distribute their installation packages in order to reduce their monthly bandwidth bills, a whole new category of “decentralized Web” applications like &lt;a href=&quot;https://zeronet.io/&quot;&gt;ZeroNet&lt;/a&gt; are using BitTorrent under the hood to make Web publishing easier and more censorship-resistant than ever before, and traditional Web sites with large bandwidth requirements like video streaming sites (e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinpeertube.org/en/&quot;&gt;PeerTube&lt;/a&gt;) are increasingly adopting a newer variant called &lt;a href=&quot;https://webtorrent.io/faq&quot;&gt;WebTorrent&lt;/a&gt; to improve download speeds and interoperate with the massive existing BitTorrent network.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner-friendly workshop, we’ll bust BitTorrent myths and set the record straight about what “torrenting” actually is, how it works, and what you can do with it. Learn how to find, download, and even create your own torrents so you can share files with friends and colleagues regardless of network obstacles like firewalls or NAT routers. Bring a laptop and you’ll be able to participate in a (legal and safe!) BitTorrent “swarm.” We’ll also discuss the implications of using BitTorrent for less-than-legal ends, and demonstrate steps you can take to improve your privacy such as enabling BitTorrent encryption, connecting to trackers through public proxies, and building private &lt;a href=&quot;https://seedboxgui.de/&quot;&gt;seedboxes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-07-01-file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">BitTorrent, the wildly popular but often maligned file sharing protocol, is now being used in everything from (legal!) video streaming sites to corporate software update servers, but you wouldn’t know that if you only listened to Big Media groups like the RIAA. In this beginner-friendly workshop, we’ll bust BitTorrent myths and set the record straight about what “torrenting” actually is, how it works, and what you can do with it. You’ll see how next generation “decentralized” Web applications are making use of the technology, how companies like Facebook and Blizzard, Inc. use it every day, how to make your own “torrents” to share files of your own, and how and why some people take protective measures to torrent more privately.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Taming Daemons: System Administration and Operation Basics</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/06/workshop-2020-06-29-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taming Daemons: System Administration and Operation Basics" /><published>2020-06-29T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-29T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/06/workshop-2020-06-29-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/06/workshop-2020-06-29-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics">&lt;p&gt;Most individuals with access to a computer system have more power today than ever before, but rarely do they make use of it or even know how much power they truly have. In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll begin learning how to “speak with the machines.” By learning to communicate more expressively with the digital devices that are increasingly responsible for mediating contemporary society, you’ll gain the power to effectively and materially change your relationship not only with your laptop, but with global systems of law, finance, and even art, literature, and philosophy governing today’s world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How much good does a powerful tool do for you if you don’t know how to use it well? How much more capable would you be if you mastered all the tools available to you? It might sound ridiculous, but failing to learn the practicalities of computer system operation basics is arguably the most common mistake people in the fast-paced tech scene make.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Modern computers are power tools, and behind each one of them is a human operator, or “system administrator,” responsible for configuring and maintaining that computer. If you have a personal computer such as a laptop or smartphone, then you are already a system administrator whether you realize it or not! Making sure the apps you want to use are installed and up to date, managing the amount of free space you have for your photos, and connecting or disconnecting from the Internet are all examples of simple system administration tasks that you probably already take on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner’s workshop, we’ll start by exploring what happens inside your computer when you take every-day tasks like open a Web browser or save files, and then dive down the rabbit hole to meet the special class of programs that make it possible for all your other programs to work. Called &lt;em&gt;daemons&lt;/em&gt;, short for Disk Access and Execution Monitors, they make up the world of Operating System services, signals, sockets, and more under the hood of your desktop environment. By the end of this workshop, you’ll have a far deeper understanding of how to care for your computer, as well as the ability to understand any new tools or services you encounter a whole lot faster than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-06-29-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Most individuals with access to a computer system have more power today than ever before, but rarely do they make use of it or even know how much power they truly have. In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll begin learning how to “speak with the machines.” By learning to communicate more expressively with the digital devices that are increasingly responsible for mediating contemporary society, you’ll gain the power to effectively and materially change your relationship not only with your laptop, but with global systems of law, finance, and even art, literature, and philosophy governing today’s world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>