<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2022-06-21T14:32:25-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective | Events</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">Tor: What is it Good For? (Absolutely Everything!)</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/workshop-2022-06-05-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tor: What is it Good For? (Absolutely Everything!)" /><published>2022-06-05T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-05T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/workshop-2022-06-05-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/workshop-2022-06-05-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything">&lt;p&gt;Come learn how the free Tor Web Browser can be your gateway to the Dark Web while simultaneously keeping you safer and your personal info more private as you browse web sites big and small. In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From illegal online drug stores like Silk Road to DDoS botnet command and control headquarters, media attention has long painted “the Dark Web” as though nothing good can come of it. But learn just a little bit more about how Tor and “hidden services” work and you’ll find a treasure trove of valuable possibilities for day-to-day Internet use. The same technology that can hide the location of a drug ring can also serve as a free VPN-like service to protect your privacy while you browse the Internet, make censored websites available again, and even let you host your own Internet services for free, all without opening a single port on your firewall!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool. They’ll demonstrate numerous Tor features such as Tor authentication, target service load balancing, and NAT-punching. In the process, you’ll finally understand—on a technical level—what the “Dark Web” actually is and how it works. Bring a laptop to class, and you’ll leave having run your own Dark Web site. This class is for everyone; whether you’re a veteran black hat or a timid newbie, this class will shine a light on the Dark Web once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-06-05-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Come learn how the free Tor Web Browser can be your gateway to the Dark Web while simultaneously keeping you safer and your personal info more private as you browse web sites big and small. In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Faster Than Light: Getting Started with Configuration Management</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/workshop-2022-06-04-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Faster Than Light: Getting Started with Configuration Management" /><published>2022-06-04T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-04T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/workshop-2022-06-04-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/workshop-2022-06-04-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to beat back configuration drift on your servers by leveraging automation tools like Ansible in this deep dive workshop demonstrating modern DevOps practices for deploying, maintaining, and auditing compute clusters. Whether for a Web application, big data processing, or other project, you need to turn old-school runbooks into computerized playbooks that can execute Standard Operating Procedures quickly and reliably so you can deploy complex systems simply and predictably. Come learn about key concepts like idempotence and change control, and learn how giant corporations implement security principles like RBAC, all using free and open source software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today, all but the most trivial of computer systems rely on an interdependent set of servers working in concert. You don’t just have one server, you have a group of them. Commonly called a &lt;em&gt;cluster&lt;/em&gt;, these servers need to be managed as a group, ensuring that their software configurations, security patches, and installed packages are deployed, maintained, and eventually updated or retired in a predictable way.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this deep dive workshop, we’ll set up our own small cluster and use &lt;a href=&quot;https://ansible.com/&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt;, which is an agentless, cross-platform, enterprise-grade, free software &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Configuration_management&quot;&gt;Configuration Management (CM)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Automate-All-the-Things-Infrastructure-as-Code-Primer&quot;&gt;Infrastructure as Code (IaC)&lt;/a&gt; framework used by giant corporations like IBM and Cisco, to turn old-school operator runbooks into computerized playbooks that can be executed quickly and easily even by novice operators. Through several hands-on exercises, you’ll learn about the entire CM lifecycle from planning through auditing so that you understand critical CM concepts like idempotence, change control, and more, which are common to all CM systems including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chef.io/configuration-management/&quot;&gt;Chef&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://puppet.com/use-cases/configuration-management/&quot;&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.saltstack.com/en/latest/topics/states/&quot;&gt;Salt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Along the way, you’ll be exposed to key concepts such as &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Ship-Shape-Computing-Working-with-Containers-and-Containzerizing-Digital-Workloads&quot;&gt;containerization&lt;/a&gt; through Ansible’s support for automating container builds, &lt;a href=&quot;/con&quot;&gt;Role-Based Access Control (RBAC)&lt;/a&gt; via Ansible’s AWX Project, and more. By adopting configuration management workflows with tools like Ansible, you can reduce operator errors, and beat back configuration drift on any long-lived infrastructure components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-06-04-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to beat back configuration drift on your servers by leveraging automation tools like Ansible in this deep dive workshop demonstrating modern DevOps practices for deploying, maintaining, and auditing compute clusters. Whether for a Web application, big data processing, or other project, you need to turn old-school runbooks into computerized playbooks that can execute Standard Operating Procedures quickly and reliably so you can deploy complex systems simply and predictably. Come learn about key concepts like idempotence and change control, and learn how giant corporations implement security principles like RBAC, all using free and open source software.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">NOT Worldwide: NYC Regional Launch</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/event-2022-06-02-not-worldwide-nyc-regional-launch" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NOT Worldwide: NYC Regional Launch" /><published>2022-06-02T22:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-02T22:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/event-2022-06-02-not-worldwide-nyc-regional-launch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/event-2022-06-02-not-worldwide-nyc-regional-launch">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://notworldwide.org/&quot;&gt;New Order Technoism&lt;/a&gt; and friends of Tech Learning Collective invite you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.liminalspace.nyc/&quot;&gt;Liminal Space&lt;/a&gt; to experience the birth of a new machine, one made in and for a new world. Among other incredible performers, this event features DJ Niyah West, a semi-regular fixture at our own Hex90 queer hacker parties, along with livecoded visuals by Char Stiles, also a Hex90 favorite, who will be joined by Livecode.NYC star Indira! More tunes by BABES the DJ, a drag performance by God Complex, and you-have-to-see-it-to-believe-it installations by Ru Electra round out the lineup for this one of a kind enigmatic experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come for the shows, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notworldwide.org/how-is-it&quot;&gt;buy a candle and pray with us&lt;/a&gt;, or read the DOOM scrolls while basking in the healing light of retro tech diagnostic testing offered by Anya Volz that may repair—or worsen—all your corruptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Have you wasted years of your life in service of a capitalist machine?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;There is a new machine taking shape, ready to build a new world.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If your existence is passive, you are an existential risk.&lt;br /&gt;
To exist in the future through cognizance is limitless.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Find purpose, submit yourself to something greater.&lt;br /&gt;
Consider your second entropy.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Compromise for a better VOID!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Thurs June 2nd // 10pm&lt;br /&gt;
Liminal Space&lt;br /&gt;
1080 Wyckoff Ave.&lt;br /&gt;
((enter through The Deep End))&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Queers + Femmes = $20 adv // $25 door&lt;br /&gt;
Cis + Str8ts = $25 adv // $30 door&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;~This is an inclusive space~&lt;br /&gt;
~This venue has gender neutral restrooms~&lt;br /&gt;
~No one will be turned away for lack of funds, email NewOrderTechnoism@gmail.com~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-dj-niyah-west&quot;&gt;About DJ Niyah West&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Niyah West (she/they) is a DJ, music curator and digital artist based in New York City. From the living rooms of dear friends to the night clubs, Niyah made her professional debut just this year during pride month. Thus, making her a bright newcomer in the queer DJ scene. She has amplified parties and dancefloors all over the boroughs, some recently including MEOW NYC, Gayjoy &amp;amp; a residency at Kind Regards in the Lower East Side. She’s also a resident of Brooklyn based queer DJ collective XOXA NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-livecodenyc&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://livecode.nyc/&quot;&gt;LiveCode.NYC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are primarily a meetup group who gets together to discuss programming in real time. We view live coding as a methodology and not medium specific. Some of our members code graphics, games, VR and a handful live code music. Many languages are used within the group, without one being prioritised. Many of us are artists. Sometimes we run events. The core of what we do is share live coding, whether discussing types at our meetups or teaching a system one of us built. We hope to continue to find ways in which we can do this, as a collective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-char-stiles&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;http://charstiles.com/&quot;&gt;Char Stiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Char Stiles is an artist, educator and programmer based in Brooklyn, NY. She works creatively in the lower levels of computational systems to bring to light how computers work. Char works and collaborates across mediums such as interactive installation, video, performance and web. She is a part of the Livecode.nyc collective, where she organizes shows, and livecodes music and visuals.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">New Order Technoism and friends of Tech Learning Collective invite you to Liminal Space to experience the birth of a new machine, one made in and for a new world. Among other incredible performers, this event features DJ Niyah West, a semi-regular fixture at our own Hex90 queer hacker parties, along with livecoded visuals by Char Stiles, also a Hex90 favorite, who will be joined by Livecode.NYC star Indira! More tunes by BABES the DJ, a drag performance by God Complex, and you-have-to-see-it-to-believe-it installations by Ru Electra round out the lineup for this one of a kind enigmatic experience.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.2022-06-02.not-worldwide-nyc-regional-launch.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.2022-06-02.not-worldwide-nyc-regional-launch.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Securing Our Servers: Basic Network Operations for Autonomous Communities</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-29-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Securing Our Servers: Basic Network Operations for Autonomous Communities" /><published>2022-05-29T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-29T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-29-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-29-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities">&lt;p&gt;Learn the basics of securing digital infrastructure by taking a deep-dive into the Secure Shell (SSH) protocol, a fundamental component of safe administrative access to remote servers. Regardless of whether you rely on one or many thousands of servers to power your daily operations, securely managing those machines is essential to the success of your efforts. This intermediate-level workshop shows you how to securely set up, access, and debug connection issues over the SSH protocol so that you’ll be ready to operate self-hosted digital infrastructure for yourself, friends, or comrades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every app you use—from messengers like &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; or WhatsApp to blogs and websites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and even other coordination tools like digital calendars and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Our-Streets,-Our-Maps-Introduction-to-OpenStreetMap&quot;&gt;online maps&lt;/a&gt;—relies on a computer called a server. Whether that computer is one in your hand (your smartphone), or a computer somewhere across the Internet (“in the cloud”), no meaningful digital communication happens without servers offering services, somewhere. So, do you know where &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; servers are? If not, you can’t know how safe your data is!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When you don’t have a clear map of how your messages and other data gets from here to there, you might be at risk of someone listening in on your conversations. When you rely on services that you don’t own yourself for critical day-to-day operations (like Google Calendar, or Facebook…) you risk losing access to those capabilities by having your account banned, even by mistake. Regardless of your specific situation, knowing more about the digital servers that are serving you is a vital first step for supporting communities or companies large and small.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This intermediate-level workshop combines various topics from the &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/sys101.html&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s System Administration&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/net101.html&quot;&gt;Networking&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/sec101.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; courses to offer an intensive crash course in secure server setup, monitoring, and maintenance. By taking a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/blob/master/train-the-trainers/practice-labs/introduction-to-securing-virtualized-secure-shell-servers/README.md&quot;&gt;deep dive into the SSH protocol&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll learn how to set up remote administrative access to a server in a safe way, and you’ll be exposed to the potential risks of network eavesdroppers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man-in-the-middle_attack&quot;&gt;Machine-in-the-Middle (MITM) attacks&lt;/a&gt;, and much more. By the end of this workshop, you’ll have a basic understanding of how to safely operate self-hosted digital infrastructures for yourself, your friends, and your comrades, as well as what first steps you need to take to keep intruders and enemies at bay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-05-29-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn the basics of securing digital infrastructure by taking a deep-dive into the Secure Shell (SSH) protocol, a fundamental component of safe administrative access to remote servers. Regardless of whether you rely on one or many thousands of servers to power your daily operations, securely managing those machines is essential to the success of your efforts. This intermediate-level workshop shows you how to securely set up, access, and debug connection issues over the SSH protocol so that you’ll be ready to operate self-hosted digital infrastructure for yourself, friends, or comrades.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Taming Daemons: System Administration and Operation Basics</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-28-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taming Daemons: System Administration and Operation Basics" /><published>2022-05-28T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-28T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-28-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-28-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics">&lt;p&gt;Most individuals with access to a computer system have more power today than ever before, but rarely do they make use of it or even know how much power they truly have. In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll begin learning how to “speak with the machines.” By learning to communicate more expressively with the digital devices that are increasingly responsible for mediating contemporary society, you’ll gain the power to effectively and materially change your relationship not only with your laptop, but with global systems of law, finance, and even art, literature, and philosophy governing today’s world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How much good does a powerful tool do for you if you don’t know how to use it well? How much more capable would you be if you mastered all the tools available to you? It might sound ridiculous, but failing to learn the practicalities of computer system operation basics is arguably the most common mistake people in the fast-paced tech scene make.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Modern computers are power tools, and behind each one of them is a human operator, or “system administrator,” responsible for configuring and maintaining that computer. If you have a personal computer such as a laptop or smartphone, then you are already a system administrator whether you realize it or not! Making sure the apps you want to use are installed and up to date, managing the amount of free space you have for your photos, and connecting or disconnecting from the Internet are all examples of simple system administration tasks that you probably already take on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner’s workshop, we’ll start by exploring what happens inside your computer when you take every-day tasks like open a Web browser or save files, and then dive down the rabbit hole to meet the special class of programs that make it possible for all your other programs to work. Called &lt;em&gt;daemons&lt;/em&gt;, short for Disk Access and Execution Monitors, they make up the world of Operating System services, signals, sockets, and more under the hood of your desktop environment. By the end of this workshop, you’ll have a far deeper understanding of how to care for your computer, as well as the ability to understand any new tools or services you encounter a whole lot faster than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-05-28-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Most individuals with access to a computer system have more power today than ever before, but rarely do they make use of it or even know how much power they truly have. In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll begin learning how to “speak with the machines.” By learning to communicate more expressively with the digital devices that are increasingly responsible for mediating contemporary society, you’ll gain the power to effectively and materially change your relationship not only with your laptop, but with global systems of law, finance, and even art, literature, and philosophy governing today’s world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guardians of the Watchtowers: Introduction to Service Monitoring and Observability</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-22-guardians-of-the-watchtowers-introduction-to-service-monitoring-and-observability" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guardians of the Watchtowers: Introduction to Service Monitoring and Observability" /><published>2022-05-22T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-22T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-22-guardians-of-the-watchtowers-introduction-to-service-monitoring-and-observability</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-22-guardians-of-the-watchtowers-introduction-to-service-monitoring-and-observability">&lt;p&gt;Knowing what’s happening on the computers you’re responsible for is a critical part of knowing how to care for and maintain any IT infrastructure. Learn how to automatically monitor and alert on operational issues such as resource exhaustion before they take down your servers and applications. In this workshop, you’ll learn about the “four golden signals” of observability, you’ll be introduced to time series databases and metrics collection with Prometheus, and you’ll learn how to create beautiful charts and graphs from that data with Grafana. Together, these free, industry-standard tools comprise the foundation of all modern and cloud-native IT monitoring stacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every computer program needs certain resources to operate well, like memory and disk space and CPU cycles. This is true both for simple programs on your laptop and also for complex, cloud-native systems like those that run in massive compute clusters in public cloud or on-premises datacenters. On a single computer, tools like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/guide/activity-monitor/welcome/mac&quot;&gt;Activity Monitor&lt;/a&gt; on macOS or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.howtogeek.com/405806/windows-task-manager-the-complete-guide/&quot;&gt;Task Manager&lt;/a&gt; on Windows can report which applications are taking up what amount of specific resources on your computer in near real-time, helping you keep watch over your digital domain. When you need to monitor whole fleets of servers, though, you need tools that can scrape or collect the same information from those servers over a network.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In decades past, IT teams were often limited to static data sets to perform tasks like asset tracking. As applications grew more complex, performance and reliability metrics became increasingly important, so instrumentation, profiling, and visualization tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/using-api/health-checks/&quot;&gt;dedicated health and readiness checks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/docs/Tools/Performance/Flame_Chart&quot;&gt;flame charts&lt;/a&gt; were developed to help engineers figure out how to both optimize the code they wrote and how to integrate it with other systems more seamlessly. Today, specialized frameworks and burgeoning standards like &lt;a href=&quot;https://opentelemetry.io/&quot;&gt;OpenTelemetry&lt;/a&gt; are designed to give system operators more visibility into both the current and historical usage trends and patterns of the resources their services need to run well. Equipped with this information, they can make better capacity planning decisions for the future or even help identify anomalous events like security breaches, bugs in code, and other subtle issues that might be hard or impossible to track down otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop, you’ll be introduced to the concepts and practices of observability for infrastructure at any level of scale. You’ll learn about the “four golden signals”—latency, traffic, errors, and saturation—and why they matter. Like the four Quarters that are called to cast a magical circle, each golden signal has a particular focus and almost elemental meaning. You’ll learn how to install and configure &lt;a href=&quot;https://prometheus.io/&quot;&gt;Prometheus&lt;/a&gt;, the open, industry-standard metrics collection solution on which many commercial offerings are based, along with its accompanying components like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prometheus.io/docs/alerting/latest/alertmanager/&quot;&gt;Alertmanager&lt;/a&gt;, metric &lt;a href=&quot;https://prometheus.io/docs/instrumenting/exporters/&quot;&gt;exporters&lt;/a&gt;, and supplemental software like &lt;a href=&quot;https://grafana.com/&quot;&gt;Grafana&lt;/a&gt; that can query Prometheus’s time series database to reveal trends, patterns, or anomalies in your systems’ stability over time. Finally, to make sense of all this data, you’ll get an introduction to &lt;a href=&quot;https://prometheus.io/docs/prometheus/latest/querying/basics/&quot;&gt;PromQL&lt;/a&gt;, the purpose-built Prometheus Query Language used for everything from triggering alerts to making custom queries so you’ll always be able to know exactly what’s going on in your infrastructure when you need to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-05-22-guardians-of-the-watchtowers-introduction-to-service-monitoring-and-observability&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Knowing what’s happening on the computers you’re responsible for is a critical part of knowing how to care for and maintain any IT infrastructure. Learn how to automatically monitor and alert on operational issues such as resource exhaustion before they take down your servers and applications. In this workshop, you’ll learn about the “four golden signals” of observability, you’ll be introduced to time series databases and metrics collection with Prometheus, and you’ll learn how to create beautiful charts and graphs from that data with Grafana. Together, these free, industry-standard tools comprise the foundation of all modern and cloud-native IT monitoring stacks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.guardians-of-the-watchtowers-introduction-to-service-monitoring-and-observability.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.guardians-of-the-watchtowers-introduction-to-service-monitoring-and-observability.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Digital Defenses for the People: Practical Digital Security</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-21-digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Defenses for the People: Practical Digital Security" /><published>2022-05-21T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-21T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-21-digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-21-digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security">&lt;p&gt;This beginner-friendly introduction to digital safety will cut through the fear, uncertainty, and doubt generated by the frenetic news cycle and the latest Internet privacy listicle, and offer an opportunity to ask your most pressing online privacy and digital security questions. By learning about foundational frameworks that cybersecurity professionals use to assess risk and safety such as the CIA triad and the three states of data, you’ll build an understanding of information security from first principles to advanced techniques. By the end of this workshop, you will be able to apply these building blocks to anything and everything you do online, or in the streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Learning how to stay safe online is on many people’s minds, but how do you start this process? With so many tools and suggestions from “experts,” how do you know which tool to use, when, and in what situation? Do you really need a VPN? (And what even is that?) What are the tools you really &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; use, and which tools aren’t worth it? Moreover, without being a cybersecurity expert yourself, how do you learn to sniff out the useful stuff from the placebos?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This beginner’s workshop taught by the &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective&lt;/a&gt;’s cybersecurity trainers offers &lt;a href=&quot;/about/persona-matrix/&quot;&gt;a simple framework&lt;/a&gt; anyone can use to understand what risks they might face and how to protect themselves from those risks. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Persona-based-training-matrix&quot;&gt;Developed and maintained by the Anarcho-Tech NYC Collective&lt;/a&gt;, an independent cybersecurity research group that provides digital security services to anti-fascist groups in New York City, this framework now forms the basis of many digital safety workshops. It is a simple three-by-three grid in which you can place both yourself and your online safety concerns by answering a few intuitive questions like “How likely is it that I will be targeted?” and “How many resources (money, people, etcetera) does my attacker have?”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Although &lt;a href=&quot;https://prism-break.org/en/&quot;&gt;there are many good and free tools available&lt;/a&gt;, most people only need to use a few basic ones: a secure messaging application (like &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Signal-and-Surveillance-How-to-Exercise-Digital-Civil-Liberties-in-a-Surveillance-State&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt;), a password manager (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://keepass.info/&quot;&gt;KeePass&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitwarden.com/&quot;&gt;Bitwarden&lt;/a&gt;, and a few of the built-in features of their existing computers, like the full-disk encryption software available for free on every modern laptop and smartphone. This short, calming introduction to digital safety cuts through the fear, uncertainty, and doubt generated by the frenetic news cycle and the latest Internet privacy listicle. You’ll leave this workshop with a security plan in place, and a much clearer picture of the first few steps you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; take to protect yourself and your information both online and offline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-05-21-digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">This beginner-friendly introduction to digital safety will cut through the fear, uncertainty, and doubt generated by the frenetic news cycle and the latest Internet privacy listicle, and offer an opportunity to ask your most pressing online privacy and digital security questions. By learning about foundational frameworks that cybersecurity professionals use to assess risk and safety such as the CIA triad and the three states of data, you’ll build an understanding of information security from first principles to advanced techniques. By the end of this workshop, you will be able to apply these building blocks to anything and everything you do online, or in the streets.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting the Right Stuff: Introduction to Data Files, Spreadsheets, and Databases</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-15-getting-the-right-stuff-introduction-to-data-files-spreadsheets-and-databases" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting the Right Stuff: Introduction to Data Files, Spreadsheets, and Databases" /><published>2022-05-15T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-15-getting-the-right-stuff-introduction-to-data-files-spreadsheets-and-databases</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-15-getting-the-right-stuff-introduction-to-data-files-spreadsheets-and-databases">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to collect, generate, and manipulate data of all kinds so that you can make decisions and meet the challenges you’re facing. You’ll see how simple, text-based data files and command-line utilities have been and are still being used in all sorts of applications today, what spreadsheets have to offer, and how all these tools differ from Relational Database Management Systems (RDMSs) like MySQL/MariaDB, PostgreSQL, Oracle, or Microsoft SQL Server. This workshop will also touch on Web scraping, form building, mail merges, data cleaning, and other techniques you need to know to make automating the boring parts of your day possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If knowledge is power, what is knowledge? On a computer, knowledge comes from data. By collecting data relevant to the problem you’re trying to solve, you can scrutinize it in various different ways until you’re able to draw meaningful conclusions from the dataset; you turn data into information, and from that information you gain knowledge, which gives you power. But this is all much easier said than done, especially if you are not already familiar with how to work with digital data.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This workshop introduces you to the concepts and techniques you need to know to collect, generate, and manipulate digital information regardless of the specific application or problem domain you’re working in. Ever since the dawn of computing, data has been a central element in computer use. After all, what good is a computer without data to compute? Early databases took the form of stacks of physical punch cards. Later on, databases were created out of structured text files (and many of these still exist on your computer today, whether you realize it or not). With the advent of “personal” computing in the 1980’s, digital spreadsheets in applications like Lotus 1-2-3 brought enterprise automation solutions to the masses—or it would have, if more people had the opportunity to learn how to use these powerful tools.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today, massive datasets with billions or trillions of records are often stored in Relational Database Management Systems (RDMSs) and are accessed using specialized computer languages such as the Structured Query Language (SQL). These databases are thus the crown jewels of every company or organization conducting business online. Everything that matters to them gets stored in a database of some kind, from email subscriber lists, customer records, call logs, and purchase orders, to social media postings, blog comments, personal photos, and much more. Practice working with different kinds of data to learn the foundations relevant to all data exploration and transformation tasks in this introductory workshop that will help you ensure you can get the right stuff to construct successful solutions to any problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-05-15-getting-the-right-stuff-introduction-to-data-files-spreadsheets-and-databases&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to collect, generate, and manipulate data of all kinds so that you can make decisions and meet the challenges you’re facing. You’ll see how simple, text-based data files and command-line utilities have been and are still being used in all sorts of applications today, what spreadsheets have to offer, and how all these tools differ from Relational Database Management Systems (RDMSs) like MySQL/MariaDB, PostgreSQL, Oracle, or Microsoft SQL Server. This workshop will also touch on Web scraping, form building, mail merges, data cleaning, and other techniques you need to know to make automating the boring parts of your day possible.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.getting-the-right-stuff-introduction-to-data-files-spreadsheets-and-databases.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.getting-the-right-stuff-introduction-to-data-files-spreadsheets-and-databases.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Computer Language Foundations: Command Line Basics</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-14-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Computer Language Foundations: Command Line Basics" /><published>2022-05-14T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-14T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-14-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-14-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics">&lt;p&gt;You have read about people who can talk to machines. Maybe you imagined secret chambers, hidden away behind locked doors, with dark rooms basking in blue from electric fires. Some of these people seemed friendly, others scary, but all of them were powerful. How did they learn to communicate with their computers? This is your chance to learn the foundations of all computer languages, the command line, and actually begin to talk to a machine yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To be useful, every computer must offer some way for you to control it. Generically, the way you can control a computer is called a &lt;em&gt;user interface&lt;/em&gt; because it allows you (the user) to interact with (that is, “to interface with”) the computer system. Most people may already be familiar with &lt;em&gt;Graphical User Interfaces&lt;/em&gt; or GUIs, which are the buttons, windows, and other controls that you can point-and-click on, but this way of controlling a computer comes with severe limitations. Chief among these is the fact that you are limited to using only one tip of one finger on one of your hands (called your &lt;em&gt;pointer&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;mouse cursor&lt;/em&gt;) and, worse, you have no access to anything outside of your immediate reach. In a GUI, if you cannot see it or touch it with the mouse, you cannot manipulate it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is why almost all hackers, programmers, and system administrators prefer a Command Line Interface or CLI over the graphical options for many, if not most, of their day-to-day tasks. In a command-line, or “terminal,” you can use the complete expressive power of spoken language to control your computer. You can use symbolism and metaphor to express any idea that you have the words for. Moreover, you always have all the words you know at your disposal at any time, even if they refer to things that are far away or that you cannot currently see.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll learn how to access the command line interface of your computer, and you’ll learn the basic grammar of command line languages such as that provided by the ubiquitous Bash command interpreter. You’ll also be introduced to the basic set of utilities required to quickly accomplish tasks that require working with files and folders, processing text, and automating common workflows that would take dozens or even hundreds of clicks with a mouse to complete in a Graphical User Interface. By learning how to “speak” to your computer using a command language, you can save hours every day and take your first step toward using your computer the way the best hackers would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-05-14-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">You have read about people who can talk to machines. Maybe you imagined secret chambers, hidden away behind locked doors, with dark rooms basking in blue from electric fires. Some of these people seemed friendly, others scary, but all of them were powerful. How did they learn to communicate with their computers? This is your chance to learn the foundations of all computer languages, the command line, and actually begin to talk to a machine yourself.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hex90: Overflow</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/event-2022-05-07-hex90-overflow" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hex90: Overflow" /><published>2022-05-07T20:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-07T20:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/event-2022-05-07-hex90-overflow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/event-2022-05-07-hex90-overflow">&lt;p&gt;Queer hackers of the world, unite! Tech Learning Collective is excited to invite you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hex90.party/&quot;&gt;Hex90’s latest queer hacker salon, “Overflow,”&lt;/a&gt; hosted at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-overflow&quot;&gt;Wonderville, where you can buy tickets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-txt&quot;&gt;R  2022-05-07
FM HEX90
TO QUEER HACKERS OF THE WORLD

OVERFLOW (SECRET//NOFORN)

HEX90 — a queer hacker salon in NYC

Everything is circles.

The past becomes the present, the present becomes the future, and the future becomes the past again. The same water in the ocean rises to the sky before returning to the sea. Which memories fade and which are refreshed? What lies beyond the waterfall of time and space?

We are hackers, the witches, the wizards, the techno-sorceresses whose shapes shift within an infinite loop. We are the essence of the more.

Constraints do not restrain us. Limitations give us powers others cannot understand because they do not see beyond the overflow.

They store integers in finite fields. We use those integers as portals into their machines. They reduce gender to a binary. We stretch those roles to (re)create theaters of infinite expressive possibility. They &quot;build&quot; software. We write reality. They &quot;engineer&quot; services. We enchant souls. They &quot;command&quot; tools. We invoke demons.

Everything is circles.

info_

May 7, 2022 @ Wonderville
1186 Broadway, Brooklyn, NY 11221
8:30pm — 2:30am

~ this venue is accessible
~ this venue has gender-neutral restrooms
~ this venue has outdoor space

# dressing up is encouraged but not required

featuring_

~ music performances by
~~ DJ Niyah West (@niyahwest, XOXA)
~~ Soo Intoit (@iamsoointoit, CRITICAL HIT)
~ visuals &amp;amp; livecoding by gwenpri.me
~ indie games by Death By Audio Arcade
~ hacking demos &amp;amp; education by Tech Learning Collective
~ text adventure cybersecurity game by Shift-CTRL Space

BRING YOUR LAPTOP SO YOU CAN HACK WITH US!

In addition to music and visuals, the most unique addition of the Hex90 parties is a hyperlocal cybersecurity (hacking) themed text-adventure game that gave the party its name: Hex90. This game is played on your own laptop, not on a console or arcade cabinet at the venue, but is still only accessible when you are physically at the party venue itself. (Aside from a short &quot;trailer,&quot; the game is not available on the public Internet.)

After you connect to the party's Wi-Fi network, you can then connect to the Hex90 game server using your Web browser. But to solve the challenges, you must download and install real hacker tools and learn how to employ real hacking techniques to progress through game levels ranging from network reconnaissance, applied cryptography, and Web exploitation. You've never seen so many queers open so many terminals in one place while being so close to a dance floor, and there's no high quite like it.

We continuously add levels to the game, so expect new challenges at most parties. Moreover, we sometimes incorporate physical-world features of the venue, like padlocks you need to pick that are safeguarding access to secret passwords, QR codes stashed in unexpected places, unassuming but exposed Ethernet cabling that turns out not to be a mistake at all, and so on. At Hex90, the game controller is your computer and the game mechanic is the real world.

All of the tools, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) used to progress in the game levels are skills taught by and equipment used by Tech Learning Collective instructors in our twice-weekly online workshops. Visit TechLearningCollective.com for more information and to enroll.

#------------------#
# START HACKING AT #
#------------------#
https://hex90.party

#------------------#
# BUY TICKETS HERE #
#------------------#
https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-overflow

Advance cover:
$15.00 - str8t cismen
$10.00 - queers and femmes

At the door:
$20.00 - str8t cismen
$15.00 - queers and femmes

/**
* Hex90 is an inclusive event.
* Door staff is instructed to respect your self-identification.
*/

NOTICE:
This is an intentionally queer space. Consent and respect are not optional! Anyone acting shitty will be removed immediately without a refund. No amount of racism, queerphobia, transphobia, or sexism will be tolerated. This event is a celebration of queer hacking for queer hackers, not for Silicon Valley entrepreneurs, brogrammers, or BitCoin bros. Don't piss off the hackers. ;)

Hex90

###
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hex90.party/&quot;&gt;Start playing immediately and buy your ticket at the invitation site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-overflow&quot;&gt;$15 - General Admission&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-overflow&quot;&gt;$10 - Queers and Femmes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from the event without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-shift-ctrl-space&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://shiftctrl.space/&quot;&gt;Shift-CTRL Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are anti-(techno)capitalists, solarpunks, and radical technologists. Our ethics place us against “Adtech,” “Fintech,” and Silicon Valley. We believe technology is an intangible earth, with which we can and should have an earthly relationship. It is power that we can harness through holistic methods as individuals and cooperative networks for the empowerment of oneself and of one’s actual communities. Our approach stands in contrast to isolationism, sterility, and authoritarianism by being participatory, flexible, and adaptive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-xoxa&quot;&gt;About XOXA&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XOXA (pronounced ex-oh-ex-ay) is a Brooklyn based queer collective of DJs, artists and performers founded in 2017. Their mission is to provide a supportive platform for women and LGBTQ+ artists to perform while creating an intentional party space for women, non-binary and trans individuals. You can follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/xoxanyc&quot;&gt;@xoxanyc on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/xoxanyc&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; for more information on upcoming events and projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-dj-niyah-west&quot;&gt;About DJ Niyah West&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Niyah West (she/they) is a DJ, music curator and digital artist based in New York City. From the living rooms of dear friends to the night clubs, Niyah made her professional debut just this year during pride month. Thus, making her a bright newcomer in the queer DJ scene. She has amplified parties and dancefloors all over the boroughs, some recently including MEOW NYC, Gayjoy &amp;amp; a residency at Kind Regards in the Lower East Side. She’s also a resident of Brooklyn based queer DJ collective XOXA NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-livecodenyc&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://livecode.nyc/&quot;&gt;LiveCode.NYC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are primarily a meetup group who gets together to discuss programming in real time. We view live coding as a methodology and not medium specific. Some of our members code graphics, games, VR and a handful live code music. Many languages are used within the group, without one being prioritised. Many of us are artists. Sometimes we run events. The core of what we do is share live coding, whether discussing types at our meetups or teaching a system one of us built. We hope to continue to find ways in which we can do this, as a collective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-gwenprime&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://gwenpri.me/&quot;&gt;gwenpri.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gwenpri.me is a creative technologist, artist, and livecoder. She makes live visuals from videos, pictures, emoji, text, and more, then composites them using live code techniques. She enjoys finding arcane ways to put pixels on screens. Past sets have included touch designer patching, Lua DSLs, command line video editors, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-death-by-audio&quot;&gt;About Death By Audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deathbyaudioarcade.com/&quot;&gt;Death By Audio Arcade&lt;/a&gt; is a series of lovingly crafted local multiplayer arcade cabinets produced by local indie game developers. We are also a progressive, open community of like-minded artists, artisans, and enthusiasts. We host events at least once a month, in NYC and at events across the country, from SXSW to the Smithsonian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Queer hackers of the world, unite! Tech Learning Collective is excited to invite you to Hex90’s latest queer hacker salon, “Overflow,” hosted at Wonderville, where you can buy tickets.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.hex90.flyer.2022-05-07.960x540.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.hex90.flyer.2022-05-07.960x540.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>