<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2021-03-10T20:03:58-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective | Events</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">LibrePlanet 2021: Beyond ‘Learning to Code’</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-21-libreplanet-2021-beyond-learning-to-code" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LibrePlanet 2021: Beyond ‘Learning to Code’" /><published>2021-03-21T16:35:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-21T16:35:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-21-libreplanet-2021-beyond-learning-to-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-21-libreplanet-2021-beyond-learning-to-code">&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, March 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;, join Tech Learning Collective and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fsf.org/&quot;&gt;Free Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt; at the all-online LibrePlanet 2021 conference about software freedom, where we will be delivering our talk, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://libreplanet.org/2021/speakers/#4763&quot;&gt;Beyond ‘Learning to Code’: How Tech Learning Collective Merges IT Training with Emancipatory Political Action&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What good is a pen if the paper it touches can refuse to show its ink? What good is your app when your API key is revoked? Through metaphor and with a unique apprenticeship-based pedagogy, Tech Learning Collective (TLC) is empowering users by doing exactly what code boot camps and corporate-funded “learn to code” programs don’t: TLC tells students to ignore new Web frameworks and focus instead on the lowest layers of an IT stack like physical network and hardware storage devices. At TLC, infrastructure is the heart of a free software curriculum eschewing common rush-to-employment training paradigms in favor of Socratic classrooms where practicing Bash commands seamlessly meld with lectures about Gnostic influences on Ethernet, the relationship between Gregorian chants and bootloaders, and more. Come see why and how TLC’s holistic approach to IT education is creating communities of activist sysadmins out of people who wouldn’t otherwise have called themselves “techies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LibrePlanet is a conference about software freedom, happening March 20 through 21, 2021. The event is hosted by the Free Software Foundation (FSF), and brings together software developers, law and policy experts, activists, students, and computer users to learn skills, celebrate free software accomplishments, and face upcoming challenges. Newcomers are always welcome, and LibrePlanet 2021 will feature programming for all ages and experience levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;Tickets are required to attend the conference; please &lt;a href=&quot;https://u.fsf.org/lp21-sp&quot;&gt;register for LibrePlanet 2021&lt;/a&gt; in advance.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-free-software-foundation&quot;&gt;About the Free Software Foundation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Free Software Foundation (FSF) is a nonprofit with a worldwide mission to promote computer user freedom. We defend the rights of all software users.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">On Sunday, March 21st, join Tech Learning Collective and the Free Software Foundation at the all-online LibrePlanet 2021 conference about software freedom, where we will be delivering our talk, “Beyond ‘Learning to Code’: How Tech Learning Collective Merges IT Training with Emancipatory Political Action.”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://libreplanet.org/2021/assets/img/logo.svg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://libreplanet.org/2021/assets/img/logo.svg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Securing Our Servers: Basic Network Operations for Autonomous Communities</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-20-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Securing Our Servers: Basic Network Operations for Autonomous Communities" /><published>2021-03-20T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-20T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-20-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-20-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities">&lt;p&gt;Learn the basics of securing digital infrastructure by taking a deep-dive into the Secure Shell (SSH) protocol, a fundamental component of safe administrative access to remote servers. Regardless of whether you rely on one or many thousands of servers to power your daily operations, securely managing those machines is essential to the success of your efforts. This intermediate-level workshop shows you how to securely set up, access, and debug connection issues over the SSH protocol so that you’ll be ready to operate self-hosted digital infrastructure for yourself, friends, or comrades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every app you use—from messengers like &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; or WhatsApp to blogs and websites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and even other coordination tools like digital calendars and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Our-Streets,-Our-Maps-Introduction-to-OpenStreetMap&quot;&gt;online maps&lt;/a&gt;—relies on a computer called a server. Whether that computer is one in your hand (your smartphone), or a computer somewhere across the Internet (“in the cloud”), no meaningful digital communication happens without servers offering services, somewhere. So, do you know where &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; servers are? If not, you can’t know how safe your data is!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When you don’t have a clear map of how your messages and other data gets from here to there, you might be at risk of someone listening in on your conversations. When you rely on services that you don’t own yourself for critical day-to-day operations (like Google Calendar, or Facebook…) you risk losing access to those capabilities by having your account banned, even by mistake. Regardless of your specific situation, knowing more about the digital servers that are serving you is a vital first step for supporting communities or companies large and small.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This intermediate-level workshop combines various topics from the &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/sys101.html&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s System Administration&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/net101.html&quot;&gt;Networking&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/sec101.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; courses to offer an intensive crash course in secure server setup, monitoring, and maintenance. By taking a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/blob/master/train-the-trainers/practice-labs/introduction-to-securing-virtualized-secure-shell-servers/README.md&quot;&gt;deep dive into the SSH protocol&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll learn how to set up remote administrative access to a server in a safe way, and you’ll be exposed to the potential risks of network eavesdroppers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man-in-the-middle_attack&quot;&gt;Machine-in-the-Middle (MITM) attacks&lt;/a&gt;, and much more. By the end of this workshop, you’ll have a basic understanding of how to safely operate self-hosted digital infrastructures for yourself, your friends, and your comrades, as well as what first steps you need to take to keep intruders and enemies at bay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-03-20-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn the basics of securing digital infrastructure by taking a deep-dive into the Secure Shell (SSH) protocol, a fundamental component of safe administrative access to remote servers. Regardless of whether you rely on one or many thousands of servers to power your daily operations, securely managing those machines is essential to the success of your efforts. This intermediate-level workshop shows you how to securely set up, access, and debug connection issues over the SSH protocol so that you’ll be ready to operate self-hosted digital infrastructure for yourself, friends, or comrades.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bare Bones Crypto: Understanding Critical Cryptographic Primitives</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-14-bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bare Bones Crypto: Understanding Critical Cryptographic Primitives" /><published>2021-03-14T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-14T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-14-bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-14-bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives">&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to have your doctorate in theoretical mathematics to understand crypto enough to use it safely, but you do need to use it safely to be secure! Come learn the magic behind the math in this cryptography primer for those of us who are not “number people.” Using simplified examples and hands-on demonstrations, this workshop (finally!) offers a practical, accessible introduction to the foundations of modern cryptographic security protocols such as RSA public-key cryptography, stream and block ciphers, digital signatures, one-way hash functions, Hash-based Message Authentication Codes (HMACs), and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every time you use a modern computer, you invoke numerous simple mathematical functions that make it possible to do things like logging in to Web sites safely or “locking” (encrypting) your secret documents behind passwords. At their root, these functions, called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptographic_primitive&quot;&gt;cryptographic primitives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, are not that much more complicated than simple addition or division. But when used in concert with the massive storage capacities and processing speeds of our modern electronic devices, they serve as the bedrock atop which every provably secure system works, from &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Password-Superpowers-How-to-Crack-Hashes-and-Stump-Hackers&quot;&gt;password vaults&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Two-Places-at-Once-Understanding-Virtual-Private-Networks&quot;&gt;Virtual Private Networks (VPNs)&lt;/a&gt; to BitCoin and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today, everyone has full access to bulletproof “military grade encryption” for free, even if they don’t realize it. &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Signal-and-Surveillance-How-to-Exercise-Digital-Civil-Liberties-in-a-Surveillance-State&quot;&gt;Signal Private Messenger&lt;/a&gt;’s “Safety Numbers?” Those are cryptographic hash functions! One-time passwords generated by apps like Google Authenticator or Authy? They use nonces! The &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Tor-What-is-it-Good-For-(Absolutely-Everything!)&quot;&gt;Tor anonymity network&lt;/a&gt;? That’s a mixnet! The padlock icon in the address bar of your Web browser? Block ciphers (and public-key cryptography, and digital signatures, oh my)!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Knowledge of cryptography was deemed so dangerous during the Cold War that ever since the end of World War II the United States and its military allies attempted to regulate access to these crypto powers by classifying them as “munitions” (i.e., mathematical &lt;em&gt;weapons&lt;/em&gt;, literally) and criminalizing their sale or export. But as the Internet gained widespread commercial adoption and more people became familiar with the underlying math, the government largely relented. It eventually lost what is now retroactively known as the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crypto_Wars&quot;&gt;Crypto Wars&lt;/a&gt;” in the 1990’s.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop, you’ll learn the kind of math that governments tried to keep secret for decades, even if you’re “not a math person.” You’ll see hash functions in practice, learn why longer “keys” are stronger by understanding how RSA secrets are generated, practice developing your own simple ciphers, and start combining primitives to create security protocols that satisfy multiple requirements like confidentiality (privacy), integrity-protection (authenticity), and more. By the end of this workshop, the dizzying vocabulary crytographers use will be well within your reach, as will the ability to understand any new “encryption” product on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-03-14-bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">You don’t need to have your doctorate in theoretical mathematics to understand crypto enough to use it safely, but you do need to use it safely to be secure! Come learn the magic behind the math in this cryptography primer for those of us who are not “number people.” Using simplified examples and hands-on demonstrations, this workshop (finally!) offers a practical, accessible introduction to the foundations of modern cryptographic security protocols such as RSA public-key cryptography, stream and block ciphers, digital signatures, one-way hash functions, Hash-based Message Authentication Codes (HMACs), and more.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Signal and Surveillance: How to Exercise Digital Civil Liberties in a Surveillance State</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-13-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Signal and Surveillance: How to Exercise Digital Civil Liberties in a Surveillance State" /><published>2021-03-13T15:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-13T15:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-13-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-13-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state">&lt;p&gt;This introductory cybersecurity workshop will show you why Signal, a free, secure, private message app is simple enough to schedule drinks with, yet secure enough to use for planning a protest. As dragnet surveillance practices are legalized at alarming speed, there has never been a more important time to flex your digital civil liberties muscle than right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whether you’re an individual chatting with friends or an organizer planning a political action, all effective coordination depends on safe and reliable communication. Lacking integrity for our communications dooms any effort from the outset, whether mundane or revolutionary. As dragnet surveillance practices are legalized at alarming speed and continue to be fueled by a dramatic expansion of the law enforcement and private defense contractor economies, there has never been a more important time to flex your digital civil liberties muscle than right now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; is the name of a Free Software, secure, private message application built on a cryptographic protocol of the same name. Formerly known as the Axolotl Ratchet or, more commonly, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Double_Ratchet_Algorithm&quot;&gt;Double-Ratchet Algorithm&lt;/a&gt;, its features are robust enough for the revolutionary activist (i.e., end-to-end encryption, message authentication, plausible deniability or message repudiation, perfect forward secrecy, and more) and yet simple enough to use as a drop-in replacement for your existing text messaging application. Signal also sports Skype-like voice and video calling, location- and file-sharing features, and even iMessage-style large font emojis!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you’ve never heard of Signal before, now’s the time to switch. If you think you already know how to use Signal, let us show you some pro-tips (trusted third-party Safety Number verification, disappearing messages, registering Signal accounts with pseudonymous phone numbers, inactivity lock-outs, and Signal relay server IP address protection). This introductory cybersecurity workshop will show you why Signal is simple enough to schedule drinks at the bar with, yet secure enough to use for planning a protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-03-13-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">This introductory cybersecurity workshop will show you why Signal, a free, secure, private message app is simple enough to schedule drinks with, yet secure enough to use for planning a protest. As dragnet surveillance practices are legalized at alarming speed, there has never been a more important time to flex your digital civil liberties muscle than right now.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Watch and Learn: Web Design and Development Livestream</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-11-watch-and-learn-web-design-and-development-livestream" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Watch and Learn: Web Design and Development Livestream" /><published>2021-03-11T21:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-11T21:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-11-watch-and-learn-web-design-and-development-livestream</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-11-watch-and-learn-web-design-and-development-livestream">&lt;p&gt;Ever wanted to peek over the shoulder of an expert developer as they write code, to pick their brain while they solve real-life problems in real time, or simply bask in the comfort of watching an experienced craftsperson at work? Tech Learning Collective’s “Watch and Learn” events are your chance to join our staff as they livestream some of the work they do, such as redesigning our Web site, building out new or upgrading old infrastructure, and performing other (non-sensitive) tasks to keep Tech Learning Collective moving forward. It’s like watching Bob Ross paint, if he were painting with bits and bytes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;livestream-topic&quot;&gt;Livestream Topic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is redesigning our Web site for 2021. In a few months, we’ll launch a brand new custom Web design for our public-facing Web site. We’ll have new colors, new layouts, and most importantly new code. So this Watch and Learn event will be focused almost exclusively on front-end Web development.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Some of the work has already been done, but there’s lots more to do. Our Web designer will be streaming the way they start by examining graphic design artifacts from the Free Software &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gimp.org/&quot;&gt;GNU Image Manipulation Program (GIMP)&lt;/a&gt;, a powerful alternative to Adobe Photoshop, translating them into liquid and dynamic layouts so that they work in a variety of Web browser makes, models, and sizes, and finally how they integrate the new code with our Web site’s simple Content Management System (CMS) called &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Along the way, you’ll get to see how an experienced front-end Web designer thinks about design elements like layout grids, how they organize and optimize Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) code, and how rich metadata in the form of semantic HTML markup makes their job easier.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;By attending, you get a front-row seat to the video livestream, along with access to a chat channel where you can ask questions about and offer feedback on the coding process live and in real time. We recommend that you have at least some familiarity with basic HTML and CSS code, as this is not a full-fledged class or workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-event-2021-03-11-watch-and-learn-web-design-and-development-livestream&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Ever wanted to peek over the shoulder of an expert developer as they write code, to pick their brain while they solve real-life problems in real time, or simply bask in the comfort of watching an experienced craftsperson at work? Tech Learning Collective’s “Watch and Learn” events are your chance to join our staff as they livestream some of the work they do, such as redesigning our Web site, building out new or upgrading old infrastructure, and performing other (non-sensitive) tasks to keep Tech Learning Collective moving forward. It’s like watching Bob Ross paint, if he were painting with bits and bytes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/poster.web201.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/poster.web201.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Down the Rabbit Hole: Anonymous Publishing on the Darknet</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-07-down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Down the Rabbit Hole: Anonymous Publishing on the Darknet" /><published>2021-03-07T15:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-07T15:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-07-down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-07-down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet">&lt;p&gt;Get your message out without revealing who you are by publishing anonymously on the “Darknet.” This workshop shows you how to create Tor Onion services for Web sites through free tools like OnionShare, and even by setting up Tor servers that are built and configured from scratch manually. You’ll learn about how Tor helps keep both publishers and consumers private and anonymous online, as well as how law enforcement might successfully de-anonymize poorly configured Onion services through host bypass, fingerprint correlation, and other similar attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s often said that if you want to tell people the truth, you’d better make them laugh—or they’ll kill you. Sometimes, humor isn’t a sufficient defense. For these situations, the only remaining defense is to become anonymous. In this deep-dive workshop on anonymous Internet publishing, you’ll learn about a special class of proxy server called a Tor Onion service that makes it possible to publish Web sites or offer network-capable services more or, if you’re really skilled, completely anonymously.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Publishing something truly anonymously on the Internet today is getting more and more difficult. And yet, with “real name” requirements pushed by social media giants like Facebook, law enforcement agents demanding travelers’ online usernames and passwords at border crossings, and global political campaigns to undermine or outright backdoor privacy-preserving encryption technologies, anonymous publishing is also getting more and more important. Whistleblowers need to be able to leak or publish anonymously to stay safe from legal and especially extralegal reprisals, and so too do politically vocal bloggers, investigative journalists, and citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this specialized workshop, you’ll see how Darknet Web sites like the now-famous Silk Road, as well as less controversial Web sites like the New York Times, actually use the same underlying technology called Tor Onion services to create their respective censorship-resistant publications. You’ll also be exposed to some of the techniques that law enforcement often tries to use to de-anonymize Onion services, and learn how to defend against them. By the end of this workshop, you’ll have a working knowledge of numerous critical modern technologies including Web servers, network relays, and Tor’s famous onion-routing protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-03-07-down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Get your message out without revealing who you are by publishing anonymously on the “Darknet.” This workshop shows you how to create Tor Onion services for Web sites through free tools like OnionShare, and even by setting up Tor servers that are built and configured from scratch manually. You’ll learn about how Tor helps keep both publishers and consumers private and anonymous online, as well as how law enforcement might successfully de-anonymize poorly configured Onion services through host bypass, fingerprint correlation, and other similar attacks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Faster Than Light: Getting Started with Configuration Management</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-06-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Faster Than Light: Getting Started with Configuration Management" /><published>2021-03-06T15:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-06T15:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-06-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-06-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to beat back configuration drift on your servers by leveraging automation tools like Ansible in this deep dive workshop demonstrating modern DevOps practices for deploying, maintaining, and auditing compute clusters. Whether for a Web application, big data processing, or other project, you need to turn old-school runbooks into computerized playbooks that can execute Standard Operating Procedures quickly and reliably so you can deploy complex systems simply and predictably. Come learn about key concepts like idempotence and change control, and learn how giant corporations implement security principles like RBAC, all using free and open source software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today, all but the most trivial of computer systems rely on an interdependent set of servers working in concert. You don’t just have one server, you have a group of them. Commonly called a &lt;em&gt;cluster&lt;/em&gt;, these servers need to be managed as a group, ensuring that their software configurations, security patches, and installed packages are deployed, maintained, and eventually updated or retired in a predictable way.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this deep dive workshop, we’ll set up our own small cluster and use &lt;a href=&quot;https://ansible.com/&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt;, which is an agentless, cross-platform, enterprise-grade, free software &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Configuration_management&quot;&gt;Configuration Management (CM)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Automate-All-the-Things-Infrastructure-as-Code-Primer&quot;&gt;Infrastructure as Code (IaC)&lt;/a&gt; framework used by giant corporations like IBM and Cisco, to turn old-school operator runbooks into computerized playbooks that can be executed quickly and easily even by novice operators. Through several hands-on exercises, you’ll learn about the entire CM lifecycle from planning through auditing so that you understand critical CM concepts like idempotence, change control, and more, which are common to all CM systems including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chef.io/configuration-management/&quot;&gt;Chef&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://puppet.com/use-cases/configuration-management/&quot;&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.saltstack.com/en/latest/topics/states/&quot;&gt;Salt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Along the way, you’ll be exposed to key concepts such as &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Ship-Shape-Computing-Working-with-Containers-and-Containzerizing-Digital-Workloads&quot;&gt;containerization&lt;/a&gt; through Ansible’s support for automating container builds, &lt;a href=&quot;/con&quot;&gt;Role-Based Access Control (RBAC)&lt;/a&gt; via Ansible’s AWX Project, and more. By adopting configuration management workflows with tools like Ansible, you can reduce operator errors, and beat back configuration drift on any long-lived infrastructure components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-03-06-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to beat back configuration drift on your servers by leveraging automation tools like Ansible in this deep dive workshop demonstrating modern DevOps practices for deploying, maintaining, and auditing compute clusters. Whether for a Web application, big data processing, or other project, you need to turn old-school runbooks into computerized playbooks that can execute Standard Operating Procedures quickly and reliably so you can deploy complex systems simply and predictably. Come learn about key concepts like idempotence and change control, and learn how giant corporations implement security principles like RBAC, all using free and open source software.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Water in a Garden: The Style and Substance of Cascading Style Sheets</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/02/workshop-2021-02-27-water-in-a-garden-the-style-and-substance-of-cascading-style-sheets" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Water in a Garden: The Style and Substance of Cascading Style Sheets" /><published>2021-02-27T15:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-02-27T15:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/02/workshop-2021-02-27-water-in-a-garden-the-style-and-substance-of-cascading-style-sheets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/02/workshop-2021-02-27-water-in-a-garden-the-style-and-substance-of-cascading-style-sheets">&lt;p&gt;The way some hypermedia object, like a Web page, presents itself is encoded using a language called Cascading Style Sheets (CSS). While CSS is one of the modern Web’s most powerful features, it’s also one of its most misunderstood and misused inventions. In this workshop, you’ll learn important CSS fundamentals that are often missing from most tutorials, like how to understand the concept of document flow, as well as gain insight into the equations and rendering algorithms that determine things like a CSS box’s size, position, and more that are at work behind the scenes in every stylesheet. We’ll also touch on how CSS can be used in contexts beyond HTML including print and mobile app styling, and how to use some more advanced features like media and feature queries, modern layout modules, and other CSS capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All physical mediums like print, music, or film can be beautiful, but they will always be constrained by the fact of their analog nature. Digital media—and specifically hypermedia—is different. It can change both its form and its function, simultaneously presenting itself as any one or a combination of multimedia formats without changing its underlying structure. The humble Web page is a good example: it can stretch to fit your screen when viewed in a Web browser, lay itself out on a page to prepare for being printed, and even embed voice cues so it can be more easily listened to when read aloud. All of this is done using a language called Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), one of the most powerful, and most often misused, features of the modern Web.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Although the CSS language itself is decades old now, its origins are even older. Rooted in the idea that form and function can simultaneously coexist in a multitude of different arrangements, CSS makes it possible for a single well-formed digital object to appear in the “best” way to any given viewer (or reader, or listener). This is a radical departure from physical media, like paper, and it requires an equally radical departure from some traditional graphic design paradigms that demands we spend an equal amount of time exploring philosophical issues like “the eye of the beholder” as it demands that we familiarize ourselves with technical implementation details such as the mathematical equations determining when, where, and how to draw specific shapes or colors.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This workshop builds on the concepts of hypertext introduced in &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/The-Web-as-a-Language-What-No-One-Ever-Told-You-About-HTML-That-You-Didn't-Know-To-Ask&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s “The Web as a Language” workshop&lt;/a&gt; by speaking of fundamental CSS concepts often omitted from other tutorials, such as “User Agents,” document flow, and rendering contexts. You’ll learn how both the design and the function of your digital creations can benefit from approaching hypermedia more fluidly, so you can work with the CSS rendering engine in most modern graphical programming environments rather than fighting against it. Like water, your Web pages, apps, and other hypertextual creations will be able to flow seamlessly into vessels of any shape, Operating System, or Web Browser vendor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-02-27-water-in-a-garden-the-style-and-substance-of-cascading-style-sheets&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">The way some hypermedia object, like a Web page, presents itself is encoded using a language called Cascading Style Sheets (CSS). While CSS is one of the modern Web’s most powerful features, it’s also one of its most misunderstood and misused inventions. In this workshop, you’ll learn important CSS fundamentals that are often missing from most tutorials, like how to understand the concept of document flow, as well as gain insight into the equations and rendering algorithms that determine things like a CSS box’s size, position, and more that are at work behind the scenes in every stylesheet. We’ll also touch on how CSS can be used in contexts beyond HTML including print and mobile app styling, and how to use some more advanced features like media and feature queries, modern layout modules, and other CSS capabilities.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.water-in-a-garden-the-style-and-substance-of-cascading-style-sheets.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.water-in-a-garden-the-style-and-substance-of-cascading-style-sheets.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Developing Digital Dexterity: Introduction to JavaScript</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/02/workshop-2021-02-21-developing-digital-dexterity-introduction-to-javascript" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Developing Digital Dexterity: Introduction to JavaScript" /><published>2021-02-21T15:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-02-21T15:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/02/workshop-2021-02-21-developing-digital-dexterity-introduction-to-javascript</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/02/workshop-2021-02-21-developing-digital-dexterity-introduction-to-javascript">&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is known for being “the Web programming language,” and while its capabilities in a Web browser have grown considerably, today JavaScript can also be used to automate mundane office jobs (e.g., Google Apps Script, Microsoft Office’s JavaScript API), develop PC games (using GDevelop), and much more. Learn what you need to know to get started with JavaScript in any environment in this workshop covering some common programming concepts as well as the quirks of the JavaScript language itself (functional scope, prototype-based object inheritance, etc.) so you can increase your digital dexterity whether in a Web browser, office job, or your own project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Over the course of ten days in 1995, the Web changed forever when Brendan Eich was hired by Netscape, Inc. and developed a programming language that could be embedded in Web pages. Briefly named LiveScript, the language became known as JavaScript three months later, and was officially standardized as ECMAScript in 1997 after taking the Internet by storm only two years later. Today, JavaScript is arguably the single most popular and prolific high-level language available to many people for many projects.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Although most people know of JavaScript as the programming language of the Web, where &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API&quot;&gt;its capabilities&lt;/a&gt; have increased dramatically over the years, many other environments outside of the Web browser or traditional Web application now embed or rely on JavaScript engines to work. Entire back-end applications can be created with “server-side JavaScript” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ringojs.org/&quot;&gt;RingoJS&lt;/a&gt;); Internet-of-Things (IoT) devices like sensors and larger microcontrollers offer JavaScript scriptable interfaces (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.espruino.com/&quot;&gt;Espruino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neonious.com/lowjs/&quot;&gt;low.js&lt;/a&gt;); mundane office jobs and “paperwork” can be accomplished in JavaScript (&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.openoffice.org/wiki/Documentation/DevGuide/Scripting/JavaScript_Editor&quot;&gt;OpenOffice&lt;/a&gt;/LibreOffice Script Provider, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/apps-script/&quot;&gt;Google Apps Script&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/javascript/api/overview&quot;&gt;Microsoft Office JavaScript API&lt;/a&gt;); JavaScript can be used to write smart contracts for blockchain-based distributed ledger technologies (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hyperledger.org/use/fabric&quot;&gt;Hyperledger Fabric&lt;/a&gt;); desktop and PC game programming can be done entirely in JavaScript (&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdevelop-app.com/javascript-game-engine/&quot;&gt;GDevelop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.babylonjs.com/&quot;&gt;Babylon.js&lt;/a&gt;); some other programming languages are implemented in JavaScript (&lt;a href=&quot;https://scratch.mit.edu/&quot;&gt;Scratch&lt;/a&gt;); and JavaScript can even be used for macOS system automation tasks using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AppleScript#Open_Scripting_Architecture&quot;&gt;Open Scripting Architecture (OSA) JavaScript for Automation extension&lt;/a&gt;. Almost no other programming language is as easy to learn while offering the breadth of options that JavaScript does, which is one clear reason for the language’s popularity among developers and desirability among employers.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop, you’ll learn what you need to know to get started with JavaScript in any environment. By focusing on the language’s built-in constructs, you’ll be able to avoid many common pitfalls and understand what makes JavaScript tick. We’ll cover some programming basics common to all languages, but we’ll also show how JavaScript’s unusual rules (functional scope, prototype-based object inheritance, etc.) make it possible to write especially elegant—or especially dangerous—code, as well as showing you why developing even minimal proficiency with JavaScript will drastically increase your “digital dexterity” as you browse the Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-02-21-developing-digital-dexterity-introduction-to-javascript&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">JavaScript is known for being “the Web programming language,” and while its capabilities in a Web browser have grown considerably, today JavaScript can also be used to automate mundane office jobs (e.g., Google Apps Script, Microsoft Office’s JavaScript API), develop PC games (using GDevelop), and much more. Learn what you need to know to get started with JavaScript in any environment in this workshop covering some common programming concepts as well as the quirks of the JavaScript language itself (functional scope, prototype-based object inheritance, etc.) so you can increase your digital dexterity whether in a Web browser, office job, or your own project.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.developing-digital-dexterity-introduction-to-javascript.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.developing-digital-dexterity-introduction-to-javascript.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Collaboration Across Universes: Basics of Version Control with Git</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/02/workshop-2021-02-20-collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Collaboration Across Universes: Basics of Version Control with Git" /><published>2021-02-20T15:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-02-20T15:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/02/workshop-2021-02-20-collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/02/workshop-2021-02-20-collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git">&lt;p&gt;Ever work on a project with other people? Of course you do. If you’ve been saving files with names like “Project-outline-1” and then saving another version of that file as “Project-outline-2” then you already understand the importance of a Version Control System (VCS). In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll see the popular Git version control system in action and learn how to improve your collaborative workflow whether you’re a software engineer, novelist, or art designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As most of us know first-hand, the creative process involves many edits and revisions. Adding a little bit here, trimming a little bit there, but then hitting “undo” a bunch and experimenting with a new direction is quite normal! When your project is a single file, pressing “Save As…” many times might suffice, but what if your project spans dozens or even hundreds of files?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is where version control systems (VCSs) shine. Designed to track, compare, and merge different versions of the same project, these tools give you the ability to make a snapshot of the state of your work at a given point in time so that you can “undo” or “redo” any number of times, across any number of files. Moreover, by naming different snapshots, you can create an infinite number of variations of your project and then build on those unique versions without affecting the others; it’s as though the new version is in its own alternate universe. This makes it possible to easily and safely experiment in one universe (called a &lt;em&gt;branch&lt;/em&gt;) without throwing away or overwriting the original version of the project on which your changes were based.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll learn the basics of &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, a free distributed version control system on which popular sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; are based. Git is lovingly called “the stupid content tracker” because it can track changes to everything and anything that can be digitized. Although it was originally invented for software programmers, Git is also useful for novelists, researchers, and anyone else whose work involves creativity in a digital medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-02-20-collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Ever work on a project with other people? Of course you do. If you’ve been saving files with names like “Project-outline-1” and then saving another version of that file as “Project-outline-2” then you already understand the importance of a Version Control System (VCS). In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll see the popular Git version control system in action and learn how to improve your collaborative workflow whether you’re a software engineer, novelist, or art designer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>