<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2022-02-15T01:29:22-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective | Events</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">Down the Rabbit Hole: Anonymous Publishing on the Darknet</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-13-down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Down the Rabbit Hole: Anonymous Publishing on the Darknet" /><published>2022-03-13T14:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-03-13T14:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-13-down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-13-down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet">&lt;p&gt;Get your message out without revealing who you are by publishing anonymously on the “Darknet.” This workshop shows you how to create Tor Onion services for Web sites through free tools like OnionShare, and even by setting up Tor servers that are built and configured from scratch manually. You’ll learn about how Tor helps keep both publishers and consumers private and anonymous online, as well as how law enforcement might successfully de-anonymize poorly configured Onion services through host bypass, fingerprint correlation, and other similar attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s often said that if you want to tell people the truth, you’d better make them laugh—or they’ll kill you. Sometimes, humor isn’t a sufficient defense. For these situations, the only remaining defense is to become anonymous. In this deep-dive workshop on anonymous Internet publishing, you’ll learn about a special class of proxy server called a Tor Onion service that makes it possible to publish Web sites or offer network-capable services more or, if you’re really skilled, completely anonymously.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Publishing something truly anonymously on the Internet today is getting more and more difficult. And yet, with “real name” requirements pushed by social media giants like Facebook, law enforcement agents demanding travelers’ online usernames and passwords at border crossings, and global political campaigns to undermine or outright backdoor privacy-preserving encryption technologies, anonymous publishing is also getting more and more important. Whistleblowers need to be able to leak or publish anonymously to stay safe from legal and especially extralegal reprisals, and so too do politically vocal bloggers, investigative journalists, and citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this specialized workshop, you’ll see how Darknet Web sites like the now-famous Silk Road, as well as less controversial Web sites like the New York Times, actually use the same underlying technology called Tor Onion services to create their respective censorship-resistant publications. You’ll also be exposed to some of the techniques that law enforcement often tries to use to de-anonymize Onion services, and learn how to defend against them. By the end of this workshop, you’ll have a working knowledge of numerous critical modern technologies including Web servers, network relays, and Tor’s famous onion-routing protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-03-13-down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Get your message out without revealing who you are by publishing anonymously on the “Darknet.” This workshop shows you how to create Tor Onion services for Web sites through free tools like OnionShare, and even by setting up Tor servers that are built and configured from scratch manually. You’ll learn about how Tor helps keep both publishers and consumers private and anonymous online, as well as how law enforcement might successfully de-anonymize poorly configured Onion services through host bypass, fingerprint correlation, and other similar attacks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Where the Sky Meets the Sea: Understanding Container Orchestration with Kubernetes</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-12-where-the-sky-meets-the-sea-understanding-container-orchestration-with-kubernetes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where the Sky Meets the Sea: Understanding Container Orchestration with Kubernetes" /><published>2022-03-12T13:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-12T13:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-12-where-the-sky-meets-the-sea-understanding-container-orchestration-with-kubernetes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-12-where-the-sky-meets-the-sea-understanding-container-orchestration-with-kubernetes">&lt;p&gt;Learn to pilot Kubernetes and find out how it helps you get the most value out of your hardware. Kubernetes is the free, enterprise-grade, cloud-native solution for automated deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications. This workshop offers an introduction to container orchestration concepts and practices by showing you how to work effectively with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt;, utilize Labels and Selectors, explore various components of the Kubernetes control plane, and more. You’ll get your own Kubernetes cluster where you can deploy apps, learn how to influence scheduling decisions, and monitor the health of clustered workloads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As anyone who has ever moved house knows, the more effectively you can pack, the easier your move will be. It’s a big task, often requiring thousands of tiny decisions to make sure delicate items are wrapped appropriately, all one’s stuff fits neatly into all the available boxes, and so on. Once the boxes are all packed, loading them onto a moving vehicle requires that you distribute their weight more or less evenly so that there are no unpleasant surprises during the move. This is more or less what container orchestration tools are for, except instead of moving physical bins, we have to ship software inside containers. Each container requires resources, like CPU time and memory space, which means we’ll need to play a sort of Tetris game to make sure all our containers fit in the most dense, yet most balanced, arrangement to keep our hardware costs as low as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; is the free and open source industry standard container orchestration platform that provides both system administrators and application developers with a set of tools for cooperatively building, deploying, and maintaining applications at all levels of scale. Its job is to help you get the most out of your hardware by “packing” all your containers (installed server software) into the fewest possible “bins” (physical or virtual machines), and then automatically monitoring, restarting, adding, removing, or shuffling those containers from one machine to another as demand for the services running on your cluster change. Your job is to tell Kubernetes what your ideal deployment situation is, and what to prioritize when resources get scarce.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this intermediate-level workshop, we’ll build on our knowledge of Linux &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Ship-Shape-Computing-Working-with-Containers-and-Containzerizing-Digital-Workloads&quot;&gt;containers&lt;/a&gt; and fundamental system administration tasks to explore a Kubernetes cluster. You’ll learn how to inspect workloads using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/overview/&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; command line utility, a graphical Web-based dashboard, and the Kubernetes API itself. By exploring the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/overview/components/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes control plane&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll get insight into how Kubernetes makes scheduling decisions and, along with using &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/overview/working-with-objects/labels/&quot;&gt;Labels and Selectors&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll learn how to influence those scheduling decisions by &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/scheduling-eviction/taint-and-toleration/&quot;&gt;tainting&lt;/a&gt; certain resources in specific ways. Finally, you’ll see how Kubernetes provides a set of “cloud-native” services and APIs that developers can use to write apps that spawn more replicas of themselves when needed and perform other forms of automated or self-healing tasks, making the system administrator’s job that much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-03-12-where-the-sky-meets-the-sea-understanding-container-orchestration-with-kubernetes&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn to pilot Kubernetes and find out how it helps you get the most value out of your hardware. Kubernetes is the free, enterprise-grade, cloud-native solution for automated deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications. This workshop offers an introduction to container orchestration concepts and practices by showing you how to work effectively with kubectl, utilize Labels and Selectors, explore various components of the Kubernetes control plane, and more. You’ll get your own Kubernetes cluster where you can deploy apps, learn how to influence scheduling decisions, and monitor the health of clustered workloads.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.where-the-sky-meets-the-sea-understanding-container-orchestration-with-kubernetes.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.where-the-sky-meets-the-sea-understanding-container-orchestration-with-kubernetes.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What’s in a Name: Understanding the Domain Name System</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-06-whats-in-a-name-understanding-the-domain-name-system" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What’s in a Name: Understanding the Domain Name System" /><published>2022-03-06T13:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-06T13:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-06-whats-in-a-name-understanding-the-domain-name-system</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-06-whats-in-a-name-understanding-the-domain-name-system">&lt;p&gt;Find out how easy it is to avoid certain forms of Internet censorship, phishing attacks, or network outages in this primer to the Domain Name System or DNS. Far from being just a way to translate names like Google.com into IP addresses, the DNS is actually a massively distributed, delegated database capable of housing all sorts of information. For administrators and programmers, understanding DNS is a crucial step to ensuring the health of applications and services. But it’s also one of the components of Internet networking most visible to users. This workshop will discuss recursive resolvers, anti-spam DNS resource records, and state-of-the-art security protocols such as DNS-over-HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the digital &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Exploring-Cyberspace-Network-Sniffing-and-Scanning&quot;&gt;world of cyperspace&lt;/a&gt; networks, such as the Internet, places don’t have names. They have numbers. Called Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, these numbers are used to identify the sources and destinations where network traffic, such as Web browsing, email, and video conferencing messages should go. But if computers use numbers and not names to route traffic, how do they know where to go when we type in addresses such as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;google.com&lt;/code&gt; in our Web browser?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The answer lies in DNS, the Domain Name System. Often described as “the Internet’s phone book,” DNS is actually a far more capable and integral component of networked systems than it’s given credit for. Ever since its inception in 1983, the DNS was a key enabler of the growth of the Internet and has been vital to its continued operation to this day. Beyond the popular understanding as a name-to-address lookup system, the DNS is actually a massive, distributed, delegated database that allows organizations to publish all kinds of useful information in the form of &lt;em&gt;resource records (RRs)&lt;/em&gt;. For instance, today DNS is also used to fight email spam and phishing attacks (using DNS-backed protocols like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sender_Policy_Framework&quot;&gt;SPF&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DomainKeys_Identified_Mail&quot;&gt;DKIM&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DMARC&quot;&gt;DMARC&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS-based_Authentication_of_Named_Entities&quot;&gt;DANE&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS_Certification_Authority_Authorization&quot;&gt;CAA&lt;/a&gt; resource records), perform service discovery (with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SRV_record&quot;&gt;SRV records&lt;/a&gt;), and more.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Understanding what DNS really is and how it actually works is a crucial, early step administrators must take to ensure applications and services are healthy. In this deep-dive workshop, we’ll &lt;a href=&quot;https://powerdns.org/hello-dns/basic.md.html&quot;&gt;dissect the DNS protocol itself&lt;/a&gt;, watching queries and replies, and we’ll trace DNS messages across recursive DNS servers, called &lt;em&gt;resolvers&lt;/em&gt;, as they get bounced from the root DNS resolvers to the ultimate authority responsible for managing the &lt;em&gt;zone&lt;/em&gt; in which our answer is to be found. We’ll also discuss the inherent insecurities of the original UDP-based DNS traffic, as well as how to secure DNS transmissions using state-of-the-art technology such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://dnscrypt.info/&quot;&gt;DNSCrypt&lt;/a&gt; v2, DNS-over-TLS (DoT), and DNS-over-HTTPS (DoH), which is increasingly finding its way into familiar apps like Web browsers and even the Windows 10 Operating System itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-03-06-whats-in-a-name-understanding-the-domain-name-system&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Find out how easy it is to avoid certain forms of Internet censorship, phishing attacks, or network outages in this primer to the Domain Name System or DNS. Far from being just a way to translate names like Google.com into IP addresses, the DNS is actually a massively distributed, delegated database capable of housing all sorts of information. For administrators and programmers, understanding DNS is a crucial step to ensuring the health of applications and services. But it’s also one of the components of Internet networking most visible to users. This workshop will discuss recursive resolvers, anti-spam DNS resource records, and state-of-the-art security protocols such as DNS-over-HTTPS.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.whats-in-a-name-understanding-the-domain-name-system.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.whats-in-a-name-understanding-the-domain-name-system.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ship Shape Computing: Working with Containers and Containerizing Digital Workloads</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-05-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ship Shape Computing: Working with Containers and Containerizing Digital Workloads" /><published>2022-03-05T13:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-05T13:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-05-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-05-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to pack up your code bases, apps, and microservices and get ready to set sail aboard container orchestration platforms in the cloud or on your own metal in this introductory workshop about working with containers. Far from a newfangled buzzword, containerizing digital workloads have precedents dating back to the invention of the UNIX operating system in the 1970’s. Today, operating container engines like Docker and orchestration platforms like Kubernetes are increasingly essential skills, but difficult to navigate. This workshop will put you back on course by providing a ground-up view of what containers really are, where they came from, and how to best use them for DevOps, site reliability, and even enhanced security tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the earliest days of computing, an application would be responsible for processing only very small amounts of input. It would then produce a similarly small amount of output, working as fast and efficiently as possible. Known as a processing “pipeline,” this early solutions paradigm is most famously expressed as the so-called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_philosophy&quot;&gt;UNIX philosophy&lt;/a&gt;,” a programmer’s adage that states each program should “do (only) one thing, and do it well,” and it’s still the beating heart of powerful computer interfaces such as &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Computer-Language-Foundations-Command-Line-Basics&quot;&gt;command line use&lt;/a&gt; to this day.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Then, all throughout the 1980’s, 90’s, and 2000’s, as computing speed relentlessly increased while its cost simultaneously plummeted, companies began building larger, more complex applications. Known as “monoliths,” this generation of apps were well-suited for their environment, where they were deployed onto singular mainframe-like computers housed inside private server rooms. But these application architectures are no longer sensible in a world where cloud computing and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/The-Imitation-Game-Introduction-to-Administering-Virtual-Machine-Systems&quot;&gt;virtualization technologies&lt;/a&gt; make it possible to dynamically reserve compute power as user demand ebbs and flows. Why over-purchase server hardware when you can spin up another virtual machine to handle a spike in traffic, then automatically have that machine shut itself down when incoming requests settle back at manageable levels?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That’s one reason why, today, online apps from Google, Facebook, and others are written as “microservices.” Far from being worthy of the buzzword-driven hype, this paradigm is actually a return to software’s original designs where the goals of a larger application are processed independently by a set of cooperating but independent smaller programs, each one performing only one job very well. To make this work in today’s cloud environments, each microservice must be “containerized,” packaged into a single &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Taming-Daemons-System-Administration-and-Operation-Basics&quot;&gt;Operating System process&lt;/a&gt; that is run by a container management engine such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://coreos.com/rkt/&quot;&gt;CoreOS’s rkt&lt;/a&gt; (pronounced “rocket”), or &lt;a href=&quot;https://linuxcontainers.org/lxd/introduction/&quot;&gt;LXD&lt;/a&gt; in preparation for being orchestrated across a fleet of hundreds or thousands of (often virtual) compute instances.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this hands-on workshop, you’ll learn how to make use of the thousands of ready-made containers available at container registries such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker Hub&lt;/a&gt;, create new containers from scratch, containerize existing codebases, manage running containers, and more. We’ll explore how to troubleshoot container failures, show how to network multiple containers together, and touch on container orchestration tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/engine/swarm/&quot;&gt;Docker’s Swarm mode&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nomadproject.io/&quot;&gt;HashiCorp Nomad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mesos.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Apache Mesos&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://mesosphere.github.io/marathon/&quot;&gt;Marathon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; to see how our containers can be automatically distributed, or “scheduled,” and be tasked with their specialized workloads across a &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Automate-All-the-Things-Infrastructure-as-Code-Primer&quot;&gt;virtual private cloud&lt;/a&gt; based on whatever resources we have available to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-03-05-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to pack up your code bases, apps, and microservices and get ready to set sail aboard container orchestration platforms in the cloud or on your own metal in this introductory workshop about working with containers. Far from a newfangled buzzword, containerizing digital workloads have precedents dating back to the invention of the UNIX operating system in the 1970’s. Today, operating container engines like Docker and orchestration platforms like Kubernetes are increasingly essential skills, but difficult to navigate. This workshop will put you back on course by providing a ground-up view of what containers really are, where they came from, and how to best use them for DevOps, site reliability, and even enhanced security tasks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">World Wide Wars: Introduction to Exploiting Web Applications</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-27-world-wide-wars-introduction-to-exploiting-web-applications" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="World Wide Wars: Introduction to Exploiting Web Applications" /><published>2022-02-27T13:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-02-27T13:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-27-world-wide-wars-introduction-to-exploiting-web-applications</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-27-world-wide-wars-introduction-to-exploiting-web-applications">&lt;p&gt;Learn the basics of website security auditing in this hands-on workshop that will introduce you to the OWASP Zed Attack Proxy (ZAP), a free, open source Web application security scanner and intercepting proxy. We’ll get set up with a practice target against which you can launch live-fire (but legal and safe!) Web exploits that run the gamut of attack categories from injection to broken authentication and access control. In the process, you’ll learn exactly how attackers, internal Red Teams, and professional penetration testers go about exploiting real vulnerabilities that are prevalent all across the Web today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://crockford.com/&quot;&gt;Douglas Crockford&lt;/a&gt;, former distinguished architect of Internet behemoths PayPal and Yahoo! before that, “The Web is the most hostile software engineering environment imaginable.” Given that it’s hard enough to make Web applications work in the first place, is it any surprise that so many of them can be broken, hacked, and exploited? Of course, it’s often not good enough merely to break some system. Our task is to break &lt;em&gt;into&lt;/em&gt; (or, &lt;em&gt;break out of&lt;/em&gt;) that system.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The “front door” to most targets is usually their Web site and so in this offensive security workshop you’ll learn exactly how attackers, internal Red Teams, and professional penetration testers go about targeting websites, identifying vulnerabilities, and exploiting them. By using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zaproxy.org/&quot;&gt;OWASP Zed Attack Proxy (ZAP)&lt;/a&gt;, a free and open source Web application security scanner, you’ll get a hands-on introduction to Web application security basics, intercepting proxy configuration, target scoping, and more. We’ll be targeting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://owasp.org/www-project-juice-shop/&quot;&gt;OWASP Juice Shop&lt;/a&gt;, an intentionally vulnerable practice target that has a slew of common Web vulnerabilities for us to learn about collectively known as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://owasp.org/www-project-top-ten/&quot;&gt;OWASP Top Ten&lt;/a&gt;. They include SQL injection, sensitive data exposure, cross-site scripting (XSS), broken authentication and access control, and many others.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today’s World Wide Web has become a worldwide battleground, economically, militarily, and culturally. By knowing how the Web-based systems we all use—or even build!—can be made to fail in just the “right” way, we can better protect ourselves and our organizations from the constant barrage of attacks flying across the Internet. Come learn how to hack yourself before your opponents do, so you can find vulnerabilities and shore up defenses in your own Web projects before attackers get the chance to leak your sensitive data such as usernames and passwords, install malware on your systems, or penetrate your network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-02-27-world-wide-wars-introduction-to-exploiting-web-applications&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn the basics of website security auditing in this hands-on workshop that will introduce you to the OWASP Zed Attack Proxy (ZAP), a free, open source Web application security scanner and intercepting proxy. We’ll get set up with a practice target against which you can launch live-fire (but legal and safe!) Web exploits that run the gamut of attack categories from injection to broken authentication and access control. In the process, you’ll learn exactly how attackers, internal Red Teams, and professional penetration testers go about exploiting real vulnerabilities that are prevalent all across the Web today.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.world-wide-wars-introduction-to-exploiting-web-applications.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.world-wide-wars-introduction-to-exploiting-web-applications.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Shields Up: Firewalls and Other Network Perimeter Defenses</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-26-shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shields Up: Firewalls and Other Network Perimeter Defenses" /><published>2022-02-26T13:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-02-26T13:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-26-shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-26-shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses">&lt;p&gt;Master the fundamentals of personal and enterprise-grade network firewalls in this hands-on workshop about network perimeter security. By learning to use the macOS, Windows, BSD, and Linux firewalls (including command-line utilities like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iptables&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nft&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pfctl&lt;/code&gt;), you can protect your devices even on untrustworthy or hostile networks, like public Wi-Fi. Intended for all audiences, you’ll gain experience with both beginner-friendly and advanced tools including dedicated firewall distributions (like pfSense and IPFire) as you get an introduction to a wide range of NetSec scenarios. We’ll also cover the important security properties of NAT routers, how deep packet inspection (DPI) works, and get you started with industry-standard Network Intrusion Detection/Prevention Systems (NIDS/NIPS) like Snort and Suricata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In today’s ubiquitous computing environment, the most frequently used entrance (and exit!) in to (or out of) any system is its &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Clearing-Away-the-Clouds-How-Computer-Networks,-Servers,-and-the-Internet-Work&quot;&gt;network connection&lt;/a&gt;. That’s why network firewalls have been a central component of every network security architecture since their introduction in the 1980’s. A firewall’s primary responsibility is to stop the spread of malware, help prevent cyberattacks and unauthorized data exfiltration, or isolate other problems in one network or network segment from affecting others. Thus, firewalls serve to compartmentalize one area of a computer network from another. And while they are most commonly thought of as being at network boundaries like your home or office router, just about &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; computer has a firewall these days, including your personal laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Modern firewalls can also do a lot more than their first or second generation ancestors that simply blocked certain ports or kept track of ongoing conversations between two endpoints. By building on so-called Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) technology, firewalls can analyze the traffic passing through them in real time, making decisions about what to allow or block based on myriad factors. On more heavily policed or otherwise protected networks, firewalls have evolved into very powerful Network Intrusion Detection or Prevention Systems (NIDS/NIPS).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But don’t make the mistake of thinking this power is reserved for rich corporations! The firewall built into the Linux kernel (called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netfilter.org/&quot;&gt;Netfilter&lt;/a&gt; and controlled with the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iptables&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nft&lt;/code&gt; commands) is the backbone of many commercial enterprise firewall distributions, and it’s available free of charge. Plus, its ability to intercept and modify traffic in-flight is the basis of many proxy technologies such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/network/&quot;&gt;Docker’s networking&lt;/a&gt; and Kubernetes’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/command-line-tools-reference/kube-proxy/&quot;&gt;kube-proxy&lt;/a&gt;, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So, are your network shields up? Find out at this workshop where we’ll show you how to use the firewall built-in to your Windows, macOS, or GNU/Linux laptop. We’ll also show you how to set up firewalled subnets using NAT routers, a bulletproof way to keep unsecured Internet of Things (IoT) or smart-home devices from infecting your more critical personal devices, or to make a super-secure guest Wi-Fi network available for visitors. You’ll leave understanding the utility of so-called Layer 7 firewalls such as Web Application Firewalls (WAFs), and knowing how to test the security of your own firewall configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-02-26-shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Master the fundamentals of personal and enterprise-grade network firewalls in this hands-on workshop about network perimeter security. By learning to use the macOS, Windows, BSD, and Linux firewalls (including command-line utilities like iptables, nft, and pfctl), you can protect your devices even on untrustworthy or hostile networks, like public Wi-Fi. Intended for all audiences, you’ll gain experience with both beginner-friendly and advanced tools including dedicated firewall distributions (like pfSense and IPFire) as you get an introduction to a wide range of NetSec scenarios. We’ll also cover the important security properties of NAT routers, how deep packet inspection (DPI) works, and get you started with industry-standard Network Intrusion Detection/Prevention Systems (NIDS/NIPS) like Snort and Suricata.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Collaboration Across Universes: Basics of Version Control with Git</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-20-collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Collaboration Across Universes: Basics of Version Control with Git" /><published>2022-02-20T13:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-02-20T13:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-20-collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-20-collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git">&lt;p&gt;Ever work on a project with other people? Of course you do. If you’ve been saving files with names like “Project-outline-1” and then saving another version of that file as “Project-outline-2” then you already understand the importance of a Version Control System (VCS). In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll see the popular Git version control system in action and learn how to improve your collaborative workflow whether you’re a software engineer, novelist, or art designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As most of us know first-hand, the creative process involves many edits and revisions. Adding a little bit here, trimming a little bit there, but then hitting “undo” a bunch and experimenting with a new direction is quite normal! When your project is a single file, pressing “Save As…” many times might suffice, but what if your project spans dozens or even hundreds of files?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is where version control systems (VCSs) shine. Designed to track, compare, and merge different versions of the same project, these tools give you the ability to make a snapshot of the state of your work at a given point in time so that you can “undo” or “redo” any number of times, across any number of files. Moreover, by naming different snapshots, you can create an infinite number of variations of your project and then build on those unique versions without affecting the others; it’s as though the new version is in its own alternate universe. This makes it possible to easily and safely experiment in one universe (called a &lt;em&gt;branch&lt;/em&gt;) without throwing away or overwriting the original version of the project on which your changes were based.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll learn the basics of &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, a free distributed version control system on which popular sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; are based. Git is lovingly called “the stupid content tracker” because it can track changes to everything and anything that can be digitized. Although it was originally invented for software programmers, Git is also useful for novelists, researchers, and anyone else whose work involves creativity in a digital medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-02-20-collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Ever work on a project with other people? Of course you do. If you’ve been saving files with names like “Project-outline-1” and then saving another version of that file as “Project-outline-2” then you already understand the importance of a Version Control System (VCS). In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll see the popular Git version control system in action and learn how to improve your collaborative workflow whether you’re a software engineer, novelist, or art designer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tor: What is it Good For? (Absolutely Everything!)</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-19-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tor: What is it Good For? (Absolutely Everything!)" /><published>2022-02-19T13:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-02-19T13:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-19-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-19-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything">&lt;p&gt;Come learn how the free Tor Web Browser can be your gateway to the Dark Web while simultaneously keeping you safer and your personal info more private as you browse web sites big and small. In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From illegal online drug stores like Silk Road to DDoS botnet command and control headquarters, media attention has long painted “the Dark Web” as though nothing good can come of it. But learn just a little bit more about how Tor and “hidden services” work and you’ll find a treasure trove of valuable possibilities for day-to-day Internet use. The same technology that can hide the location of a drug ring can also serve as a free VPN-like service to protect your privacy while you browse the Internet, make censored websites available again, and even let you host your own Internet services for free, all without opening a single port on your firewall!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool. They’ll demonstrate numerous Tor features such as Tor authentication, target service load balancing, and NAT-punching. In the process, you’ll finally understand—on a technical level—what the “Dark Web” actually is and how it works. Bring a laptop to class, and you’ll leave having run your own Dark Web site. This class is for everyone; whether you’re a veteran black hat or a timid newbie, this class will shine a light on the Dark Web once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-02-19-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Come learn how the free Tor Web Browser can be your gateway to the Dark Web while simultaneously keeping you safer and your personal info more private as you browse web sites big and small. In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Two Places at Once: Understanding Virtual Private Networks</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-13-two-places-at-once-understanding-virtual-private-networks" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Two Places at Once: Understanding Virtual Private Networks" /><published>2022-02-13T13:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-02-13T13:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-13-two-places-at-once-understanding-virtual-private-networks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-13-two-places-at-once-understanding-virtual-private-networks">&lt;p&gt;Find out how Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) can help you evade Internet censorship, protect your network traffic, and offer easier access to remote services on firewalled internal networks. You’ll learn how to set up and use OpenVPN, a free and widely-deployed VPN solution, so that you can connect securely to your home, office, or other provider’s networks no matter where you are and no matter who’s watching you. Using a VPN can also make it appear that you are accessing the Internet from a location other than where you are, which means it’s simple to access some files or services that would otherwise be blocked where you live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How often have you wished you could be in two places at once? That’s exactly what Virtual Private Networking (VPN) technology was designed to allow computers to do. First popularized in 1996 by Microsoft’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Point-to-Point_Tunneling_Protocol&quot;&gt;Point-to-Point Tunneling Protocol (PPTP)&lt;/a&gt;, using VPN technology made it possible for two disconnected networks to be knit back together into one as long as each of them were connected to a third middle network, even if that middle network was hostile or untrusted. Today, that middle network is usually the Internet, which can certainly be hostile and untrusted! With a VPN, it’s possible to be “here” (on your actual network) and “there” (on the other side of the VPN connection) at the same time; by signing into a VPN service, you create a “VPN tunnel” that acts like a wormhole in space-time in that whatever you send into the tunnel emerges on the other side as though the two sides of the tunnel are next to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Throughout the late 1990’s and 2000’s, VPN technology saw a surge in use among businesses looking for ways to enable remote workers. Using VPNs made it simpler for a colleague to travel because they could still be “directly connected” to their office network. By 2001, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://openvpn.org/&quot;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt; project made this amazing technology free and open source for GNU/Linux systems, with cross-platform implementations for Mac OS X and Windows arriving shortly thereafter. Today, OpenVPN servers form the bedrock of many modern free and commercial VPN solutions, and are still the most widely deployed VPN solution for most use cases.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop, you’ll get to see what happens when network packets are sent into VPN tunnels and how they appear on the other side in order to learn exactly how VPNs encapsulate—and secure—your computer’s communication with Web sites, office servers, or other services. You’ll see what it takes to set up your own OpenVPN server (not much!), as well as how to troubleshoot connection issues. You’ll also get introduced to several newer but less mature VPN protocols such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wireguard.com/&quot;&gt;Wireguard&lt;/a&gt;, and learn about Layer 2 and Layer 3 VPN solutions such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPsec&quot;&gt;IPsec&lt;/a&gt; and its related tunneling (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Layer_2_Tunneling_Protocol&quot;&gt;L2TP&lt;/a&gt;) and security (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPsec#Encapsulating_Security_Payload&quot;&gt;ESP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Key_Exchange&quot;&gt;IKE&lt;/a&gt;, etcetera) protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-02-13-two-places-at-once-understanding-virtual-private-networks&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Find out how Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) can help you evade Internet censorship, protect your network traffic, and offer easier access to remote services on firewalled internal networks. You’ll learn how to set up and use OpenVPN, a free and widely-deployed VPN solution, so that you can connect securely to your home, office, or other provider’s networks no matter where you are and no matter who’s watching you. Using a VPN can also make it appear that you are accessing the Internet from a location other than where you are, which means it’s simple to access some files or services that would otherwise be blocked where you live.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.two-places-at-once-understanding-virtual-private-networks.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.two-places-at-once-understanding-virtual-private-networks.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Taming Daemons: System Administration and Operation Basics</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-12-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taming Daemons: System Administration and Operation Basics" /><published>2022-02-12T13:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-02-12T13:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-12-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/02/workshop-2022-02-12-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics">&lt;p&gt;Most individuals with access to a computer system have more power today than ever before, but rarely do they make use of it or even know how much power they truly have. In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll begin learning how to “speak with the machines.” By learning to communicate more expressively with the digital devices that are increasingly responsible for mediating contemporary society, you’ll gain the power to effectively and materially change your relationship not only with your laptop, but with global systems of law, finance, and even art, literature, and philosophy governing today’s world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How much good does a powerful tool do for you if you don’t know how to use it well? How much more capable would you be if you mastered all the tools available to you? It might sound ridiculous, but failing to learn the practicalities of computer system operation basics is arguably the most common mistake people in the fast-paced tech scene make.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Modern computers are power tools, and behind each one of them is a human operator, or “system administrator,” responsible for configuring and maintaining that computer. If you have a personal computer such as a laptop or smartphone, then you are already a system administrator whether you realize it or not! Making sure the apps you want to use are installed and up to date, managing the amount of free space you have for your photos, and connecting or disconnecting from the Internet are all examples of simple system administration tasks that you probably already take on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner’s workshop, we’ll start by exploring what happens inside your computer when you take every-day tasks like open a Web browser or save files, and then dive down the rabbit hole to meet the special class of programs that make it possible for all your other programs to work. Called &lt;em&gt;daemons&lt;/em&gt;, short for Disk Access and Execution Monitors, they make up the world of Operating System services, signals, sockets, and more under the hood of your desktop environment. By the end of this workshop, you’ll have a far deeper understanding of how to care for your computer, as well as the ability to understand any new tools or services you encounter a whole lot faster than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-02-12-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Most individuals with access to a computer system have more power today than ever before, but rarely do they make use of it or even know how much power they truly have. In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll begin learning how to “speak with the machines.” By learning to communicate more expressively with the digital devices that are increasingly responsible for mediating contemporary society, you’ll gain the power to effectively and materially change your relationship not only with your laptop, but with global systems of law, finance, and even art, literature, and philosophy governing today’s world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>