<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2020-08-18T20:48:22-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective | Events</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">The Genesis Project: Making and Maintaining Cloud Infrastructure with Terraform</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-15-the-genesis-project-making-and-maintaining-cloud-infrastructure-with-terraform" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Genesis Project: Making and Maintaining Cloud Infrastructure with Terraform" /><published>2020-09-15T16:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-15T16:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-15-the-genesis-project-making-and-maintaining-cloud-infrastructure-with-terraform</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-15-the-genesis-project-making-and-maintaining-cloud-infrastructure-with-terraform">&lt;p&gt;Learn to manage your own Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) datacenter environment and make the most of cloud infrastructure providers (“IaaS platforms”) by automatically deploying underlying infrastructure, including network topology, firewall rulesets, DNS records, and other resources. This intermediate-level workshop introduces you to Terraform, a free, agentless, masterless, Infrastructure-as-Code (IaC) digital operations provisioning tool used by many of the largest organizations in the world but simple enough to use on a team of one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the beginning, there was the mainframe: a single, gigantic machine that held all the data and did all the work by itself, like a digital planet suspended in the vast emptiness of cyberspace. Then came networks, the personal computer, the Internet, Web 2.0, cloud computing, microservices, and containers—a whole &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Exploring-Cyberspace-Network-Sniffing-and-Scanning&quot;&gt;cybergalaxy to explore&lt;/a&gt;. While the world today looks very different than it did in the days of the mainframe, every project still needs to start at the beginning: get at least one computer to hold all project data and do all project work. So how do modern projects go from a single computer to a whole galaxy so quickly?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;For many (including Tech Learning Collective!), the answer is &lt;a href=&quot;https://terraform.io/&quot;&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt;, a free, open source, and extensible tool that can provision and manage any number of infrastructural resources from source code repositories to cloud compute instances to DNS records and much, much more. Using Terraform, engineers describe the digital environment they’d &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; to have by writing it down in a simple, declarative configuration language called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.terraform.io/docs/configuration/syntax.html&quot;&gt;HCL&lt;/a&gt;. Then, when instructed, Terraform does the work of metaphorically, well, terraforming cyberspace to match the engineer’s description.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop, you’ll learn the basics of how to set up Terraform for your organization. We’ll also go over best practices for ensuring testing, staging, and production infrastructures stay isolated from one another, how to compose reusable modules, and how to share your Terraform configurations as well as project state with collaborators. At the end of this workshop, you’ll understand how to bring the cloud down to earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-09-15-the-genesis-project-making-and-maintaining-cloud-infrastructure-with-terraform&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn to manage your own Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) datacenter environment and make the most of cloud infrastructure providers (“IaaS platforms”) by automatically deploying underlying infrastructure, including network topology, firewall rulesets, DNS records, and other resources. This intermediate-level workshop introduces you to Terraform, a free, agentless, masterless, Infrastructure-as-Code (IaC) digital operations provisioning tool used by many of the largest organizations in the world but simple enough to use on a team of one.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.the-genesis-project-making-and-maintaining-cloud-infrastructure-with-terraform.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.the-genesis-project-making-and-maintaining-cloud-infrastructure-with-terraform.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ship Shape Computing: Working with Containers and Containerizing Digital Workloads</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-13-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ship Shape Computing: Working with Containers and Containerizing Digital Workloads" /><published>2020-09-13T16:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-13T16:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-13-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-13-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to pack up your code bases, apps, and microservices and get ready to set sail aboard container orchestration platforms in the cloud or on your own metal in this introductory workshop about working with containers. Far from a newfangled buzzword, containerizing digital workloads have precedents dating back to the invention of the UNIX operating system in the 1970’s. Today, operating container engines like Docker and orchestration platforms like Kubernetes are increasingly essential skills, but difficult to navigate. This workshop will put you back on course by providing a ground-up view of what containers really are, where they came from, and how to best use them for DevOps, site reliability, and even enhanced security tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the earliest days of computing, an application would be responsible for processing only very small amounts of input. It would then produce a similarly small amount of output, working as fast and efficiently as possible. Known as a processing “pipeline,” this early solutions paradigm is most famously expressed as the so-called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_philosophy&quot;&gt;UNIX philosophy&lt;/a&gt;,” a programmer’s adage that states each program should “do (only) one thing, and do it well,” and it’s still the beating heart of powerful computer interfaces such as &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Computer-Language-Foundations-Command-Line-Basics&quot;&gt;command line use&lt;/a&gt; to this day.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Then, all throughout the 1980’s, 90’s, and 2000’s, as computing speed relentlessly increased while its cost simultaneously plummeted, companies began building larger, more complex applications. Known as “monoliths,” this generation of apps were well-suited for their environment, where they were deployed onto singular mainframe-like computers housed inside private server rooms. But these application architectures are no longer sensible in a world where cloud computing and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/The-Imitation-Game-Introduction-to-Administering-Virtual-Machine-Systems&quot;&gt;virtualization technologies&lt;/a&gt; make it possible to dynamically reserve compute power as user demand ebbs and flows. Why over-purchase server hardware when you can spin up another virtual machine to handle a spike in traffic, then automatically have that machine shut itself down when incoming requests settle back at manageable levels?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That’s one reason why, today, online apps from Google, Facebook, and others are written as “microservices.” Far from being worthy of the buzzword-driven hype, this paradigm is actually a return to software’s original designs where the goals of a larger application are processed independently by a set of cooperating but independent smaller programs, each one performing only one job very well. To make this work in today’s cloud environments, each microservice must be “containerized,” packaged into a single &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Taming-Daemons-System-Administration-and-Operation-Basics&quot;&gt;Operating System process&lt;/a&gt; that is run by a container management engine such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://coreos.com/rkt/&quot;&gt;CoreOS’s rkt&lt;/a&gt; (pronounced “rocket”), or &lt;a href=&quot;https://linuxcontainers.org/lxd/introduction/&quot;&gt;LXD&lt;/a&gt; in preparation for being orchestrated across a fleet of hundreds or thousands of (often virtual) compute instances.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this hands-on workshop, you’ll learn how to make use of the thousands of ready-made containers available at container registries such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker Hub&lt;/a&gt;, create new containers from scratch, containerize existing codebases, manage running containers, and more. We’ll explore how to troubleshoot container failures, show how to network multiple containers together, and touch on container orchestration tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/engine/swarm/&quot;&gt;Docker’s Swarm mode&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nomadproject.io/&quot;&gt;HashiCorp Nomad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mesos.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Apache Mesos&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; to see how our containers can be automatically distributed, or “scheduled,” and be tasked with their specialized workloads across a &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Automate-All-the-Things-Infrastructure-as-Code-Primer&quot;&gt;virtual private cloud&lt;/a&gt; based on whatever resources we have available to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-09-13-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to pack up your code bases, apps, and microservices and get ready to set sail aboard container orchestration platforms in the cloud or on your own metal in this introductory workshop about working with containers. Far from a newfangled buzzword, containerizing digital workloads have precedents dating back to the invention of the UNIX operating system in the 1970’s. Today, operating container engines like Docker and orchestration platforms like Kubernetes are increasingly essential skills, but difficult to navigate. This workshop will put you back on course by providing a ground-up view of what containers really are, where they came from, and how to best use them for DevOps, site reliability, and even enhanced security tasks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Free Guided Tour of Tech Learning Collective Foundations</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/event-2020-09-12-free-guided-tour-of-tech-learning-collective-foundations" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Free Guided Tour of Tech Learning Collective Foundations" /><published>2020-09-12T17:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-12T17:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/event-2020-09-12-free-guided-tour-of-tech-learning-collective-foundations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/event-2020-09-12-free-guided-tour-of-tech-learning-collective-foundations">&lt;p&gt;Just getting started learning computer technologies? Join Tech Learning Collective instructors for this free, guided tour of the Tech Learning Collective Foundations curriculum. These self-paced courses and practice labs are great for jump-starting your learning as they introduce you to the most important foundations of Tech Learning Collective course material, such as command line basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;We are asking for a $10 suggested &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;donation&lt;/a&gt; if you can afford it. Help support our incredible teachers and expert support teams! No one will be turned away for lack of funds.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot;&gt;Click here to support Tech Learning Collective with your donation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;form action=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;cmd&quot; value=&quot;_s-xclick&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;hosted_button_id&quot; value=&quot;PW4TUNMA53J3J&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_donate_LG.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; name=&quot;submit&quot; alt=&quot;Donate with PayPal&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or scan or click this QR code to donate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot; style=&quot;display: block; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/qr-code.donate.paypal.png&quot; alt=&quot;QR code for PayPal donation.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for your support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our online events, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gobrunch.com/events/129606&quot;&gt;CLICK HERE TO JOIN THE EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Just getting started learning computer technologies? Join Tech Learning Collective instructors for this free, guided tour of the Tech Learning Collective Foundations curriculum. These self-paced courses and practice labs are great for jump-starting your learning as they introduce you to the most important foundations of Tech Learning Collective course material, such as command line basics.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.generic.tech-learning-collective.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.generic.tech-learning-collective.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Shields Up: Firewalls and Other Network Perimeter Defenses</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-10-shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shields Up: Firewalls and Other Network Perimeter Defenses" /><published>2020-09-10T16:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T16:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-10-shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-10-shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses">&lt;p&gt;Master the fundamentals of personal and enterprise-grade network firewalls in this hands-on workshop about network perimeter security. By learning to use the macOS, Windows, BSD, and Linux firewalls (including command-line utilities like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iptables&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nft&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pfctl&lt;/code&gt;), you can protect your devices even on untrustworthy or hostile networks, like public Wi-Fi. Intended for all audiences, you’ll gain experience with both beginner-friendly and advanced tools like pfSense as you get an introduction to a wide range of NetSec scenarios. We’ll also cover the important security properties of NAT routers, how deep packet inspection (DPI) works, and get you started with industry-standard Network Intrusion Detection/Prevention Systems (NIDS/NIPS) like Snort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In today’s ubiquitous computing environment, the most frequently used entrance (and exit!) in to (or out of) any system is its &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Clearing-Away-the-Clouds-How-Computer-Networks,-Servers,-and-the-Internet-Work&quot;&gt;network connection&lt;/a&gt;. That’s why network firewalls have been a central component of every network security architecture since their introduction in the 1980’s. A firewall’s primary responsibility is to stop the spread of malware, help prevent cyberattacks and unauthorized data exfiltration, or isolate other problems in one network or network segment from affecting others. Thus, firewalls serve to compartmentalize one area of a computer network from another. And while they are most commonly thought of as being at network boundaries like your home or office router, just about &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; computer has a firewall these days, including your personal laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Modern firewalls can also do a lot more than their first or second generation ancestors that simply blocked certain ports or kept track of ongoing conversations between two endpoints. By building on so-called Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) technology, firewalls can analyze the traffic passing through them in real time, making decisions about what to allow or block based on myriad factors. On more heavily policed or otherwise protected networks, firewalls have evolved into very powerful Network Intrusion Detection or Prevention Systems (NIDS/NIPS).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But don’t make the mistake of thinking this power is reserved for rich corporations! The firewall built into the Linux kernel (called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netfilter.org/&quot;&gt;Netfilter&lt;/a&gt; and controlled with the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iptables&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nft&lt;/code&gt; commands) is the backbone of almost all commercial enterprise firewall distributions, and it’s available free of charge. Plus, its ability to intercept and modify traffic in-flight is the basis of many proxy technologies such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/network/&quot;&gt;Docker’s networking&lt;/a&gt; and Kubernetes’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/command-line-tools-reference/kube-proxy/&quot;&gt;kube-proxy&lt;/a&gt;, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So, are your network shields up? Find out at this workshop where we’ll show you how to use the firewall built-in to your Windows, macOS, or GNU/Linux laptop. We’ll also show you how to set up firewalled subnets using NAT routers, a bulletproof way to keep unsecured Internet of Things (IoT) or smart-home devices from infecting your more critical personal devices, or to make a super-secure guest Wi-Fi network available for visitors. You’ll leave understanding the utility of so-called Layer 7 firewalls such as Web Application Firewalls (WAFs), and knowing how to test the security of your own firewall configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-09-10-shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Master the fundamentals of personal and enterprise-grade network firewalls in this hands-on workshop about network perimeter security. By learning to use the macOS, Windows, BSD, and Linux firewalls (including command-line utilities like iptables, nft, and pfctl), you can protect your devices even on untrustworthy or hostile networks, like public Wi-Fi. Intended for all audiences, you’ll gain experience with both beginner-friendly and advanced tools like pfSense as you get an introduction to a wide range of NetSec scenarios. We’ll also cover the important security properties of NAT routers, how deep packet inspection (DPI) works, and get you started with industry-standard Network Intrusion Detection/Prevention Systems (NIDS/NIPS) like Snort.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing with Blue Fire: Shell Scripting for Beginners</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-08-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing with Blue Fire: Shell Scripting for Beginners" /><published>2020-09-08T16:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-08T16:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-08-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-08-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to inscribe your thoughts, dreams, and desires into your computer and take your command line skills to the next level by learning how to write simple programs called shell scripts. In a way, invoking commands one at a time is like writing a program interactively, whereas writing a script inscribes that knowledge into a more permanent form. By learning how to turn commands into simple scripted programs, you can unlock the almost magical potential of your computer and more easily share that potential with others to whom you distribute your scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At their core, digital computers are very complex writing instruments. Like pen and paper, they allow us to record our thoughts, dreams, and desires for later review. Unlike pen and paper, they allow us to do this at the speed of electricity and at a scale never before imagined possible, and their ability to directly manipulate the physical world through servomotors, industrial control systems, biomedical devices, and other robotic prosthesis means they can potentially supercharge every facet of our humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When a system administrator or programmer uses a computer, they often issue instructions one by one using a special-purpose, text-only interface called a &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/&quot;&gt;command line&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Individually, these instructions are called &lt;em&gt;invocations&lt;/em&gt;. (Yes, that’s their technical term!) In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll learn how to write whole spells, rituals, or (sacred) texts called &lt;em&gt;shell scripts&lt;/em&gt; to inscribe your own thoughts, dreams, and desires in the electrified silicon and minerals of your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;By saving your scripts in files, you can invoke arbitrarily complex routines to reproduce tasks or automate complex procedures with a single command. Writing scripts also makes it possible to share what you can do with others and, as such, are one the simplest forms of computer program that you can write and distribute. Come learn how the magic of digital inscription can help you do your work, and increase your power to accomplish your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-09-08-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to inscribe your thoughts, dreams, and desires into your computer and take your command line skills to the next level by learning how to write simple programs called shell scripts. In a way, invoking commands one at a time is like writing a program interactively, whereas writing a script inscribes that knowledge into a more permanent form. By learning how to turn commands into simple scripted programs, you can unlock the almost magical potential of your computer and more easily share that potential with others to whom you distribute your scripts.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Faster Than Light: Getting Started with Configuration Management</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-06-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Faster Than Light: Getting Started with Configuration Management" /><published>2020-09-06T16:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T16:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-06-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-06-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to beat back configuration drift on your servers by leveraging automation tools like Ansible in this deep dive workshop demonstrating modern DevOps practices for deploying, maintaining, and auditing compute clusters. Whether for a Web application, big data processing, or other project, you need to turn old-school runbooks into computerized playbooks that can execute Standard Operating Procedures quickly and reliably so you can deploy complex systems simply and predictably. Come learn about key concepts like idempotence and change control, and learn how giant corporations implement security principles like RBAC, all using free and open source software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today, all but the most trivial of computer systems rely on an interdependent set of servers working in concert. You don’t just have one server, you have a group of them. Commonly called a &lt;em&gt;cluster&lt;/em&gt;, these servers need to be managed as a group, ensuring that their software configurations, security patches, and installed packages are deployed, maintained, and eventually updated or retired in a predictable way.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this deep dive workshop, we’ll set up our own small cluster and use &lt;a href=&quot;https://ansible.com/&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt;, which is an agentless, cross-platform, enterprise-grade, free software &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Configuration_management&quot;&gt;Configuration Management (CM)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Automate-All-the-Things-Infrastructure-as-Code-Primer&quot;&gt;Infrastructure as Code (IaC)&lt;/a&gt; framework used by giant corporations like IBM and Cisco, to turn old-school operator runbooks into computerized playbooks that can be executed quickly and easily even by novice operators. Through several hands-on exercises, you’ll learn about the entire CM lifecycle from planning through auditing so that you understand critical CM concepts like idempotence, change control, and more, which are common to all CM systems including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chef.io/configuration-management/&quot;&gt;Chef&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://puppet.com/use-cases/configuration-management/&quot;&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.saltstack.com/en/latest/topics/states/&quot;&gt;Salt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Along the way, you’ll be exposed to key concepts such as &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Ship-Shape-Computing-Working-with-Containers-and-Containzerizing-Digital-Workloads&quot;&gt;containerization&lt;/a&gt; through Ansible’s support for automating container builds, &lt;a href=&quot;/con&quot;&gt;Role-Based Access Control (RBAC)&lt;/a&gt; via Ansible’s AWX Project, and more. By adopting configuration management workflows with tools like Ansible, you can reduce operator errors, and beat back configuration drift on any long-lived infrastructure components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-09-06-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to beat back configuration drift on your servers by leveraging automation tools like Ansible in this deep dive workshop demonstrating modern DevOps practices for deploying, maintaining, and auditing compute clusters. Whether for a Web application, big data processing, or other project, you need to turn old-school runbooks into computerized playbooks that can execute Standard Operating Procedures quickly and reliably so you can deploy complex systems simply and predictably. Come learn about key concepts like idempotence and change control, and learn how giant corporations implement security principles like RBAC, all using free and open source software.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Get in the Zone: Technological Autonomous Zone</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/event-2020-09-04-get-in-the-zone-technological-autonomous-zone" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Get in the Zone: Technological Autonomous Zone" /><published>2020-09-04T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-04T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/event-2020-09-04-get-in-the-zone-technological-autonomous-zone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/event-2020-09-04-get-in-the-zone-technological-autonomous-zone">&lt;p&gt;Watch servers and software get built (or hacked) before your very eyes. Get answers to your technical questions about how to build revolutionary infrastructure for an anti-capitalist, cop-free world. Learn how to protect your own data and the data of your friends or affinity groups with Tech Learning Collective’s expert cybersecurity trainers. Get to know other radical technologists in a safer and moderated virtual classroom space. Get in the Zone, the Technological Autonomous Zone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;We are asking for a $10 suggested &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;donation&lt;/a&gt; if you can afford it. Help support our incredible teachers and expert support teams! No one will be turned away for lack of funds.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot;&gt;Click here to support Tech Learning Collective with your donation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;form action=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;cmd&quot; value=&quot;_s-xclick&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;hosted_button_id&quot; value=&quot;PW4TUNMA53J3J&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_donate_LG.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; name=&quot;submit&quot; alt=&quot;Donate with PayPal&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or scan or click this QR code to donate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot; style=&quot;display: block; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/qr-code.donate.paypal.png&quot; alt=&quot;QR code for PayPal donation.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for your support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our online events, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gobrunch.com/events/126956&quot;&gt;CLICK HERE TO JOIN THE EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Watch servers and software get built (or hacked) before your very eyes. Get answers to your technical questions about how to build revolutionary infrastructure for an anti-capitalist, cop-free world. Learn how to protect your own data and the data of your friends or affinity groups with Tech Learning Collective’s expert cybersecurity trainers. Get to know other radical technologists in a safer and moderated virtual classroom space. Get in the Zone, the Technological Autonomous Zone!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.get-in-the-zone-technological-autonomous-zone.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.get-in-the-zone-technological-autonomous-zone.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tor: What is it Good For? (Absolutely Everything!)</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-01-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tor: What is it Good For? (Absolutely Everything!)" /><published>2020-09-01T16:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-01T16:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-01-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/09/workshop-2020-09-01-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything">&lt;p&gt;Come learn how the free Tor Web Browser can be your gateway to the Dark Web while simultaneously keeping you safer and your personal info more private as you browse web sites big and small. In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From illegal online drug stores like Silk Road to DDoS botnet command and control headquarters, media attention has long painted “the Dark Web” as though nothing good can come of it. But learn just a little bit more about how Tor and “hidden services” work and you’ll find a treasure trove of valuable possibilities for day-to-day Internet use. The same technology that can hide the location of a drug ring can also serve as a free VPN-like service to protect your privacy while you browse the Internet, make censored websites available again, and even let you host your own Internet services for free, all without opening a single port on your firewall!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool. They’ll demonstrate numerous Tor features such as Tor authentication, target service load balancing, and NAT-punching. In the process, you’ll finally understand—on a technical level—what the “Dark Web” actually is and how it works. Bring a laptop to class, and you’ll leave having run your own Dark Web site. This class is for everyone; whether you’re a veteran black hat or a timid newbie, this class will shine a light on the Dark Web once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-09-01-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Come learn how the free Tor Web Browser can be your gateway to the Dark Web while simultaneously keeping you safer and your personal info more private as you browse web sites big and small. In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/event-2020-08-29-mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mr. Robot's Hacker Happy Hour" /><published>2020-08-29T21:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-29T21:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/event-2020-08-29-mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/event-2020-08-29-mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour">&lt;p&gt;Join us for another in our series of free cybersecurity crash courses and virtual socials featuring themes from the critically-acclaimed TV show, Mr. Robot. This time, we’ll focus on the hacks of Season 1, Episode 3, but all hacks from all previous episodes will be in scope, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;We are asking for a $10 USD suggested &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;donation&lt;/a&gt; from all attendees to help support our incredible team of teachers and staff. No one will be turned away for lack of funds.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gobrunch.com/events/114733&quot;&gt;CLICK HERE TO REGISTER AND JOIN THE EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll get the most out of the event if you watch the featured episode of &lt;cite&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/cite&gt; on your own. That way we can’t spoil anything! We’ll begin with a brief look at some of the tools and concepts featured in the episode, and then have a free-for-all Q&amp;amp;A session where you’ll get the opportunity to go in-depth with Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers. Stick around for as long as you’re enjoying yourself—you may even catch a live demo or two!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event offers a brief inside look at some of the topics covered by Tech Learning Collective’s more in-depth security-related &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt; and our &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/sec101.html&quot;&gt;SEC101 course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No previous experience with the show or cybersecurity is required for this event. We are materially and culturally very welcoming for total newbies and experienced hackers alike. Please be aware that &lt;cite&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/cite&gt; contains potentially triggering content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;We are asking for a $10 USD suggested &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;donation&lt;/a&gt; from all attendees to help support our incredible team of teachers and staff! No one will be turned away for lack of funds.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot;&gt;Click here to support Tech Learning Collective with your donation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;form action=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;cmd&quot; value=&quot;_s-xclick&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;hosted_button_id&quot; value=&quot;PW4TUNMA53J3J&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_donate_LG.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; name=&quot;submit&quot; alt=&quot;Donate with PayPal&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or scan or click this QR code to donate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot; style=&quot;display: block; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/qr-code.donate.paypal.png&quot; alt=&quot;QR code for PayPal donation.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for your support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from the space without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Join us for another in our series of free cybersecurity crash courses and virtual socials featuring themes from the critically-acclaimed TV show, Mr. Robot. This time, we’ll focus on the hacks of Season 1, Episode 3, but all hacks from all previous episodes will be in scope, too.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Digital Defenses for the People: Practical Digital Security</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-27-digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Defenses for the People: Practical Digital Security" /><published>2020-08-27T16:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-27T16:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-27-digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-27-digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security">&lt;p&gt;This beginner-friendly introduction to digital safety will cut through the fear, uncertainty, and doubt generated by the frenetic news cycle and the latest Internet privacy listicle, and offer an opportunity to ask the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers your most pressing online privacy and digital security questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Learning how to stay safe online is on many people’s minds, but how do you start this process? With so many tools and suggestions from “experts,” how do you know which tool to use, when, and in what situation? Do you really need a VPN? (And what even is that?) What are the tools you really &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; use, and which tools aren’t worth it? Moreover, without being a cybersecurity expert yourself, how do you learn to sniff out the useful stuff from the placebos?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This beginner’s workshop taught by the &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective&lt;/a&gt;’s cybersecurity trainers offers &lt;a href=&quot;/about/persona-matrix/&quot;&gt;a simple framework&lt;/a&gt; anyone can use to understand what risks they might face and how to protect themselves from those risks. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Persona-based-training-matrix&quot;&gt;Developed and maintained by the Anarcho-Tech NYC Collective&lt;/a&gt;, an independent cybersecurity research group that provides digital security services to anti-fascist groups in New York City, this framework now forms the basis of many digital safety workshops. It is a simple three-by-three grid in which you can place both yourself and your online safety concerns by answering a few intuitive questions like “How likely is it that I will be targeted?” and “How many resources (money, people, etcetera) does my attacker have?”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Although &lt;a href=&quot;https://prism-break.org/en/&quot;&gt;there are many good and free tools available&lt;/a&gt;, most people only need to use a few basic ones: a secure messaging application (like &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Signal-and-Surveillance-How-to-Exercise-Digital-Civil-Liberties-in-a-Surveillance-State&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt;), a password manager (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://keepass.info/&quot;&gt;KeePass&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://lastpass.com/&quot;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt;), and a few of the built-in features of their existing computers, like the full-disk encryption software available for free on every modern laptop and smartphone. This short, calming introduction to digital safety cuts through the fear, uncertainty, and doubt generated by the frenetic news cycle and the latest Internet privacy listicle. You’ll leave this workshop with a security plan in place, and a much clearer picture of the first few steps you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; take to protect yourself and your information both online and offline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-08-27-digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">This beginner-friendly introduction to digital safety will cut through the fear, uncertainty, and doubt generated by the frenetic news cycle and the latest Internet privacy listicle, and offer an opportunity to ask the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers your most pressing online privacy and digital security questions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.digital-defenses-for-the-people-practical-digital-security.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>