<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2020-07-24T12:16:44-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective | Events</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">Mr. Robot’s Hacker Happy Hour</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/event-2020-08-29-mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mr. Robot's Hacker Happy Hour" /><published>2020-08-29T21:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-29T21:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/event-2020-08-29-mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/event-2020-08-29-mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour">&lt;p&gt;Join us for another in our series of free cybersecurity crash courses and virtual socials featuring themes from the critically-acclaimed TV show, Mr. Robot. This time, we’ll focus on the hacks of Season 1, Episode 3, but all hacks from all previous episodes will be in scope, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;We are asking for a $10 USD suggested &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;donation&lt;/a&gt; from all attendees to help support our incredible team of teachers and staff. No one will be turned away for lack of funds.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gobrunch.com/events/114733&quot;&gt;CLICK HERE TO REGISTER AND JOIN THE EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll get the most out of the event if you watch the featured episode of &lt;cite&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/cite&gt; on your own. That way we can’t spoil anything! We’ll begin with a brief look at some of the tools and concepts featured in the episode, and then have a free-for-all Q&amp;amp;A session where you’ll get the opportunity to go in-depth with Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers. Stick around for as long as you’re enjoying yourself—you may even catch a live demo or two!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event offers a brief inside look at some of the topics covered by Tech Learning Collective’s more in-depth security-related &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt; and our &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/sec101.html&quot;&gt;SEC101 course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No previous experience with the show or cybersecurity is required for this event. We are materially and culturally very welcoming for total newbies and experienced hackers alike. Please be aware that &lt;cite&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/cite&gt; contains potentially triggering content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;We are asking for a $10 USD suggested &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;donation&lt;/a&gt; from all attendees to help support our incredible team of teachers and staff! No one will be turned away for lack of funds.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot;&gt;Click here to support Tech Learning Collective with your donation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;form action=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;cmd&quot; value=&quot;_s-xclick&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;hosted_button_id&quot; value=&quot;PW4TUNMA53J3J&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_donate_LG.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; name=&quot;submit&quot; alt=&quot;Donate with PayPal&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or scan or click this QR code to donate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot; style=&quot;display: block; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/qr-code.donate.paypal.png&quot; alt=&quot;QR code for PayPal donation.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for your support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from the space without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Join us for another in our series of free cybersecurity crash courses and virtual socials featuring themes from the critically-acclaimed TV show, Mr. Robot. This time, we’ll focus on the hacks of Season 1, Episode 3, but all hacks from all previous episodes will be in scope, too.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.mr-robots-hacker-happy-hour.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Free Play Night: Backdoors and Breaches (for Beginners)</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/event-2020-08-21-free-play-night-backdoors-and-breaches-for-beginners" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Free Play Night: Backdoors and Breaches (for Beginners)" /><published>2020-08-21T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/event-2020-08-21-free-play-night-backdoors-and-breaches-for-beginners</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/event-2020-08-21-free-play-night-backdoors-and-breaches-for-beginners">&lt;p&gt;Join us to play several rounds of &lt;cite&gt;Backdoors and Breaches&lt;/cite&gt; with our experienced cybersecurity instructors. Backdoors and Breaches is an incident response card game that teaches critical information security skills by putting players in realistic attack scenarios. The players must then work together with fellow members of their team to repel wave after wave of cyberattacks launched by a Tech Learning Collective cybersecurity trainer. In the process, they learn about professional tools, techniques, and procedures for responding to cyber threat incidents as well as how to think critically about organizational preparedness, risk assessment, and disaster recovery priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is open-ended and non-deterministic, which means anything can happen and players are encouraged to talk through strategies with one another in order to get super creative! Our Free Play Nights are completely free to join. Beginners are especially welcomed and encouraged to participate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;We are asking for a $10 USD suggested &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;donation&lt;/a&gt; from all attendees to help support our incredible team of teachers and staff. No one will be turned away for lack of funds.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gobrunch.com/events/119874&quot;&gt;CLICK HERE TO REGISTER AND JOIN THE EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20200422223931if_/https://www.blackhillsinfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/CARDS_blog__4-1-1024x940.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20200422223931if_/https://www.blackhillsinfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/CARDS_blog__4-1-1024x940.png&quot; alt=&quot;Example cards from the Backdoors and Breaches core deck.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;We are asking for a $10 USD suggested &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;donation&lt;/a&gt; from all attendees to help support our incredible team of teachers and staff! No one will be turned away for lack of funds.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot;&gt;Click here to support Tech Learning Collective with your donation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;form action=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;cmd&quot; value=&quot;_s-xclick&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;hosted_button_id&quot; value=&quot;PW4TUNMA53J3J&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_donate_LG.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; name=&quot;submit&quot; alt=&quot;Donate with PayPal&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or scan or click this QR code to donate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot; style=&quot;display: block; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/qr-code.donate.paypal.png&quot; alt=&quot;QR code for PayPal donation.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for your support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from the space without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Join us to play several rounds of Backdoors and Breaches with our experienced cybersecurity instructors. Backdoors and Breaches is an incident response card game that teaches critical information security skills by putting players in realistic attack scenarios. The players must then work together with fellow members of their team to repel wave after wave of cyberattacks launched by a Tech Learning Collective cybersecurity trainer. In the process, they learn about professional tools, techniques, and procedures for responding to cyber threat incidents as well as how to think critically about organizational preparedness, risk assessment, and disaster recovery priorities. The game is open-ended and non-deterministic, which means anything can happen and players are encouraged to talk through strategies with one another in order to get super creative! Our Free Play Nights are completely free to join. Beginners are especially welcomed and encouraged to participate.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/backdoors-and-breaches.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/backdoors-and-breaches.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">File Sharing for Fun and Profit: How BitTorrent Works and What You Can Do With It</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-18-file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="File Sharing for Fun and Profit: How BitTorrent Works and What You Can Do With It" /><published>2020-08-18T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-18T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-18-file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-18-file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it">&lt;p&gt;BitTorrent, the wildly popular but often maligned file sharing protocol, is now being used in everything from (legal!) video streaming sites to corporate software update servers, but you wouldn’t know that if you only listened to Big Media groups like the RIAA. In this beginner-friendly workshop, we’ll bust BitTorrent myths and set the record straight about what “torrenting” actually is, how it works, and what you can do with it. You’ll see how next generation “decentralized” Web applications are making use of the technology, how companies like Facebook and Blizzard, Inc. use it every day, how to make your own “torrents” to share files of your own, and how and why some people take protective measures to torrent more privately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you’ve heard anything about “downloading free movies on the Internet,” you probably heard of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BitTorrent&quot;&gt;BitTorrent&lt;/a&gt; or its more colloquial synonym, “torrents.” You have also probably heard of companies threatening BitTorrent users with Internet service bans, financial penalties, and even lawsuits for “stealing intellectual property.“ Through expensive and coordinated disinformation campaigns, companies like Disney and other “Big Content” media conglomerates represented by special interest groups like the Record Industry Association of America (RIAA) and the Motion Picture Association of America (MPAA) have linked BitTorrent with music and movie piracy in the public mind. They continue to try convincing people that BitTorrent is hard, immoral, and unsafe to use, but the reality is far less one-sided.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BitTorrent&lt;/em&gt; refers to a file transfer technology that has been around since 2001 and is designed to make it easy for you to more quickly share very large files across a computer network, even if your computer lacked a high-speed Internet connection. It worked so well that by the end of 2013 there were more than a quarter billion individual BitTorrent users on the Internet. While the media painted this as an epidemic of criminal behavior, most BitTorrent uses were and still are both legal and mundane. Moreover, the heaviest BitTorrent users were actually companies who built the technology into their own products, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.howtogeek.com/141257/htg-explains-how-does-bittorrent-work/&quot;&gt;Blizzard, Inc. (the World of WarCraft company), who used BitTorrent to deliver updates of its game software to players&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today, BitTorrent is still one of the most popular, cost-efficient, and speediest large-file transfer technologies available to both individuals and multinational corporations alike. Cash-strapped Free Software projects such as GNU/Linux distributions use BitTorrent to distribute their installation packages in order to reduce their monthly bandwidth bills, a whole new category of “decentralized Web” applications like &lt;a href=&quot;https://zeronet.io/&quot;&gt;ZeroNet&lt;/a&gt; are using BitTorrent under the hood to make Web publishing easier and more censorship-resistant than ever before, and traditional Web sites with large bandwidth requirements like video streaming sites (e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinpeertube.org/en/&quot;&gt;PeerTube&lt;/a&gt;) are increasingly adopting a newer variant called &lt;a href=&quot;https://webtorrent.io/faq&quot;&gt;WebTorrent&lt;/a&gt; to improve download speeds and interoperate with the massive existing BitTorrent network.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner-friendly workshop, we’ll bust BitTorrent myths and set the record straight about what “torrenting” actually is, how it works, and what you can do with it. Learn how to find, download, and even create your own torrents so you can share files with friends and colleagues regardless of network obstacles like firewalls or NAT routers. Bring a laptop and you’ll be able to participate in a (legal and safe!) BitTorrent “swarm.” We’ll also discuss the implications of using BitTorrent for less-than-legal ends, and demonstrate steps you can take to improve your privacy such as enabling BitTorrent encryption, connecting to trackers through public proxies, and building private &lt;a href=&quot;https://seedboxgui.de/&quot;&gt;seedboxes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-08-18-file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">BitTorrent, the wildly popular but often maligned file sharing protocol, is now being used in everything from (legal!) video streaming sites to corporate software update servers, but you wouldn’t know that if you only listened to Big Media groups like the RIAA. In this beginner-friendly workshop, we’ll bust BitTorrent myths and set the record straight about what “torrenting” actually is, how it works, and what you can do with it. You’ll see how next generation “decentralized” Web applications are making use of the technology, how companies like Facebook and Blizzard, Inc. use it every day, how to make your own “torrents” to share files of your own, and how and why some people take protective measures to torrent more privately.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What’s in a Name: Understanding the Domain Name System</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-15-whats-in-a-name-understanding-the-domain-name-system" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What's in a Name: Understanding the Domain Name System" /><published>2020-08-15T16:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-15T16:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-15-whats-in-a-name-understanding-the-domain-name-system</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-15-whats-in-a-name-understanding-the-domain-name-system">&lt;p&gt;Find out how easy it is to avoid certain forms of Internet censorship, phishing attacks, or network outages in this primer to the Domain Name System or DNS. Far from being just a way to translate names like Google.com into IP addresses, the DNS is actually a massively distributed, delegated database capable of housing all sorts of information. For administrators and programmers, understanding DNS is a crucial step to ensuring the health of applications and services. But it’s also one of the components of Internet networking most visible to users. This workshop will discuss recursive resolvers, anti-spam DNS resource records, and state-of-the-art security protocols such as DNS-over-HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the digital &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Exploring-Cyberspace-Network-Sniffing-and-Scanning&quot;&gt;world of cyperspace&lt;/a&gt; networks, such as the Internet, places don’t have names. They have numbers. Called Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, these numbers are used to identify the sources and destinations where network traffic, such as Web browsing, email, and video conferencing messages should go. But if computers use numbers and not names to route traffic, how do they know where to go when we type in addresses such as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;google.com&lt;/code&gt; in our Web browser?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The answer lies in DNS, the Domain Name System. Often described as “the Internet’s phone book,” DNS is actually a far more capable and integral component of networked systems than it’s given credit for. Ever since its inception in 1983, the DNS was a key enabler of the growth of the Internet and has been vital to its continued operation to this day. Beyond the popular understanding as a name-to-address lookup system, the DNS is actually a massive, distributed, delegated database that allows organizations to publish all kinds of useful information in the form of &lt;em&gt;resource records (RRs)&lt;/em&gt;. For instance, today DNS is also used to fight email spam and phishing attacks (using DNS-backed protocols like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sender_Policy_Framework&quot;&gt;SPF&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DomainKeys_Identified_Mail&quot;&gt;DKIM&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DMARC&quot;&gt;DMARC&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS-based_Authentication_of_Named_Entities&quot;&gt;DANE&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS_Certification_Authority_Authorization&quot;&gt;CAA&lt;/a&gt; resource records), perform service discovery (with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SRV_record&quot;&gt;SRV records&lt;/a&gt;), and more.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Understanding what DNS really is and how it actually works is a crucial, early step administrators must take to ensure applications and services are healthy. In this deep-dive workshop, we’ll dissect the DNS protocol itself, watching queries and replies, and we’ll trace DNS messages across recursive DNS servers, called &lt;em&gt;resolvers&lt;/em&gt;, as they get bounced from the root DNS resolvers to the ultimate authority responsible for managing the &lt;em&gt;zone&lt;/em&gt; in which our answer is to be found. We’ll also discuss the inherent insecurities of the original UDP-based DNS traffic, as well as how to secure DNS transmissions using state-of-the-art technology such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://dnscrypt.info/&quot;&gt;DNSCrypt&lt;/a&gt; v2, DNS-over-TLS (DoT), and DNS-over-HTTPS (DoH), which is increasingly finding its way into familiar apps like Web browsers and even the Windows 10 Operating System itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-08-15-whats-in-a-name-understanding-the-domain-name-system&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Find out how easy it is to avoid certain forms of Internet censorship, phishing attacks, or network outages in this primer to the Domain Name System or DNS. Far from being just a way to translate names like Google.com into IP addresses, the DNS is actually a massively distributed, delegated database capable of housing all sorts of information. For administrators and programmers, understanding DNS is a crucial step to ensuring the health of applications and services. But it’s also one of the components of Internet networking most visible to users. This workshop will discuss recursive resolvers, anti-spam DNS resource records, and state-of-the-art security protocols such as DNS-over-HTTPS.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.whats-in-a-name-understanding-the-domain-name-system.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.whats-in-a-name-understanding-the-domain-name-system.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ship Shape Computing: Working with Containers and Containerizing Digital Workloads</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-13-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ship Shape Computing: Working with Containers and Containerizing Digital Workloads" /><published>2020-08-13T16:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-13T16:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-13-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-13-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to pack up your code bases, apps, and microservices and get ready to set sail aboard container orchestration platforms in the cloud or on your own metal in this introductory workshop about working with containers. Far from a newfangled buzzword, containerizing digital workloads have precedents dating back to the invention of the UNIX operating system in the 1970’s. Today, operating container engines like Docker and orchestration platforms like Kubernetes are increasingly essential skills, but difficult to navigate. This workshop will put you back on course by providing a ground-up view of what containers really are, where they came from, and how to best use them for DevOps, site reliability, and even enhanced security tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the earliest days of computing, an application would be responsible for processing only very small amounts of input. It would then produce a similarly small amount of output, working as fast and efficiently as possible. Known as a processing “pipeline,” this early solutions paradigm is most famously expressed as the so-called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_philosophy&quot;&gt;UNIX philosophy&lt;/a&gt;,” a programmer’s adage that states each program should “do (only) one thing, and do it well,” and it’s still the beating heart of powerful computer interfaces such as &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Computer-Language-Foundations-Command-Line-Basics&quot;&gt;command line use&lt;/a&gt; to this day.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Then, all throughout the 1980’s, 90’s, and 2000’s, as computing speed relentlessly increased while its cost simultaneously plummeted, companies began building larger, more complex applications. Known as “monoliths,” this generation of apps were well-suited for their environment, where they were deployed onto singular mainframe-like computers housed inside private server rooms. But these application architectures are no longer sensible in a world where cloud computing and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/The-Imitation-Game-Introduction-to-Administering-Virtual-Machine-Systems&quot;&gt;virtualization technologies&lt;/a&gt; make it possible to dynamically reserve compute power as user demand ebbs and flows. Why over-purchase server hardware when you can spin up another virtual machine to handle a spike in traffic, then automatically have that machine shut itself down when incoming requests settle back at manageable levels?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That’s one reason why, today, online apps from Google, Facebook, and others are written as “microservices.” Far from being worthy of the buzzword-driven hype, this paradigm is actually a return to software’s original designs where the goals of a larger application are processed independently by a set of cooperating but independent smaller programs, each one performing only one job very well. To make this work in today’s cloud environments, each microservice must be “containerized,” packaged into a single &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Taming-Daemons-System-Administration-and-Operation-Basics&quot;&gt;Operating System process&lt;/a&gt; that is run by a container management engine such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://coreos.com/rkt/&quot;&gt;CoreOS’s rkt&lt;/a&gt; (pronounced “rocket”), or &lt;a href=&quot;https://linuxcontainers.org/lxd/introduction/&quot;&gt;LXD&lt;/a&gt; in preparation for being orchestrated across a fleet of hundreds or thousands of (often virtual) compute instances.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this hands-on workshop, you’ll learn how to make use of the thousands of ready-made containers available at container registries such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker Hub&lt;/a&gt;, create new containers from scratch, containerize existing codebases, manage running containers, and more. We’ll explore how to troubleshoot container failures, show how to network multiple containers together, and touch on container orchestration tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/engine/swarm/&quot;&gt;Docker’s Swarm mode&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nomadproject.io/&quot;&gt;HashiCorp Nomad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mesos.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Apache Mesos&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; to see how our containers can be automatically distributed, or “scheduled,” and be tasked with their specialized workloads across a &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Automate-All-the-Things-Infrastructure-as-Code-Primer&quot;&gt;virtual private cloud&lt;/a&gt; based on whatever resources we have available to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-08-13-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to pack up your code bases, apps, and microservices and get ready to set sail aboard container orchestration platforms in the cloud or on your own metal in this introductory workshop about working with containers. Far from a newfangled buzzword, containerizing digital workloads have precedents dating back to the invention of the UNIX operating system in the 1970’s. Today, operating container engines like Docker and orchestration platforms like Kubernetes are increasingly essential skills, but difficult to navigate. This workshop will put you back on course by providing a ground-up view of what containers really are, where they came from, and how to best use them for DevOps, site reliability, and even enhanced security tasks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Collaboration Across Universes: Basics of Version Control with Git</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-11-collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Collaboration Across Universes: Basics of Version Control with Git" /><published>2020-08-11T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-11T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-11-collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-11-collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git">&lt;p&gt;Ever work on a project with other people? Of course you do. If you’ve been saving files with names like “Project-outline-1” and then saving another version of that file as “Project-outline-2” then you already understand the importance of a Version Control System (VCS). In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll see the popular Git version control system in action and learn how to improve your collaborative workflow whether you’re a software engineer, novelist, or art designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As most of us know first-hand, the creative process involves many edits and revisions. Adding a little bit here, trimming a little bit there, but then hitting “undo” a bunch and experimenting with a new direction is quite normal! When your project is a single file, pressing “Save As…” many times might suffice, but what if your project spans dozens or even hundreds of files?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is where version control systems (VCSs) shine. Designed to track, compare, and merge different versions of the same project, these tools give you the ability to make a snapshot of the state of your work at a given point in time so that you can “undo” or “redo” any number of times, across any number of files. Moreover, by naming different snapshots, you can create an infinite number of variations of your project and then build on those unique versions without affecting the others; it’s as though the new version is in its own alternate universe. This makes it possible to easily and safely experiment in one universe (called a &lt;em&gt;branch&lt;/em&gt;) without throwing away or overwriting the original version of the project on which your changes were based.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll learn the basics of &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, a free distributed version control system on which popular sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; are based. Git is lovingly called “the stupid content tracker” because it can track changes to everything and anything that can be digitized. Although it was originally invented for software programmers, Git is also useful for novelists, researchers, and anyone else whose work involves creativity in a digital medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-08-11-collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Ever work on a project with other people? Of course you do. If you’ve been saving files with names like “Project-outline-1” and then saving another version of that file as “Project-outline-2” then you already understand the importance of a Version Control System (VCS). In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll see the popular Git version control system in action and learn how to improve your collaborative workflow whether you’re a software engineer, novelist, or art designer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.collaboration-across-universes-basics-of-version-control-with-git.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Free Guided Tour of Tech Learning Collective Foundations</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/event-2020-08-09-free-guided-tour-of-tech-learning-collective-foundations" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Free Guided Tour of Tech Learning Collective Foundations" /><published>2020-08-09T17:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-09T17:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/event-2020-08-09-free-guided-tour-of-tech-learning-collective-foundations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/event-2020-08-09-free-guided-tour-of-tech-learning-collective-foundations">&lt;p&gt;Just getting started learning computer technologies? Join Tech Learning Collective instructors for this free, guided tour of the Tech Learning Collective Foundations curriculum. These self-paced courses and practice labs are great for jump-starting your learning as they introduce you to the most important foundations of Tech Learning Collective course material, such as command line basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;We are asking for a $10 suggested &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;donation&lt;/a&gt; if you can afford it. Help support our incredible teachers and expert support teams! No one will be turned away for lack of funds.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot;&gt;Click here to support Tech Learning Collective with your donation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;form action=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;cmd&quot; value=&quot;_s-xclick&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;hosted_button_id&quot; value=&quot;PW4TUNMA53J3J&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;input type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_donate_LG.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; name=&quot;submit&quot; alt=&quot;Donate with PayPal&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or scan or click this QR code to donate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=PW4TUNMA53J3J&amp;amp;source=url&quot; style=&quot;display: block; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/qr-code.donate.paypal.png&quot; alt=&quot;QR code for PayPal donation.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for your support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our online events, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gobrunch.com/events/119870&quot;&gt;CLICK HERE TO JOIN THE EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Just getting started learning computer technologies? Join Tech Learning Collective instructors for this free, guided tour of the Tech Learning Collective Foundations curriculum. These self-paced courses and practice labs are great for jump-starting your learning as they introduce you to the most important foundations of Tech Learning Collective course material, such as command line basics.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.generic.tech-learning-collective.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.generic.tech-learning-collective.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Imitation Game: Introduction to Administering Virtual Machine Systems</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-08-the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Imitation Game: Introduction to Administering Virtual Machine Systems" /><published>2020-08-08T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-08T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-08-the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-08-the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems">&lt;p&gt;This workshop is a practical introduction to creating, using, and administering virtual machine (VM) systems. Even if you’ve never heard of a virtual machine before, you probably already use the underlying technology. And you can get a lot out of using a virtual machine even if you aren’t a software developer because they can help secure your Web browsing activity, give you a sandbox in which to try out new software, and much more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Virtualization and containerization are concepts almost as old as computing itself so, no matter what you’re doing on your computer, you’re probably using one form of it or another. For example, partitioning a hard disk chunks its total capacity into smaller units useful for specific purposes, much like the individual drawers in a dresser might separate undergarments from outerwear. Organizing, or “containerizing,” your closet this way is useful in its own right because it helps you keep things neat and orderly. But this organizing method also offers dramatic security enhancements because a misbehaving program (or dirty sock) will be confined to its own container.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today, virtualization has become integral to how desktop computers, servers, and global data networks work, and cross-platform, Free Software virtualization programs have never been easier to use. Storage virtualization makes it possible for a single file on your computer to appear to be an entire hard disk drive (such as provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.veracrypt.fr/&quot;&gt;VeraCrypt&lt;/a&gt;), network virtualization makes it possible to simulate different networks (e.g., using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_LAN&quot;&gt;VLANs&lt;/a&gt;) or even the whole Internet (using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inetsim.org/&quot;&gt;INetSim&lt;/a&gt;), processor virtualization makes it possible to run programs built for one microchip architecture on computers running a completely different one (e.g., in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qemu.org/&quot;&gt;QEMU&lt;/a&gt;), and fully-fledged virtual machine monitors (VMMs) or hypervisors can construct and modify entire hardware environments complete with virtual video monitors and other peripherals on the fly (as is offered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.proxmox.com/&quot;&gt;Proxmox&lt;/a&gt;). Virtualization is even the bedrock of numerous Operating System and Web browser security features, such as in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qubes-os.org/&quot;&gt;Qubes Operating System&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/archive/documentation/Security/Conceptual/AppSandboxDesignGuide/AboutAppSandbox/AboutAppSandbox.html&quot;&gt;macOS’s App Sandbox&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/kb/containers&quot;&gt;Firefox Containers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Whether you’re using your computer for fun or for profit, this workshop will get you up and running with Virtual Machines using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualbox.org/&quot;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; type-2 hypervisor so you can experiment with unfamiliar software more boldly, browse the Web more safely, and play games you otherwise wouldn’t have been able to. By learning how to take advantage of the virtualization capabilities your computer already offers, you can revive your love of that long-lost DOS point-and-click adventure, reliably build and test single- and multi-machine networked software systems, or simply create an almost unlimited number of purpose-built virtual machines that all exist, like inception, inside your existing laptop or other personal computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-08-08-the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">This workshop is a practical introduction to creating, using, and administering virtual machine (VM) systems. Even if you’ve never heard of a virtual machine before, you probably already use the underlying technology. And you can get a lot out of using a virtual machine even if you aren’t a software developer because they can help secure your Web browsing activity, give you a sandbox in which to try out new software, and much more!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Taming Daemons: System Administration and Operation Basics</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-06-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taming Daemons: System Administration and Operation Basics" /><published>2020-08-06T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-06T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-06-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-06-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics">&lt;p&gt;Most individuals with access to a computer system have more power today than ever before, but rarely do they make use of it or even know how much power they truly have. In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll begin learning how to “speak with the machines.” By learning to communicate more expressively with the digital devices that are increasingly responsible for mediating contemporary society, you’ll gain the power to effectively and materially change your relationship not only with your laptop, but with global systems of law, finance, and even art, literature, and philosophy governing today’s world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How much good does a powerful tool do for you if you don’t know how to use it well? How much more capable would you be if you mastered all the tools available to you? It might sound ridiculous, but failing to learn the practicalities of computer system operation basics is arguably the most common mistake people in the fast-paced tech scene make.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Modern computers are power tools, and behind each one of them is a human operator, or “system administrator,” responsible for configuring and maintaining that computer. If you have a personal computer such as a laptop or smartphone, then you are already a system administrator whether you realize it or not! Making sure the apps you want to use are installed and up to date, managing the amount of free space you have for your photos, and connecting or disconnecting from the Internet are all examples of simple system administration tasks that you probably already take on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner’s workshop, we’ll start by exploring what happens inside your computer when you take every-day tasks like open a Web browser or save files, and then dive down the rabbit hole to meet the special class of programs that make it possible for all your other programs to work. Called &lt;em&gt;daemons&lt;/em&gt;, short for Disk Access and Execution Monitors, they make up the world of Operating System services, signals, sockets, and more under the hood of your desktop environment. By the end of this workshop, you’ll have a far deeper understanding of how to care for your computer, as well as the ability to understand any new tools or services you encounter a whole lot faster than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-08-06-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Most individuals with access to a computer system have more power today than ever before, but rarely do they make use of it or even know how much power they truly have. In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll begin learning how to “speak with the machines.” By learning to communicate more expressively with the digital devices that are increasingly responsible for mediating contemporary society, you’ll gain the power to effectively and materially change your relationship not only with your laptop, but with global systems of law, finance, and even art, literature, and philosophy governing today’s world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Developing Digital Dexterity: Introduction to JavaScript</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-04-developing-digital-dexterity-introduction-to-javascript" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Developing Digital Dexterity: Introduction to JavaScript" /><published>2020-08-04T16:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-04T16:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-04-developing-digital-dexterity-introduction-to-javascript</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2020/08/workshop-2020-08-04-developing-digital-dexterity-introduction-to-javascript">&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is known for being “the Web programming language,” and while its capabilities in a Web browser have grown considerably, today JavaScript can also be used to automate mundane office jobs (e.g., Google Apps Script, Microsoft Office’s JavaScript API), develop PC games (using GDevelop), and much more. Learn what you need to know to get started with JavaScript in any environment in this workshop covering some common programming concepts as well as the quirks of the JavaScript language itself (functional scope, prototype-based object inheritance, etc.) so you can increase your digital dexterity whether in a Web browser, office job, or your own project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Over the course of ten days in 1995, the Web changed forever when Brendan Eich was hired by Netscape, Inc. and developed a programming language that could be embedded in Web pages. Briefly named LiveScript, the language became known as JavaScript three months later, and was officially standardized as ECMAScript in 1997 after taking the Internet by storm only two years later. Today, JavaScript is arguably the single most popular and prolific high-level language available to many people for many projects.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Although most people know of JavaScript as the programming language of the Web, where &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API&quot;&gt;its capabilities&lt;/a&gt; have increased dramatically over the years, many other environments outside of the Web browser or traditional Web application now embed or rely on JavaScript engines to work. Entire back-end applications can be created with “server-side JavaScript” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ringojs.org/&quot;&gt;RingoJS&lt;/a&gt;), Internet-of-Things (IoT) devices like sensors and larger microcontrollers offer JavaScript scriptable interfaces (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.espruino.com/&quot;&gt;Espruino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neonious.com/lowjs/&quot;&gt;low.js&lt;/a&gt;), mundane office jobs and “paperwork” can be accomplished in JavaScript (&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.openoffice.org/wiki/Documentation/DevGuide/Scripting/JavaScript_Editor&quot;&gt;OpenOffice&lt;/a&gt;/LibreOffice Script Provider, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/apps-script/&quot;&gt;Google Apps Script&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/javascript/api/overview&quot;&gt;Microsoft Office JavaScript API&lt;/a&gt;), desktop and PC game programming can be done entirely in JavaScript (&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdevelop-app.com/javascript-game-engine/&quot;&gt;GDevelop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.babylonjs.com/&quot;&gt;Babylon.js&lt;/a&gt;), some other programming languages are implemented in JavaScript (&lt;a href=&quot;https://scratch.mit.edu/&quot;&gt;Scratch&lt;/a&gt;), and JavaScript can even be used for macOS system automation tasks using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AppleScript#Open_Scripting_Architecture&quot;&gt;Open Scripting Architecture (OSA) JavaScript for Automation extension&lt;/a&gt;. Almost no other programming language is as easy to learn while offering the breadth of options that JavaScript does, which is one clear reason for the language’s popularity among developers and desirability among employers.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop, you’ll learn what you need to know to get started with JavaScript in any environment. By focusing on the language’s built-in constructs, you’ll be able to avoid many common pitfalls and understand what makes JavaScript tick. We’ll cover some programming basics common to all languages, but we’ll also show how JavaScript’s unusual rules (functional scope, prototype-based object inheritance, etc.) make it possible to write especially elegant—or especially dangerous—code, as well as showing you why developing even minimal proficiency with JavaScript will drastically increase your “digital dexterity” as you browse the Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2020-08-04-developing-digital-dexterity-introduction-to-javascript&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">JavaScript is known for being “the Web programming language,” and while its capabilities in a Web browser have grown considerably, today JavaScript can also be used to automate mundane office jobs (e.g., Google Apps Script, Microsoft Office’s JavaScript API), develop PC games (using GDevelop), and much more. Learn what you need to know to get started with JavaScript in any environment in this workshop covering some common programming concepts as well as the quirks of the JavaScript language itself (functional scope, prototype-based object inheritance, etc.) so you can increase your digital dexterity whether in a Web browser, office job, or your own project.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.developing-digital-dexterity-introduction-to-javascript.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.developing-digital-dexterity-introduction-to-javascript.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>