<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2022-03-20T02:30:26-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective | Events</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">The Web as a Language: What No One Ever Told You About HTML That You Didn’t Know To Ask</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/04/workshop-2022-04-10-the-web-as-a-language-what-no-one-ever-told-you-about-html-that-you-didnt-know-to-ask" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Web as a Language: What No One Ever Told You About HTML That You Didn’t Know To Ask" /><published>2022-04-10T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-10T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/04/workshop-2022-04-10-the-web-as-a-language-what-no-one-ever-told-you-about-html-that-you-didnt-know-to-ask</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/04/workshop-2022-04-10-the-web-as-a-language-what-no-one-ever-told-you-about-html-that-you-didnt-know-to-ask">&lt;p&gt;To take full advantage of the Web, especially as a digital publishing medium, you need to start by using the full expressive power of its most fundamental part: the simple HTML “Web page.” This workshop covers HTML, the HyperText Markup Language, as though it were a language in which you can write poems as well as tables of facts and figures, because it is! Learn how to structure your pages in digital rhyme and meter and find out why this approach results in better code for both beautiful designs and automated processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Hypertext Markup Language (HTML) is the de-facto standard for publishing information online, a kind of digital equivalent to learning to read and write. Why, then, is it so rarely explained in terms of the &lt;em&gt;language&lt;/em&gt; that it actually is? What is HTML’s grammar, where do HTML “sentences” begin and end, and how is meaning represented in its elements? You don’t need a computer science degree to learn a foreign language, and that includes HTML.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This workshop is designed for anyone who ever wanted to toy with HTML once or twice, whether it was in the 90’s or just last week. Based on a portion of the &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/web101.html&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s WEB101 course&lt;/a&gt;, it is a remarkably thorough treatment of some of the Web’s most powerful and most-often overlooked parts. Covering the structure of HTML and extending to the richness of semantic data formats like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microdata_%28HTML%29&quot;&gt;Microdata&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RDFa&quot;&gt;RDFa&lt;/a&gt;, learn how to write in the Web’s native language so that both humans (like your friends and comrades) and machines (like Google!) can find, use, and most importantly &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; what you’re saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-04-10-the-web-as-a-language-what-no-one-ever-told-you-about-html-that-you-didnt-know-to-ask&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">To take full advantage of the Web, especially as a digital publishing medium, you need to start by using the full expressive power of its most fundamental part: the simple HTML “Web page.” This workshop covers HTML, the HyperText Markup Language, as though it were a language in which you can write poems as well as tables of facts and figures, because it is! Learn how to structure your pages in digital rhyme and meter and find out why this approach results in better code for both beautiful designs and automated processes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.the-web-as-a-language-what-no-one-ever-told-you-about-html-that-you-didnt-know-to-ask.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.the-web-as-a-language-what-no-one-ever-told-you-about-html-that-you-didnt-know-to-ask.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Exploring Cyberspace: Network Sniffing and Scanning</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/04/workshop-2022-04-09-exploring-cyberspace-network-sniffing-and-scanning" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring Cyberspace: Network Sniffing and Scanning" /><published>2022-04-09T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-09T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/04/workshop-2022-04-09-exploring-cyberspace-network-sniffing-and-scanning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/04/workshop-2022-04-09-exploring-cyberspace-network-sniffing-and-scanning">&lt;p&gt;Come exploring with us as we show you how to map out interconnections between computers, trace packet routes across network gateways, and find information about network operators. In this workshop all about the voyages of frames, packets, and segments, we use tools like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt; to send probes into cyberspace and tap into the wire with Wireshark to understand how they function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered what’s between your computer and the websites you visit? Are you curious about where your messages actually go in order to get from here to there? Do you wonder what a map of computer networks really looks like? Come exploring with us as we embark on a journey into cyberspace, the final Final Frontier! In this beginner-friendly workshop, we’ll throw a metaphorical message in a bottle into the expanse of cyberspace, and learn how to sense and track its movement as it makes its way back to us—or not!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;These are the voyages of frames, packets, and segments—our messages—as they make their way across the vast reaches of the Internet. On the way, they’ll encounter both friendly and unfriendly devices, such as routers, firewalls, traffic inspectors, or NAT tables. At each step of their journey, a complex series of decisions are made to determine where they’ll be routed to next, or if their journey is at an end. By using network mapping tools such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://nmap.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; along with digital wiretapping tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wireshark.org/&quot;&gt;Wireshark&lt;/a&gt; we can sense what happens on the far side of a network connection in much the same way as looking at the ripples on the surface of a river can tell us something about the shape of the riverbed.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Join us to explore strange new networks, to seek out new devices and new organizations, to boldly go where only packets have gone before!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-04-09-exploring-cyberspace-network-sniffing-and-scanning&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Come exploring with us as we show you how to map out interconnections between computers, trace packet routes across network gateways, and find information about network operators. In this workshop all about the voyages of frames, packets, and segments, we use tools like nmap to send probes into cyberspace and tap into the wire with Wireshark to understand how they function.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.exploring-cyberspace-network-sniffing-and-scanning.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.exploring-cyberspace-network-sniffing-and-scanning.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Clearing Away the Clouds: How Computer Networks, Servers, and the Internet Work</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/04/workshop-2022-04-03-clearing-away-the-clouds-how-computer-networks-servers-and-the-internet-work" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clearing Away the Clouds: How Computer Networks, Servers, and the Internet Work" /><published>2022-04-03T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-03T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/04/workshop-2022-04-03-clearing-away-the-clouds-how-computer-networks-servers-and-the-internet-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/04/workshop-2022-04-03-clearing-away-the-clouds-how-computer-networks-servers-and-the-internet-work">&lt;p&gt;Learn the basics of computer networking in this workshop that starts by watching a “conversation” between two computers as it’s happening in real time. You’ll be introduced to the free professional network analysis application called Wireshark so that you can listen in on what the programs on your computer are saying to or hearing from other computers across the Internet. By the end of this workshop, you’ll understand all about the basics of computer networking. If you’ve ever been curious about what happens “on the wire” when you’re browsing a Web site, or if you ever wanted to take a look “under the hood” of your Wi-Fi connection, this is the class for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Our ability to browse Web sites, send and receive digital messages like emails and text messages, and make phone or video calls depends on the connections our digital devices make with one another. That makes it critical to understand how these connections are made, and where they lead to. Far from being an amorphous “cloud,” modern telecommunications networks and services like the Internet are made up of physical devices. Some of these you can see, like your own computer or the router and modem in your house, and others you can’t, like distant servers or Layer 2 switches that make up the network infrastructure itself.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop derived from a portion of the &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/net101.html&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s NET101 course&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll have the opportunity to actually look—visually and with great detail—at how your computer “talks” to other computers like those that power Google Drive, Facebook, and other cloud services. By using an industry-standard tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://wireshark.org/&quot;&gt;Wireshark&lt;/a&gt;, we’ll dissect a conversation between your computer and a server and walk through the process of encapsulating a packet of application layer data, emitting it onto a network, and watching it travel to its destination. We’ll also touch on some illustrative counter-examples to explore how things can go wrong on a network, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamic_Host_Configuration_Protocol&quot;&gt;DHCP&lt;/a&gt; server misconfigurations, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ARP_spoofing&quot;&gt;ARP spoofing attacks&lt;/a&gt;, and unsecured or weakly-secured Wi-Fi networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-04-03-clearing-away-the-clouds-how-computer-networks-servers-and-the-internet-work&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn the basics of computer networking in this workshop that starts by watching a “conversation” between two computers as it’s happening in real time. You’ll be introduced to the free professional network analysis application called Wireshark so that you can listen in on what the programs on your computer are saying to or hearing from other computers across the Internet. By the end of this workshop, you’ll understand all about the basics of computer networking. If you’ve ever been curious about what happens “on the wire” when you’re browsing a Web site, or if you ever wanted to take a look “under the hood” of your Wi-Fi connection, this is the class for you!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.clearing-away-the-clouds-how-computer-networks-servers-and-the-internet-work.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.clearing-away-the-clouds-how-computer-networks-servers-and-the-internet-work.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Something for Everyone: File Servers and Other Network Attached Storage</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/04/workshop-2022-04-02-something-for-everyone-file-servers-and-other-network-attached-storage" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Something for Everyone: File Servers and Other Network Attached Storage" /><published>2022-04-02T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-02T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/04/workshop-2022-04-02-something-for-everyone-file-servers-and-other-network-attached-storage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/04/workshop-2022-04-02-something-for-everyone-file-servers-and-other-network-attached-storage">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to provide file sharing services by creating your own networked file server so that your family, friends, or colleagues have a private place to save, share, and work on documents or photos together. Maintaining the humble file server is among the most fundamental Information Technology (IT) department tasks in businesses or organizations big and small because most other activities revolve around document storage and retrieval. In this workshop, you’ll be introduced to numerous free and open technologies such as Nextcloud that can replace more familiar Web-based online file storage services like Google Docs, along with many of the file sharing protocols integral to Network Attached Storage (NAS) devices used in today’s enterprises, like NFS, SMB, and WebDAV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As early as 1964, computer makers like IBM, Inc. were publicizing the idea that businesses could use computers to eliminate or drastically reduce the drudgery and tedium of paperwork by converting paper documents into electronic files. Of course, even today not all businesses have what IBM promised would be a “paperless office,” but many of them have a rapidly growing number of important digital documents that need to be stored reliably, secured properly, and shared privately. This is what makes the humble file server a centerpiece of Information Technology (IT) department responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;These days, however, it’s not just businesses who must manage loads of electronic documents. As society becomes increasingly digitized, individuals, community groups, political organizers, and even hobbyists are much more reliant on electronic files today than we have ever been before. This is where familiar Web-based online file storage services like Google Docs, Microsoft Office 365, and Dropbox Paper come in, making it easy for people to save their work in “the cloud,” as long as they’re comfortable letting the company providing the storage service have a peek at their work. But like most things in the Internet age, the file storage and retrieval services that these companies offer are built on the back of Free, Libre, and Open Source Software programs and protocols available to everyone from individuals to large enterprises without paying a dime for them in either monetary cost or privacy exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop, you’ll learn what it takes to build your own online file storage service for yourself, for a small group of friends, or for a much larger organization. Starting with a simple “shared folder,” you’ll get introduced to network protocols like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebDAV&quot;&gt;WebDAV&lt;/a&gt; to see how they enable Web-based distributed authoring and versioning of files including Word documents, Excel spreadsheets, and PDFs, and how these protocols fit into enterprise-ready file storage systems like &lt;a href=&quot;https://nextcloud.com/&quot;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll also discuss filesystem-level networked filing protocols that define a whole category of computer equipment called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network-attached_storage&quot;&gt;Network-Attached Storage (NAS)&lt;/a&gt; devices like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SSH_File_Transfer_Protocol&quot;&gt;(Secure) File Transfer Protocol (SFTP)&lt;/a&gt; that are common in Web hosting environments, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_File_System_%28protocol%29&quot;&gt;Network File System (NFS)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Server_Message_Block&quot;&gt;Server Message Block (SMB)&lt;/a&gt; protocols that are common in homes and offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-04-02-something-for-everyone-file-servers-and-other-network-attached-storage&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to provide file sharing services by creating your own networked file server so that your family, friends, or colleagues have a private place to save, share, and work on documents or photos together. Maintaining the humble file server is among the most fundamental Information Technology (IT) department tasks in businesses or organizations big and small because most other activities revolve around document storage and retrieval. In this workshop, you’ll be introduced to numerous free and open technologies such as Nextcloud that can replace more familiar Web-based online file storage services like Google Docs, along with many of the file sharing protocols integral to Network Attached Storage (NAS) devices used in today’s enterprises, like NFS, SMB, and WebDAV.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.something-for-everyone-file-servers-and-other-network-attached-storage.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.something-for-everyone-file-servers-and-other-network-attached-storage.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bare Bones Crypto: Understanding Critical Cryptographic Primitives</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-27-bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bare Bones Crypto: Understanding Critical Cryptographic Primitives" /><published>2022-03-27T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-03-27T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-27-bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-27-bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives">&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to have your doctorate in theoretical mathematics to understand crypto enough to use it safely, but you do need to use it safely to be secure! Come learn the magic behind the math in this cryptography primer for those of us who are not “number people.” Using simplified examples and hands-on demonstrations, this workshop (finally!) offers a practical, accessible introduction to the foundations of modern cryptographic security protocols such as RSA public-key cryptography, stream and block ciphers, digital signatures, one-way hash functions, Hash-based Message Authentication Codes (HMACs), and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every time you use a modern computer, you invoke numerous simple mathematical functions that make it possible to do things like logging in to Web sites safely or “locking” (encrypting) your secret documents behind passwords. At their root, these functions, called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptographic_primitive&quot;&gt;cryptographic primitives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, are not that much more complicated than simple addition or division. But when used in concert with the massive storage capacities and processing speeds of our modern electronic devices, they serve as the bedrock atop which every provably secure system works, from &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Password-Superpowers-How-to-Crack-Hashes-and-Stump-Hackers&quot;&gt;password vaults&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Two-Places-at-Once-Understanding-Virtual-Private-Networks&quot;&gt;Virtual Private Networks (VPNs)&lt;/a&gt; to BitCoin and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today, everyone has full access to bulletproof “military grade encryption” for free, even if they don’t realize it. &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Signal-and-Surveillance-How-to-Exercise-Digital-Civil-Liberties-in-a-Surveillance-State&quot;&gt;Signal Private Messenger&lt;/a&gt;’s “Safety Numbers?” Those are cryptographic hash functions! One-time passwords generated by apps like Google Authenticator or Authy? They use nonces! The &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Tor-What-is-it-Good-For-(Absolutely-Everything!)&quot;&gt;Tor anonymity network&lt;/a&gt;? That’s a mixnet! The padlock icon in the address bar of your Web browser? Block ciphers (and public-key cryptography, and digital signatures, oh my)!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Knowledge of cryptography was deemed so dangerous during the Cold War that ever since the end of World War II the United States and its military allies attempted to regulate access to these crypto powers by classifying them as “munitions” (i.e., mathematical &lt;em&gt;weapons&lt;/em&gt;, literally) and criminalizing their sale or export. But as the Internet gained widespread commercial adoption and more people became familiar with the underlying math, the government largely relented. It eventually lost what is now retroactively known as the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crypto_Wars&quot;&gt;Crypto Wars&lt;/a&gt;” in the 1990’s.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop, you’ll learn the kind of math that governments tried to keep secret for decades, even if you’re “not a math person.” You’ll see hash functions in practice, learn why longer “keys” are stronger by understanding how RSA secrets are generated, practice developing your own simple ciphers, and start combining primitives to create security protocols that satisfy multiple requirements like confidentiality (privacy), integrity-protection (authenticity), and more. By the end of this workshop, the dizzying vocabulary crytographers use will be well within your reach, as will the ability to understand any new “encryption” product on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-03-27-bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">You don’t need to have your doctorate in theoretical mathematics to understand crypto enough to use it safely, but you do need to use it safely to be secure! Come learn the magic behind the math in this cryptography primer for those of us who are not “number people.” Using simplified examples and hands-on demonstrations, this workshop (finally!) offers a practical, accessible introduction to the foundations of modern cryptographic security protocols such as RSA public-key cryptography, stream and block ciphers, digital signatures, one-way hash functions, Hash-based Message Authentication Codes (HMACs), and more.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Automate All the Things: A Primer to Infrastructure as Code</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-26-automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automate All the Things: A Primer to Infrastructure as Code" /><published>2022-03-26T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-03-26T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-26-automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-26-automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to make your own Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), automatically install software on the servers in your cloud, and write executable runbooks to automatically perform upgrades and other maintenance with the press of a button. With today’s modern automation toolkits, a two-person hobby project can outperform a 100-person company, as long as they use the right tools the right way. In this workshop, you’ll get a practical introduction to cloud infrastructure automation with tools like Ansible, Vagrant, and Terraform, and a chance to solidify your understanding of fundamental DevOps skills that every IT professional needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In today’s IT environments, application servers, databases, file shares, and even network devices are too numerous for any individual or team to provision, configure, and administer one at a time. To deploy, maintain, and secure large digital fleets, site reliability engineers leverage the inherent power of computerized automation to perform everything from daily tasks (patching, updating code) to critical but rare operations (migrations, incident response). But even small groups can take advantage of this sort of automation to massively amplify their impact; today, a two-person hobby project can outperform a 100-person company if they use the right tools the right way.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Generically called &lt;em&gt;Infrastructure as Code (IaC)&lt;/em&gt;, modern configuration management tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ansible.com/&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chef.io/&quot;&gt;Chef&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://saltstack.com/&quot;&gt;SaltStack&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://puppet.com/&quot;&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt; make it possible for a single operator to paralellize executing Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) like initiating backups or performing blue-green deployments on hundreds or thousands of machines at once. By using virtualization through IaC tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://vagrantup.com/&quot;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt;, entire “cloud” environments can be emulated for heterogenous development teams, massively streamlining everything from software development, to R&amp;amp;D, to education and onboarding. (Tech Learning Collective’s own course exercises and practice labs are defined in code as Vagrant configurations!) Encoding your organization’s infrastructure requirements in standard, vendor-neutral, open formats such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://terraform.io/&quot;&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt; means you can switch from one infrastructure provider to another with ease. But perhaps most important of all, “automating all the things” means that potential disasters like ransomware extortion attempts, outages, or even mere accidents can be audited, diagnosed, and remediated in a matter of minutes instead of days or weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop, you’ll get a practical introduction to cloud infrastructure automation. You’ll learn how to create your first virtual private cloud (VPC), add multiple machines to it, automatically install server software on those machines, and write exectuable runbooks to automatically perform upgrades and other maintenance tasks on your new infrastructure. Whether you’re already administering a fleet of servers at work, or just want to slim your “weekend project” time down to size, this far-reaching workshop will solidify your understanding of the development operations (DevOps) skills every IT professional needs to hone to have success with modern digital infrastructure projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-03-26-automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to make your own Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), automatically install software on the servers in your cloud, and write executable runbooks to automatically perform upgrades and other maintenance with the press of a button. With today’s modern automation toolkits, a two-person hobby project can outperform a 100-person company, as long as they use the right tools the right way. In this workshop, you’ll get a practical introduction to cloud infrastructure automation with tools like Ansible, Vagrant, and Terraform, and a chance to solidify your understanding of fundamental DevOps skills that every IT professional needs.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">File Sharing for Fun and Profit: How BitTorrent Works and What You Can Do With It</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-20-file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="File Sharing for Fun and Profit: How BitTorrent Works and What You Can Do With It" /><published>2022-03-20T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-03-20T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-20-file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-20-file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it">&lt;p&gt;BitTorrent, the wildly popular but often maligned file sharing protocol, is now being used in everything from (legal!) video streaming sites to corporate software update servers, but you wouldn’t know that if you only listened to Big Media groups like the RIAA. In this beginner-friendly workshop, we’ll bust BitTorrent myths and set the record straight about what “torrenting” actually is, how it works, and what you can do with it. You’ll see how next generation “decentralized” Web applications are making use of the technology, how companies like Facebook and Blizzard, Inc. use it every day, how to make your own “torrents” to share files of your own, and how and why some people take protective measures to torrent more privately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you’ve heard anything about “downloading free movies on the Internet,” you probably heard of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BitTorrent&quot;&gt;BitTorrent&lt;/a&gt; or its more colloquial synonym, “torrents.” You have also probably heard of companies threatening BitTorrent users with Internet service bans, financial penalties, and even lawsuits for “stealing intellectual property.“ Through expensive and coordinated disinformation campaigns, companies like Disney and other “Big Content” media conglomerates represented by special interest groups like the Record Industry Association of America (RIAA) and the Motion Picture Association of America (MPAA) have linked BitTorrent with music and movie piracy in the public mind. They continue to try convincing people that BitTorrent is hard, immoral, and unsafe to use, but the reality is far less one-sided.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BitTorrent&lt;/em&gt; refers to a file transfer technology that has been around since 2001 and is designed to make it easy for you to more quickly share very large files across a computer network, even if your computer lacked a high-speed Internet connection. It worked so well that by the end of 2013 there were more than a quarter billion individual BitTorrent users on the Internet. While the media painted this as an epidemic of criminal behavior, most BitTorrent uses were and still are both legal and mundane. Moreover, the heaviest BitTorrent users were actually companies who built the technology into their own products, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.howtogeek.com/141257/htg-explains-how-does-bittorrent-work/&quot;&gt;Blizzard, Inc. (the World of WarCraft company), who used BitTorrent to deliver updates of its game software to players&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today, BitTorrent is still one of the most popular, cost-efficient, and speediest large-file transfer technologies available to both individuals and multinational corporations alike. Cash-strapped Free Software projects such as GNU/Linux distributions use BitTorrent to distribute their installation packages in order to reduce their monthly bandwidth bills, a whole new category of “decentralized Web” applications like &lt;a href=&quot;https://zeronet.io/&quot;&gt;ZeroNet&lt;/a&gt; are using BitTorrent under the hood to make Web publishing easier and more censorship-resistant than ever before, and traditional Web sites with large bandwidth requirements like video streaming sites (e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinpeertube.org/en/&quot;&gt;PeerTube&lt;/a&gt;) are increasingly adopting a newer variant called &lt;a href=&quot;https://webtorrent.io/faq&quot;&gt;WebTorrent&lt;/a&gt; to improve download speeds and interoperate with the massive existing BitTorrent network.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner-friendly workshop, we’ll bust BitTorrent myths and set the record straight about what “torrenting” actually is, how it works, and what you can do with it. Learn how to find, download, and even create your own torrents so you can share files with friends and colleagues regardless of network obstacles like firewalls or NAT routers. Bring a laptop and you’ll be able to participate in a (legal and safe!) BitTorrent “swarm.” We’ll also discuss the implications of using BitTorrent for less-than-legal ends, and demonstrate steps you can take to improve your privacy such as enabling BitTorrent encryption, connecting to trackers through public proxies and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Two-Places-at-Once-Understanding-Virtual-Private-Networks&quot;&gt;Virtual Private Networks&lt;/a&gt;, and building private &lt;a href=&quot;https://seedboxgui.de/&quot;&gt;seedboxes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-03-20-file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">BitTorrent, the wildly popular but often maligned file sharing protocol, is now being used in everything from (legal!) video streaming sites to corporate software update servers, but you wouldn’t know that if you only listened to Big Media groups like the RIAA. In this beginner-friendly workshop, we’ll bust BitTorrent myths and set the record straight about what “torrenting” actually is, how it works, and what you can do with it. You’ll see how next generation “decentralized” Web applications are making use of the technology, how companies like Facebook and Blizzard, Inc. use it every day, how to make your own “torrents” to share files of your own, and how and why some people take protective measures to torrent more privately.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.file-sharing-for-fun-and-profit-how-bittorrent-works-and-what-you-can-do-with-it.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Signal and Surveillance: How to Exercise Digital Civil Liberties in a Surveillance State</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-19-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Signal and Surveillance: How to Exercise Digital Civil Liberties in a Surveillance State" /><published>2022-03-19T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-03-19T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-19-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-19-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state">&lt;p&gt;This introductory cybersecurity workshop will show you why Signal, a free, secure, private message app is simple enough to schedule drinks with, yet secure enough to use for planning a protest. As dragnet surveillance practices are legalized at alarming speed, there has never been a more important time to flex your digital civil liberties muscle than right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whether you’re an individual chatting with friends or an organizer planning a political action, all effective coordination depends on safe and reliable communication. Lacking integrity for our communications dooms any effort from the outset, whether mundane or revolutionary. As dragnet surveillance practices are legalized at alarming speed and continue to be fueled by a dramatic expansion of the law enforcement and private defense contractor economies, there has never been a more important time to flex your digital civil liberties muscle than right now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; is the name of a Free Software, secure, private message application built on a cryptographic protocol of the same name. Formerly known as the Axolotl Ratchet or, more commonly, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Double_Ratchet_Algorithm&quot;&gt;Double-Ratchet Algorithm&lt;/a&gt;, its features are robust enough for the revolutionary activist (i.e., end-to-end encryption, message authentication, plausible deniability or message repudiation, perfect forward secrecy, and more) and yet simple enough to use as a drop-in replacement for your existing text messaging application. Signal also sports Skype-like voice and video calling, location- and file-sharing features, and even iMessage-style large font emojis!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you’ve never heard of Signal before, now’s the time to switch. If you think you already know how to use Signal, let us show you some pro-tips (trusted third-party Safety Number verification, disappearing messages, registering Signal accounts with pseudonymous phone numbers, inactivity lock-outs, and Signal relay server IP address protection). This introductory cybersecurity workshop will show you why Signal is simple enough to schedule drinks at the bar with, yet secure enough to use for planning a protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-03-19-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">This introductory cybersecurity workshop will show you why Signal, a free, secure, private message app is simple enough to schedule drinks with, yet secure enough to use for planning a protest. As dragnet surveillance practices are legalized at alarming speed, there has never been a more important time to flex your digital civil liberties muscle than right now.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Down the Rabbit Hole: Anonymous Publishing on the Darknet</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-13-down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Down the Rabbit Hole: Anonymous Publishing on the Darknet" /><published>2022-03-13T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-03-13T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-13-down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-13-down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet">&lt;p&gt;Get your message out without revealing who you are by publishing anonymously on the “Darknet.” This workshop shows you how to create Tor Onion services for Web sites through free tools like OnionShare, and even by setting up Tor servers that are built and configured from scratch manually. You’ll learn about how Tor helps keep both publishers and consumers private and anonymous online, as well as how law enforcement might successfully de-anonymize poorly configured Onion services through host bypass, fingerprint correlation, and other similar attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s often said that if you want to tell people the truth, you’d better make them laugh—or they’ll kill you. Sometimes, humor isn’t a sufficient defense. For these situations, the only remaining defense is to become anonymous. In this deep-dive workshop on anonymous Internet publishing, you’ll learn about a special class of proxy server called a Tor Onion service that makes it possible to publish Web sites or offer network-capable services more or, if you’re really skilled, completely anonymously.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Publishing something truly anonymously on the Internet today is getting more and more difficult. And yet, with “real name” requirements pushed by social media giants like Facebook, law enforcement agents demanding travelers’ online usernames and passwords at border crossings, and global political campaigns to undermine or outright backdoor privacy-preserving encryption technologies, anonymous publishing is also getting more and more important. Whistleblowers need to be able to leak or publish anonymously to stay safe from legal and especially extralegal reprisals, and so too do politically vocal bloggers, investigative journalists, and citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this specialized workshop, you’ll see how Darknet Web sites like the now-famous Silk Road, as well as less controversial Web sites like the New York Times, actually use the same underlying technology called Tor Onion services to create their respective censorship-resistant publications. You’ll also be exposed to some of the techniques that law enforcement often tries to use to de-anonymize Onion services, and learn how to defend against them. By the end of this workshop, you’ll have a working knowledge of numerous critical modern technologies including Web servers, network relays, and Tor’s famous onion-routing protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-03-13-down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Get your message out without revealing who you are by publishing anonymously on the “Darknet.” This workshop shows you how to create Tor Onion services for Web sites through free tools like OnionShare, and even by setting up Tor servers that are built and configured from scratch manually. You’ll learn about how Tor helps keep both publishers and consumers private and anonymous online, as well as how law enforcement might successfully de-anonymize poorly configured Onion services through host bypass, fingerprint correlation, and other similar attacks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.down-the-rabbit-hole-anonymous-publishing-on-the-darknet.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Where the Sky Meets the Sea: Understanding Container Orchestration with Kubernetes</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-12-where-the-sky-meets-the-sea-understanding-container-orchestration-with-kubernetes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Where the Sky Meets the Sea: Understanding Container Orchestration with Kubernetes" /><published>2022-03-12T13:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-12T13:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-12-where-the-sky-meets-the-sea-understanding-container-orchestration-with-kubernetes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/03/workshop-2022-03-12-where-the-sky-meets-the-sea-understanding-container-orchestration-with-kubernetes">&lt;p&gt;Learn to pilot Kubernetes and find out how it helps you get the most value out of your hardware. Kubernetes is the free, enterprise-grade, cloud-native solution for automated deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications. This workshop offers an introduction to container orchestration concepts and practices by showing you how to work effectively with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt;, utilize Labels and Selectors, explore various components of the Kubernetes control plane, and more. You’ll get your own Kubernetes cluster where you can deploy apps, learn how to influence scheduling decisions, and monitor the health of clustered workloads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As anyone who has ever moved house knows, the more effectively you can pack, the easier your move will be. It’s a big task, often requiring thousands of tiny decisions to make sure delicate items are wrapped appropriately, all one’s stuff fits neatly into all the available boxes, and so on. Once the boxes are all packed, loading them onto a moving vehicle requires that you distribute their weight more or less evenly so that there are no unpleasant surprises during the move. This is more or less what container orchestration tools are for, except instead of moving physical bins, we have to ship software inside containers. Each container requires resources, like CPU time and memory space, which means we’ll need to play a sort of Tetris game to make sure all our containers fit in the most dense, yet most balanced, arrangement to keep our hardware costs as low as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; is the free and open source industry standard container orchestration platform that provides both system administrators and application developers with a set of tools for cooperatively building, deploying, and maintaining applications at all levels of scale. Its job is to help you get the most out of your hardware by “packing” all your containers (installed server software) into the fewest possible “bins” (physical or virtual machines), and then automatically monitoring, restarting, adding, removing, or shuffling those containers from one machine to another as demand for the services running on your cluster change. Your job is to tell Kubernetes what your ideal deployment situation is, and what to prioritize when resources get scarce.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this intermediate-level workshop, we’ll build on our knowledge of Linux &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Ship-Shape-Computing-Working-with-Containers-and-Containzerizing-Digital-Workloads&quot;&gt;containers&lt;/a&gt; and fundamental system administration tasks to explore a Kubernetes cluster. You’ll learn how to inspect workloads using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/overview/&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; command line utility, a graphical Web-based dashboard, and the Kubernetes API itself. By exploring the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/overview/components/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes control plane&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll get insight into how Kubernetes makes scheduling decisions and, along with using &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/overview/working-with-objects/labels/&quot;&gt;Labels and Selectors&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll learn how to influence those scheduling decisions by &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/scheduling-eviction/taint-and-toleration/&quot;&gt;tainting&lt;/a&gt; certain resources in specific ways. Finally, you’ll see how Kubernetes provides a set of “cloud-native” services and APIs that developers can use to write apps that spawn more replicas of themselves when needed and perform other forms of automated or self-healing tasks, making the system administrator’s job that much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-03-12-where-the-sky-meets-the-sea-understanding-container-orchestration-with-kubernetes&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn to pilot Kubernetes and find out how it helps you get the most value out of your hardware. Kubernetes is the free, enterprise-grade, cloud-native solution for automated deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications. This workshop offers an introduction to container orchestration concepts and practices by showing you how to work effectively with kubectl, utilize Labels and Selectors, explore various components of the Kubernetes control plane, and more. You’ll get your own Kubernetes cluster where you can deploy apps, learn how to influence scheduling decisions, and monitor the health of clustered workloads.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.where-the-sky-meets-the-sea-understanding-container-orchestration-with-kubernetes.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.where-the-sky-meets-the-sea-understanding-container-orchestration-with-kubernetes.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>