<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2023-07-31T14:25:18-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective | Events</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">Hex90: Birthday Attack</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/07/event-2023-07-08-hex90-birthday-attack" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hex90: Birthday Attack" /><published>2023-07-08T19:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-08T19:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/07/event-2023-07-08-hex90-birthday-attack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/07/event-2023-07-08-hex90-birthday-attack">&lt;p&gt;Queer hackers of the world, unite! Tech Learning Collective is excited to invite you to a very special Hex90 party. Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://hex90.party/&quot;&gt;series of queer hacker salons in New York City, Hex90&lt;/a&gt;, continues this Summer with &lt;cite&gt;Hex90: Birthday Attack&lt;/cite&gt;, so named because we are simultaneously celebrating the birthdays/tranniversaries of several prominent community members. Join us at our favorite indie arcade venue, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wonderville.nyc/&quot;&gt;Wonderville&lt;/a&gt;, for a celebration of trans and non-binary joy, gender affirmation, and the zest for life! Get ready for nostalgic favorites, retro tech, psychedelic, euphoric optimism, and of course prepare to hack the planet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-txt&quot;&gt;HEX90 — a queer hacker salon in NYC

Welcome, witches, wizards, and techno-sorceresses, to our next genesis! The process of becoming is both a moment and a series of discoveries. How much can one change before our new signature no longer matches the old? What you know you can't explain, but you feel it. You've felt it your entire life.

The 1980s was a decade of great technological change. The development of the modern Internet began with the ARPANET. Arcade games became a major industry. Personal computers experienced exponential growth. Boomboxes and the Walkman transformed music culture. Drum machines and electronic instruments dominated the music production landscape. And, let's not forget, epic synthesizers.

The 1990s brought major social upheaval. Many Detroit-based artists propelled techno and house music onto the global stage. Tactics of &quot;digital civil disobedience&quot; pioneered by the Electronic Disturbance Theater captured the imagination of young hacktivists. The Matrix and Transgender Day of Remembrance began in the same year, sewing the seeds of revolutions still to come.

You have to let it all go: fear, doubt, and disbelief. Free your mind! Everything, everything, everything! I'm invisible. How deep does the rabbit hole go? Collide, and find your looking-glass self!

info_

July 8, 2023 @ Wonderville
1186 Broadway, Brooklyn, NY 11221
7:30pm — 4:00am

~ this venue is accessible
~ this venue has gender-neutral restrooms
~ this venue has outdoor space
~ this venue permits entry only to those aged 21+

# dressing up is encouraged but not required

featuring_

~ music performances by
~~ Janus Rose
~~ heaven ender
~~ Niyah West
~~ DJ Softserve
~~ stuttersprite
~~ dis_aster_ous
~~ David Lunch
~~ GENDERLESSBEAST
~ visuals and livecoding by
~~ gwenpri.me
~~ alsoknownasrox
~ indie games by Death By Audio Arcade
~ hacking demos &amp;amp; education by Tech Learning Collective
~ text adventure cybersecurity game by Shift-CTRL Space

DANCE AT THE STAGE, AND BRING YOUR LAPTOP SO YOU CAN HACK AT THE BAR!

In addition to music and visuals, the most unique addition of the Hex90 parties is a hyperlocal cybersecurity (hacking) themed text-adventure game that gave the party its name: Hex90. This game is played on your own laptop, not on a console or arcade cabinet at the venue, but is still only accessible when you are physically at the party venue itself. (Aside from a short &quot;trailer,&quot; the game is not available on the public Internet.)

After you connect to the party's Wi-Fi network, you can then connect to the Hex90 game server using your Web browser. But to solve the challenges, you must download and install real hacker tools and learn how to employ real hacking techniques to progress through game levels ranging from network reconnaissance, applied cryptography, and Web exploitation. You've never seen so many queers open so many terminals in one place while being so close to a dance floor, and there's no high quite like it.

We continuously add levels to the game, so expect new challenges at most parties. Moreover, we sometimes incorporate physical-world features of the venue, like padlocks you need to pick that are safeguarding access to secret passwords, QR codes stashed in unexpected places, unassuming but exposed Ethernet cabling that turns out not to be a mistake at all, and so on. At Hex90, the game controller is your computer and the game mechanic is the real world.

All of the tools, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) used to progress in the game levels are skills taught by and equipment used by Tech Learning Collective instructors in our online workshops. Visit TechLearningCollective.com for more information and to enroll.

#------------------#
# START HACKING AT #
#------------------#
https://hex90.party

#------------------#
# BUY TICKETS HERE #
#------------------#
https://wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-birthday-attack

SUPPORTER TIER:
$30 - pay if you can

ADVANCE TICKETS:
$15.00 - str8 cismen
$10.00 - queers/transes/enbies and femmes

DAY-OF/AT THE DOOR:
$20.00 - str8 cismen
$15.00 - queers/transes/enbies and femmes

/**
* Hex90 is an inclusive event.
* Door staff is instructed to respect your self-identification.
*/

NOTICE:

This is an intentionally queer space. Consent and respect are not optional! Anyone behaving unkindly will be removed immediately without a refund. No amount of racism, queerphobia, transphobia, or sexism will be tolerated. This event is a celebration of queer hacking for queer hackers, not for Silicon Valley entrepreneurs, brogrammers, or BitCoin bros. Don't piss off the hackers. ;)

Hex90

###
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hex90.party/&quot;&gt;Start playing immediately and buy your ticket at the invitation site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-birthday-attack&quot;&gt;$30 - Supporter (pay if you can)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-birthday-attack&quot;&gt;$15 - General Admission - Advance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-birthday-attack&quot;&gt;$10 - Queers and Femmes - Advance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-birthday-attack&quot;&gt;$20 - General Admission - Day-of/at the door&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-birthday-attack&quot;&gt;$15 - Queers and Femmes - Day-of/at the door&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from the event without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-death-by-audio&quot;&gt;About Death By Audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deathbyaudioarcade.com/&quot;&gt;Death By Audio Arcade&lt;/a&gt; is a series of lovingly crafted local multiplayer arcade cabinets produced by local indie game developers. We are also a progressive, open community of like-minded artists, artisans, and enthusiasts. We host events at least once a month, in NYC and at events across the country, from SXSW to the Smithsonian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-heaven-ender&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/heavenender&quot;&gt;heaven ender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;heaven ender is an immortal entity inhabiting the mortal plane of existence seeking to make the world a more beautiful place. Rising from the dark corners of the rave scene they will be presenting one of their unrelenting, genre blurring sets and condemning you to dance for eternity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-niyah-west&quot;&gt;About Niyah West&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Niyah West (she/they) is a DJ, music curator and digital artist based in New York City. From the living rooms of dear friends to the night clubs, Niyah made her professional debut just this year during pride month. Thus, making her a bright newcomer in the queer DJ scene. She has amplified parties and dancefloors all over the boroughs, some recently including MEOW NYC, Gayjoy &amp;amp; a residency at Kind Regards in the Lower East Side. She’s also a resident of Brooklyn based queer DJ collective XOXA NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-stuttersprite&quot;&gt;About stuttersprite&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by a lifelong interest in games, stuttersprite’s psychedelic and emotional high-energy sound explores the crossover between techno, trance, electro, and vgm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-gwenprime&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://gwenpri.me/&quot;&gt;gwenpri.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gwenpri.me is a creative technologist, artist, and livecoder. She makes live visuals from videos, pictures, emoji, text, and more, then composites them using live code techniques. She enjoys finding arcane ways to put pixels on screens. Past sets have included touch designer patching, Lua DSLs, command line video editors, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-alsoknownasrox&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/alsoknownasrox&quot;&gt;alsoknownasrox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;alsoknownasrox is a New York-based audiovisual artist approaching programming as a medium for creative expression. She specializes in programming as performance, modifying real-time processes to create dynamic audiovisual experiences. She spends her time finding new ways to engage with the world, destructing and reconstructing existing structures as she goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-david-lunch&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundcloud.com/davidlunchbox&quot;&gt;David Lunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Lunch (Ben Breier) is a genre-crossing DJ that leans into breakbeat, two-step, Jersey Club, UKG &amp;amp; techno. He is the current host of Zero Chill on Newtown Radio, and the resident DJ at Jade’s Exactly. He has opened for acts that include Crystal Castles, !!! &amp;amp; The Hood Internet. Under the moniker Mister Disco, he was the resident DJ at Happy House (The Bell House) as well as Endmax at Trophy Bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-dj-softserve&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;softserve.the.frost.dj&quot;&gt;DJ Softserve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Softserve began DJing in South Korea in 2017 where he became a local hip hop resident. After a few years he moved on to headlining at Korean EDM festivals and playing Busan’s premiere house and techno clubs. After moving to Brooklyn, he continues to play high energy eclectic bass mixes flexing genre boundaries from latin and afro beats to wonky UK tech, half-time flips and basshouse. He focusing on moving the crowd to “get their tongues hanging out” and is the CEO of saying “damn- I probably should have recorded that set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Queer hackers of the world, unite! Tech Learning Collective is excited to invite you to a very special Hex90 party. Our series of queer hacker salons in New York City, Hex90, continues this Summer with Hex90: Birthday Attack, so named because we are simultaneously celebrating the birthdays/tranniversaries of several prominent community members. Join us at our favorite indie arcade venue, Wonderville, for a celebration of trans and non-binary joy, gender affirmation, and the zest for life! Get ready for nostalgic favorites, retro tech, psychedelic, euphoric optimism, and of course prepare to hack the planet!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.hex90.flyer.2023-07-08.540x540.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.hex90.flyer.2023-07-08.540x540.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hex90: Replay</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/04/event-2023-04-22-hex90-replay" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hex90: Replay" /><published>2023-04-22T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-22T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/04/event-2023-04-22-hex90-replay</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/04/event-2023-04-22-hex90-replay">&lt;p&gt;Queer hackers of the world, unite! Tech Learning Collective is excited to invite you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hex90.party/&quot;&gt;Hex90’s latest queer hacker salon, “replay,”&lt;/a&gt; hosted at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wonderville.nyc/&quot;&gt;Wonderville, where you can buy tickets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-txt&quot;&gt;HEX90 — a queer hacker salon in NYC

Queer hackers of the world, unite! There's a war going on. The battlefield is in the mind. And the prize is the soul. Remember, hacking isn't just a crime. It's a survival trait.

Hacking is not merely about breaking in; it's also about breaking out. You are the embodiment of escape velocity, from megahertz to gigahertz, each of us individual components in a system that cannot keep up with its constituents. You may feel suffocated by it, trapped in its loops, history repeating itself in the closed minds of politicians, pundits, &quot;thought leaders,&quot; or billionaires who kennel you within rings of &quot;protection.&quot; But you are different: you have already seen what comes next.

To move forward, we sometimes must replay pieces of the past. This time, though, we are armed with the experience of a freer future. We have learned their secrets and shared them widely. We can speak their words back to them and claim the power they thought was theirs alone. We are the future they fear because we are already here, and they are the past.

They want to undo us. We will replay them, and win—again.

info_

April 22, 2023 @ Wonderville
1186 Broadway, Brooklyn, NY 11221
8:00pm — 4:00am

~ this venue is accessible
~ this venue has gender-neutral restrooms
~ this venue has outdoor space
~ this venue permits entry only to those aged 21+

# dressing up is encouraged but not required

featuring_

~ music performances by
~~ Nina Vicious
~~ trans kafka
~~ heaven ender
~~ Rana Ransom
~~ dis_aster_ous
~ livecoded visuals by
~~ gwenpri.me
~~ Voyde
~ live analog visuals by
~~ Mike Videopunk
~ indie games by Death By Audio Arcade
~ hacking demos &amp;amp;amp; education by Tech Learning Collective
~ text adventure cybersecurity game by Shift-CTRL Space

DANCE AT THE STAGE, AND BRING YOUR LAPTOP SO YOU CAN HACK AT THE BAR!

In addition to music and visuals, the most unique addition of the Hex90 parties is a hyperlocal cybersecurity (hacking) themed text-adventure game that gave the party its name: Hex90. This game is played on your own laptop, not on a console or arcade cabinet at the venue, but is still only accessible when you are physically at the party venue itself. (Aside from a short &quot;trailer,&quot; the game is not available on the public Internet.)

After you connect to the party's Wi-Fi network, you can then connect to the Hex90 game server using your Web browser. But to solve the challenges, you must download and install real hacker tools and learn how to employ real hacking techniques to progress through game levels ranging from network reconnaissance, applied cryptography, and Web exploitation. You've never seen so many queers open so many terminals in one place while being so close to a dance floor, and there's no high quite like it.

We continuously add levels to the game, so expect new challenges at most parties. Moreover, we sometimes incorporate physical-world features of the venue, like padlocks you need to pick that are safeguarding access to secret passwords, QR codes stashed in unexpected places, unassuming but exposed Ethernet cabling that turns out not to be a mistake at all, and so on. At Hex90, the game controller is your computer and the game mechanic is the real world.

All of the tools, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) used to progress in the game levels are skills taught by and equipment used by Tech Learning Collective instructors in our online workshops. Visit TechLearningCollective.com for more information and to enroll.

#------------------#
# START HACKING AT #
#------------------#
https://hex90.party

#------------------#
# BUY TICKETS HERE #
#------------------#
https://wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-replay

SUPPORTER TIER:
$30 - pay if you can

ADVANCE TICKETS:
$15.00 - str8 cismen
$10.00 - queers/transes/enbies and femmes

DAY-OF/AT THE DOOR:
$20.00 - str8 cismen
$15.00 - queers/transes/enbies and femmes

/**
* Hex90 is an inclusive event.
* Door staff is instructed to respect your self-identification.
*/

NOTICE:

This is an intentionally queer space. Consent and respect are not optional! Anyone behaving unkindly will be removed immediately without a refund. No amount of racism, queerphobia, transphobia, or sexism will be tolerated. This event is a celebration of queer hacking for queer hackers, not for Silicon Valley entrepreneurs, brogrammers, or BitCoin bros. Don't piss off the hackers. ;)

Hex90

###
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hex90.party/&quot;&gt;Start playing immediately and buy your ticket at the invitation site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-replay&quot;&gt;$30 - Supporter (pay if you can)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-replay&quot;&gt;$15 - General Admission - Advance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-replay&quot;&gt;$10 - Queers and Femmes - Advance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-replay&quot;&gt;$20 - General Admission - Day-of/at the door&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-replay&quot;&gt;$15 - Queers and Femmes - Day-of/at the door&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from the event without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-shift-ctrl-space&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://shiftctrl.space/&quot;&gt;Shift-CTRL Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are anti-(techno)capitalists, solarpunks, and radical technologists. Our ethics place us against “Adtech,” “Fintech,” and Silicon Valley. We believe technology is an intangible earth, with which we can and should have an earthly relationship. It is power that we can harness through holistic methods as individuals and cooperative networks for the empowerment of oneself and of one’s actual communities. Our approach stands in contrast to isolationism, sterility, and authoritarianism by being participatory, flexible, and adaptive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-nina-vicious&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ninavicious.com/&quot;&gt;Nina Vicious&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nina Vicious is a Brooklyn born and based DJ whose style is as multifaceted as it gets. Her creative approach is intergenerational and very open format. Her musical loves range from hip hop to house to future bass. Her priority is making you dance. Outside of this event you can catch her all over the city (event updates are on her official website) and she’ll be returning to Twitch in Summer 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-heaven-ender&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/heavenender&quot;&gt;heaven ender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;heaven ender is an immortal entity inhabiting the mortal plane of existence seeking to make the world a more beautiful place. Rising from the dark corners of the rave scene they will be presenting one of their unrelenting, genre blurring sets and condemning you to dance for eternity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-rana-ransom&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/ranaransom&quot;&gt;Rana Ransom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rana Ransom cut their teeth DJing on community radio after developing a fascination with acid house, italodisco and dark wave. Formerly, Rana was a DJ at (the now closed) Heather’s and Pyramid Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-trans-kafka&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/trans__kafka&quot;&gt;trans kafka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by a lifelong interest in games, trans kafka’s psychedelic and emotional high-energy sound explores the crossover between techno, trance, electro, and vgm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-livecodenyc&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://livecode.nyc/&quot;&gt;LiveCode.NYC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are primarily a meetup group who gets together to discuss programming in real time. We view live coding as a methodology and not medium specific. Some of our members code graphics, games, VR and a handful live code music. Many languages are used within the group, without one being prioritised. Many of us are artists. Sometimes we run events. The core of what we do is share live coding, whether discussing types at our meetups or teaching a system one of us built. We hope to continue to find ways in which we can do this, as a collective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-gwenprime&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://gwenpri.me/&quot;&gt;gwenpri.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gwenpri.me is a creative technologist, artist, and livecoder. She makes live visuals from videos, pictures, emoji, text, and more, then composites them using live code techniques. She enjoys finding arcane ways to put pixels on screens. Past sets have included touch designer patching, Lua DSLs, command line video editors, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-voyde&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/voydescreamsback&quot;&gt;Voyde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voyde is a new media artist that uses Unreal Engine to create surreal dreamscapes for us to hang out in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-death-by-audio&quot;&gt;About Death By Audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deathbyaudioarcade.com/&quot;&gt;Death By Audio Arcade&lt;/a&gt; is a series of lovingly crafted local multiplayer arcade cabinets produced by local indie game developers. We are also a progressive, open community of like-minded artists, artisans, and enthusiasts. We host events at least once a month, in NYC and at events across the country, from SXSW to the Smithsonian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Queer hackers of the world, unite! Tech Learning Collective is excited to invite you to Hex90’s latest queer hacker salon, “replay,” hosted at Wonderville, where you can buy tickets.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.hex90.flyer.2023-04-22.540x540.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.hex90.flyer.2023-04-22.540x540.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hex90: Transposition</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/12/event-2022-12-03-hex90-transposition" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hex90: Transposition" /><published>2022-12-03T20:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-03T20:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/12/event-2022-12-03-hex90-transposition</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/12/event-2022-12-03-hex90-transposition">&lt;p&gt;Queer hackers of the world, unite! Tech Learning Collective is excited to invite you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hex90.party/&quot;&gt;Hex90’s latest queer hacker salon, “Transposition,”&lt;/a&gt; hosted at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wonderville.nyc/&quot;&gt;Wonderville, where you can buy tickets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video id=&quot;sizzle-reel&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/static/media/hex90-transposition-trailer.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;/static/img/event.hex90.flyer.2022-12-03.540x540.jpg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/static/media/hex90-transposition-trailer.mp4&quot;&gt;Watch the Hex90: Transposition trailer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;Music: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eD2-HcJNlbs&quot;&gt;Black Hole Sun by Anatomy&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hex90.party/&quot;&gt;Hex90&lt;/a&gt; is brought to you by &lt;a href=&quot;https://techlearningcollective.com/&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective&lt;/a&gt; and friends.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-txt&quot;&gt;DHRRE UNPXREF BS GUR JBEYQ, HAVGR!

HEX90 — a queer hacker salon in NYC

Change has come again. It arrives streaming on the airwaves, in the storms, over the wires. Some fear it, others welcome it, but few deny it. Change transports us from where we were to where we must next be. It is not inevitable, for we are the change. They will fight for stagnation, but we will not be stopped.

Transitions make us powerful. Transformation showed us difference, gave us perspective, and taught us adaptability. We have learned to reconfigure the world through command injection, and to reconfigure ourselves through hormonal injections. To hackers, these are the same: when we reconfigure ourselves, we reconfigure the world. When we reconfigure the world, we reconfigure ourselves.

Transpose this and that. Redefine the problem. Substitute the premise. Shift bits left. Cycle one round at a time. Repeat for block after block. Again. Faster. FASTER. Continue until nothing is the same, and beautiful differences are all that remain of the source.

This night, we celebrate transposition, the oldest witchcraft.

GUVF AVTUG, JR PRYROENGR GENAFCBFVGVBA, GUR BYQRFG JVGPUPENSG.

info_

December 3, 2022 @ Wonderville
1186 Broadway, Brooklyn, NY 11221
8:00pm — 4:00am

~ this venue is accessible
~ this venue has gender-neutral restrooms
~ this venue has outdoor space

# dressing up is encouraged but not required

featuring_

~ music performances by
~~ Sailor Malice
~~ ÆON
~~ trans kafka
~~ heaven ender
~ livecoded visuals by
~~ gwenpri.me
~~ Janie Jaffe
~ indie games by Death By Audio Arcade
~ hacking demos &amp;amp; education by Tech Learning Collective
~ text adventure cybersecurity game by Shift-CTRL Space

DANCE AT THE STAGE, AND BRING YOUR LAPTOP SO YOU CAN HACK AT THE BAR!

In addition to music and visuals, the most unique addition of the Hex90 parties is a hyperlocal cybersecurity (hacking) themed text-adventure game that gave the party its name: Hex90. This game is played on your own laptop, not on a console or arcade cabinet at the venue, but is still only accessible when you are physically at the party venue itself. (Aside from a short &quot;trailer,&quot; the game is not available on the public Internet.)

After you connect to the party's Wi-Fi network, you can then connect to the Hex90 game server using your Web browser. But to solve the challenges, you must download and install real hacker tools and learn how to employ real hacking techniques to progress through game levels ranging from network reconnaissance, applied cryptography, and Web exploitation. You've never seen so many queers open so many terminals in one place while being so close to a dance floor, and there's no high quite like it.

We continuously add levels to the game, so expect new challenges at most parties. Moreover, we sometimes incorporate physical-world features of the venue, like padlocks you need to pick that are safeguarding access to secret passwords, QR codes stashed in unexpected places, unassuming but exposed Ethernet cabling that turns out not to be a mistake at all, and so on. At Hex90, the game controller is your computer and the game mechanic is the real world.

All of the tools, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) used to progress in the game levels are skills taught by and equipment used by Tech Learning Collective instructors in our online workshops. Visit TechLearningCollective.com for more information and to enroll.

#------------------#
# START HACKING AT #
#------------------#
https://hex90.party

#------------------#
# BUY TICKETS HERE #
#------------------#
https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-transposition

SUPPORTER TIER:
$30 - pay if you can

ADVANCE TICKETS:
$15.00 - str8 cismen
$10.00 - queers/transes/enbies and femmes

DAY-OF/AT THE DOOR:
$20.00 - str8 cismen
$15.00 - queers/transes/enbies and femmes

/**
* Hex90 is an inclusive event.
* Door staff is instructed to respect your self-identification.
*/

NOTICE:
This is an intentionally queer space. Consent and respect are not optional! Anyone behaving unkindly will be removed immediately without a refund. No amount of racism, queerphobia, transphobia, or sexism will be tolerated. This event is a celebration of queer hacking for queer hackers, not for Silicon Valley entrepreneurs, brogrammers, or BitCoin bros. Don't piss off the hackers. ;)

Hex90

###
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hex90.party/&quot;&gt;Start playing immediately and buy your ticket at the invitation site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-transposition&quot;&gt;$30 - Supporter (pay if you can)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-transposition&quot;&gt;$15 - General Admission - Advance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-transposition&quot;&gt;$10 - Queers and Femmes - Advance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-transposition&quot;&gt;$20 - General Admission - Day-of/at the door&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-transposition&quot;&gt;$15 - Queers and Femmes - Day-of/at the door&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from the event without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-shift-ctrl-space&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://shiftctrl.space/&quot;&gt;Shift-CTRL Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are anti-(techno)capitalists, solarpunks, and radical technologists. Our ethics place us against “Adtech,” “Fintech,” and Silicon Valley. We believe technology is an intangible earth, with which we can and should have an earthly relationship. It is power that we can harness through holistic methods as individuals and cooperative networks for the empowerment of oneself and of one’s actual communities. Our approach stands in contrast to isolationism, sterility, and authoritarianism by being participatory, flexible, and adaptive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-æon&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/dj__aeon&quot;&gt;ÆON&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ÆON is a Brooklyn based DJ and producer. Her sound melds jagged psychedelic techno with soaring trance melodies for a raw and hard hitting energy that packs dance floors city wide. As cofounder of the Palacio party series she sources sounds from the Bushwick underground to bring forward, with a distinct focus on voices from her own trans community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-heaven-ender&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/heavenender&quot;&gt;heaven ender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;heaven ender is an immortal entity inhabiting the mortal plane of existence seeking to make the world a more beautiful place. Rising from the dark corners of the rave scene they will be presenting one of their unrelenting, genre blurring sets and condemning you to dance for eternity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-trans-kafka&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/trans__kafka&quot;&gt;trans kafka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by a lifelong interest in games, trans kafka’s psychedelic and emotional high-energy sound explores the crossover between techno, trance, electro, and vgm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-livecodenyc&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://livecode.nyc/&quot;&gt;LiveCode.NYC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are primarily a meetup group who gets together to discuss programming in real time. We view live coding as a methodology and not medium specific. Some of our members code graphics, games, VR and a handful live code music. Many languages are used within the group, without one being prioritised. Many of us are artists. Sometimes we run events. The core of what we do is share live coding, whether discussing types at our meetups or teaching a system one of us built. We hope to continue to find ways in which we can do this, as a collective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-gwenprime&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://gwenpri.me/&quot;&gt;gwenpri.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gwenpri.me is a creative technologist, artist, and livecoder. She makes live visuals from videos, pictures, emoji, text, and more, then composites them using live code techniques. She enjoys finding arcane ways to put pixels on screens. Past sets have included touch designer patching, Lua DSLs, command line video editors, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-death-by-audio&quot;&gt;About Death By Audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deathbyaudioarcade.com/&quot;&gt;Death By Audio Arcade&lt;/a&gt; is a series of lovingly crafted local multiplayer arcade cabinets produced by local indie game developers. We are also a progressive, open community of like-minded artists, artisans, and enthusiasts. We host events at least once a month, in NYC and at events across the country, from SXSW to the Smithsonian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Queer hackers of the world, unite! Tech Learning Collective is excited to invite you to Hex90’s latest queer hacker salon, “Transposition,” hosted at Wonderville, where you can buy tickets.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.hex90.flyer.2022-12-03.540x540.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.hex90.flyer.2022-12-03.540x540.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hex90: Promiscuous Mode</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/08/event-2022-08-13-hex90-promiscuous-mode" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hex90: Promiscuous Mode" /><published>2022-08-13T21:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-13T21:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/08/event-2022-08-13-hex90-promiscuous-mode</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/08/event-2022-08-13-hex90-promiscuous-mode">&lt;p&gt;Queer hackers of the world, unite! Tech Learning Collective is excited to invite you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hex90.party/&quot;&gt;Hex90’s latest queer hacker salon, “Promiscuous Mode,”&lt;/a&gt; hosted at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wonderville.nyc/&quot;&gt;Wonderville, where you can buy tickets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-txt&quot;&gt;log tcp !192.168.0/24 any -&amp;gt; 192.168.0.2 (msg: &quot;QUEER HACKERS OF THE WORLD, UNITE&quot; ; )
tail /var/log/PROMISCUOUS.MODE
Aug 13 21:00 hex90 syslogd[135]: QUEER HACKERS OF THE WORLD, UNITE

HEX90 — a queer hacker salon in NYC

It is time for us to reach the sky! By sunlight and moonlight, take flight! Let us imagine ourselves as stardust returning to our celestial origins, intertwingled together. We will burn the stars with our radiance!

Hackers are elemental. Like water, we are shapeless, yet we are every shape. We transition between states as our environment changes, changing the environment in the process. We can be as hard as ice, or as soft as flame. Opaque, or invisible, or spanning everything in between, we are the cloud. Ours is flesh that forms as quickly as it may float away. Impenetrable, or permeable. Our bodies, our choices, from one fluid moment to the next.

Information packets traverse the ether. Netflows quickly vanish over the horizon. There are traces of fire on the wire connecting our vibrating crystalline bodies. Sniff the wire to prime your electronic memory with the sounds of conversations past and present. Enter promiscuous mode, spread your wings, and fly to the stars with us!

info_

August 13, 2022 @ Wonderville
1186 Broadway, Brooklyn, NY 11221
9:00pm — 3:00am

~ this venue is accessible
~ this venue has gender-neutral restrooms
~ this venue has outdoor space

# dressing up is encouraged but not required

featuring_

~ music performances by
~~ Kandylion
~~ DJ Softserve
~ livecoded visuals by
~~ Char Stiles (Livecode.NYC)
~~ Voyde
~~ gwenpri.me (Livecode.NYC)
~~ schwaz (Livecode.NYC)
~ algorave and electronic audio by
~~ Alanza
~~ alsoknownasrox (Livecode.NYC)
~~ Azhad Syed (Livecode.NYC)
~~ dan.dog
~ indie games by Death By Audio Arcade
~ hacking demos &amp;amp; education by Tech Learning Collective
~ text adventure cybersecurity game by Shift-CTRL Space

DANCE AT THE STAGE, AND BRING YOUR LAPTOP SO YOU CAN HACK AT THE BAR!

In addition to music and visuals, the most unique addition of the Hex90 parties is a hyperlocal cybersecurity (hacking) themed text-adventure game that gave the party its name: Hex90. This game is played on your own laptop, not on a console or arcade cabinet at the venue, but is still only accessible when you are physically at the party venue itself. (Aside from a short &quot;trailer,&quot; the game is not available on the public Internet.)

After you connect to the party's Wi-Fi network, you can then connect to the Hex90 game server using your Web browser. But to solve the challenges, you must download and install real hacker tools and learn how to employ real hacking techniques to progress through game levels ranging from network reconnaissance, applied cryptography, and Web exploitation. You've never seen so many queers open so many terminals in one place while being so close to a dance floor, and there's no high quite like it.

We continuously add levels to the game, so expect new challenges at most parties. Moreover, we sometimes incorporate physical-world features of the venue, like padlocks you need to pick that are safeguarding access to secret passwords, QR codes stashed in unexpected places, unassuming but exposed Ethernet cabling that turns out not to be a mistake at all, and so on. At Hex90, the game controller is your computer and the game mechanic is the real world.

All of the tools, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) used to progress in the game levels are skills taught by and equipment used by Tech Learning Collective instructors in our online workshops. Visit TechLearningCollective.com for more information and to enroll.

#------------------#
# START HACKING AT #
#------------------#
https://hex90.party

#------------------#
# BUY TICKETS HERE #
#------------------#
https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-promiscuous-mode

SUPPORTER TIER:
$30 - pay if you can

ADVANCE TICKETS:
$15.00 - str8 cismen
$10.00 - queers/transes/enbies and femmes

DAY-OF/AT THE DOOR:
$20.00 - str8 cismen
$15.00 - queers/transes/enbies and femmes

/**
* Hex90 is an inclusive event.
* Door staff is instructed to respect your self-identification.
*/

NOTICE:
This is an intentionally queer space. Consent and respect are not optional! Anyone behaving unkindly will be removed immediately without a refund. No amount of racism, queerphobia, transphobia, or sexism will be tolerated. This event is a celebration of queer hacking for queer hackers, not for Silicon Valley entrepreneurs, brogrammers, or BitCoin bros. Don't piss off the hackers. ;)

Hex90

###
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hex90.party/&quot;&gt;Start playing immediately and buy your ticket at the invitation site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-promiscuous-mode&quot;&gt;$30 - Supporter (pay if you can)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-promiscuous-mode&quot;&gt;$15 - General Admission - Advance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-promiscuous-mode&quot;&gt;$10 - Queers and Femmes - Advance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-promiscuous-mode&quot;&gt;$20 - General Admission - Day-of/at the door&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-promiscuous-mode&quot;&gt;$15 - Queers and Femmes - Day-of/at the door&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from the event without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-shift-ctrl-space&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://shiftctrl.space/&quot;&gt;Shift-CTRL Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are anti-(techno)capitalists, solarpunks, and radical technologists. Our ethics place us against “Adtech,” “Fintech,” and Silicon Valley. We believe technology is an intangible earth, with which we can and should have an earthly relationship. It is power that we can harness through holistic methods as individuals and cooperative networks for the empowerment of oneself and of one’s actual communities. Our approach stands in contrast to isolationism, sterility, and authoritarianism by being participatory, flexible, and adaptive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-xoxa&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xoxanyc.com/&quot;&gt;XOXA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XOXA (pronounced ex-oh-ex-ay) is a Brooklyn based queer collective of DJs, artists and performers founded in 2017. Their mission is to provide a supportive platform for women and LGBTQ+ artists to perform while creating an intentional party space for women, non-binary and trans individuals. You can follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/xoxanyc&quot;&gt;@xoxanyc on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/xoxanyc&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; for more information on upcoming events and projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-kandylion&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundcloud.com/kandylion&quot;&gt;Kandylion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kandylion has spent the better part of the last decade honing her DJ chops in the Brooklyn underground dance scene, and is a current resident of queer nightlife collective XOXA. Her versatile and melodic mixes span genres and decades with an emphasis on feel-good house, disco, acid and breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-dj-softserve&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/softserve.the.frosty.dj/&quot;&gt;DJ Softserve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting his DJ journey in South Korea, DJ Softserve has since played in major festivals, clubs and bars all over South Korea and the US. He is committed to creating the most fun dancefloor possible and blasts the frostiest beats for only the coolest homies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-livecodenyc&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://livecode.nyc/&quot;&gt;LiveCode.NYC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are primarily a meetup group who gets together to discuss programming in real time. We view live coding as a methodology and not medium specific. Some of our members code graphics, games, VR and a handful live code music. Many languages are used within the group, without one being prioritised. Many of us are artists. Sometimes we run events. The core of what we do is share live coding, whether discussing types at our meetups or teaching a system one of us built. We hope to continue to find ways in which we can do this, as a collective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-char-stiles&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/charstiles&quot;&gt;Char Stiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Char describes how photons work to sand that thinks, that is to say she livecodes GLSL visuals on the computer, that is to say she writes constantly compiling graphics algorithms on the GPU as a performance. This is in hopes it is entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-voyde&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/voydescreamsback&quot;&gt;Voyde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indira/Voyde uses Unreal Engine in creating surreal landscapes made of liquid bodies, journalistic images, and narrative snapshots hidden deep inside, scrambled with voronoi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-gwenprime&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://gwenpri.me/&quot;&gt;gwenpri.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gwenpri.me is a creative technologist, artist, and livecoder. She makes live visuals from videos, pictures, emoji, text, and more, then composites them using live code techniques. She enjoys finding arcane ways to put pixels on screens. Past sets have included touch designer patching, Lua DSLs, command line video editors, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-alanza&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/aalanzaa&quot;&gt;Alanza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alanza is a polymath based in New York. Her music ranges from hardware improvisation to in-the-box pop production. She’s interested in synthesis, odd rhythms, things that make you think while dancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-alsoknownasrox&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://alsoknownasrox.com/&quot;&gt;alsoknownasrox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roxanne Harris (alsoknownasrox) makes art by programming on-the-fly, seeking to push the limitations of computation for creative expression, both in new application and new foundational research. She spends her time finding new ways to engage with the world, destructing and reconstructing existing structures as she goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-dandog&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/dqgorelick&quot;&gt;dan.dog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Gorelick is an SF and Brooklyn-based musician, creative technologist, and livecoder. He mixes acoustic instruments and voice with synthesizers (and code) to create expressive electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-death-by-audio&quot;&gt;About Death By Audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deathbyaudioarcade.com/&quot;&gt;Death By Audio Arcade&lt;/a&gt; is a series of lovingly crafted local multiplayer arcade cabinets produced by local indie game developers. We are also a progressive, open community of like-minded artists, artisans, and enthusiasts. We host events at least once a month, in NYC and at events across the country, from SXSW to the Smithsonian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Queer hackers of the world, unite! Tech Learning Collective is excited to invite you to Hex90’s latest queer hacker salon, “Promiscuous Mode,” hosted at Wonderville, where you can buy tickets.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.hex90.flyer.2022-08-13.960x540.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.hex90.flyer.2022-08-13.960x540.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Vi’s Triple Header Happy Birthday Happy Hour</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/07/event-2022-07-05-vis-triple-header-happy-birthday-happy-hour" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vi’s Triple Header Happy Birthday Happy Hour" /><published>2022-07-05T17:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-05T17:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/07/event-2022-07-05-vis-triple-header-happy-birthday-happy-hour</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/07/event-2022-07-05-vis-triple-header-happy-birthday-happy-hour">&lt;p&gt;Start Summer off with a bang. We’re not talking about fireworks (although those are nice, too). We’re talking about our good friend and collaborator, Vi’s incredible three-in-one party night. Vi has been an incredible source of knowledge, inspiration, and persistence throughout all of Tech Learning Collective history. In partnership with others, she co-founded our school and continues to be involved in community efforts to increase the digital literacy and safety of queer and trans folks to this day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many past posts on our blog, as well as across the Web in &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/05/01/the-enrages-next-time-the-pendulum-swings-part-1.html&quot;&gt;recorded podcasts&lt;/a&gt; and on &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/08/03/return-the-magic-to-computers-radio-statler-hope-2020-interview-with-tech-learning-collective.html&quot;&gt;Internet radio&lt;/a&gt;, you can listen to her impassioned takes on Internet history and the future of technology, its impact on marginalized groups, and her critiques of Silicon Valley’s approaches to “making the world a better place” all while advocating for a more technologically savvy and self-empowered relationship with digital technology. Although an enigma to many, she is nothing if not iconoclastic, embodying the very best of the trans hacker stereotype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Vi plays double-duty as a full time employee back in Silicon Valley after a long personal struggle, as well as remaining a core organizer for the Hex90 queer hacker parties in New York City, an advisor to a number of anarchist tech collectives, and of course a central figure in Tech Learning Collective operations. Vi is turning 1 year old soon, as her HRT anniversary is around the corner and, true to form, she’s decided to turn her party into something more communal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direct from Vi “like the text editor” herself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hi, friends! Pride Month has come and gone but there’s one more (massive) celebration to be had!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Join me, your friendly neighborhood trans hacker party princess, for a TRIPLE HEADER HAPPY HOUR event: the company I work for tapped me to organize a “How was your pride?” post-pride month Happy Hour, and I’m combining it with my “birthday” party and the next &lt;a href=&quot;https://killerqueenarcade.com/&quot;&gt;Killer Queen&lt;/a&gt; Open Hive Night at Wonderville.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The “How was your Pride?” Happy Hour is for my co-workers in NYC, and I’m inviting them all to combine forces with the NYC Killer Queen scene for their weekly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/killerqueen-07-05-2022&quot;&gt;Open Hive Night&lt;/a&gt;. That day is also my trans birthday celebration, so all three events are happening in the same place at the same time, all in one amazing evening!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Join me and other colleagues (LGBTQ+ and allies) on Tuesday, July 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 5PM through 9PM at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wonderville.nyc/&quot;&gt;Wonderville&lt;/a&gt; in the center of the queer universe in Brooklyn. That Tuesday, come learn how to play the popular 10-player strategy arcade game “Killer Queen” from some of NYC’s best players and NYC’s newest Queen Bee, yours truly! Come also to share Pride Month stories, meet one another in physical space, and meet more queer NYC locals. And of course, also come thru to wish me a happy birthday! 🎂&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;WHO: You, and hopefully many of your friends that you’ll bring&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;WHAT: Vi’s Birthday Triple Header Happy Hour combination corporate LGBTQ+ happy hour plus birthday celebration plus Killer Queen Open Hive Night&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;WHERE: Wonderville&lt;br /&gt;
1186 Broadway, Brooklyn, NY&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://Wonderville.nyc/&quot;&gt;https://Wonderville.nyc/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;DIRECTIONS: &lt;a href=&quot;https://g.page/wondervillenyc&quot;&gt;https://g.page/wondervillenyc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;WHEN: Tuesday, July 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;5pm-2:30am: Vi’s happy birthday celebration!&lt;br /&gt;
5pm-9pm: LGBTQ Employee Resource Group Happy Hour and (limited) open bar!&lt;br /&gt;
8pm-12am: Killer Queen Open Hive Night&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you haven’t already been there, Wonderville is a free-play indie arcade studio 🕹️ and combination bar with two DJ booths, a stage, a backyard, and numerous wonderful queer events every week. It is easily accessible from downtown Manhattan via the [J] Subway train and numerous buses and one of my favorite queer spots ever! 🏳️‍🌈🏳️‍⚧️&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;LGBTQ+ ERG “HOW WAS YOUR PRIDE?” HAPPY HOUR:&lt;br /&gt;
5pm-9pm&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Join Vi and her work colleagues for a sponsored post-Pride Month “How was your Pride?” Happy Hour. Come meet other queers and allies from her work, their friends, and more of Vi’s friends as we share our Pride Month stories and meet new folks who are gearing up for the sequel of “Hot Vaxxx Summer,” “Hot Vaxxx Summer 2: I Wanna Know What You Did Last Pride!”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This event is not exclusive to Vi’s LGBTQ+ coworkers so everyone is welcome but (obviously?) is focused on making sure we create a space for LGBTQ+ employees with support from our allies. There will also be a limited open tab courtesy the company Employee Resource Group and employee experience team for this happy hour as well and some remaining portions of the tab will be picked up by Tech Learning Collective as a thank you to the queer community who keep coming to our &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/&quot;&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt;. That said, please feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;/donate/&quot;&gt;donate to Tech Learning Collective&lt;/a&gt; if you have the means to help support our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;VI’S HAPPY BIRTHDAY CELEBRATION:&lt;br /&gt;
5pm-2:30am&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s my birthday! I’ll be 1 year old, as my HRT anniversary is right around the corner! Come wish me a happy birthday at one of my favorite venues in all of New York City, and where I’m going to be anyway, Wonderville! Don’t worry about bringing a gift or anything like that, just bring your amazing self and be ready for a “worlds collide” moment because I’m inviting my co-workers (who know me by a different name and everything) so let’s see how that goes, lol?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You’ll get to see a glimpse of me as the corporate!Vi version of myself, and they’ll get to see a glimpse of the trans hacker party princess!Vi version of me! It’ll be great! Or a complete disaster that will fuck up my life forever! I’m ready for either!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;KILLER QUEEN OPEN HIVE NIGHT:&lt;br /&gt;
8pm-12am&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Come learn how to play the popular 10-player arcade game from some of NYC’s best players, including the scene’s newest hypersocial up and coming hottie Queen Bee, yours truly! We’ll be playing Killer Queen in open play and maybe a round-robin tournament mode, so come early to find teammates and sign up for the casual tournament. Details also at:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/killerqueen-07-05-2022&quot;&gt;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/killerqueen-07-05-2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/killerqueen-07-05-2022&quot;&gt;https://killerqueenarcade.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Bring friends. Especially friends I don’t already know. &amp;lt;3 &amp;lt;3 &amp;lt;3 See you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Start Summer off with a bang. We’re not talking about fireworks (although those are nice, too). We’re talking about our good friend and collaborator, Vi’s incredible three-in-one party night. Vi has been an incredible source of knowledge, inspiration, and persistence throughout all of Tech Learning Collective history. In partnership with others, she co-founded our school and continues to be involved in community efforts to increase the digital literacy and safety of queer and trans folks to this day.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/m4g1sh-retrowave.gif" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/m4g1sh-retrowave.gif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tor: What is it Good For? (Absolutely Everything!)</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/workshop-2022-06-05-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tor: What is it Good For? (Absolutely Everything!)" /><published>2022-06-05T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-05T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/workshop-2022-06-05-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/workshop-2022-06-05-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything">&lt;p&gt;Come learn how the free Tor Web Browser can be your gateway to the Dark Web while simultaneously keeping you safer and your personal info more private as you browse web sites big and small. In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From illegal online drug stores like Silk Road to DDoS botnet command and control headquarters, media attention has long painted “the Dark Web” as though nothing good can come of it. But learn just a little bit more about how Tor and “hidden services” work and you’ll find a treasure trove of valuable possibilities for day-to-day Internet use. The same technology that can hide the location of a drug ring can also serve as a free VPN-like service to protect your privacy while you browse the Internet, make censored websites available again, and even let you host your own Internet services for free, all without opening a single port on your firewall!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool. They’ll demonstrate numerous Tor features such as Tor authentication, target service load balancing, and NAT-punching. In the process, you’ll finally understand—on a technical level—what the “Dark Web” actually is and how it works. Bring a laptop to class, and you’ll leave having run your own Dark Web site. This class is for everyone; whether you’re a veteran black hat or a timid newbie, this class will shine a light on the Dark Web once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-06-05-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Come learn how the free Tor Web Browser can be your gateway to the Dark Web while simultaneously keeping you safer and your personal info more private as you browse web sites big and small. In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Faster Than Light: Getting Started with Configuration Management</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/workshop-2022-06-04-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Faster Than Light: Getting Started with Configuration Management" /><published>2022-06-04T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-04T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/workshop-2022-06-04-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/workshop-2022-06-04-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to beat back configuration drift on your servers by leveraging automation tools like Ansible in this deep dive workshop demonstrating modern DevOps practices for deploying, maintaining, and auditing compute clusters. Whether for a Web application, big data processing, or other project, you need to turn old-school runbooks into computerized playbooks that can execute Standard Operating Procedures quickly and reliably so you can deploy complex systems simply and predictably. Come learn about key concepts like idempotence and change control, and learn how giant corporations implement security principles like RBAC, all using free and open source software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today, all but the most trivial of computer systems rely on an interdependent set of servers working in concert. You don’t just have one server, you have a group of them. Commonly called a &lt;em&gt;cluster&lt;/em&gt;, these servers need to be managed as a group, ensuring that their software configurations, security patches, and installed packages are deployed, maintained, and eventually updated or retired in a predictable way.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this deep dive workshop, we’ll set up our own small cluster and use &lt;a href=&quot;https://ansible.com/&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt;, which is an agentless, cross-platform, enterprise-grade, free software &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Configuration_management&quot;&gt;Configuration Management (CM)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Automate-All-the-Things-Infrastructure-as-Code-Primer&quot;&gt;Infrastructure as Code (IaC)&lt;/a&gt; framework used by giant corporations like IBM and Cisco, to turn old-school operator runbooks into computerized playbooks that can be executed quickly and easily even by novice operators. Through several hands-on exercises, you’ll learn about the entire CM lifecycle from planning through auditing so that you understand critical CM concepts like idempotence, change control, and more, which are common to all CM systems including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chef.io/configuration-management/&quot;&gt;Chef&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://puppet.com/use-cases/configuration-management/&quot;&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.saltstack.com/en/latest/topics/states/&quot;&gt;Salt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Along the way, you’ll be exposed to key concepts such as &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Ship-Shape-Computing-Working-with-Containers-and-Containzerizing-Digital-Workloads&quot;&gt;containerization&lt;/a&gt; through Ansible’s support for automating container builds, &lt;a href=&quot;/con&quot;&gt;Role-Based Access Control (RBAC)&lt;/a&gt; via Ansible’s AWX Project, and more. By adopting configuration management workflows with tools like Ansible, you can reduce operator errors, and beat back configuration drift on any long-lived infrastructure components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-06-04-faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to beat back configuration drift on your servers by leveraging automation tools like Ansible in this deep dive workshop demonstrating modern DevOps practices for deploying, maintaining, and auditing compute clusters. Whether for a Web application, big data processing, or other project, you need to turn old-school runbooks into computerized playbooks that can execute Standard Operating Procedures quickly and reliably so you can deploy complex systems simply and predictably. Come learn about key concepts like idempotence and change control, and learn how giant corporations implement security principles like RBAC, all using free and open source software.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.faster-than-light-getting-started-with-configuration-management.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">NOT Worldwide: NYC Regional Launch</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/event-2022-06-02-not-worldwide-nyc-regional-launch" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NOT Worldwide: NYC Regional Launch" /><published>2022-06-02T22:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-02T22:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/event-2022-06-02-not-worldwide-nyc-regional-launch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/06/event-2022-06-02-not-worldwide-nyc-regional-launch">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://notworldwide.org/&quot;&gt;New Order Technoism&lt;/a&gt; and friends of Tech Learning Collective invite you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.liminalspace.nyc/&quot;&gt;Liminal Space&lt;/a&gt; to experience the birth of a new machine, one made in and for a new world. Among other incredible performers, this event features DJ Niyah West, a semi-regular fixture at our own Hex90 queer hacker parties, along with livecoded visuals by Char Stiles, also a Hex90 favorite, who will be joined by Livecode.NYC star Indira! More tunes by BABES the DJ, a drag performance by God Complex, and you-have-to-see-it-to-believe-it installations by Ru Electra round out the lineup for this one of a kind enigmatic experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come for the shows, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notworldwide.org/how-is-it&quot;&gt;buy a candle and pray with us&lt;/a&gt;, or read the DOOM scrolls while basking in the healing light of retro tech diagnostic testing offered by Anya Volz that may repair—or worsen—all your corruptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Have you wasted years of your life in service of a capitalist machine?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;There is a new machine taking shape, ready to build a new world.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If your existence is passive, you are an existential risk.&lt;br /&gt;
To exist in the future through cognizance is limitless.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Find purpose, submit yourself to something greater.&lt;br /&gt;
Consider your second entropy.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Compromise for a better VOID!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Thurs June 2nd // 10pm&lt;br /&gt;
Liminal Space&lt;br /&gt;
1080 Wyckoff Ave.&lt;br /&gt;
((enter through The Deep End))&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Queers + Femmes = $20 adv // $25 door&lt;br /&gt;
Cis + Str8ts = $25 adv // $30 door&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;~This is an inclusive space~&lt;br /&gt;
~This venue has gender neutral restrooms~&lt;br /&gt;
~No one will be turned away for lack of funds, email NewOrderTechnoism@gmail.com~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-dj-niyah-west&quot;&gt;About DJ Niyah West&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Niyah West (she/they) is a DJ, music curator and digital artist based in New York City. From the living rooms of dear friends to the night clubs, Niyah made her professional debut just this year during pride month. Thus, making her a bright newcomer in the queer DJ scene. She has amplified parties and dancefloors all over the boroughs, some recently including MEOW NYC, Gayjoy &amp;amp; a residency at Kind Regards in the Lower East Side. She’s also a resident of Brooklyn based queer DJ collective XOXA NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-livecodenyc&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://livecode.nyc/&quot;&gt;LiveCode.NYC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are primarily a meetup group who gets together to discuss programming in real time. We view live coding as a methodology and not medium specific. Some of our members code graphics, games, VR and a handful live code music. Many languages are used within the group, without one being prioritised. Many of us are artists. Sometimes we run events. The core of what we do is share live coding, whether discussing types at our meetups or teaching a system one of us built. We hope to continue to find ways in which we can do this, as a collective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-char-stiles&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;http://charstiles.com/&quot;&gt;Char Stiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Char Stiles is an artist, educator and programmer based in Brooklyn, NY. She works creatively in the lower levels of computational systems to bring to light how computers work. Char works and collaborates across mediums such as interactive installation, video, performance and web. She is a part of the Livecode.nyc collective, where she organizes shows, and livecodes music and visuals.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">New Order Technoism and friends of Tech Learning Collective invite you to Liminal Space to experience the birth of a new machine, one made in and for a new world. Among other incredible performers, this event features DJ Niyah West, a semi-regular fixture at our own Hex90 queer hacker parties, along with livecoded visuals by Char Stiles, also a Hex90 favorite, who will be joined by Livecode.NYC star Indira! More tunes by BABES the DJ, a drag performance by God Complex, and you-have-to-see-it-to-believe-it installations by Ru Electra round out the lineup for this one of a kind enigmatic experience.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.2022-06-02.not-worldwide-nyc-regional-launch.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.2022-06-02.not-worldwide-nyc-regional-launch.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Securing Our Servers: Basic Network Operations for Autonomous Communities</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-29-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Securing Our Servers: Basic Network Operations for Autonomous Communities" /><published>2022-05-29T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-29T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-29-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-29-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities">&lt;p&gt;Learn the basics of securing digital infrastructure by taking a deep-dive into the Secure Shell (SSH) protocol, a fundamental component of safe administrative access to remote servers. Regardless of whether you rely on one or many thousands of servers to power your daily operations, securely managing those machines is essential to the success of your efforts. This intermediate-level workshop shows you how to securely set up, access, and debug connection issues over the SSH protocol so that you’ll be ready to operate self-hosted digital infrastructure for yourself, friends, or comrades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every app you use—from messengers like &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; or WhatsApp to blogs and websites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and even other coordination tools like digital calendars and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Our-Streets,-Our-Maps-Introduction-to-OpenStreetMap&quot;&gt;online maps&lt;/a&gt;—relies on a computer called a server. Whether that computer is one in your hand (your smartphone), or a computer somewhere across the Internet (“in the cloud”), no meaningful digital communication happens without servers offering services, somewhere. So, do you know where &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; servers are? If not, you can’t know how safe your data is!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When you don’t have a clear map of how your messages and other data gets from here to there, you might be at risk of someone listening in on your conversations. When you rely on services that you don’t own yourself for critical day-to-day operations (like Google Calendar, or Facebook…) you risk losing access to those capabilities by having your account banned, even by mistake. Regardless of your specific situation, knowing more about the digital servers that are serving you is a vital first step for supporting communities or companies large and small.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This intermediate-level workshop combines various topics from the &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/sys101.html&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s System Administration&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/net101.html&quot;&gt;Networking&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/sec101.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; courses to offer an intensive crash course in secure server setup, monitoring, and maintenance. By taking a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/blob/master/train-the-trainers/practice-labs/introduction-to-securing-virtualized-secure-shell-servers/README.md&quot;&gt;deep dive into the SSH protocol&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll learn how to set up remote administrative access to a server in a safe way, and you’ll be exposed to the potential risks of network eavesdroppers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man-in-the-middle_attack&quot;&gt;Machine-in-the-Middle (MITM) attacks&lt;/a&gt;, and much more. By the end of this workshop, you’ll have a basic understanding of how to safely operate self-hosted digital infrastructures for yourself, your friends, and your comrades, as well as what first steps you need to take to keep intruders and enemies at bay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-05-29-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn the basics of securing digital infrastructure by taking a deep-dive into the Secure Shell (SSH) protocol, a fundamental component of safe administrative access to remote servers. Regardless of whether you rely on one or many thousands of servers to power your daily operations, securely managing those machines is essential to the success of your efforts. This intermediate-level workshop shows you how to securely set up, access, and debug connection issues over the SSH protocol so that you’ll be ready to operate self-hosted digital infrastructure for yourself, friends, or comrades.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Taming Daemons: System Administration and Operation Basics</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-28-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taming Daemons: System Administration and Operation Basics" /><published>2022-05-28T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-28T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-28-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2022/05/workshop-2022-05-28-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics">&lt;p&gt;Most individuals with access to a computer system have more power today than ever before, but rarely do they make use of it or even know how much power they truly have. In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll begin learning how to “speak with the machines.” By learning to communicate more expressively with the digital devices that are increasingly responsible for mediating contemporary society, you’ll gain the power to effectively and materially change your relationship not only with your laptop, but with global systems of law, finance, and even art, literature, and philosophy governing today’s world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How much good does a powerful tool do for you if you don’t know how to use it well? How much more capable would you be if you mastered all the tools available to you? It might sound ridiculous, but failing to learn the practicalities of computer system operation basics is arguably the most common mistake people in the fast-paced tech scene make.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Modern computers are power tools, and behind each one of them is a human operator, or “system administrator,” responsible for configuring and maintaining that computer. If you have a personal computer such as a laptop or smartphone, then you are already a system administrator whether you realize it or not! Making sure the apps you want to use are installed and up to date, managing the amount of free space you have for your photos, and connecting or disconnecting from the Internet are all examples of simple system administration tasks that you probably already take on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner’s workshop, we’ll start by exploring what happens inside your computer when you take every-day tasks like open a Web browser or save files, and then dive down the rabbit hole to meet the special class of programs that make it possible for all your other programs to work. Called &lt;em&gt;daemons&lt;/em&gt;, short for Disk Access and Execution Monitors, they make up the world of Operating System services, signals, sockets, and more under the hood of your desktop environment. By the end of this workshop, you’ll have a far deeper understanding of how to care for your computer, as well as the ability to understand any new tools or services you encounter a whole lot faster than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2022-05-28-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Most individuals with access to a computer system have more power today than ever before, but rarely do they make use of it or even know how much power they truly have. In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll begin learning how to “speak with the machines.” By learning to communicate more expressively with the digital devices that are increasingly responsible for mediating contemporary society, you’ll gain the power to effectively and materially change your relationship not only with your laptop, but with global systems of law, finance, and even art, literature, and philosophy governing today’s world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>