<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2024-08-06T21:40:22-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective | Events</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">Password Superpowers: How to Crack Hashes and Stump Hackers</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/11/workshop-2023-11-11-password-superpowers-how-to-crack-hashes-and-stump-hackers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Password Superpowers: How to Crack Hashes and Stump Hackers" /><published>2023-11-11T13:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-11T13:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/11/workshop-2023-11-11-password-superpowers-how-to-crack-hashes-and-stump-hackers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/11/workshop-2023-11-11-password-superpowers-how-to-crack-hashes-and-stump-hackers">&lt;p&gt;Get an accessible introduction to the basics of password management by learning how to perform a password cracking attack yourself. Learn exactly what Web sites do with your password when you log in, how to find out if you have been “pwned,” what the risks are, and what you can do to protect yourself from brute-force, credential stuffing, and other forms of account takeover attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Have you been “pwned”? For years, security researcher Troy Hunt has been running a website at &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/&quot;&gt;HaveIBeenPwned.com&lt;/a&gt; that lets you check to see if your online accounts have been pwned—that is, if your personal information such as your password, has been leaked, accessed, or (worst of all!) “cracked.” Go on, check for yourself!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you’ve been “pwned,” this workshop is your chance to learn exactly what the risk might be, and what you can do about it. Derived from one portion of the &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/sec101.html&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s popular “Hacking with Mr. Robot” (Security 101) course&lt;/a&gt;, this class will clarify the basics of cryptography and encryption within a context that actually applies to your day to day life online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Learn what websites do with your password when you log in to them, and why using free password management software can make you both safer and more productive. On the flip side, learn &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/blob/master/train-the-trainers/mr-robots-netflix-n-hack/week-2/strengthening-passwords-to-defend-against-john/README.md&quot;&gt;professional techniques for recovering passwords&lt;/a&gt; from their “encrypted” (hashed) representation, such as using optimized wordlists, word-mangling rulesets, and employing basic doxing techniques for creating personally targeted password-cracking attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2023-11-11-password-superpowers-how-to-crack-hashes-and-stump-hackers&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Get an accessible introduction to the basics of password management by learning how to perform a password cracking attack yourself. Learn exactly what Web sites do with your password when you log in, how to find out if you have been “pwned,” what the risks are, and what you can do to protect yourself from brute-force, credential stuffing, and other forms of account takeover attacks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.password-superpowers-how-to-crack-hashes-and-stump-hackers.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.password-superpowers-how-to-crack-hashes-and-stump-hackers.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing with Blue Fire: Shell Scripting for Beginners</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/11/workshop-2023-11-05-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing with Blue Fire: Shell Scripting for Beginners" /><published>2023-11-05T14:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-05T14:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/11/workshop-2023-11-05-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/11/workshop-2023-11-05-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to inscribe your thoughts, dreams, and desires into your computer and take your command line skills to the next level by learning how to write simple programs called shell scripts. In a way, invoking commands one at a time is like writing a program interactively, whereas writing a script inscribes that knowledge into a more permanent form. By learning how to turn commands into simple scripted programs, you can unlock the almost magical potential of your computer and more easily share that potential with others to whom you distribute your scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At their core, digital computers are very complex writing instruments. Like pen and paper, they allow us to record our thoughts, dreams, and desires for later review. Unlike pen and paper, they allow us to do this at the speed of electricity and at a scale never before imagined possible, and their ability to directly manipulate the physical world through servomotors, industrial control systems, biomedical devices, and other robotic prosthesis means they can potentially supercharge every facet of our humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When a system administrator or programmer uses a computer, they often issue instructions one by one using a special-purpose, text-only interface called a &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/foundations/&quot;&gt;command line&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Individually, these instructions are called &lt;em&gt;invocations&lt;/em&gt;. (Yes, that’s their technical term!) In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll learn how to write whole spells, rituals, or (sacred) texts called &lt;em&gt;shell scripts&lt;/em&gt; to inscribe your own thoughts, dreams, and desires in the electrified silicon and minerals of your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;By saving your scripts in files, you can invoke arbitrarily complex routines to reproduce tasks or automate complex procedures with a single command. Writing scripts also makes it possible to share what you can do with others and, as such, are one the simplest forms of computer program that you can write and distribute. Come learn how the magic of digital inscription can help you do your work, and increase your power to accomplish your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2023-11-05-writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to inscribe your thoughts, dreams, and desires into your computer and take your command line skills to the next level by learning how to write simple programs called shell scripts. In a way, invoking commands one at a time is like writing a program interactively, whereas writing a script inscribes that knowledge into a more permanent form. By learning how to turn commands into simple scripted programs, you can unlock the almost magical potential of your computer and more easily share that potential with others to whom you distribute your scripts.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.writing-with-blue-fire-shell-scripting-for-beginners.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">November, November Trance Party</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/11/event-2023-11-04-november-november-trance-party" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="November, November Trance Party" /><published>2023-11-04T21:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-11-04T21:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/11/event-2023-11-04-november-november-trance-party</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/11/event-2023-11-04-november-november-trance-party">&lt;p&gt;Noble neighors!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note this night of November the 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, a noctural celebration notwithstanding November’s numbing nonchalance, surely introduced by its nippy temperatures. Nay, our evening’s novel narrative is nonfiction, and hosted by the neighborhood’s most notorious gender nonconforming hacker nymph on skates, Vi, with her network of naturally talented nightingale performers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, you navigated the seasons! Now, this 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of November, nourish a nonstandard way to fall into Fall!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the eve of November 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, we’ll prepare for the coming cold of Winter in the way we know best: enjoying cathartic, dreamy trance beats spun by some of Brooklyn’s hottest DJs, basking in radio waves from WiFi-enabled digital libraries letting you browse thousands of e-books for free, and drinks with huggable friends, all bathed in the warm glow of Wonderville’s many arcade cabinets. Drift into an exemplary, shimmering plane of possibilities to recharge your bio-batteries!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;November the 4th is also DJ Astral_Dejection’s birthday, so come early (before the show starts) to participate in a delicious name day treat this November, November that will never be forgot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featuring:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Shift-CTRL Space&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Death By Audio Arcade&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;lain__d&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Astral_Dejection&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;heaven ender&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;dis_aster_ous&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;stuttersprite&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/november-november-trance-party&quot;&gt;$10 - General Admission&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from the event without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-astral_dejection&quot;&gt;About Astral_Dejection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-lain__d&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/lain_d&quot;&gt;lain__d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-heaven-ender&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/heavenender&quot;&gt;heaven ender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;heaven ender is an immortal entity inhabiting the mortal plane of existence seeking to make the world a more beautiful place. Host of Gender Experts Party, producer of Str8 to DVD and all around creature of the New York underground rave scene, they are known for their unrelenting, genre blurring sets and condemning you to dance for eternity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-dis_aster_ous&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/dis_aster_ous&quot;&gt;dis_aster_ous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-stuttersprite&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://ra.co/dj/stuttersprite&quot;&gt;stuttersprite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New York based, New Jersey raised DJ favoring the atmospheric, psychedelic, and experimental side of dance music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-shift-ctrl-space&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://shiftctrl.space/&quot;&gt;Shift-CTRL Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shift-CTRL Space is an elusive collective of New York City-based hacktivists whose mission is to strengthen local affinity groups with the power of contemporary digital technologies often hoarded by or made illegible by large corporations. As anti-(techno)capitalists, solarpunks, and radical technologists. Our ethics place us against “Adtech,” “Fintech,” and Silicon Valley. We believe technology is an intangible earth, with which we can and should have an earthly relationship. It &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; power that we can harness through holistic methods as individuals and cooperative networks for the empowerment of oneself and of one’s actual communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-vi-like-the-text-editor&quot;&gt;About Vi “like the text editor”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve spent time in Bushwick’s post-quarantine queer party scene or in a number of billiards bars around the city, you may have seen Vi zipping around on her rollerblades. As Brooklyn’s own trans hacker roller slut, she has the type of main character energy found in cyberpunk hentai and is best known for her approachable, sporty whirlwind of kind, extroverted energy radiating from a hard femme candy shell. Whether she’s holding a pool cue, a keyboard, a tequila shot, or all three, it’s all about having a good, safe, and memorable time making people feel comfortable at the party. Say hi!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-death-by-audio&quot;&gt;About Death By Audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deathbyaudioarcade.com/&quot;&gt;Death By Audio Arcade&lt;/a&gt; is a series of lovingly crafted local multiplayer arcade cabinets produced by local indie game developers. We are also a progressive, open community of like-minded artists, artisans, and enthusiasts. We host events at least once a month, in NYC and at events across the country, from SXSW to the Smithsonian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Noble neighors!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ca40c7b40978c0001458f5d/62ba1e7e-6ba8-49be-bdcd-5b1fa2a76277/poster.1080x1080+-+Tech+LearningCollective.jpg?format=540w" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5ca40c7b40978c0001458f5d/62ba1e7e-6ba8-49be-bdcd-5b1fa2a76277/poster.1080x1080+-+Tech+LearningCollective.jpg?format=540w" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Imitation Game: Introduction to Administering Virtual Machine Systems</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-29-the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Imitation Game: Introduction to Administering Virtual Machine Systems" /><published>2023-10-29T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-29T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-29-the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-29-the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems">&lt;p&gt;This workshop is a practical introduction to creating, using, and administering virtual machine (VM) systems. Even if you’ve never heard of a virtual machine before, you probably already use the underlying technology. And you can get a lot out of using a virtual machine even if you aren’t a software developer because they can help secure your Web browsing activity, give you a sandbox in which to try out new software, and much more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Virtualization and containerization are concepts almost as old as computing itself so, no matter what you’re doing on your computer, you’re probably using one form of it or another. For example, partitioning a hard disk chunks its total capacity into smaller units useful for specific purposes, much like the individual drawers in a dresser might separate undergarments from outerwear. Organizing, or “containerizing,” your closet this way is useful in its own right because it helps you keep things neat and orderly. But this organizing method also offers dramatic security enhancements because a misbehaving program (or dirty sock) will be confined to its own container.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today, virtualization has become integral to how desktop computers, servers, and global data networks work, and cross-platform, Free Software virtualization programs have never been easier to use. Storage virtualization makes it possible for a single file on your computer to appear to be an entire hard disk drive (such as provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.veracrypt.fr/&quot;&gt;VeraCrypt&lt;/a&gt;), network virtualization makes it possible to simulate different networks (e.g., using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_LAN&quot;&gt;VLANs&lt;/a&gt;) or even the whole Internet (using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inetsim.org/&quot;&gt;INetSim&lt;/a&gt;), processor virtualization makes it possible to run programs built for one microchip architecture on computers running a completely different one (e.g., in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qemu.org/&quot;&gt;QEMU&lt;/a&gt;), and fully-fledged virtual machine monitors (VMMs) or hypervisors can construct and modify entire hardware environments complete with virtual video monitors and other peripherals on the fly (as is offered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.proxmox.com/&quot;&gt;Proxmox&lt;/a&gt;). Virtualization is even the bedrock of numerous Operating System and Web browser security features, such as in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qubes-os.org/&quot;&gt;Qubes Operating System&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/archive/documentation/Security/Conceptual/AppSandboxDesignGuide/AboutAppSandbox/AboutAppSandbox.html&quot;&gt;macOS’s App Sandbox&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/kb/containers&quot;&gt;Firefox Containers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Whether you’re using your computer for fun or for profit, this workshop will get you up and running with Virtual Machines using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualbox.org/&quot;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; type-2 hypervisor so you can experiment with unfamiliar software more boldly, browse the Web more safely, and play games you otherwise wouldn’t have been able to. By learning how to take advantage of the virtualization capabilities your computer already offers, you can revive your love of that long-lost DOS point-and-click adventure, reliably build and test single- and multi-machine networked software systems, or simply create an almost unlimited number of purpose-built virtual machines that all exist, like inception, inside your existing laptop or other personal computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2023-10-29-the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">This workshop is a practical introduction to creating, using, and administering virtual machine (VM) systems. Even if you’ve never heard of a virtual machine before, you probably already use the underlying technology. And you can get a lot out of using a virtual machine even if you aren’t a software developer because they can help secure your Web browsing activity, give you a sandbox in which to try out new software, and much more!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tor: What is it Good For? (Absolutely Everything!)</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-28-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tor: What is it Good For? (Absolutely Everything!)" /><published>2023-10-28T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-28T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-28-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-28-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything">&lt;p&gt;Come learn how the free Tor Web Browser can be your gateway to the Dark Web while simultaneously keeping you safer and your personal info more private as you browse web sites big and small. In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From illegal online drug stores like Silk Road to DDoS botnet command and control headquarters, media attention has long painted “the Dark Web” as though nothing good can come of it. But learn just a little bit more about how Tor and “hidden services” work and you’ll find a treasure trove of valuable possibilities for day-to-day Internet use. The same technology that can hide the location of a drug ring can also serve as a free VPN-like service to protect your privacy while you browse the Internet, make censored websites available again, and even let you host your own Internet services for free, all without opening a single port on your firewall!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool. They’ll demonstrate numerous Tor features such as Tor authentication, target service load balancing, and NAT-punching. In the process, you’ll finally understand—on a technical level—what the “Dark Web” actually is and how it works. Bring a laptop to class, and you’ll leave having run your own Dark Web site. This class is for everyone; whether you’re a veteran black hat or a timid newbie, this class will shine a light on the Dark Web once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2023-10-28-tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Come learn how the free Tor Web Browser can be your gateway to the Dark Web while simultaneously keeping you safer and your personal info more private as you browse web sites big and small. In this deep dive workshop on Tor, the Tech Learning Collective’s cybersecurity trainers will show you how to make the most of this widely available and free digital safety tool.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.tor-what-is-it-good-for-absolutely-everything.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Taming Daemons: System Administration and Operation Basics</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-22-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taming Daemons: System Administration and Operation Basics" /><published>2023-10-22T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-22T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-22-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-22-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics">&lt;p&gt;Most individuals with access to a computer system have more power today than ever before, but rarely do they make use of it or even know how much power they truly have. In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll begin learning how to “speak with the machines.” By learning to communicate more expressively with the digital devices that are increasingly responsible for mediating contemporary society, you’ll gain the power to effectively and materially change your relationship not only with your laptop, but with global systems of law, finance, and even art, literature, and philosophy governing today’s world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How much good does a powerful tool do for you if you don’t know how to use it well? How much more capable would you be if you mastered all the tools available to you? It might sound ridiculous, but failing to learn the practicalities of computer system operation basics is arguably the most common mistake people in the fast-paced tech scene make.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Modern computers are power tools, and behind each one of them is a human operator, or “system administrator,” responsible for configuring and maintaining that computer. If you have a personal computer such as a laptop or smartphone, then you are already a system administrator whether you realize it or not! Making sure the apps you want to use are installed and up to date, managing the amount of free space you have for your photos, and connecting or disconnecting from the Internet are all examples of simple system administration tasks that you probably already take on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner’s workshop, we’ll start by exploring what happens inside your computer when you take every-day tasks like open a Web browser or save files, and then dive down the rabbit hole to meet the special class of programs that make it possible for all your other programs to work. Called &lt;em&gt;daemons&lt;/em&gt;, short for Disk Access and Execution Monitors, they make up the world of Operating System services, signals, sockets, and more under the hood of your desktop environment. By the end of this workshop, you’ll have a far deeper understanding of how to care for your computer, as well as the ability to understand any new tools or services you encounter a whole lot faster than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2023-10-22-taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Most individuals with access to a computer system have more power today than ever before, but rarely do they make use of it or even know how much power they truly have. In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll begin learning how to “speak with the machines.” By learning to communicate more expressively with the digital devices that are increasingly responsible for mediating contemporary society, you’ll gain the power to effectively and materially change your relationship not only with your laptop, but with global systems of law, finance, and even art, literature, and philosophy governing today’s world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.taming-daemons-system-administration-and-operation-basics.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Clearing Away the Clouds: How Computer Networks, Servers, and the Internet Work</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-21-clearing-away-the-clouds-how-computer-networks-servers-and-the-internet-work" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clearing Away the Clouds: How Computer Networks, Servers, and the Internet Work" /><published>2023-10-21T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-21T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-21-clearing-away-the-clouds-how-computer-networks-servers-and-the-internet-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-21-clearing-away-the-clouds-how-computer-networks-servers-and-the-internet-work">&lt;p&gt;Learn the basics of computer networking in this workshop that starts by watching a “conversation” between two computers as it’s happening in real time. You’ll be introduced to the free professional network analysis application called Wireshark so that you can listen in on what the programs on your computer are saying to or hearing from other computers across the Internet. By the end of this workshop, you’ll understand all about the basics of computer networking. If you’ve ever been curious about what happens “on the wire” when you’re browsing a Web site, or if you ever wanted to take a look “under the hood” of your Wi-Fi connection, this is the class for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Our ability to browse Web sites, send and receive digital messages like emails and text messages, and make phone or video calls depends on the connections our digital devices make with one another. That makes it critical to understand how these connections are made, and where they lead to. Far from being an amorphous “cloud,” modern telecommunications networks and services like the Internet are made up of physical devices. Some of these you can see, like your own computer or the router and modem in your house, and others you can’t, like distant servers or Layer 2 switches that make up the network infrastructure itself.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop derived from a portion of the &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/net101.html&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s NET101 course&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll have the opportunity to actually look—visually and with great detail—at how your computer “talks” to other computers like those that power Google Drive, Facebook, and other cloud services. By using an industry-standard tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://wireshark.org/&quot;&gt;Wireshark&lt;/a&gt;, we’ll dissect a conversation between your computer and a server and walk through the process of encapsulating a packet of application layer data, emitting it onto a network, and watching it travel to its destination. We’ll also touch on some illustrative counter-examples to explore how things can go wrong on a network, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dynamic_Host_Configuration_Protocol&quot;&gt;DHCP&lt;/a&gt; server misconfigurations, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ARP_spoofing&quot;&gt;ARP spoofing attacks&lt;/a&gt;, and unsecured or weakly-secured Wi-Fi networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2023-10-21-clearing-away-the-clouds-how-computer-networks-servers-and-the-internet-work&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn the basics of computer networking in this workshop that starts by watching a “conversation” between two computers as it’s happening in real time. You’ll be introduced to the free professional network analysis application called Wireshark so that you can listen in on what the programs on your computer are saying to or hearing from other computers across the Internet. By the end of this workshop, you’ll understand all about the basics of computer networking. If you’ve ever been curious about what happens “on the wire” when you’re browsing a Web site, or if you ever wanted to take a look “under the hood” of your Wi-Fi connection, this is the class for you!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.clearing-away-the-clouds-how-computer-networks-servers-and-the-internet-work.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.clearing-away-the-clouds-how-computer-networks-servers-and-the-internet-work.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Automate All the Things: A Primer to Infrastructure as Code</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-15-automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automate All the Things: A Primer to Infrastructure as Code" /><published>2023-10-15T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-15T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-15-automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-15-automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to make your own Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), automatically install software on the servers in your cloud, and write executable runbooks to automatically perform upgrades and other maintenance with the press of a button. With today’s modern automation toolkits, a two-person hobby project can outperform a 100-person company, as long as they use the right tools the right way. In this workshop, you’ll get a practical introduction to cloud infrastructure automation with tools like Ansible, Vagrant, and Terraform, and a chance to solidify your understanding of fundamental DevOps skills that every IT professional needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In today’s IT environments, application servers, databases, file shares, and even network devices are too numerous for any individual or team to provision, configure, and administer one at a time. To deploy, maintain, and secure large digital fleets, site reliability engineers leverage the inherent power of computerized automation to perform everything from daily tasks (patching, updating code) to critical but rare operations (migrations, incident response). But even small groups can take advantage of this sort of automation to massively amplify their impact; today, a two-person hobby project can outperform a 100-person company if they use the right tools the right way.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Generically called &lt;em&gt;Infrastructure as Code (IaC)&lt;/em&gt;, modern configuration management tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ansible.com/&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chef.io/&quot;&gt;Chef&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://saltstack.com/&quot;&gt;SaltStack&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://puppet.com/&quot;&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt; make it possible for a single operator to paralellize executing Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) like initiating backups or performing blue-green deployments on hundreds or thousands of machines at once. By using virtualization through IaC tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://vagrantup.com/&quot;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt;, entire “cloud” environments can be emulated for heterogenous development teams, massively streamlining everything from software development, to R&amp;amp;D, to education and onboarding. (Tech Learning Collective’s own course exercises and practice labs are defined in code as Vagrant configurations!) Encoding your organization’s infrastructure requirements in standard, vendor-neutral, open formats such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://terraform.io/&quot;&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt; means you can switch from one infrastructure provider to another with ease. But perhaps most important of all, “automating all the things” means that potential disasters like ransomware extortion attempts, outages, or even mere accidents can be audited, diagnosed, and remediated in a matter of minutes instead of days or weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop, you’ll get a practical introduction to cloud infrastructure automation. You’ll learn how to create your first virtual private cloud (VPC), add multiple machines to it, automatically install server software on those machines, and write exectuable runbooks to automatically perform upgrades and other maintenance tasks on your new infrastructure. Whether you’re already administering a fleet of servers at work, or just want to slim your “weekend project” time down to size, this far-reaching workshop will solidify your understanding of the development operations (DevOps) skills every IT professional needs to hone to have success with modern digital infrastructure projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2023-10-15-automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to make your own Virtual Private Cloud (VPC), automatically install software on the servers in your cloud, and write executable runbooks to automatically perform upgrades and other maintenance with the press of a button. With today’s modern automation toolkits, a two-person hobby project can outperform a 100-person company, as long as they use the right tools the right way. In this workshop, you’ll get a practical introduction to cloud infrastructure automation with tools like Ansible, Vagrant, and Terraform, and a chance to solidify your understanding of fundamental DevOps skills that every IT professional needs.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.automate-all-the-things-a-primer-to-infrastructure-as-code.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Computer Language Foundations: Command Line Basics</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-14-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Computer Language Foundations: Command Line Basics" /><published>2023-10-14T13:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-14T13:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-14-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/10/workshop-2023-10-14-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics">&lt;p&gt;You have read about people who can talk to machines. Maybe you imagined secret chambers, hidden away behind locked doors, with dark rooms basking in blue from electric fires. Some of these people seemed friendly, others scary, but all of them were powerful. How did they learn to communicate with their computers? This is your chance to learn the foundations of all computer languages, the command line, and actually begin to talk to a machine yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To be useful, every computer must offer some way for you to control it. Generically, the way you can control a computer is called a &lt;em&gt;user interface&lt;/em&gt; because it allows you (the user) to interact with (that is, “to interface with”) the computer system. Most people may already be familiar with &lt;em&gt;Graphical User Interfaces&lt;/em&gt; or GUIs, which are the buttons, windows, and other controls that you can point-and-click on, but this way of controlling a computer comes with severe limitations. Chief among these is the fact that you are limited to using only one tip of one finger on one of your hands (called your &lt;em&gt;pointer&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;mouse cursor&lt;/em&gt;) and, worse, you have no access to anything outside of your immediate reach. In a GUI, if you cannot see it or touch it with the mouse, you cannot manipulate it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is why almost all hackers, programmers, and system administrators prefer a Command Line Interface or CLI over the graphical options for many, if not most, of their day-to-day tasks. In a command-line, or “terminal,” you can use the complete expressive power of spoken language to control your computer. You can use symbolism and metaphor to express any idea that you have the words for. Moreover, you always have all the words you know at your disposal at any time, even if they refer to things that are far away or that you cannot currently see.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll learn how to access the command line interface of your computer, and you’ll learn the basic grammar of command line languages such as that provided by the ubiquitous Bash command interpreter. You’ll also be introduced to the basic set of utilities required to quickly accomplish tasks that require working with files and folders, processing text, and automating common workflows that would take dozens or even hundreds of clicks with a mouse to complete in a Graphical User Interface. By learning how to “speak” to your computer using a command language, you can save hours every day and take your first step toward using your computer the way the best hackers would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2023-10-14-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">You have read about people who can talk to machines. Maybe you imagined secret chambers, hidden away behind locked doors, with dark rooms basking in blue from electric fires. Some of these people seemed friendly, others scary, but all of them were powerful. How did they learn to communicate with their computers? This is your chance to learn the foundations of all computer languages, the command line, and actually begin to talk to a machine yourself.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hex90: Birthday Attack</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/07/event-2023-07-08-hex90-birthday-attack" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hex90: Birthday Attack" /><published>2023-07-08T19:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-08T19:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/07/event-2023-07-08-hex90-birthday-attack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2023/07/event-2023-07-08-hex90-birthday-attack">&lt;p&gt;Queer hackers of the world, unite! Tech Learning Collective is excited to invite you to a very special Hex90 party. Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://hex90.party/&quot;&gt;series of queer hacker salons in New York City, Hex90&lt;/a&gt;, continues this Summer with &lt;cite&gt;Hex90: Birthday Attack&lt;/cite&gt;, so named because we are simultaneously celebrating the birthdays/tranniversaries of several prominent community members. Join us at our favorite indie arcade venue, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wonderville.nyc/&quot;&gt;Wonderville&lt;/a&gt;, for a celebration of trans and non-binary joy, gender affirmation, and the zest for life! Get ready for nostalgic favorites, retro tech, psychedelic, euphoric optimism, and of course prepare to hack the planet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre style=&quot;white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-txt&quot;&gt;HEX90 — a queer hacker salon in NYC

Welcome, witches, wizards, and techno-sorceresses, to our next genesis! The process of becoming is both a moment and a series of discoveries. How much can one change before our new signature no longer matches the old? What you know you can't explain, but you feel it. You've felt it your entire life.

The 1980s was a decade of great technological change. The development of the modern Internet began with the ARPANET. Arcade games became a major industry. Personal computers experienced exponential growth. Boomboxes and the Walkman transformed music culture. Drum machines and electronic instruments dominated the music production landscape. And, let's not forget, epic synthesizers.

The 1990s brought major social upheaval. Many Detroit-based artists propelled techno and house music onto the global stage. Tactics of &quot;digital civil disobedience&quot; pioneered by the Electronic Disturbance Theater captured the imagination of young hacktivists. The Matrix and Transgender Day of Remembrance began in the same year, sewing the seeds of revolutions still to come.

You have to let it all go: fear, doubt, and disbelief. Free your mind! Everything, everything, everything! I'm invisible. How deep does the rabbit hole go? Collide, and find your looking-glass self!

info_

July 8, 2023 @ Wonderville
1186 Broadway, Brooklyn, NY 11221
7:30pm — 4:00am

~ this venue is accessible
~ this venue has gender-neutral restrooms
~ this venue has outdoor space
~ this venue permits entry only to those aged 21+

# dressing up is encouraged but not required

featuring_

~ music performances by
~~ Janus Rose
~~ heaven ender
~~ Niyah West
~~ DJ Softserve
~~ stuttersprite
~~ dis_aster_ous
~~ David Lunch
~~ GENDERLESSBEAST
~ visuals and livecoding by
~~ gwenpri.me
~~ alsoknownasrox
~ indie games by Death By Audio Arcade
~ hacking demos &amp;amp; education by Tech Learning Collective
~ text adventure cybersecurity game by Shift-CTRL Space

DANCE AT THE STAGE, AND BRING YOUR LAPTOP SO YOU CAN HACK AT THE BAR!

In addition to music and visuals, the most unique addition of the Hex90 parties is a hyperlocal cybersecurity (hacking) themed text-adventure game that gave the party its name: Hex90. This game is played on your own laptop, not on a console or arcade cabinet at the venue, but is still only accessible when you are physically at the party venue itself. (Aside from a short &quot;trailer,&quot; the game is not available on the public Internet.)

After you connect to the party's Wi-Fi network, you can then connect to the Hex90 game server using your Web browser. But to solve the challenges, you must download and install real hacker tools and learn how to employ real hacking techniques to progress through game levels ranging from network reconnaissance, applied cryptography, and Web exploitation. You've never seen so many queers open so many terminals in one place while being so close to a dance floor, and there's no high quite like it.

We continuously add levels to the game, so expect new challenges at most parties. Moreover, we sometimes incorporate physical-world features of the venue, like padlocks you need to pick that are safeguarding access to secret passwords, QR codes stashed in unexpected places, unassuming but exposed Ethernet cabling that turns out not to be a mistake at all, and so on. At Hex90, the game controller is your computer and the game mechanic is the real world.

All of the tools, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) used to progress in the game levels are skills taught by and equipment used by Tech Learning Collective instructors in our online workshops. Visit TechLearningCollective.com for more information and to enroll.

#------------------#
# START HACKING AT #
#------------------#
https://hex90.party

#------------------#
# BUY TICKETS HERE #
#------------------#
https://wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-birthday-attack

SUPPORTER TIER:
$30 - pay if you can

ADVANCE TICKETS:
$15.00 - str8 cismen
$10.00 - queers/transes/enbies and femmes

DAY-OF/AT THE DOOR:
$20.00 - str8 cismen
$15.00 - queers/transes/enbies and femmes

/**
* Hex90 is an inclusive event.
* Door staff is instructed to respect your self-identification.
*/

NOTICE:

This is an intentionally queer space. Consent and respect are not optional! Anyone behaving unkindly will be removed immediately without a refund. No amount of racism, queerphobia, transphobia, or sexism will be tolerated. This event is a celebration of queer hacking for queer hackers, not for Silicon Valley entrepreneurs, brogrammers, or BitCoin bros. Don't piss off the hackers. ;)

Hex90

###
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hex90.party/&quot;&gt;Start playing immediately and buy your ticket at the invitation site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-birthday-attack&quot;&gt;$30 - Supporter (pay if you can)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-birthday-attack&quot;&gt;$15 - General Admission - Advance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-birthday-attack&quot;&gt;$10 - Queers and Femmes - Advance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-birthday-attack&quot;&gt;$20 - General Admission - Day-of/at the door&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wonderville.nyc/events/hex90-birthday-attack&quot;&gt;$15 - Queers and Femmes - Day-of/at the door&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from the event without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-death-by-audio&quot;&gt;About Death By Audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deathbyaudioarcade.com/&quot;&gt;Death By Audio Arcade&lt;/a&gt; is a series of lovingly crafted local multiplayer arcade cabinets produced by local indie game developers. We are also a progressive, open community of like-minded artists, artisans, and enthusiasts. We host events at least once a month, in NYC and at events across the country, from SXSW to the Smithsonian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-heaven-ender&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/heavenender&quot;&gt;heaven ender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;heaven ender is an immortal entity inhabiting the mortal plane of existence seeking to make the world a more beautiful place. Rising from the dark corners of the rave scene they will be presenting one of their unrelenting, genre blurring sets and condemning you to dance for eternity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-niyah-west&quot;&gt;About Niyah West&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Niyah West (she/they) is a DJ, music curator and digital artist based in New York City. From the living rooms of dear friends to the night clubs, Niyah made her professional debut just this year during pride month. Thus, making her a bright newcomer in the queer DJ scene. She has amplified parties and dancefloors all over the boroughs, some recently including MEOW NYC, Gayjoy &amp;amp; a residency at Kind Regards in the Lower East Side. She’s also a resident of Brooklyn based queer DJ collective XOXA NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-stuttersprite&quot;&gt;About stuttersprite&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by a lifelong interest in games, stuttersprite’s psychedelic and emotional high-energy sound explores the crossover between techno, trance, electro, and vgm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-gwenprime&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://gwenpri.me/&quot;&gt;gwenpri.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gwenpri.me is a creative technologist, artist, and livecoder. She makes live visuals from videos, pictures, emoji, text, and more, then composites them using live code techniques. She enjoys finding arcane ways to put pixels on screens. Past sets have included touch designer patching, Lua DSLs, command line video editors, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-alsoknownasrox&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/alsoknownasrox&quot;&gt;alsoknownasrox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;alsoknownasrox is a New York-based audiovisual artist approaching programming as a medium for creative expression. She specializes in programming as performance, modifying real-time processes to create dynamic audiovisual experiences. She spends her time finding new ways to engage with the world, destructing and reconstructing existing structures as she goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-david-lunch&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundcloud.com/davidlunchbox&quot;&gt;David Lunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Lunch (Ben Breier) is a genre-crossing DJ that leans into breakbeat, two-step, Jersey Club, UKG &amp;amp; techno. He is the current host of Zero Chill on Newtown Radio, and the resident DJ at Jade’s Exactly. He has opened for acts that include Crystal Castles, !!! &amp;amp; The Hood Internet. Under the moniker Mister Disco, he was the resident DJ at Happy House (The Bell House) as well as Endmax at Trophy Bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-dj-softserve&quot;&gt;About &lt;a href=&quot;softserve.the.frost.dj&quot;&gt;DJ Softserve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Softserve began DJing in South Korea in 2017 where he became a local hip hop resident. After a few years he moved on to headlining at Korean EDM festivals and playing Busan’s premiere house and techno clubs. After moving to Brooklyn, he continues to play high energy eclectic bass mixes flexing genre boundaries from latin and afro beats to wonky UK tech, half-time flips and basshouse. He focusing on moving the crowd to “get their tongues hanging out” and is the CEO of saying “damn- I probably should have recorded that set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Queer hackers of the world, unite! Tech Learning Collective is excited to invite you to a very special Hex90 party. Our series of queer hacker salons in New York City, Hex90, continues this Summer with Hex90: Birthday Attack, so named because we are simultaneously celebrating the birthdays/tranniversaries of several prominent community members. Join us at our favorite indie arcade venue, Wonderville, for a celebration of trans and non-binary joy, gender affirmation, and the zest for life! Get ready for nostalgic favorites, retro tech, psychedelic, euphoric optimism, and of course prepare to hack the planet!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.hex90.flyer.2023-07-08.540x540.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/event.hex90.flyer.2023-07-08.540x540.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>