<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_US" /><updated>2021-03-17T08:41:24-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/feed/events.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Learning Collective | Events</title><subtitle>Apprenticeship-based technology school for hypermedia, Information Technology, cybersecurity, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by cyber armies and governments.</subtitle><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><entry><title type="html">Shields Up: Firewalls and Other Network Perimeter Defenses</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/04/workshop-2021-04-04-shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shields Up: Firewalls and Other Network Perimeter Defenses" /><published>2021-04-04T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-04T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/04/workshop-2021-04-04-shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/04/workshop-2021-04-04-shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses">&lt;p&gt;Master the fundamentals of personal and enterprise-grade network firewalls in this hands-on workshop about network perimeter security. By learning to use the macOS, Windows, BSD, and Linux firewalls (including command-line utilities like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iptables&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nft&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pfctl&lt;/code&gt;), you can protect your devices even on untrustworthy or hostile networks, like public Wi-Fi. Intended for all audiences, you’ll gain experience with both beginner-friendly and advanced tools like pfSense as you get an introduction to a wide range of NetSec scenarios. We’ll also cover the important security properties of NAT routers, how deep packet inspection (DPI) works, and get you started with industry-standard Network Intrusion Detection/Prevention Systems (NIDS/NIPS) like Snort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In today’s ubiquitous computing environment, the most frequently used entrance (and exit!) in to (or out of) any system is its &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Clearing-Away-the-Clouds-How-Computer-Networks,-Servers,-and-the-Internet-Work&quot;&gt;network connection&lt;/a&gt;. That’s why network firewalls have been a central component of every network security architecture since their introduction in the 1980’s. A firewall’s primary responsibility is to stop the spread of malware, help prevent cyberattacks and unauthorized data exfiltration, or isolate other problems in one network or network segment from affecting others. Thus, firewalls serve to compartmentalize one area of a computer network from another. And while they are most commonly thought of as being at network boundaries like your home or office router, just about &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; computer has a firewall these days, including your personal laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Modern firewalls can also do a lot more than their first or second generation ancestors that simply blocked certain ports or kept track of ongoing conversations between two endpoints. By building on so-called Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) technology, firewalls can analyze the traffic passing through them in real time, making decisions about what to allow or block based on myriad factors. On more heavily policed or otherwise protected networks, firewalls have evolved into very powerful Network Intrusion Detection or Prevention Systems (NIDS/NIPS).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But don’t make the mistake of thinking this power is reserved for rich corporations! The firewall built into the Linux kernel (called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netfilter.org/&quot;&gt;Netfilter&lt;/a&gt; and controlled with the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iptables&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nft&lt;/code&gt; commands) is the backbone of almost all commercial enterprise firewall distributions, and it’s available free of charge. Plus, its ability to intercept and modify traffic in-flight is the basis of many proxy technologies such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/network/&quot;&gt;Docker’s networking&lt;/a&gt; and Kubernetes’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/command-line-tools-reference/kube-proxy/&quot;&gt;kube-proxy&lt;/a&gt;, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So, are your network shields up? Find out at this workshop where we’ll show you how to use the firewall built-in to your Windows, macOS, or GNU/Linux laptop. We’ll also show you how to set up firewalled subnets using NAT routers, a bulletproof way to keep unsecured Internet of Things (IoT) or smart-home devices from infecting your more critical personal devices, or to make a super-secure guest Wi-Fi network available for visitors. You’ll leave understanding the utility of so-called Layer 7 firewalls such as Web Application Firewalls (WAFs), and knowing how to test the security of your own firewall configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-04-04-shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Master the fundamentals of personal and enterprise-grade network firewalls in this hands-on workshop about network perimeter security. By learning to use the macOS, Windows, BSD, and Linux firewalls (including command-line utilities like iptables, nft, and pfctl), you can protect your devices even on untrustworthy or hostile networks, like public Wi-Fi. Intended for all audiences, you’ll gain experience with both beginner-friendly and advanced tools like pfSense as you get an introduction to a wide range of NetSec scenarios. We’ll also cover the important security properties of NAT routers, how deep packet inspection (DPI) works, and get you started with industry-standard Network Intrusion Detection/Prevention Systems (NIDS/NIPS) like Snort.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.shields-up-firewalls-and-other-network-perimeter-defenses.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Computer Language Foundations: Command Line Basics</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/04/workshop-2021-04-03-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Computer Language Foundations: Command Line Basics" /><published>2021-04-03T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-03T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/04/workshop-2021-04-03-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/04/workshop-2021-04-03-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics">&lt;p&gt;You have read about people who can talk to machines. Maybe you imagined secret chambers, hidden away behind locked doors, with dark rooms basking in blue from electric fires. Some of these people seemed friendly, others scary, but all of them were powerful. How did they learn to communicate with their computers? This is your chance to learn the foundations of all computer languages, the command line, and actually begin to talk to a machine yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To be useful, every computer must offer some way for you to control it. Generically, the way you can control a computer is called a &lt;em&gt;user interface&lt;/em&gt; because it allows you (the user) to interact with (that is, “to interface with”) the computer system. Most people may already be familiar with &lt;em&gt;Graphical User Interfaces&lt;/em&gt; or GUIs, which are the buttons, windows, and other controls that you can point-and-click on, but this way of controlling a computer comes with severe limitations. Chief among these is the fact that you are limited to using only one tip of one finger on one of your hands (called your &lt;em&gt;pointer&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;mouse cursor&lt;/em&gt;) and, worse, you have no access to anything outside of your immediate reach. In a GUI, if you cannot see it or touch it with the mouse, you cannot manipulate it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is why almost all hackers, programmers, and system administrators prefer a Command Line Interface or CLI over the graphical options for many, if not most, of their day-to-day tasks. In a command-line, or “terminal,” you can use the complete expressive power of spoken language to control your computer. You can use symbolism and metaphor to express any idea that you have the words for. Moreover, you always have all the words you know at your disposal at any time, even if they refer to things that are far away or that you cannot currently see.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this beginner’s workshop, you’ll learn how to access the command line interface of your computer, and you’ll learn the basic grammar of command line languages such as that provided by the ubiquitous Bash command interpreter. You’ll also be introduced to the basic set of utilities required to quickly accomplish tasks that require working with files and folders, processing text, and automating common workflows that would take dozens or even hundreds of clicks with a mouse to complete in a Graphical User Interface. By learning how to “speak” to your computer using a command language, you can save hours every day and take your first step toward using your computer the way the best hackers would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-04-03-computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">You have read about people who can talk to machines. Maybe you imagined secret chambers, hidden away behind locked doors, with dark rooms basking in blue from electric fires. Some of these people seemed friendly, others scary, but all of them were powerful. How did they learn to communicate with their computers? This is your chance to learn the foundations of all computer languages, the command line, and actually begin to talk to a machine yourself.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.computer-language-foundations-command-line-basics.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ship Shape Computing: Working with Containers and Containerizing Digital Workloads</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-28-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ship Shape Computing: Working with Containers and Containerizing Digital Workloads" /><published>2021-03-28T14:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-28T14:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-28-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-28-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads">&lt;p&gt;Learn how to pack up your code bases, apps, and microservices and get ready to set sail aboard container orchestration platforms in the cloud or on your own metal in this introductory workshop about working with containers. Far from a newfangled buzzword, containerizing digital workloads have precedents dating back to the invention of the UNIX operating system in the 1970’s. Today, operating container engines like Docker and orchestration platforms like Kubernetes are increasingly essential skills, but difficult to navigate. This workshop will put you back on course by providing a ground-up view of what containers really are, where they came from, and how to best use them for DevOps, site reliability, and even enhanced security tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the earliest days of computing, an application would be responsible for processing only very small amounts of input. It would then produce a similarly small amount of output, working as fast and efficiently as possible. Known as a processing “pipeline,” this early solutions paradigm is most famously expressed as the so-called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_philosophy&quot;&gt;UNIX philosophy&lt;/a&gt;,” a programmer’s adage that states each program should “do (only) one thing, and do it well,” and it’s still the beating heart of powerful computer interfaces such as &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Computer-Language-Foundations-Command-Line-Basics&quot;&gt;command line use&lt;/a&gt; to this day.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Then, all throughout the 1980’s, 90’s, and 2000’s, as computing speed relentlessly increased while its cost simultaneously plummeted, companies began building larger, more complex applications. Known as “monoliths,” this generation of apps were well-suited for their environment, where they were deployed onto singular mainframe-like computers housed inside private server rooms. But these application architectures are no longer sensible in a world where cloud computing and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/The-Imitation-Game-Introduction-to-Administering-Virtual-Machine-Systems&quot;&gt;virtualization technologies&lt;/a&gt; make it possible to dynamically reserve compute power as user demand ebbs and flows. Why over-purchase server hardware when you can spin up another virtual machine to handle a spike in traffic, then automatically have that machine shut itself down when incoming requests settle back at manageable levels?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That’s one reason why, today, online apps from Google, Facebook, and others are written as “microservices.” Far from being worthy of the buzzword-driven hype, this paradigm is actually a return to software’s original designs where the goals of a larger application are processed independently by a set of cooperating but independent smaller programs, each one performing only one job very well. To make this work in today’s cloud environments, each microservice must be “containerized,” packaged into a single &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Taming-Daemons-System-Administration-and-Operation-Basics&quot;&gt;Operating System process&lt;/a&gt; that is run by a container management engine such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://coreos.com/rkt/&quot;&gt;CoreOS’s rkt&lt;/a&gt; (pronounced “rocket”), or &lt;a href=&quot;https://linuxcontainers.org/lxd/introduction/&quot;&gt;LXD&lt;/a&gt; in preparation for being orchestrated across a fleet of hundreds or thousands of (often virtual) compute instances.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this hands-on workshop, you’ll learn how to make use of the thousands of ready-made containers available at container registries such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker Hub&lt;/a&gt;, create new containers from scratch, containerize existing codebases, manage running containers, and more. We’ll explore how to troubleshoot container failures, show how to network multiple containers together, and touch on container orchestration tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/engine/swarm/&quot;&gt;Docker’s Swarm mode&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nomadproject.io/&quot;&gt;HashiCorp Nomad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mesos.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Apache Mesos&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; to see how our containers can be automatically distributed, or “scheduled,” and be tasked with their specialized workloads across a &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Automate-All-the-Things-Infrastructure-as-Code-Primer&quot;&gt;virtual private cloud&lt;/a&gt; based on whatever resources we have available to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-03-28-ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn how to pack up your code bases, apps, and microservices and get ready to set sail aboard container orchestration platforms in the cloud or on your own metal in this introductory workshop about working with containers. Far from a newfangled buzzword, containerizing digital workloads have precedents dating back to the invention of the UNIX operating system in the 1970’s. Today, operating container engines like Docker and orchestration platforms like Kubernetes are increasingly essential skills, but difficult to navigate. This workshop will put you back on course by providing a ground-up view of what containers really are, where they came from, and how to best use them for DevOps, site reliability, and even enhanced security tasks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.ship-shape-computing-working-with-containers-and-containerizing-digital-workloads.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Imitation Game: Introduction to Administering Virtual Machine Systems</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-27-the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Imitation Game: Introduction to Administering Virtual Machine Systems" /><published>2021-03-27T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-27T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-27-the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-27-the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems">&lt;p&gt;This workshop is a practical introduction to creating, using, and administering virtual machine (VM) systems. Even if you’ve never heard of a virtual machine before, you probably already use the underlying technology. And you can get a lot out of using a virtual machine even if you aren’t a software developer because they can help secure your Web browsing activity, give you a sandbox in which to try out new software, and much more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Virtualization and containerization are concepts almost as old as computing itself so, no matter what you’re doing on your computer, you’re probably using one form of it or another. For example, partitioning a hard disk chunks its total capacity into smaller units useful for specific purposes, much like the individual drawers in a dresser might separate undergarments from outerwear. Organizing, or “containerizing,” your closet this way is useful in its own right because it helps you keep things neat and orderly. But this organizing method also offers dramatic security enhancements because a misbehaving program (or dirty sock) will be confined to its own container.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today, virtualization has become integral to how desktop computers, servers, and global data networks work, and cross-platform, Free Software virtualization programs have never been easier to use. Storage virtualization makes it possible for a single file on your computer to appear to be an entire hard disk drive (such as provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.veracrypt.fr/&quot;&gt;VeraCrypt&lt;/a&gt;), network virtualization makes it possible to simulate different networks (e.g., using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_LAN&quot;&gt;VLANs&lt;/a&gt;) or even the whole Internet (using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inetsim.org/&quot;&gt;INetSim&lt;/a&gt;), processor virtualization makes it possible to run programs built for one microchip architecture on computers running a completely different one (e.g., in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qemu.org/&quot;&gt;QEMU&lt;/a&gt;), and fully-fledged virtual machine monitors (VMMs) or hypervisors can construct and modify entire hardware environments complete with virtual video monitors and other peripherals on the fly (as is offered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.proxmox.com/&quot;&gt;Proxmox&lt;/a&gt;). Virtualization is even the bedrock of numerous Operating System and Web browser security features, such as in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qubes-os.org/&quot;&gt;Qubes Operating System&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/archive/documentation/Security/Conceptual/AppSandboxDesignGuide/AboutAppSandbox/AboutAppSandbox.html&quot;&gt;macOS’s App Sandbox&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/kb/containers&quot;&gt;Firefox Containers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Whether you’re using your computer for fun or for profit, this workshop will get you up and running with Virtual Machines using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualbox.org/&quot;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; type-2 hypervisor so you can experiment with unfamiliar software more boldly, browse the Web more safely, and play games you otherwise wouldn’t have been able to. By learning how to take advantage of the virtualization capabilities your computer already offers, you can revive your love of that long-lost DOS point-and-click adventure, reliably build and test single- and multi-machine networked software systems, or simply create an almost unlimited number of purpose-built virtual machines that all exist, like inception, inside your existing laptop or other personal computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-03-27-the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">This workshop is a practical introduction to creating, using, and administering virtual machine (VM) systems. Even if you’ve never heard of a virtual machine before, you probably already use the underlying technology. And you can get a lot out of using a virtual machine even if you aren’t a software developer because they can help secure your Web browsing activity, give you a sandbox in which to try out new software, and much more!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.the-imitation-game-introduction-to-administering-virtual-machine-systems.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">LibrePlanet 2021: Beyond ‘Learning to Code’</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-21-libreplanet-2021-beyond-learning-to-code" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LibrePlanet 2021: Beyond ‘Learning to Code’" /><published>2021-03-21T16:35:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-21T16:35:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-21-libreplanet-2021-beyond-learning-to-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-21-libreplanet-2021-beyond-learning-to-code">&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, March 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;, join Tech Learning Collective and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fsf.org/&quot;&gt;Free Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt; at the all-online LibrePlanet 2021 conference about software freedom, where we will be delivering our talk, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://libreplanet.org/2021/speakers/#4763&quot;&gt;Beyond ‘Learning to Code’: How Tech Learning Collective Merges IT Training with Emancipatory Political Action&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What good is a pen if the paper it touches can refuse to show its ink? What good is your app when your API key is revoked? Through metaphor and with a unique apprenticeship-based pedagogy, Tech Learning Collective (TLC) is empowering users by doing exactly what code boot camps and corporate-funded “learn to code” programs don’t: TLC tells students to ignore new Web frameworks and focus instead on the lowest layers of an IT stack like physical network and hardware storage devices. At TLC, infrastructure is the heart of a free software curriculum eschewing common rush-to-employment training paradigms in favor of Socratic classrooms where practicing Bash commands seamlessly meld with lectures about Gnostic influences on Ethernet, the relationship between Gregorian chants and bootloaders, and more. Come see why and how TLC’s holistic approach to IT education is creating communities of activist sysadmins out of people who wouldn’t otherwise have called themselves “techies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LibrePlanet is a conference about software freedom, happening March 20 through 21, 2021. The event is hosted by the Free Software Foundation (FSF), and brings together software developers, law and policy experts, activists, students, and computer users to learn skills, celebrate free software accomplishments, and face upcoming challenges. Newcomers are always welcome, and LibrePlanet 2021 will feature programming for all ages and experience levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;Tickets are required to attend the conference; please &lt;a href=&quot;https://u.fsf.org/lp21-sp&quot;&gt;register for LibrePlanet 2021&lt;/a&gt; in advance.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-free-software-foundation&quot;&gt;About the Free Software Foundation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Free Software Foundation (FSF) is a nonprofit with a worldwide mission to promote computer user freedom. We defend the rights of all software users.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">On Sunday, March 21st, join Tech Learning Collective and the Free Software Foundation at the all-online LibrePlanet 2021 conference about software freedom, where we will be delivering our talk, “Beyond ‘Learning to Code’: How Tech Learning Collective Merges IT Training with Emancipatory Political Action.”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://libreplanet.org/2021/assets/img/logo.svg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://libreplanet.org/2021/assets/img/logo.svg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Securing Our Servers: Basic Network Operations for Autonomous Communities</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-20-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Securing Our Servers: Basic Network Operations for Autonomous Communities" /><published>2021-03-20T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-20T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-20-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-20-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities">&lt;p&gt;Learn the basics of securing digital infrastructure by taking a deep-dive into the Secure Shell (SSH) protocol, a fundamental component of safe administrative access to remote servers. Regardless of whether you rely on one or many thousands of servers to power your daily operations, securely managing those machines is essential to the success of your efforts. This intermediate-level workshop shows you how to securely set up, access, and debug connection issues over the SSH protocol so that you’ll be ready to operate self-hosted digital infrastructure for yourself, friends, or comrades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every app you use—from messengers like &lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; or WhatsApp to blogs and websites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and even other coordination tools like digital calendars and &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Our-Streets,-Our-Maps-Introduction-to-OpenStreetMap&quot;&gt;online maps&lt;/a&gt;—relies on a computer called a server. Whether that computer is one in your hand (your smartphone), or a computer somewhere across the Internet (“in the cloud”), no meaningful digital communication happens without servers offering services, somewhere. So, do you know where &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; servers are? If not, you can’t know how safe your data is!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When you don’t have a clear map of how your messages and other data gets from here to there, you might be at risk of someone listening in on your conversations. When you rely on services that you don’t own yourself for critical day-to-day operations (like Google Calendar, or Facebook…) you risk losing access to those capabilities by having your account banned, even by mistake. Regardless of your specific situation, knowing more about the digital servers that are serving you is a vital first step for supporting communities or companies large and small.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This intermediate-level workshop combines various topics from the &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/sys101.html&quot;&gt;Tech Learning Collective’s System Administration&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/net101.html&quot;&gt;Networking&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;/courses/sec101.html&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt; courses to offer an intensive crash course in secure server setup, monitoring, and maintenance. By taking a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/blob/master/train-the-trainers/practice-labs/introduction-to-securing-virtualized-secure-shell-servers/README.md&quot;&gt;deep dive into the SSH protocol&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll learn how to set up remote administrative access to a server in a safe way, and you’ll be exposed to the potential risks of network eavesdroppers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man-in-the-middle_attack&quot;&gt;Machine-in-the-Middle (MITM) attacks&lt;/a&gt;, and much more. By the end of this workshop, you’ll have a basic understanding of how to safely operate self-hosted digital infrastructures for yourself, your friends, and your comrades, as well as what first steps you need to take to keep intruders and enemies at bay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-03-20-securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Learn the basics of securing digital infrastructure by taking a deep-dive into the Secure Shell (SSH) protocol, a fundamental component of safe administrative access to remote servers. Regardless of whether you rely on one or many thousands of servers to power your daily operations, securely managing those machines is essential to the success of your efforts. This intermediate-level workshop shows you how to securely set up, access, and debug connection issues over the SSH protocol so that you’ll be ready to operate self-hosted digital infrastructure for yourself, friends, or comrades.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.securing-our-servers-basic-network-operations-for-autonomous-communities.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Watch and Learn: Web Design and Development Livestream</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-18-watch-and-learn-web-design-and-development-livestream" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Watch and Learn: Web Design and Development Livestream" /><published>2021-03-18T21:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-18T21:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-18-watch-and-learn-web-design-and-development-livestream</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-18-watch-and-learn-web-design-and-development-livestream">&lt;p&gt;Ever wanted to peek over the shoulder of an expert developer as they write code, to pick their brain while they solve real-life problems in real time, or simply bask in the comfort of watching an experienced craftsperson at work? Tech Learning Collective’s “Watch and Learn” events are your chance to join our staff as they livestream some of the work they do, such as redesigning our Web site, building out new or upgrading old infrastructure, and performing other (non-sensitive) tasks to keep Tech Learning Collective moving forward. It’s like watching Bob Ross paint, if he were painting with bits and bytes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;livestream-topic&quot;&gt;Livestream Topic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is redesigning our Web site for 2021. In a few months, we’ll launch a brand new custom Web design for our public-facing Web site. We’ll have new colors, new layouts, and most importantly new code. So this Watch and Learn event will be focused almost exclusively on front-end Web development.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Some of the work has already been done, but there’s lots more to do. Our Web designer will be streaming the way they start by examining graphic design artifacts from the Free Software &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gimp.org/&quot;&gt;GNU Image Manipulation Program (GIMP)&lt;/a&gt;, a powerful alternative to Adobe Photoshop, translating them into liquid and dynamic layouts so that they work in a variety of Web browser makes, models, and sizes, and finally how they integrate the new code with our Web site’s simple Content Management System (CMS) called &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Along the way, you’ll get to see how an experienced front-end Web designer thinks about design elements like layout grids, how they organize and optimize Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) code, and how rich metadata in the form of semantic HTML markup makes their job easier.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;By attending, you get a front-row seat to the video livestream, along with access to a chat channel where you can ask questions about and offer feedback on the coding process live and in real time. We recommend that you have at least some familiarity with basic HTML and CSS code, as this is not a full-fledged class or workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-event-2021-03-18-watch-and-learn-web-design-and-development-livestream&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Ever wanted to peek over the shoulder of an expert developer as they write code, to pick their brain while they solve real-life problems in real time, or simply bask in the comfort of watching an experienced craftsperson at work? Tech Learning Collective’s “Watch and Learn” events are your chance to join our staff as they livestream some of the work they do, such as redesigning our Web site, building out new or upgrading old infrastructure, and performing other (non-sensitive) tasks to keep Tech Learning Collective moving forward. It’s like watching Bob Ross paint, if he were painting with bits and bytes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/poster.web201.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/poster.web201.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bare Bones Crypto: Understanding Critical Cryptographic Primitives</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-14-bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bare Bones Crypto: Understanding Critical Cryptographic Primitives" /><published>2021-03-14T15:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-03-14T15:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-14-bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-14-bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives">&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to have your doctorate in theoretical mathematics to understand crypto enough to use it safely, but you do need to use it safely to be secure! Come learn the magic behind the math in this cryptography primer for those of us who are not “number people.” Using simplified examples and hands-on demonstrations, this workshop (finally!) offers a practical, accessible introduction to the foundations of modern cryptographic security protocols such as RSA public-key cryptography, stream and block ciphers, digital signatures, one-way hash functions, Hash-based Message Authentication Codes (HMACs), and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every time you use a modern computer, you invoke numerous simple mathematical functions that make it possible to do things like logging in to Web sites safely or “locking” (encrypting) your secret documents behind passwords. At their root, these functions, called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptographic_primitive&quot;&gt;cryptographic primitives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, are not that much more complicated than simple addition or division. But when used in concert with the massive storage capacities and processing speeds of our modern electronic devices, they serve as the bedrock atop which every provably secure system works, from &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Password-Superpowers-How-to-Crack-Hashes-and-Stump-Hackers&quot;&gt;password vaults&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Two-Places-at-Once-Understanding-Virtual-Private-Networks&quot;&gt;Virtual Private Networks (VPNs)&lt;/a&gt; to BitCoin and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today, everyone has full access to bulletproof “military grade encryption” for free, even if they don’t realize it. &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Signal-and-Surveillance-How-to-Exercise-Digital-Civil-Liberties-in-a-Surveillance-State&quot;&gt;Signal Private Messenger&lt;/a&gt;’s “Safety Numbers?” Those are cryptographic hash functions! One-time passwords generated by apps like Google Authenticator or Authy? They use nonces! The &lt;a href=&quot;/workshops/Tor-What-is-it-Good-For-(Absolutely-Everything!)&quot;&gt;Tor anonymity network&lt;/a&gt;? That’s a mixnet! The padlock icon in the address bar of your Web browser? Block ciphers (and public-key cryptography, and digital signatures, oh my)!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Knowledge of cryptography was deemed so dangerous during the Cold War that ever since the end of World War II the United States and its military allies attempted to regulate access to these crypto powers by classifying them as “munitions” (i.e., mathematical &lt;em&gt;weapons&lt;/em&gt;, literally) and criminalizing their sale or export. But as the Internet gained widespread commercial adoption and more people became familiar with the underlying math, the government largely relented. It eventually lost what is now retroactively known as the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crypto_Wars&quot;&gt;Crypto Wars&lt;/a&gt;” in the 1990’s.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop, you’ll learn the kind of math that governments tried to keep secret for decades, even if you’re “not a math person.” You’ll see hash functions in practice, learn why longer “keys” are stronger by understanding how RSA secrets are generated, practice developing your own simple ciphers, and start combining primitives to create security protocols that satisfy multiple requirements like confidentiality (privacy), integrity-protection (authenticity), and more. By the end of this workshop, the dizzying vocabulary crytographers use will be well within your reach, as will the ability to understand any new “encryption” product on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-03-14-bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">You don’t need to have your doctorate in theoretical mathematics to understand crypto enough to use it safely, but you do need to use it safely to be secure! Come learn the magic behind the math in this cryptography primer for those of us who are not “number people.” Using simplified examples and hands-on demonstrations, this workshop (finally!) offers a practical, accessible introduction to the foundations of modern cryptographic security protocols such as RSA public-key cryptography, stream and block ciphers, digital signatures, one-way hash functions, Hash-based Message Authentication Codes (HMACs), and more.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives.rectangle.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.bare-bones-crypto-understanding-critical-cryptographic-primitives.rectangle.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Signal and Surveillance: How to Exercise Digital Civil Liberties in a Surveillance State</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-13-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Signal and Surveillance: How to Exercise Digital Civil Liberties in a Surveillance State" /><published>2021-03-13T15:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-13T15:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-13-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/workshop-2021-03-13-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state">&lt;p&gt;This introductory cybersecurity workshop will show you why Signal, a free, secure, private message app is simple enough to schedule drinks with, yet secure enough to use for planning a protest. As dragnet surveillance practices are legalized at alarming speed, there has never been a more important time to flex your digital civil liberties muscle than right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshop-description&quot;&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whether you’re an individual chatting with friends or an organizer planning a political action, all effective coordination depends on safe and reliable communication. Lacking integrity for our communications dooms any effort from the outset, whether mundane or revolutionary. As dragnet surveillance practices are legalized at alarming speed and continue to be fueled by a dramatic expansion of the law enforcement and private defense contractor economies, there has never been a more important time to flex your digital civil liberties muscle than right now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; is the name of a Free Software, secure, private message application built on a cryptographic protocol of the same name. Formerly known as the Axolotl Ratchet or, more commonly, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Double_Ratchet_Algorithm&quot;&gt;Double-Ratchet Algorithm&lt;/a&gt;, its features are robust enough for the revolutionary activist (i.e., end-to-end encryption, message authentication, plausible deniability or message repudiation, perfect forward secrecy, and more) and yet simple enough to use as a drop-in replacement for your existing text messaging application. Signal also sports Skype-like voice and video calling, location- and file-sharing features, and even iMessage-style large font emojis!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you’ve never heard of Signal before, now’s the time to switch. If you think you already know how to use Signal, let us show you some pro-tips (trusted third-party Safety Number verification, disappearing messages, registering Signal accounts with pseudonymous phone numbers, inactivity lock-outs, and Signal relay server IP address protection). This introductory cybersecurity workshop will show you why Signal is simple enough to schedule drinks at the bar with, yet secure enough to use for planning a protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-workshop-2021-03-13-signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">This introductory cybersecurity workshop will show you why Signal, a free, secure, private message app is simple enough to schedule drinks with, yet secure enough to use for planning a protest. As dragnet surveillance practices are legalized at alarming speed, there has never been a more important time to flex your digital civil liberties muscle than right now.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state.rectangle.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/workshop.signal-and-surveillance-how-to-exercise-digital-civil-liberties-in-a-surveillance-state.rectangle.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Watch and Learn: Web Design and Development Livestream</title><link href="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-11-watch-and-learn-web-design-and-development-livestream" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Watch and Learn: Web Design and Development Livestream" /><published>2021-03-11T21:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-11T21:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-11-watch-and-learn-web-design-and-development-livestream</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://techlearningcollective.com/events/2021/03/event-2021-03-11-watch-and-learn-web-design-and-development-livestream">&lt;p&gt;Ever wanted to peek over the shoulder of an expert developer as they write code, to pick their brain while they solve real-life problems in real time, or simply bask in the comfort of watching an experienced craftsperson at work? Tech Learning Collective’s “Watch and Learn” events are your chance to join our staff as they livestream some of the work they do, such as redesigning our Web site, building out new or upgrading old infrastructure, and performing other (non-sensitive) tasks to keep Tech Learning Collective moving forward. It’s like watching Bob Ross paint, if he were painting with bits and bytes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;livestream-topic&quot;&gt;Livestream Topic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is redesigning our Web site for 2021. In a few months, we’ll launch a brand new custom Web design for our public-facing Web site. We’ll have new colors, new layouts, and most importantly new code. So this Watch and Learn event will be focused almost exclusively on front-end Web development.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Some of the work has already been done, but there’s lots more to do. Our Web designer will be streaming the way they start by examining graphic design artifacts from the Free Software &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gimp.org/&quot;&gt;GNU Image Manipulation Program (GIMP)&lt;/a&gt;, a powerful alternative to Adobe Photoshop, translating them into liquid and dynamic layouts so that they work in a variety of Web browser makes, models, and sizes, and finally how they integrate the new code with our Web site’s simple Content Management System (CMS) called &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Along the way, you’ll get to see how an experienced front-end Web designer thinks about design elements like layout grids, how they organize and optimize Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) code, and how rich metadata in the form of semantic HTML markup makes their job easier.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;By attending, you get a front-row seat to the video livestream, along with access to a chat channel where you can ask questions about and offer feedback on the coding process live and in real time. We recommend that you have at least some familiarity with basic HTML and CSS code, as this is not a full-fledged class or workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a remote/online-only event, there is no physical class space, but attendance is still limited to 15 students, so &lt;a href=&quot;#tickets-event-2021-03-11-watch-and-learn-web-design-and-development-livestream&quot;&gt;purchase your ticket now&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate in our webinars, you will need access to a modern Web browser such as an up-to-date copy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need a reliable Internet connection. We recommend disabling Wi-Fi and plugging your computer in to a hard-wired Ethernet network cable for the duration of the webinar, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to share your video screen or appear on camera, you will need to have and activate your own camera, such as the one built-in to many modern laptops. Similarly, to speak with the rest of the webinar participants, you will need a microphone. If you do choose to activate your microphone, we ask that you please plug in headphones/ear buds or use a headset in order to help reduce audio feedback loops that can degrade the webinar experience for other participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;/faq/#workshops-and-webinars&quot;&gt;our workshops and webinars FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for additional tips and advice before you join the video conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Tech Learning Collective events, racism, queerphobia, transphobia, sexism, “brogrammer,” “manarchist,” or any kind of similarly awful behavior &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; result in immediate removal from class without a refund. Please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AnarchoTechNYC/meta/wiki/Social-rules&quot;&gt;our lightweight social rules&lt;/a&gt; for details on our strictly enforced no-tolerance policy against bigotry of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-tech-learning-collective&quot;&gt;About Tech Learning Collective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Learning Collective is an apprenticeship-based technology school that trains politically self-motivated individuals in the arts of hypermedia, Information Technology, and radical political practice. We offer unparalleled free, by-donation, and low-cost computer classes on topics ranging from fundamental computer literacy to the same offensive computer hacking techniques used by national intelligence agencies and military powers (cyber armies). For more information and to enroll, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;TechLearningCollective.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tech Learning Collective</name><email>techlearningcollective@riseup.net</email></author><summary type="html">Ever wanted to peek over the shoulder of an expert developer as they write code, to pick their brain while they solve real-life problems in real time, or simply bask in the comfort of watching an experienced craftsperson at work? Tech Learning Collective’s “Watch and Learn” events are your chance to join our staff as they livestream some of the work they do, such as redesigning our Web site, building out new or upgrading old infrastructure, and performing other (non-sensitive) tasks to keep Tech Learning Collective moving forward. It’s like watching Bob Ross paint, if he were painting with bits and bytes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/poster.web201.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://techlearningcollective.com/static/images/poster.web201.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>